import{_ as h,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as k,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as c,p,e as f,f as j,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},S={class:"review-title"},N={class:"review-content"};function T(e,a,s,d,t,u){return i(),o("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",S,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(k(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",N,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(k(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const I=h(q,[["render",T],["__scopeId","data-v-8bcf4f1d"]]),x=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"جمله زیر را کامل کن: قهرمان این دوره از مسابقات به‌طور مستقیم به مسابقات جام باشگاه‌های جهان ۲۰۱۶ که در ژاپن برگزار می‌شود صعود می‌کند. اگر یک تیم از کشور ژاپن قهرمان این دوره شود،","answer":"کشور ژاپن با دو سهمیه در رقابت‌های جام باشگاه‌های جهان حضور پیدا می‌کند."},{"question":"Ayda 500 TL yardım kimler alabilir?","answer":"Ödemeler aylık yapılmaktadır. Sosyal güvencesi olmayan ve aylık bağlanacak kişinin kendisi ve eşi dikkate alınmak suretiyle kişi başına düşen aylık geliri net asgari ücretin 1/3'ünden (2023 yılı için 3.800,78 TL) az olan 65 yaş üstü vatandaşlarımıza yapılan yardımlardır."},{"question":"2021年、メジャーリーグでアメリカンリーグの最優秀選手に選ばれた、二刀流で活躍するロサンゼルス・エンゼルスの選手は誰？","answer":"大谷翔平です。"},{"question":"¿De qué categoría es la pregunta?Pregunta: ¿Qué estado en los Estados Unidos tiene la mayor cantidad de lagos?Respuesta: ","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es geografía. "},{"question":"Ayat 1: Danijel Šarić (lahir 27 Julai, 1977 ) adalah penjaga gol bola tangan yang berasal dari Bosnia-Serb untuk Al Quiada dan pasukan kebangsaan Cataran. Ayat 2: Danijel Šarić (lahir 27 Julai 1977 ) adalah penjaga gol bola tangan Qatar yang berasal dari Bosnia Serbia untuk Al Quiada dan pasukan kebangsaan Qatar. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : ఏ అర్ధగోళంలో గరిష్ట సంఖ్యలో ఖండాలున్నాయి?","answer":"ఉత్తరార్ధగోళంలో గరిష్ట సంఖ్యలో ఖండాలున్నాయి."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa  qoomkii lagu halaagay isu galmoodka ragga?","answer":"Waa qoomkii Nebi Luud CS."},{"question":"\\"Kowe apa sida mangan ono warung?\\"Krama inggile saka ukara ing dhuwur iku ...A. Panjenengan apa sida nedo ing warung?B. Panjenengan punapa siyos dhahar wonten warung?C. Sampean punapa siyos nedi wonten warung?D. Sampean punapa sida dhahar ono warung?Jawaban: ","answer":"Jawaban: B. Panjenengan punapa siyos dhahar wonten warung?"},{"question":"アルゼンチン童話「みにくいアヒルの子」。本当は何の子だった？","answer":"白鳥です。"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"பார்ப்பான் உயிர் கடவுள் பொம்மையிலும், கல்லிலும் தான் இருக்கிறது."},{"question":"Question: అత్తలూరు గ్రామంలో అధికంగా పండే పంట ఏది?Answer the question with Yes or No. If it is not possible then answer None.Hint: అత్తలూరు, గుంటూరు జిల్లా, అమరావతి మండలానికి చెందిన గ్రామము. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన అమరావతి నుండి 14 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన సత్తెనపల్లి నుండి 29 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 1188 ఇళ్లతో, 4783 జనాభాతో 1524 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 2406, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 2377. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 1653 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 377. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 589939[2].పిన్ కోడ్: 522436.గ్రామ చరిత్రఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాజధాని ప్రాంత అభివృద్ధి ప్రాధికార సంస్థ (సీఆర్‌డీఏ) పరిధిలోకి వస్తున్న మండలాలు, గ్రామాలను ప్రభుత్వం విడిగా గుర్తిస్తూ ఉత్తర్వులు జారీచేసింది. ప్రస్తుతం గుర్తించిన వాటిలోని చాలా గ్రామాలు వీజీటీఎం పరిధిలో ఉన్నాయి. గతంలో వీజీటీఎం పరిధిలో ఉన్న వాటితోపాటుగా ఇప్పుడు మరిన్ని కొన్ని గ్రామాలు చేరాయి. సీఆర్‌డీఏ పరిధిలోకి వచ్చే గుంటూరు, కృష్ణా జిల్లాల్లోని మండలాలు, గ్రామాలను గుర్తిస్తూ పురపాలక శాఖ ముఖ్య కార్యదర్శి ఉత్తర్వులు జారీ చేశారు.[3]గుంటూరు జిల్లా పరిధిలోని మండలాలుతాడేపల్లి, మంగళగిరి, తుళ్లూరు, దుగ్గిరాల, తెనాలి, తాడికొండ, గుంటూరు మండలం, చేబ్రోలు, మేడికొండూరు, పెదకాకాని, వట్టిచెరుకూరు, అమరావతి, కొల్లిపర, వేమూరు, కొల్లూరు, అమృతలూరు, చుండూరు మండలాలతో పాటు ఆయా మండలాల పట్టణ ప్రాంతం కూడా సీఆర్‌డీఏ పరిధిలోకి వస్తుంది.అత్తలూరు ఆ చుట్టుపక్కల గ్రామాలకు మంచి విద్యా కేంద్రము. కమ్మ వారు ప్రధాన సామాజిక వర్గము గల గ్రామములో వ్యవసాయము వారి ముఖ్య వృత్తి. అత్తలూరు జిల్లా కేంద్రమైన గుంటూరు నుండి 50కి.మి మరియు అమరావతి నుండి 15కి.మి దూరమున ఉంది. శివారు గ్రామమైన నూతలపాటి వారి పాలెం, అత్తలూరు గ్రామ పంచాయితిలో అంతరభాగంగా ఉంది. పూర్వము అత్తలూరు 6 సామాజిక ప్రాంతాలుగా వుండేది.తూర్పు బజారునడిమ బజారుపడమటి బజారుపెద్ద పల్లెచిన్న పల్లెఎరుకల గుడిసెలుకాల గమనంలో గ్రామము కొత్త ప్లాటుల ద్వార విస్తరించినది. ఈ కొత్త ప్లాటులు అన్ని సామాజిక వర్గాలకు నిలయమై సరికొత్త గ్రామ జీవనవిధానానికి నెలవైనది. అత్తలూరు నాగార్జున సాగర్ జలాశయము యొక్క కుడి కాలువ ఆయకట్టున వుండుట చేత వ్యవసాయానికి నీటి యెద్దడి ఎక్కువగా ఉంది. ప్రస్తుతం ఏర్పాటు చేయబడిన ఎత్తిపొతల పధకము కొన్ని హెక్టారుల పంట భూమికి కృష్ణానది నీటిని సరఫరా చేస్తున్నవి.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాలలు నాలుగు, కలవు. ","answer":"None"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cepat tangan terjembakan, cepat kaki terlangkahkan, cepat mulut terkatakan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud jika melakukan sesuatu dengan tidak difikirkan buruk baiknya, boleh mendatangkan kesusahan"},{"question":"'Cha mama, nawe dadewethu, ngizoya laphaya kumthandazi njengoba nisho kodwamina ithemba lami elikhulu likuNonkamfela. Nokho-ke ukuze nigculiseke, okungconongibona kungcono siqale laphaya kumthandazi, kwaHlazakazi sengiyovukela khonaekuseni kusasa.''Cha fana, ngoba asikazilungisi kahle zonke izimfanelo zakhona, kungcono siye khonakusasa uma usubuya kwaHlazakazi.''Hhayi kulungile mama, kungcono ngisale sengikwenza konke khona kusasa ngobanakhu sengathi selishonile kanti nale ndlela ikude. Sengiyovuka ekuseni ukuzengisheshe ngibuye ngithole nethuba lokuya esayonini.'1. Uhlala kuphi uNokulindela ngokwalesi siqeshana?","answer":"KwaHlazakazi/Esigodini sakwaHlazakazi."},{"question":"isingumlando. Ngibonga kakhulu sayitsheni.Ubonga ngakhona Duma kodwa nguwe oyimbangela yalokhu.Usho ukuthini sayitsheni? Yimi yini ovimba intuthuko lapha kulendawo?Uyakhumbula ngikubuza ukuthi uyathathisa na enkosini umauzokwenza utho endaweni yayo? Wathini wena? Angithi wadazainkani? Nenhlangano yakho yaphinde yakuyala ngokuhlonipha inkosi,wena wenza okuthandwa nguwe. Bafile-ke manje abantu. UMbandlwasiyezwa ukuthi ubengungqa phambili ekutheni wenze lokhuobukwenza. Naye uDlamini kuyavela ukuthi ubethukuthela aze enzeizinto ezingalungile njengakho ukushaya uMbandlwa.Angimsoli-ke yena kakhulu ngoba ubehlukunyezwa ngukubona wenauthela inkosi yakhe ngothuli.(ukuzithoba kuyadlondlobala. Useze watshekisa ngisho nekhanda.Izandla zakhe ulokhu ezihlanganisa njengomuntu okhuluma nomuntuamhlonipha ngendlela exakile) Ngiyezwa sayitsheni. (athule kancane)Sekwenzekile-ke okubuhlungu sayitsheni. Ngiyaphinda ngithi velesekonakele. Manje, ngizocela nigcine ukuthula endaweni, minasengizowuyeka-ke lo msebenzi wobukhansela.(enyuse izwi ngenxa yentukuthelo) Uthini? Uyeke? Niqala izinto besenigabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele? Lutho! Wena yelekelelaekucisheni lo mlilo wothathe osuwokhele.Kahle sayitsheni. Ngizowucisha kanjani lo mlilo? Bazongibulala phelaabantu.1. Yikuphi kule ngxoxo engenhla okukhombisa ukuthi usayitsheni ubona ukuthinguDuma ongumphehli wodweshu kule ndawo?","answer":"USayitsheni uthi uDuma wenqaba ukuthathisa enkosini. √√/• Wadaza inkani nangesikhathi inhlangano yakhe imeluleka ukuthiakasebenzisane nenkosi.√ √/• Uthi baqala izinto bese begabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele. √√/• Uthi akamsoli uDlamini ngokushaya uMbandlwa ngoba ubehlukunyezwaukubona uDuma ethela inkosi yakhe ngothuli. √"},{"question":"Sunday Igboho yari: A maa bẹrẹ si i wọgbo lọọ ba awọn Fulani kaakiri ilẹ Yoruba","answer":"Gbajugbaja ajijagbara ilẹ Yoruba nni, Sunday Adeyẹmọ, ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, ti kede pe nibi tọrọ aabo to mẹhẹ lorileede yii de duro bayii, bẹrẹ lati ọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii, oun atawọn eeyan oun yoo bẹrẹ si i wọgbo lọọ ba awọn janduku agbebọn, awọn ajinigbe atawọn Fulani darandaran nibikibi ti wọn ba sa pamọ si.Ninu fidio kan to fi lede, nibi ti amugbalẹgbẹẹ ati agbẹnusọrọ rẹ, Ọgbẹni Ọlayọmi Koiki, ti fọrọ wa a lẹnu wo, Sunday Igboho ni asiko ti to wayi lati da iwa ọdaran awọn Fulani agbebọnrin duro nilẹ Yoruba.O ni, “Awọn eeyan ni ki n ma sọrọ pupọ mọ ni mo fi dakẹ tẹlẹ, ki i ṣe ti ojo. Ṣugbọn ni bayii, emi funra mi gan-an ni mo maa wọgbo lọọ ba awọn Fulani atawọn janduku agbebọn lati ọjọ Mọnde yii lọ. Iṣẹ ti bẹrẹ bayii. Ko sọrọ bandiiti (bandits) mọ, ko si pe ẹnikan n gbegi dina, tabi jiiyan gbe mọ.Ọkunrin naa leri pe gbogbo nnkan ija awọn agbebọn naa lawọn maa gba lọwọ wọn tabi kawọn sọ ọ di otubantẹ mọ wọn lọwọ.“Gbogbo inu igbo ilẹ Yoruba la maa fẹ atẹgun si, gbogbo ibi tawọn kọlọransi naa ba wa ni wọn ti maa jade wa, a maa jẹwọ Yoruba fun wọn.”"},{"question":"what important event is this text about: Το Εθνικό Απελευθερωτικό Μέτωπο (ΕΑΜ) είναι ένα πολιτικό κόμμα της Αλγερίας το οποίο προέκυψε από το προηγούμενο απελευθερωτικό κίνημα της χώρας.","answer":"Εθνικό Απελευθερωτικό Μέτωπο Αλγερίας"},{"question":"Fundisisa le nkondlo bese uphendula imibuzo elandelayo.UMZUZWANA OWODWA NJE – EJ MhlangaNkosi ngisize, ngiqinise,Ngiph' umzuzwana owodwa nje,Nom' umzuzwana kuwenaUyiminyakanyak' engabalwa,Ngenyule kuleli fokozanaElifuswa yisisi senzondo,Ngiqinis' ungiph' amandlaNanxa sebengivukel' abakwethu,Bengigenca ngezimbemba zomona,Bengisunduzel' eweni lokufa:Ngifez' owangijubela khona,Lokh' umngenandlini uyafuneka,Sengibhekene nesihlalo sakho sokwahlulela,Ungahlulela ngemisebenzi yami.1. Nikeza ukuxhumana okutholakala","answer":"1. Ngiph' umzuzwana owodwa nje,Nom' umzuzwana kuwenaUkuxhumana-maphakathi"},{"question":"Австралия бандикуттары булар ...","answer":"Австралия бандикуттары (лат. Peramelidae) — ичке тумшук, узун кулак, баштыкчан майда айбандардын бир тукуму; ичке тумшук, узун кулак, баштыкчан майда айбандардын бир тукуму; булардын кыйла уруусу жана түрү бар: кадимки узун мурун бандикут (лат. Perameles nasuta), кадимки чолок мурун бандикут (Isoodan obesulus), доңузаяк бандикут (Chaeropus ecaudatus), узун тумшук бандикуттар (Perameles) (уруу), чолок тумшук бандикуттар (Isoodan) (уруу) ж.у.с."},{"question":"અહીં ગુજરાતી નાટક ના કલાકારો વચ્ચેની વાતો નીચે મુજબ આપેલી છે:\\"રાજા: અમારા ઉપર મહાદેવજી પ્રસન્ન છે તેથી આશા છે કે જરૂર આંખ્યો સારી કરીશું.ભીમ૦: નહીં તો પેલા નથુડા હજામ પાસે લેઈ જઈને ખોતરાવીશું એટલે આંખ્યો સારી થશે કોડા જેવી.લક્ષ્મી: મહાદેવે તમને એ વાતનો કાંઈ અભિપ્રાય આપ્યો છે ?ભીમડો: અરે માંહી મરચાં ભરશું, એટલે તરત સારી થશે.રાજા: તમારે તેનું શું કામ છે, તમારે આંખ્યોનું કામ છે કે બીજું કાંઈ ?લક્ષ્મી: સાંભળો ત્યારે.રાજા: અરે માજી તમારે એ વાતની કાંઈ ચિંતા રાખવી નહીં એ કામ કરવું અમારા માથાસાટે છે.ભીમડો: કહેશો તો હું પણ એ કામમાં કાંઈ કરવા લાગીશ. અને આંખ્યો કરાવીશું રૂપાળી ઘુડના જેવી.\\"આ કલાકારો ની આગળની વાતો શું હશે?","answer":"રાજા: વળી જગતમાં અન્યાયની કમાણી ન કરનારા દરિદ્રી થયા છે તે લોકો પણ સૌ સહાય કરશે.લક્ષ્મી: એ બિચારા શી સહાય કરશે ?રાજા: તે લોકોને ધન મળશે, એટલે ગરીબે છે, તે તુરત મોટા થશે, અરે ભીમડા તું ઊતાવળો જા.ભીમડો: શું કરવા સારૂં ?રાજા: દાજીભાઈ મુખીને બોલાવ એને પણ હમણાં દીકરો પરણાવા સારૂ ઘર ફુલચંદશેઠને ઘેર ડુલ થાય છે માટે તેને પણ દયાળુ માતાજી ભાગ આપશે.ભીમડો: હું જાઊં છું ત્યારે તમે અને એ ડોશી મારો આ રોટલો ઝાલી રાખજો.રાજા: સારૂં જા. પણ દોડતો જજે (પછી ભીમડો ગયો.) ​રાજા: માતાજી તમો ભલાં થઈને આપણા ઘરમાં પધારો, આજ આ ઘરમાં ગમે તેમ કરીને પણ ધન મેળવવું છે.લક્ષ્મી: હે દૈવ મારા કરમનો કાંઈ પાર આવ્યો નહીં, મારે પારકા ઘરમાં જઈને રેહેવું પડે છે, વળી કોઈ લોભિયાને ઘેર જાઊં છું ત્યારે મને પ્રથ્વીમાં ખોદી ઘાલે છે; ને તેને ઘેર કોઈ સજ્જન લોક માગવા આવે તો કેહેશે કે અમે તો કોઈ દહાડે લક્ષ્મી નજરે દેખતા નથી, અને હું કોઈ દેવાળિયાને ઘેર જઊં છું તો મને કશબણને ઘેર સુંપે છે અથવા જુગટું રમવામાં નાંખી દે છે.રાજા: પણ માતાજી તમે અમ જેવા લોકોને ઘેર આજ સુધી ગયાં નથી, અમે તમને કશબણને ઘેર આપનાર નહીં પ્રથ્વીમાં ડાટનાર નહીં, અમે તો સારે માર્ગે વાવરનારા, હમણાં ચાલો અમારા ઠકરાલાંને તથા કુંવરજીને તમે મળો, પ્રથમ અમારાં વાલેશરી તમે છો, અને પછી તે છે.લક્ષ્મી: તે હશે.રાજા: હશે નહીતો અહિ જુઠું બોલવામાં શો લાભ છે.લક્ષ્મી: હું જાણું છું કે, લાભ વિના તમે જરૂર જુઠું નહીં બોલો."},{"question":"Kodi nsomba yodziwika kwambiri ku Malawi ndi iti?","answer":"1) Mbuna CichlidsNsomba zodziwika kwambiri ku Malawi ndi cichlids za ku Africa, nsomba zamitundumitundu. Gulu limodzi la ma cichlids omwe amapezeka ku Nyanja ya Malawi ndi mbuna cichild kapena \\"rockfish\\". Pali mitundu 295 ya mbuna mu Nyanja ya Malawi mokha."},{"question":"フィギュアスケートや体操などでも行われる勝ち負け関係なしでおこなわれる特別実演のことをなんという？","answer":"エキシビションです。"},{"question":"Trái ngược với El Niño là hiện tượng gì? Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi trên trong những câu sau:A. El NiñaB. El LañaC. La Niña","answer":"Đáp án: C. La NiñaGiải thích: Theo Cơ quan Quản lý Khí quyển và Đại dương Quốc gia Mỹ (NOAA), La Niña có nghĩa là \\"cô bé\\" trong tiếng Tây Ban Nha. La Niña đôi khi còn được gọi là El Viejo, anti-El Niño, hay \\"sự kiện lạnh giá\\". La Niña có tác động ngược lại với El Niño. Trong các sự kiện La Niña, gió mậu dịch thậm chí còn mạnh hơn bình thường, đẩy nhiều nước ấm hơn về phía châu Á. Ngoài khơi bờ biển phía tây của châu Mỹ, nước trồi tăng lên, mang nước lạnh, giàu chất dinh dưỡng lên bề mặt.El Niño, La Niña là hai nửa của chu kỳ dao động phương Nam (ENSO) có ảnh hưởng lớn đến các kiểu khí hậu ở nhiều nơi trên thế giới. ENSO là sự dao động tự nhiên nhiệt độ đại dương ở trung tâm và phía đông xích đạo Thái Bình Dương, cùng với những thay đổi trong khí quyển.El Niño và La Niña đều có thể có tác động toàn cầu đến thời tiết, cháy rừng, hệ sinh thái và nền kinh tế. Các đợt El Niño và La Niña thường kéo dài từ 9 đến 12 tháng, nhưng đôi khi có thể kéo dài hàng năm. El Niño xảy ra thường xuyên hơn La Niña."},{"question":"د ادم سمیټ کار د کلاسیک اقتصاد په پراختیا او د وروستیو اقتصاد پوهانو نظرونو باندې څه اغیزه درلوده؟","answer":"د ادم سمیټ کار د کلاسیک اقتصاد بنسټ کېښود، د فکر یو ښوونځی چې په راتلونکو اقتصادي مفکرینو یې خورا اغیز وکړ. د آزاد بازارونو مفکورې، پټ لاس، او د کار ویش د کلاسیک اقتصاد اصلي اصول وګرځیدل. وروسته اقتصاد پوهانو، لکه ډیویډ ریکارډو او جان سټوارټ مل، د سمیټ نظرونه جوړ او پراخ کړل، د کلاسیک اقتصادي تیورۍ بنسټ یې جوړ کړ."},{"question":"මයිකල් ක්ලාක් දේශීය මට්ටමින් ක්‍රිකට් නියෝජනය කළේ කුමන ප්‍රාන්තයද?","answer":"මයිකල් ක්ලාක් ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩාවේ දේශීය මට්ටමින් නිව් සවුත් වේල්ස් ප්‍රාන්තය නියෝජනය කළේය."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී දළදා මාළිගාව යනු කුමක් ද?  බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේගේ වම් දන්තධාතූන් වහන්සේ වර්තමානයේ තැන්පත් කර ඇති මාළිගාවයි. වර්තමාන දළදා මාළිගාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මහනුවර නගරයේ පිහිටා ඇත. ","answer":"ශ්‍රී දළදා මාළිගාව යනු බෞද්ධාගමිකයන් පූජා භූමියකි. බෞද්ධාගමිකයන්ගේ ශාස්තෘන් වහන්සේ වන බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේගේ වම් දන්තධාතූන් වහන්සේ වර්තමානයේ එහි තැන්පත් කර තිබේ. වර්තමාන දළදා මාළිගාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මහනුවර නගරයේ පිහිටා ඇත. "},{"question":"Descreva a sensação de alegria ao ver um ente querido após muito tempo.","answer":"O coração disparou ao avistar o rosto familiar. Um abraço apertado selou a saudade enquanto sorrisos iluminavam nos seus olhos. A alegria do reencontro encheu o ar de emoção e calor."},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, Buruji ti rele ikẹyin, ọmọ Kasamu ti wọ kaa ilẹ lọ","answer":"Beeyan ba jẹ ori ahun, to ba de ibi isinku ọkunrin olowo nla ati oloṣelu pataki ipinlẹ Ogun nni, Sẹnetọ Buruji Kashamu, lonii, ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọjọ kẹsan-an, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun 2020 yii, tọhun yoo sunkun kikoro lai mọ ọkunrin naa ri tẹlẹ.Niṣe lero n wọ bii omi ninu ọkan ninu awọn ile rẹ ti wọn sin in si n’Ijẹbu-Igbo. Ẹkun n pe ẹkun ran niṣẹ ni, bẹẹ lawọn eeyan to lọ rẹpẹtẹ, ti wọn n fọhun aro, kaluku n sọ ohun ti wọn padanu bi iku ṣe mu Baba Ṣẹri ti wọn n pe ni alaaanu mẹkunnu lọ.Ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ni gudugbẹ ja lojiji, ti iroyin ọhun kọkọ n lọ labẹnu pe Ẹshọ Jinadu, bi wọn ṣe tun maa n pe Buruji, jade laye.Awuyewuye lo kọkọ jọ tẹlẹ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọkunrin ọmọ Ijẹbu-Igbo naa ti wa lọsibitu nla kan niluu Eko tojọ mẹta, to n gba itọju lori aisan Korona to mu un.Ṣugbọn ko sẹni to ro iku ro Buruji, ko sẹni to mọ pe erin yoo wo logun ọdun, nitori wọn ni o ti gbadun ti Korona yii, wọn ni awọn arun kan to ti wa lara rẹ tẹlẹ ni wọn n tọju. Afi bi ajanaku ṣe sun bii oke lojiji, ti Buruji Kashamu ṣe bẹẹ jade laye.Alẹ Satide ni wọn ti gbe oku de siluu Ijẹbu-Igbo, wọn ti gbẹ koto silẹ nigba ti yoo fi di aarọ, bẹẹ lero n ya bii omi lati igba to ti di mimọ pe Ẹshọ Jinadu ti jade laye.Nigba to si jẹ pe koto loore oku, ko tun si oore mi-in tawọn ara aye ri ṣe fẹni to ku ju ki wọn gbe e si koto naa lọ. Eyi naa lo fa a ti ẹbi Shodipẹ Kashamu ti Ijẹbu-igbo, nipinlẹ Ogun, ko ṣe fi isinku ọmọ wọn falẹ, ti wọn gbe e sin tẹkun-tẹkun lonii, ti i ṣe ọjọ Aiku.Ni nnkan bii aago kan ọsan ku iṣẹju mẹtala ni wọn gbe Buruji wọ kaa ilẹ lọ, awọn aafaa agba nipinlẹ Ogun lo ṣeto isinku, Imaamu Mukaeel Shile Rufai lo ṣe waasi. Bẹẹ lawọn oloṣẹlu nipinlẹ Ogun bii Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun,Sẹnetọ Gbenga Kaka, Ọmọọba Ṣẹgun Adeṣẹgun, Sẹnetọ Lekan Mustapha atawọn mi-in wa nibẹ.Ọpọlọpọ eeyan lo ti n ba wọn kẹdun nile awọn Buruji, bẹrẹ latori Gomina ipinlẹ Ogun, Ọmọọba Dapọ Abiọdun, Sẹnetọ Ibikunle Amosun. Ọtunba Gbenga Daniel tilẹ ni inu oun dun pe oun ti fori ji Kashamu ko too ku, bẹẹ ni Gboyega Nasir Isiaka naa fi ọrọ ibanikẹdun ranṣẹ."},{"question":"Lyta","answer":"Babatunde Rahim, tí orúkọ ìnagijẹ̀ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Lyta, jẹ́ olórin orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó tẹwọ́bọ̀wé iṣẹ́ pẹ̀lú YBNL Nation, ní ọdún 2018, àmọ́ ó kúrò lẹ́yìn èdè-àìyedè tó wáyé láàárín òun àti ẹni tó ní ilé-iṣẹ́ náà, ìyẹn Olamide. Ó ṣàgbéjáde àwo-orin olórin márùn-ún, EP Id, ní ọdún 2019."},{"question":"Aiza no misy ny toeram-pitrandrahana vato sarobidy eto Magasikara?","answer":"Ilakaka no ivon' ny fitrandrahana vato sarobidy eto Madagasikara."},{"question":"\\"වට්ටෝරු වෙදා\\" ,මෙම සාම්ප්‍රදායික යෙදුමේ අදහස කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ආයුර්වේද යේ කසාය වර්ග වලින් ප්‍රතිකාර කරන අය සහ නිශ්පාදනය කරන ලද බෙහෙත් වලින් ප්‍රතිකාර කරන අය , කියල කොටස් දෙකක් ඉන්නව . එයින් පලමු කොටස වට්ටෝරු වෙදුන් ලෙස සැලකිය හැකි . ඔවුන් රෝග නිස්චය කර වට්ටෝරු ලියල දෙනව .(ඔවුන්ගේ දැනුම මත ) . අනෙක් අය රෝග නිස්චය කර , නිශ්පාදනය කල බෙහෙත් දෙනවා නිශ්පාදකයාගේ නිර්දේශය මත . ඒඅනුව බුද්දිමත් නිවැරදි ප්‍රතිකාර කරන්නේ වට්ටෝරු වෙදාය ."},{"question":"విద్వాన్ విశ్వం కవితను ప్రశంసిస్తూ మిత్రునికి లేఖ రాయండి.","answer":"మిత్రునకు లేఖగుంటూరు,x x x x xమిత్రుడు రామారావునకు,శుభాభినందనలు. నీ లేఖ అందింది. నేను ఈ మధ్య విద్వాన్ విశ్వంగారి ‘మాణిక్యవీణ’ వచన కవిత చదివాను. విశ్వంగారు గొప్ప కవి పండితుడు. ఆయన ‘విశ్వరూపి నా హృదయం’ అని ప్రకటించుకున్నాడు. ఈ కవితలో చక్కని అభ్యుదయ భావాలు వెలిబుచ్చాడు.మానవులు కేన్సరుతో బాధపడుతూ ఉంటే, దానికి మందులు కనుక్కోకుండా, రోదసిలోకి ఉపగ్రహాలు పంపడం వల్ల ప్రయోజనం ఏముంటుందని శాస్త్రజ్ఞులను ప్రశ్నించాడు.తంత్రాలతో సమాజ సమస్యలు దారికి రావని హెచ్చరించాడు. శాస్త్రజ్ఞులు నిప్పునూ, చక్రాన్ని కనిపెట్టినరోజు నిజంగా, మానవ చరిత్రలో పండుగరోజు అని గుర్తు చేశాడు.మానవ జీవితాన్ని కళలూ, కవిత్వం, విజ్ఞానం నడిపిస్తాయన్న యథార్థాన్ని విశ్వంగారు చెప్పాడు.వచన కవితా రచనలో ఆయన చిన్న చిన్న పదాలతో లోతైన భావాలను తేలికగా అందించాడు.విశ్వంగారు మాణిక్యవీణను మీటి, మానవీయ రాగాల్ని పలికించాడు. చక్కని లలిత పదాలతో, అనుప్రాసలతో కవిత మనోహరంగా చెప్పాడు.తప్పక నీవు ఈ కవిత చదువు. ఉంటా.ఇట్లు,నీ ప్రియమిత్రుడు,యన్. శ్రీకాంత్.చిరునామా :యస్. రామారావు,S/o యస్: కృష్ణారావుగారు,రామారావు పేట,కాకినాడ, తూర్పుగోదావరి జిల్లా."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe Repoblika fahadimy frantsay?","answer":"Ny Repoblika fahadimy no fitondrana ara-politikan’i Frantsa amin’izao fotoana izao, naorin’ny Lalàm-panorenana tamin’ny taona 1958 teo ambany fitarihan’ny Jeneraly Charles de Gaulle."},{"question":"બંગાળની ખાડી વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"બંગાળની ખાડી  એ એશિયા ખંડમાં આવેલ એક દરિયાઈ ખાડી છે. તે હિંદ મહાસાગરનો ઉત્તર-પૂર્વ ભાગ છે. આ ખાડીના પૂર્વ ભાગમાં મલય દ્વિપકલ્પ છે અને તે ભારત દેશના ઉત્તર-પૂર્વભાગના પશ્ચિમ ભાગમાં છે. આ ખાડીનો આકાર ત્રિકોણ જેવો છે. આ ખાડીના ઉત્તર ભાગમાં ભારતનું પશ્ચિમ બંગાળ રાજ્ય અને બાંગ્લા દેશ આવેલ હોવાને કારણે તે ''બંગાળની ખાડી'' અથવા ''બંગાળાની ખાડી'' તરીકે ઓળખાય છે"},{"question":"मद्रास में परिषद चुनावों का बहिष्कार क्यों नहीं किया गया?","answer":"मद्रास को छोड़कर अधिकांश प्रांतों में परिषद के चुनावों का बहिष्कार किया गया था, जहां न्याय दल, गैर-ब्राह्मणों की पार्टी ने महसूस किया कि परिषद में प्रवेश करना कुछ शक्ति हासिल करने का एक तरीका था कुछ ऐसा जो आमतौर पर केवल ब्राह्मणों के पास था।"},{"question":"قم بكتابة مقال يجيب على هذا السؤال من هو مخترع نظام الند للند ؟.","answer":"جامعه كاليفورنيا، معهد ايرفين لبحوث البرمجيات مشروع \\"تيره\\" هو خلق \\"النمط المعماري لإدارة الثقة في التطبيقات اللامركزية\\". واعتمدت تعريف \\"روهيت خليس\\" اللامركزية: \\"النظام اللامركزي هو الذي يتطلب من الأطراف المتعددة اتخاذ قراراتها المستقلة\\" وتطبيقها علي إنشاء البرمجيات من الند إلى الند، كتابه:"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਗੁਆਰੇਰੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਗੁਰ ਸੇਵਾ ਜੁਗ ਚਾਰੇ ਹੋਈ ॥ਪੂਰਾ ਜਨੁ ਕਾਰ ਕਮਾਵੈ ਕੋਈ ॥ਅਖੁਟੁ ਨਾਮ ਧਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਤੋਟਿ ਨ ਹੋਈ ॥ਐਥੈ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਦਰਿ ਸੋਭਾ ਹੋਈ ॥੧॥ਏ ਮਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਰਮੁ ਨ ਕੀਜੈ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੇਵਾ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਰਸੁ ਪੀਜੈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਹਿ ਸੇ ਮਹਾਪੁਰਖ ਸੰਸਾਰੇ ॥ਆਪਿ ਉਧਰੇ ਕੁਲ ਸਗਲ ਨਿਸਤਾਰੇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਰਖਹਿ ਉਰ ਧਾਰੇ ॥ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਭਉਜਲ ਉਤਰਹਿ ਪਾਰੇ ॥੨॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਹਿ ਸਦਾ ਮਨਿ ਦਾਸਾ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਮਾਰਿ ਕਮਲੁ ਪਰਗਾਸਾ ॥ਅਨਹਦੁ ਵਾਜੈ ਨਿਜ ਘਰਿ ਵਾਸਾ ॥ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਘਰ ਮਾਹਿ ਉਦਾਸਾ ॥੩॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਹਿ ਤਿਨ ਕੀ ਸਚੀ ਬਾਣੀ ॥ਜੁਗੁ ਜੁਗੁ ਭਗਤੀ ਆਖਿ ਵਖਾਣੀ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਜਪਹਿ ਹਰਿ ਸਾਰੰਗਪਾਣੀ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਨਿਹਕੇਵਲ ਨਿਰਬਾਣੀ ॥੪॥੧੩॥੩੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 161 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਨਿਯਮ ਸਦਾ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਚਲਿਆ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ (ਚੌਹਾਂ ਜੁਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਪਰਵਾਨ ਹੈ) ।ਕੋਈ ਪੂਰਨ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਕਾਰ (ਪੂਰੀ ਸ਼ਰਧਾ ਨਾਲ) ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਕਾਰ ਪੂਰੀ ਸ਼ਰਧਾ ਨਾਲ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ) ਕਦੇ ਨਾਹ ਮੁਕਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ (ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਧਨ ਵਿਚ ਕਦੇ) ਘਾਟਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦਾ ।(ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਇਸ ਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੋਭਾ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਉਤੇ) ਸ਼ੱਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ,ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਰਸ ਪੀਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਮਹਾ ਪੁਰਖ ਮੰਨੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ,ਉਹ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੰੁਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਆਪ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਕੁਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ,ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ (ਦੇ ਰੰਗ) ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੰੁਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨।ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ (ਸਭਨਾਂ ਦੇ) ਦਾਸ ਬਣੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ,ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਹਿਰਦਾ-ਕਮਲ ਖਿੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ (ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਵਾਜਾ) ਇਕ-ਰਸ ਵੱਜਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗ੍ਰਿਹਸਤ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਭੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਤੋਂ ਨਿਰਲੇਪ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੩।ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਉਚਾਰੀ ਹੋਈ) ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਅਟੱਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਹਰੇਕ ਜੁਗ ਵਿਚ (ਸਦਾ ਹੀ) ਭਗਤ ਜਨ ਉਹ ਬਾਣੀ ਉਚਾਰ ਕੇ (ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ) ਸੁਣਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਸਾਰੰਗ-ਪਾਣੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਵਾਸਨਾ-ਰਹਿਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।੧੩।੩੩।\\""},{"question":"\\" චර්‍යා පිටක ග්‍රන්ථය \\" යනු කුමක්ද ?","answer":"\\" චර්‍යා පිටක ග්‍රන්ථය \\" යනු ජාතක කතා පොත ය."},{"question":"Апыртма жалган калп деген сөздөрдү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Апыртма аркылуу жалганды айырмалап билүү калпты тануу. Адамдын аң-сезиминде көркөм элес калтыруу менен ой жүгүртүүсүн фантазиясын, кыял чабытын байытуу. Мисалы,Таштан 🪨 тарам кечтим,Кумдан🏜️ аркан 🧶 эштим.Китти  🐳минип мухитте🏊‍♀️ сүздүм,Акула 🦈 менен жарышка түштүм,Секирип айга 🌛жеттим,Ал жакта селкинчек тептим."},{"question":"من آخر من توفى من الصحابة ؟","answer":"أنس بن مالك ."},{"question":"هل توجد فلسطين في القاره الاوروبيه؟","answer":"لا، فلسطين لا تقع في القارة الأوروبية. فلسطين تقع في جنوب غرب قارة آسيا وتحدها من الشمال البحر الأبيض المتوسط، ومن الغرب البحر الأبيض المتوسط والبحر الأحمر ومصر، ومن الشمال الأردن، ومن الشرق الأردن."},{"question":"*مما خلق الله الملائكة ؟","answer":"من النور"},{"question":"Can you summarize the following document?        The National Theater of Korea was established in 1950 by the government of South Korea and hosts the National Drama Company of Korea, which performs both Korean and international plays; the National Changgeuk Company of Korea, which performs traditional Korean \\"changgeuk\\"; the National Dance Company of Korea; and the National Orchestra Company of Korea.  The Youth Performing Arts Festival of the National Theater, held every April until May, is a festival for youth. With the theme ‘Youth Embracing the Sky,’ the festival contributes to fostering the positive emotions of youth through programs allowing the experience of traditional dance music, musicals, mime, plays, and dance of both Korean and international classics. In 2008, when the first festival was held, \\"The Journey to Folksong with Suksun Ahn\\" was performed for youth and multi-cultural families in culturally neglected areas. The Youth Performing Arts Festival is the signature event of the National Theater, with the goal of inspiring those who will be the future leaders of society and the performing arts.Starting in 2007, the World Festival of National Theaters takes place from September to October every year. The festival promotes the mutual understanding of cultures from every country, whereby Korean audiences can enjoy many excellent domestic and overseas performances. At the same time, the National Theater of Korea can better solidify its position as the center of performing arts in Korea. Performances representing national theaters of various nations are on stage, along with additional events like shows and exhibitions. National theaters, embassies, and cultural centers of every country gather here for active cultural and artistic communication. The World Festival of National Theaters is the biggest festival hosted by the National Theater of Korea and is considered by some to be one of the greatest festivals in Korea.Since 1993, the Saturday Cultural Plaza has been the oldest open-air performance by the National Theater. Various concerts and performances, such as ballets, concerts of contemporary music, and orchestra concerts, are held in the open-air cultural plaza every May to September on Saturdays at 6:00 p.m.So far, 350 thousand people have visited the Saturday Cultural Plaza. From 2002 to 2007, the Plaza was sponsored by Renault-Samsung Motors and, starting in 2008, by KB Kookmin Bank, which received the Mecenat Award in 2008. This activity aspires to serve as a model of partnership between art and business.The Midday Concert was designed to show the potential of traditional classical music so the public can easily understand Korean music’s past and present. Folksongs, contemporary music, and original sound tracks of soap operas and films are rearranged and modernized by the National Orchestra. Commentaries on each work by the artistic director Byeongki Hwang in order to enrich the concert’s content.The National Theater of Korea provides various events every spring, summer, fall, and winter.","answer":"The National Theater of Korea is a national theater located in the neighborhood of Jangchung-dong, Jung-gu, South Korea. It is the first nationally managed theater in Asia."},{"question":" ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ නිෂ්පාදි​ත \\"ෆයිසර්\\" එන්නත තම රටේ වැසියන් වෙත ලබා දු​න් පළමුවැනි ආසියානු රට කුමක්ද?","answer":" ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ නිෂ්පාදි​ත \\"ෆයිසර්\\" එන්නත තම රටේ වැසියන් වෙත ලබා දු​න් පළමුවැනි ආසියානු රට සිංගප්පූරුවයි. සිංගප්පූරුව මෙම එන්නත 2020 දෙසැම්බර් 14 වන දින තම රට වැසියන් සඳ​හා අනුමත කරන ලදී."},{"question":"Wie is Hadley Irwin?","answer":"Hadley Irwin was het pseudoniem van een schrijversduo, bestaande uit Lee Hadley (Earlham (Iowa), 10 oktober 1934 - 22 augustus 1995) en Annabelle Irwin (Peterson (Iowa), 8 oktober 1915 - 13 september 1998), beiden hoogleraar Engels aan de Iowa State University. Hun boek Abby, My Love uit 1985 wordt beschouwd als het eerste jeugdboek over incest/seksueel misbruik."},{"question":"Giáo sư Ngô Bảo Châu bảo vệ luận án tiến sĩ năm bao nhiêu tuổi?","answer":"Năm 1989, ông sang Pháp học tại Đại học Paris 6. Ông bảo vệ luận án tiến sĩ khi 25 tuổi tại Đại học Sư phạm Paris - ngôi trường danh tiếng bậc nhất nước Pháp. Năm 2003, ở tuổi 31, giáo sư hoàn thành luận án habilitation (tương đương tiến sĩ khoa học) tại Đại học Paris 11. Đầu năm sau ông trở thành giáo sư của đại học này.Ngô Bảo Châu được phong hàm giáo sư tại Việt Nam vào năm 2005 và trở thành giáo sư trẻ nhất của Việt Nam khi nhận chức danh này ở tuổi 33."},{"question":"平成元年に消費税を導入した時の首相は竹下登、ではその孫で女優北川景子と結婚したミュージシャンは誰？","answer":"ＤＡＩＧＯです。"},{"question":"ما هو السؤال للجملة التالية: \\"المستوحى من رواية ستيفن كينغ \\"ريتا هايورث\\" و\\"شاوشانك ريدمبشن\\" الفيلم يروي قصة \\"آندي دوفريز\\" مصرفي يقضي ما يقرب من عقدين في سجن ولاية \\"شاوشانك\\" لقتل زوجته وعشيقها على الرغم من ادعاءات براءته\\" الموضوع هو \\"مصرفي\\"","answer":"ماذا كانت وضيفة آندي دوفريز؟"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഒരു ഫ്ലാറ്റ് ടയർ എങ്ങനെ ശെരിയാകാം?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഒരു ഫ്ലാറ്റ് ടയർ ശരിയാക്കാൻ ഈ ഘട്ടങ്ങൾ പാലിക്കുക:1. നിങ്ങളുടെ വാഹനത്തിലെ സ്പെയർ ടയർ, ജാക്ക്, ലഗ് റെഞ്ച് എന്നിവ കണ്ടെത്തുക. 2. ഫ്ലാറ്റ് ടയറിലെ ലഗ് നട്ട്സ് അഴിക്കാൻ ലഗ് റെഞ്ച് ഉപയോഗിക്കുക. 3. വാഹനം നിലത്തു നിന്ന് ഉയർത്താൻ ജാക്ക് ഉപയോഗിക്കുക. 4. ലഗ് നട്ടുകളും ഫ്ലാറ്റ് ടയറും നീക്കം ചെയ്യുക. 5. സ്പെയർ ടയർ ഇൻസ്റ്റാൾ ചെയ്ത് ലഗ് നട്ട്സ് ശക്തമാക്കുക. 6. വാഹനം തിരികെ നിലത്തേക്ക് താഴ്ത്തി ലഗ് നട്ടുകൾ സുരക്ഷിതമായി മുറുക്കുക."},{"question":"Ajụjụ: Ònye bụ onye mbụ bụrụ abụ 'It's a wonderful world?'Azịza ya:","answer":"Onye bụ onye mbụ bụrụ abụ 'It's a wonderful world' bụ Louis Armstrong."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Sáp nhập 3 trường thành Đại học Nghệ An","answer":"UBND tỉnh Nghệ An vừa có quyết định phê duyệt chiến lược phát triển bền vững giáo dục và đào tạo Nghệ An đến năm 2030, tầm nhìn đến năm 2045. Trong chiến lược phát triển này, Nghệ An thực sự coi giáo dục là quốc sách hàng đầu. Phát triển bền vững giáo dục và đào tạo gắn với phát triển kinh tế, xã hội của địa phương. Theo đó, các trường Đại học kinh tế Nghệ An; Cao đẳng Sư phạm Nghệ An và Cao đẳng Văn hóa nghệ thuật Nghệ An sẽ được sáp nhập và đổi tên thành trường Đại học Nghệ An. Đến năm 2025, Nghệ An tái cơ cấu các trường đại học, cao đẳng trên địa bàn thành trường đại học lớn của tỉnh. Đến năm 2030 phát triển theo hướng chuẩn hóa khu vực và quốc tế. Đến năm 2045, Nghệ An trở thành trung tâm đào tạo của khu vực Bắc Trung Bộ và cả nước. Bên cạnh đó, với giáo dục phổ thông, Nghệ An tiếp tục sáp nhập trường lớp gắn với chủ trương sáp nhập địa bàn hành chính; dồn dịch các điểm trường. Tỉnh đặt mục tiêu giảm từ 23 - 25 trường, 35 - 65 điểm trường và 50 - 70% lớp ghép. Nghệ An có hơn 1.000 điểm trường. Do đó, điểm trường được dồn dịch nhằm tập trung nguồn lực xây dựng cơ sở vật chất, nâng cao chất lượng đội ngũ giáo viên. Ngoài ra, Nghệ An đặt mục tiêu giáo dục đến năm 2030 có ít nhất 80% trường đạt chuẩn quốc gia, xây dựng được 20% trường mầm non, phổ thông tự chủ, tiên tiến theo xu thế hội nhập quốc tế... Nghệ An phấn đấu đến năm 2030, có ít nhất một trường phổ thông quốc tế, Đại học Nghệ An được xếp hạng khu vực quốc tế. Có đủ 100% phòng học, phòng chức năng kiên cố và bán kiên cố, trong đó 15% cơ sở có phòng học thông minh. Tỷ lệ huy động đảm bảo yêu cầu phổ cập giáo dục mầm non cho trẻ 3 tuổi, duy trì mức độ phổ cập đã đạt, trong đó có 45% đơn vị đạt phổ cập giáo dục Trung học cơ sở mức độ 3. Nghệ An phấn đấu nâng chất lượng giáo dục toàn diện của tỉnh lên vị trí thứ 15 toàn quốc từ vị trí khoảng 20 hiện nay và dẫn đầu các tỉnh Bắc Trung Bộ. Tỉnh đặt mục tiêu xây dựng một trường phổ thông quốc tế và đại học của Nghệ An được xếp hạng khu vực, quốc tế."},{"question":"Aṣiri tu! Wọn ni biliọnu kan Naira lawọn kan ti gba lọwọ ijọba nitori iwọde SARS","answer":"Nibi ti ẹmi awọn eeyan kan ti ṣofozeem nibi iwọde to n lọ kaakiri Naijiria, owo biliọnu rẹpẹtẹ ni wọn sọ pe awọn eeyan kan ti fi gba sapo ara wọn bayii lọwọ ijọba.Latigba ti iwọde ti bẹrẹ kaakiri orilẹ-ede yii, ti awon eeyan da ibinu bolẹ wi pe awon ko fẹ ajọ SARS mọ, iroyin to gba igboro kan bayii ni pe, aimọye biliọnu owo naira lawọn olokoowo nla kan tawọn mi-in ti wọn n dari awọn ọdọ kan ti gba sapo bayii.Ninu ọrọ ti Ọmọyẹle Ṣoworẹ, ọga agba to nileese iroyin Sahara Reporters sọ lo ti sọ pe awọn eeyan kan wa, owo nlanla  ni wọn ti fi iwọde ọhun gba lọwọ ijọba pẹlu ileri wi pe awọn yoo ba awọn to n ṣe iwọde kiri sọrọ, ti kaluku yoo si jokoo sile ẹ jẹẹ.Ṣoworẹ sọ pe, adehun ẹyọ kanṣoṣọ toun le ba ẹnikẹni fọwọ si ni ki wọn gba ohun gbogbo ti araalu n fẹ, ati pe ẹnikan bayii, ko le fi abẹtẹlẹ kankan lọ oun lati kọyin si ohun ti ọmọ Naijiria n fẹ.Ni ti Aisha Yesufu, obinrin ọmọ Hausa toun naa jẹ jafẹtọọ sọ pe, loootọ lawọn eeyan kan ti di olowo, ṣugbọn alaye ti oun ṣe fun ọga agba apapọ banki Naijiria (CBN), Ọgbẹni Godwin Emefiele ni pe, ti ijọba ba ti ṣe ohun ti araalu n fẹ, ko ni i si iwọde kankan mọ nibikibi ni Naijiria.Ṣa o, ọkunrin kan ti wọn n pe ni Sẹgun Awosanya to ṣagbatẹru awọn to n ṣe iwọde ‘A ko fẹ ẹṣọ SARS mọ’ ti sọ pe loootọ ni awọn eeyan kan ti ja eto ọhun gba mọ awọn ti awọn da a silẹ lọwọ.Ọkan lara awọn aṣoju ọdọ ti wọn tun fẹsun kan ni Debọla Williams, wọn loun lo sọ pe, o to gẹ, ki kaluku gbale ẹ lọ, ṣugbọn niṣe lo ni ọrọ ko ri bẹẹ rara, oun ko wi nnkankan ni toun.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, lati nnkan bi ọjọ meloo kan sẹyin lawọn ọdọ kaakiri orile-ede yii ti n ṣe iwọde, ohun ti wọn si n beere lọwọ ijọba ni pe, ko fagile ẹṣọ to n gbogun ti idigunjale, nitori wọn ko ṣiṣẹ tijọba ran wọn mo, awọn eeyan ilu ni wọn n pa kiri, ti wọn si tun n ja wọn lole pẹlu.Ọpọ eeyan lo ku o, bẹẹ lawọn ọlọpaa paapaa padanu ẹmi wọn. Ninu wahala ọhun ni ̀ọga ọlọpaa ti sare fofin de awọn SARS, ti Buhari paapaa si kede wi pe, oun naa fọwọ si i.Sugbọn niṣe lawon ọmọ Naijiria ṣi kun oju titi bamu, bi wọn ṣe n ru posi Buhari, bẹẹ ni wọn n ṣepe gidi. Lojoojumọ ni iwọde ọhun n fẹju si i, to si ti fẹẹ kari gbogbo ipinlẹ ni Najiria atawọn ilẹ okeere ti awọn ọmọ Naijiria wa."},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.She was curious about Giraffe. \\"Why do you have a long neck?\\", she asked.Terjemahan:","answer":"Terjemahan dari penggalan teks tersebut dalam Bahasa Indonesia adalah:Bayi Gajah sangat ingin tahu mengenai jerapah.\\"Jerapah, mengapa lehermu panjang?\\", tanyanya."},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள் - இவரது கல்லூரி நண்பரான மகாதேவ தேசாய், 1920 ஆம் ஆண்டில் மோதிலால் நேருவின் மகளான சொரூப குமாரியிடம், \\"மாடர்ன் ரிவியூ\\" என்ற பத்திரிக்கையில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட பண்டிட்டின் \\"அட் த பீட் ஆப் த குரு\\" என்ற கட்டுரையை படிக்க பரிந்துரைத்தார். தேசாய் அப்போது மகாத்மா காந்தியின் செயலாளராக இருந்தார். தேசாய் கத்தியவாரில் பண்டிதர்களுக்கு குடும்ப நண்பராக இருந்த காரணத்தால் இவர் மூலம் சொரூப குமாரி நேருவை பண்டிட்டுக்கு திருமணம் செய்து வைக்க ஒப்பந்தம் செய்யப்பட்டது. 1857 ஆம்","answer":"ஆண்டு இந்தியக் கிளர்ச்சியின் ஆண்டுவிழாவான 10 மே 1921 இல், இவர்கள் திருமணம் செய்து கொண்டனர், அதன் பின்னர், இவர் விஜயலட்சுமி பண்டிட் என்ற பெயரை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார். நேரு குடும்பம் அப்போது இந்திய ஒத்துழையாமை இயக்கத்திலும், அன்னியப் பொருட்களை புறக்கணிப்பதிலும் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த நிலையில், இத்திருமணமானது ஆனந்த பவனில் நடந்தது. இவர்களது முதல் மகள் வத்சலா தனது ஒன்பது மாத குழந்தையாக இருக்கும் போதே இறந்தார். அதைத் தொடர்ந்து, இவர்களுக்கு சந்திரலேகா மேத்தா, நயன்தாரா சாகல் மற்றும் இரீட்டா தர் என்ற மூன்று மகள்கள் முறையே 1924, 1927 மற்றும் 1929 இல் பிறந்தார்கள்."},{"question":"Almanya iş vizesi kaç günde çıkar?","answer":"Vize işlemleri, konsoloslukların yoğunluğuna bağlı olarak, resmi tatiller hariç 15 iş günü içinde sonuçlanmaktadır."},{"question":"لە ساڵی چەند کۆڕەوەکەی کورد کەی دەستیپێکرد؟ ","answer":"١٩٩١"},{"question":"Wat is het verschil tussen een rode appel en een Granny Smith appel?","answer":"Een rode appel is gebruikelijk zoet terwijl een Granny Smith appel groen en zuur is."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:తే. సర్వతీర్థాభిగమనంబు సర్వవేదసమధిగమము సత్యంబుతో సరియుఁ గావుఎఱుఁగు మెల్లధర్మంబుల కెందుఁ బెద్దయండ్రు సత్యంబు ధర్మజ్ఞులైన మునులు.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :సర్వతీర్థ + అభిగమనంబు = సకల తీర్థాలనూ దర్శించటం, సర్వ వేద, వేదాలను అన్నింటినీసమధిగమము = అధ్యయనం చేయటంసత్యంబుతోన్ = సత్యంతోసరియున్ + కావు = సాటి కావుధర్మజ్ఞులు + ఐన = ధర్మం బాగా తెలిసినమునులు = ఋషులుఎందున్ = ఎప్పుడైనాసత్యంబు = సత్యమేఎల్ల ధర్మంబులకున్ = ధర్మాలన్నింటికంటేపెద్ద + అండ్రు = గొప్పది అంటారు అనిఎఱుఁగుము = తెలుసుకో.తాత్పర్యం :ఓ రాజా ! సకల తీర్థాలనూ సేవించటంగానీ, వేదాలను అన్నింటినీ ఆధ్యయనం : చేయటంగానీ సత్యానికి సాటిరావు, ధర్మం బాగా తెలిసిన ఋషులు ఎల్లప్పుడూ అన్ని ధర్మాలకంటే సత్యమే గొప్పదని అంటారని గమనించు అని తాత్పర్యం."},{"question":"「モズ」「チドリ」「ジュウシマツ」を漢字で書いたとき、出てくる数字を合計するといくつでしょう？","answer":"1110です。"},{"question":"Euskal Herriko arkitektura tradizionalean, baserriaren ezaugarri batzuk zer diren aipatu.","answer":"Baserria Euskal Herriko etxe tradizionala da, normalean harria erabiliz eraikia. Ezaugarri nagusiak hurrengoak dira: teilatu bikoitzak, egurrezko barandilak eta sabaia. Baserrien antolakuntza, abereak eta lanbide-agrarioa izateko egokituak dira."},{"question":"Khối lớp 6 của một trường trung học cơ sở có các lớp 6A, 6B, 6C, 6D, 6E với số học sinh lần lượt là 40; 45; 39; 44; 42.a) Lớp nào có thể xếp thành 2 hàng với số lượng học sinh ở mỗi hàng là như nhau?b) Lớp nào có thể xếp thành 5 hàng với số lượng học sinh ở mỗi hàng là như nhau?","answer":"Lời giải:a) Để biết được lớp nào có thể xếp thành 2 hàng với số lượng học sinh ở mỗi hàng là như nhau thì ta lần lượt lấy số học sinh của mỗi lớp chia cho 2:40 : 2 = 20; 45 : 2 = 22 (dư 1); 39 : 2 = 19 (dư 1); 44 : 2 = 22; 42 : 2 = 21Ta thấy 40; 44; 42 chia hết cho 2.Do đó các lớp 6A, 6D và 6E có thể xếp thành 2 hàng với số lượng học sinh ở mỗi hàng là như nhau.b) Để biết được lớp nào có thể xếp thành 5 hàng với số lượng học sinh ở mỗi hàng là như nhau thì ta lần lượt lấy số học sinh của mỗi lớp chia cho 5:40 : 5 = 8; 45 : 5 = 9; 39 : 5 = 7 (dư 4); 44 : 5 = 8 (dư 4); 42 : 5 = 8 (dư 2)Ta thấy 40; 45 chia hết cho 5.Do đó các lớp 6A và 6B có thể xếp thành 5 hàng với số lượng học sinh ở mỗi hàng là như nhau."},{"question":"Mitovy hevitra sa mifanipa-kevitra sa tsy misy ifandraisany ireto fehezanteny roa ireto?Fehezanteny A: Tsy nihetsika teo mihitsy ianao androany tontolo.Fehezanteny B: Andana mividy laoka vetivety fa tsy misy atokona ato.","answer":"Tsy misy ifandraisany ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"Инфляцияга каралбаган бардык убактагы эң көп кирешелүү тасма кайсы?","answer":"Жеймс Кэмерон тарабынан тартылган \\"Аватар\\" (2009-ж.) инфляцияны эске албаганда, дүйнөлүк прокатта түшкөн кирешеси 2,7 миллиард доллардан ашкан бардык убактагы эң көп кирешелүү тасма болуп саналат."},{"question":"Pra mudha kudu sekolahWiwit biyen pinuju isih cilikSregep ngupadi ilmuWanci enjing lan awanMirengake pamulange para guruMrih saged ngerti agamaAgama kersaning GustiPesen kang kinandhut sajroning tembang Pangkur ing dhuwur yaiku ...A. wigatine gilek ngilmuB. manut tatanan negaraC. ora mendhem kahanan donyaD. aja ngremehake wong liyaE. menungsa kang unggul ing budiJawaban:","answer":"Jawaban: A. wigatine gilek ngilmu"},{"question":"इस इमोजी का प्रतिक्रिया क्या हो सकता है? 😇","answer":"😇 मासूम चेहरा: यह इमोजी अच्छाई, सादगी और नम्रता की भावना को दर्शाता है। जब कोई व्यक्ति उचित और ईमानदारी से किसी काम को करता है, तो यह इमोजी उनकी सच्चाई और नम्रता को प्रकट करता है।"},{"question":"O tan, ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ ko ba pasitọ n’Ileefẹ","answer":"Ajọ to n ri si iwa magomago ati ṣiṣe owo ilu mọkumọku, EFCC, ẹka tipinlẹ Gombe ti nawọ gan Pasitọ Gbenga Moses ti ṣọọṣi rẹ wa n’Ileefẹ, ipinlẹ Ọṣun, pẹlu ọmọdekunrin kan toun n ṣe jibiti ori ayelujara ti wọn n pe ni ‘Yahoo’ torukọ tiẹ n jẹ Adebayọ Ọlawale, wọn ni wọn lu jibiti miliọnu mejila ati ẹgbẹrun lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹrin(12.7m) naira.Ẹnikan torukọ ẹ n jẹ Umar Hayatu, toun n gbe ni Lafia, nipinlẹ Gombe, ni ALAROYE gbọ pe Adebayọ Ọlawale bẹrẹ si i ba sọrọ lori ẹka Fesibuuku, to n sọ fun un pe baba oun ni ileeṣẹ nla kan niluu oyinbo, o si fẹẹ da iru ẹ silẹ niluu Eko, o n wa ẹni ti yoo ba a ṣe maneja ileeṣẹ naa.Ọmọ Yahoo yii fi ye Hayatu pe oun yoo ba a ṣe e ki baba oun le gba a sileeṣẹ tuntun naa gẹgẹ bii maneja. N lo ba n sọ fun un pe ṣugbọn oore toun fẹẹ ṣe fun un naa ki i ṣe ọfẹ o, nitori owo nla nla ni yoo maa gba tiṣẹ ba bọ si i tan, koda, awọn aworan ile ati mọto arumọjẹ lo fi n han ọmọ Hausa naa lori ayelujara, to n sọ fun un pe awọn ohun ti ileeṣẹ naa yoo gbe fun un gẹgẹ bii maneja niyẹn to ba ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ.Eyi lo fa a to fi ni ko maa fowo ranṣẹ soun toun yoo fi ba a ṣeto iṣẹ nla naa, iyẹn si n sanwo fun un loootọ, ko mọ pe gbaju-ẹ lasan ni ọmọkunrin naa n ṣe foun.Nigba ti aṣiri Adebayọ tu tan, owo to le ni miliọnu mejila  ni wọn ba lakanti ẹ. Ibi to ti kan Pasitọ Gbenga ni tiẹ ni pe wọn lo gba mọto BMW kan, pulọọti ilẹ kan ati ọpọlọpọ owo lọwọ ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ yii, lara owo tiyẹn gba lọwọ Hayatu si ni.Ni bayii, awọn mejeeji ti wa lakolo EFCC, wọn si lawọn yoo foju wọn bale-ẹjọ lẹyin iwadii awọn."},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho: Nas décadas de 1950 e 1960, Paris se tornou uma frente da","answer":"Guerra de Independência Argelina; em agosto de 1961, a FLN, pró-independência, atacou e matou 11 policiais de Paris, levando à imposição de um toque de recolher aos muçulmanos da Argélia (que na época eram cidadãos franceses). Em 17 de outubro de 1961, uma manifestação não autorizada, mas pacífica, de argelinos contra o toque de recolher levou a violentos confrontos entre a polícia e manifestantes, nos quais pelo menos 40 pessoas foram mortas, incluindo algumas jogadas no Sena. A anti-independência Organisation Armée Secrète, por sua vez, realizou uma série de atentados em Paris ao longo de 1961 e 1962."},{"question":"Ndipe maresiphi mashoma aungaite nechingwa, bhata, mazai, uye chizi apo ndine stovetop, toaster, uye pani yekufiyira.","answer":"\\"Heano mashoma ekubika iwe aunogona kugadzira nemidziyo uye zvishandiso zvawataura.1. Chizi yakagochwa nemazai ane zuva:Dziisai pani yenyu yekufiisa pamusoro pechitofu. Pisai bhotela shoma pani kusvika yanyunguduka woisa zvimedu zviviri zvechingwa padivi nepadivi mupani. Isa chizi pachidimbu chimwe chechingwa uye kupisa kusvikira chingwa chave crispy uye cheese chatanga kunyunguduka. Zvadaro vhara chimedu chechingwa nechesi yakanyunguduka neimwe chidimbu chechingwa uye bvisa kubva pani inopisa.Zvinyoro nyoro pwanya zai woriisa mupani. Bika kusvika mazai machena aoma. Iwe unogona ipapo kubika kusvika ma yolks ave ekuenderana kwako kwaunoda.2. Toast uye cheese omelette:Isa chingwa mune toaster uye gadzira kusvika padanho raunoda. Paridza bhata raunoda pachingwa.Dziisai pani yenyu yekufiisa pamusoro pechitofu. Pisa bhotela shoma pane frying pan kusvikira yanyunguduka. Panguva ino, zvinyoronyoro pwanya mazai mundiro uye whisk mazai. Isa mazai akarohwa mupani inopisa kusvikira mazai atanga kuoma. Isa cheese pamazai uye peta.3. Mazai akakushwa ane tositi:Isa chingwa mune toaster uye gadzira kusvika padanho raunoda. Paridza bhata raunoda pachingwa.Dziisai pani yenyu yekufiisa pamusoro pechitofu. Pisa bhotela shoma pane frying pan kusvikira yanyunguduka. Panguva ino, zvinyoronyoro pwanya mazai mundiro uye whisk mazai. Isai mazai akarohwa mupani inopisa uye musanganise nguva dzose. Isa cheese mupani uye ramba uchisanganisa kusvikira mazai apera. \\""},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe rhinite allergique ?","answer":"Arak’izany fiantsoana azy izany, ny rhinite allergique dia aretina iray azo avy amin’ny fifampikasohana amin’ny allergènes."},{"question":"Cé hé Micheál Ó hAirtnéide? ","answer":"File Éireannach ab ea Micheál Ó hAirtnéide nó Michael Hartnett a chum a chuid saothar i nGaeilge agus Béarla. Rugadh sé ar an 18 Meán Fómhair 1941 é agus a d'éag ar an 13 Deireadh Fómhair 1999. Rugadh i gCromadh i gContae Luimnigh é agus d'fhás sé aníos sa Chaisleán Nua Thiar i dteach a mháthar móire faoin tuath. Mhaígh sé go gcloiseadh sí Mamó ag labhairt Gaeilge lena cuid cairde san áit sin. A thúisce is a bhí an Ardteistiméireacht críochnaithe aige, chuaigh sé ar deoraíocht go Londain. "},{"question":"\\"নবান্ন উৎসব\\" শিরোনামে ১টি অনুচ্ছেদ লিখুন।","answer":"'নব' মানে নতুন আর 'অন্ন' মানে ভাত। নবান্ন শব্দটির অর্থ হচ্ছে নতুন চাল বা নতুন ভাত। হেমন্তকালে নতুন ধান কাটার পর গ্রামের মানুষ যে উৎসব করত তাই নবান্ন উৎসব নামে পরিচিত। একসময় এদেশে নবান্ন উৎসবের ঐতিহ্য ছিল। হেমন্তকালে নতুন ধান কেটে ঘরে তুললে গ্রামে গ্রামে এ উৎসব হতো। গ্রামের মানুষ নতুন ধানের পিঠা-পায়েস তৈরি করে এ উৎসব পালন করত। এ নবান্ন উৎসবের সাথে গ্রামের মানুষের আনন্দ, হাসি-কান্না জড়িত। কিন্তু কালের বিবর্তনে প্রাকৃতিক বিপর্যয় ও অনিয়মিত ঋতু পরিবর্তনের কারণে এখন আর নবান্ন উৎসব দেখা যায় না। সারাদেশের দু'একটি জায়গা ছাড়া নবান্ন উৎসব প্রায় বিলুপ্ত হয়ে গেছে বলা যায়। তবে ভিন্ন আঙ্গিকে নগর সভ্যতায় কোথাও কোথাও নবান্ন উৎসব দেখা যায়। বিশেষ করে ঢাকা বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ের চারুকলা ইনস্টিটিউটে নবান্ন উৎসব পালিত হয়ে থাকে প্রতি বছর। এ উপলক্ষে দেশের সংস্কৃতিকর্মীর বিভিন্ন রকমের পিঠার প্রদর্শনী করে থাকে। এছাড়া দিনব্যাপী চলে দেশীয় ঐতিহ্যকে ধারণ করে বিভিন্ন সাংস্কৃতিক অনুষ্ঠান। নবান্ন উৎসব আমাদের বাঙালি জীবনে তাৎপর্য ও ঐতিহ্যময় উৎসব। এ উৎসব মানুষের মাঝে প্রাণের জোয়ার বয়ে আনে। বাঙালির ঐতিহ্য ও ইতিহাস ধরে রাখার জন্য এ উৎসব নিয়মিত পালন করা উচিত। এক্ষেত্রে সরকারি ও বেসরকারিভাবে সকলের এগিয়ে আসা উচিত।"},{"question":"Sheeg Kumuu ahaa nabigii samada iyo dhulkuba ku tukaday?","answer":"Wuxuu Nabiyullahi Muxamed SCW. "},{"question":"મને નિવસન તંત્ર  વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"નિવસન તંત્ર (ઇકોસિસ્ટમ) એટલે કુદરતમાં જૈવિક ઘટકો જેવા કે પ્રાણીઓ, વનસ્પતિઓ અને સુક્ષ્મ જીવો તેઓની આસપાસના નિર્જીવ ઘટકો જેવા કે પાણી, વાયુઓ, જમીન, પ્રકાશ વગેરે સાથે જટિલ રીતે જોડાઇને એક સ્વયં સચાલિત તંત્રની રચના કરે છે તે તંત્ર કે પ્રણાલી.નિવસન તંત્ર મુખ્યત્વે બે ઘટકો નું બનેલુ હોય છે: જૈવિક ઘટકો અને અજૈવિક ઘટકો.જૈવિક ઘટકો: નિવસન તંત્રનાં જૈવિક ઘટકોમાં પ્રાણીઓ, વનસ્પતિ અને સુક્ષ્મ જીવોનો સમાવેશ થાય છે. જૈવિક ઘટકોને પોષણ પદ્ધતિના આધારે બે પ્રકારમાં વિભાજીત કરી શકાય છે:(૧) ઉત્પાદકો: નિવસન તંત્રના જૈવિક ઘટકો પોતનો ખોરાક પ્રકાશસંષ્લેશણથી જાતે જ તૈયાર કરે છે. આથી તેઓને સ્વપોષી ઘટકો પણ કહેવાય છે. દા.ત. લીલી વનસ્પતિ, લીલ અને જીવાણું અને(૨) ઉપભોકતા: નિવસન તંત્રના આ જૈવિક ઘટકો પોતના ખોરાક માટે ઉત્પાદકો પર આધાર રાખે છે. માટે જ તેઓને પરપોષી ઘટકો પણ કહેવાય છે, દા.ત. પરોપજીવી વનસ્પતિ, પ્રાણી, ફૂગ, વગેરે.અજૈવિક ઘટકોનિવસન તંત્રના અજૈવિક ઘટકોને નીચે મુજબ વિભાજીત કરી શકાય છે.૧.અકાર્બનિક પોષક ઘટકો - દા.ત. ઓક્સિજન, કાર્બન ડાયોક્સાઇડ, ફોસ્ફરસ, પોટેશિયમ, વગેરે૨.કાર્બનિક પોષક ઘટકો - દા.ત. કાર્બોદિત પદાર્થો, નત્રલ, ચરબી, વગેરે3.આબોહવાકિય પરિબળો - જેવા કે પવન, ભેજ, હવા, આબોહવા, વગેરે."},{"question":"ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਾਥੀ ਦੀ ਗ਼ਲਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਫ਼ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਸਦੀ ਨੀਅਤ ਠੀਕ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਬਿਹਤਰ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਸਦੀ ਨੀਅਤ ਠੀਕ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Коала эмнеге эң жалкоо жаныбар катары таанымал?","answer":"Анткени, ал 1 күн сайын (суткада) 18-22 саатын уйкуга бөлөт (уктайт)."},{"question":"Nelson Mandela aiva ani, uye basa rake raiva rei munhoroondo yeSouth Africa?","answer":"VaNelson Mandela vaive mutungamiri akakosha mukurwisa rusaruraganda muSouth Africa. Akave mutungamiri wechitema wekutanga munyika uye anorangarirwa nekuedza kwake kusimudzira kuyanana nekuenzaniswa."},{"question":"Преамбула деген эмне ?","answer":"Преамбула - баш сөз, алгачкы сөз, сөз башы, кириш сөз. Мыйзамдагы преамбула – ченемдик актынын кириш же кириш бөлүгү. Преамбуласы бар ченемдик укуктук актыларга жарлыктар, мыйзамдар жана жоболор кирет."},{"question":"दोन अक्षरात सामावले माझे नावमस्तक झाकणे आपले माझे कामओळखा पाहू मी आहे कोण => उत्तर- ","answer":"टोपी"},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?මෛත්‍රිය ","answer":"වෛරය"},{"question":"මේ වචන දෙකම හරිද? පාසල් පාසැල්","answer":"පාසල තමයි හරි වචනය. පාඨශාලාව තමයි පාසල වෙලා  තියෙන්නෙ.පා සැ ල = පා  + සැ ල,  මේකට පා  විකුණන කඩේ(සැල) වගේ අදහසක් තමයි තියෙන්නේ."},{"question":"ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਸੁਣਵਾਈ 5 ਅਗਸਤ ਤੋਂ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਈਪੀਸੀ ਦੀ ਧਾਰਾ 376 ਅਤੇ ਪੋਕਸੋ ਐਕਟ ਦੀ 5ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਧਾਰਾ 6 ਤਹਿਤ ਇਹ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਸੁਣਾਈ ਗਈ ਹੈ।ਅਦਾਲਤ ਨੇ ਕੁਲਦੀਪ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਤੇ 25 ਲੱਖ ਜ਼ੁਰਮਾਨਾ ਵੀ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ 10 ਲੱਖ ਪੀੜਤ ਕੁੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਣ ਦਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਸੁਣਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।ਅਦਾਲਤ ਨੇ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਨੂੰ ਅਗਵਾ ਅਤੇ ਬਲਾਤਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋਸ਼ੀ ਕਰਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਹਿ ਮੁਲਜ਼ਮ ਸ਼ਸ਼ੀ ਸਿੰਘ ਬਰੀ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ।ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਦੇ ਦਖਲ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਇਹ ਮਾਮਲਾ ਲਖਨਊ ਤੋਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੀ ਅਦਾਲਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਟਰਾਂਸਫਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਪੰਜ ਅਗਸਤ ਤੋਂ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਸੁਣਵਾਈ ਚੱਸਲ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ।ਸਾਲ 2017 ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਲਦੀਪ ਸੇਂਗਰ 'ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਮਹਿਲਾ ਨੇ ਅਗਵਾ ਅਤੇ ਰੇਪ ਦਾ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਸੀ, ਉਸ ਵੇਲੇ ਉਹ ਨਾਬਾਲਿਗ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਗੱਲ ਕਰਨ ਗਈ ਸੀ।ਜਾਣੋ ਪੂਰਾ ਘਟਨਾਕ੍ਰਮ -4 ਜੂਨ 2017 - ਪੀੜਤਾ ਨੇ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ ਲਾਇਆ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਕੁਲਦੀਪ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਕੋਲ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦਿਵਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਮੰਗਣ ਲਈ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਨੇ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਰੇਪ ਕੀਤਾ।11 ਜੂਨ 2017 - ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ 11 ਜੂਨ ਨੂੰ ਕੁੜੀ ਗਾਇਬ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਕੁੜੀ ਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਲਾਪਤਾ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਈ।20 ਜੂਨ, 2017 - ਪੀੜਤਾ ਕੁੜੀ ਯੂਪੀ ਦੇ ਔਰਿਆ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਪਿੰਡ ਤੋਂ ਮਿਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨ ਉਨਾਓ ਲਿਆਂਦਾ ਗਿਆ।3 ਜੁਲਾਈ 2017- ਬਿਆਨ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਦੇ 10 ਦਿਨਾਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਪੀੜਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਸੌਂਪ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਪੀੜਤਾ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਆ ਗਈ। ਪੀੜਤਾ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ  ਸ਼ੋਸ਼ਣ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਪੀੜਤਾ ਨੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਯੋਗੀ ਅਦਿੱਤਿਆਨਾਥ ਕੋਲ ਵੀ ਗੁਹਾਰ ਲਗਾਈ ਕਿ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਕੁਲਦੀਪ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਅਤੁਲ ਸਿੰਘ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ FIR ਦਰਜ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਵੇ।24 ਫਰਵਰੀ 2018- ਪੀੜਤਾ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਈ ਅਤੇ ਉਨਾਓ ਦੇ ਚੀਫ ਜੁਡੀਸ਼ੀਅਲ ਮੈਜਿਸਟਰੇਟ ਕੋਰਟ ਦਾ ਰੁਖ਼ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਸੀਆਰਪੀਸੀ ਦੇ ਸੈਕਸ਼ਨ 156 (3) ਦੇ ਤਹਿਤ ਐਫਆਈਆਰ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਕੀਤੀ।3 ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ 2018- ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ ਨੇ ਕਿ ਕੁੜੀ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਕੁਲਦੀਪ ਸਿੰਘ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਅਤੁਲ ਸਿੰਘ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਨੇ ਕੁੱਟਮਾਰ ਕੀਤੀ।4 ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ 2018- ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਨਾਓ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਕੁੜੀ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਆਰਮਜ਼ ਐਕਟ ਦੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਗ੍ਰਿਫ਼ਤਾਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ।28 ਜੁਲਾਈ ਨੂੰ ਪੀੜਤ ਕੁੜੀ ਦੀ ਗੱਡੀ ਦੁਰਘਟਾਗ੍ਰਸਤ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ।8 ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ 2018- ਪੀੜਤਾ ਨੇ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ 'ਤੇ ਐਫਆਈਆਰ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਅਦਿੱਤਿਆਨਾਥ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਦੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਖੁਦਕੁਸ਼ੀ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਉਦਾਸੀਨਤਾ ਦਾ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ ਲਗਾਇਆ। ","answer":"ਉਨਾਓ ਰੇਪ ਮਾਮਲਾ: ਕੁਲਦੀਪ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਨੂੰ ਉਮਰ ਕੈਦ, ਜਾਣੋ ਸੇਂਗਰ ਦੇ ਇੰਨੇ ਦਬਦਬੇ ਦੀ ਵਜ੍ਹਾ ਕੀ ਸੀ?"},{"question":"たなばたの日に願い事を書いて飾る小さな細長い紙のことを何という？","answer":"たんざくです。"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Anda ingin makan jika berasa ini.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah lapar. Kelaparan seseorang menyebabkannya ingin makan. "},{"question":"શું તમે મુસાફરી ટિપ્સ વિશેની બ્લોગ પોસ્ટ માટે રસપ્રદ વિષયો સૂચવી શકો છો?","answer":"શું કરવું અને શું નહીં1. પરિવારો, યુગલો, બાળકો અને વિદ્યાર્થીઓ માટે ટોચનું ગંતવ્યજો તમારી પાસે ટ્રાવેલ બ્લોગ છે, તો તમારી પાસે બહુવિધ રુચિઓ સાથે વૈવિધ્યસભર પ્રેક્ષકો હોઈ શકે છે. તેઓ પરિવારો, યુગલો, બાળકો, સોલો વગેરે માટે આદર્શ સ્થળો શોધી શકે છે.2. X કારણો શા માટે તમારે મુલાકાત લેવી જોઈએતમારા વાચકોને સમજાવો કે શા માટે ચોક્કસ ગંતવ્યની મુલાકાત લેવા યોગ્ય છે અને તમામ જરૂરી વિગતો પ્રકાશિત કરો જે તે સ્થળને પ્રવાસીઓ માટે શ્રેષ્ઠ વિકલ્પ બનાવે છે.3. સ્થાન-વિશિષ્ટ સાંસ્કૃતિક તત્વોથી વાકેફ રહેવુંનવી જગ્યાએ મુસાફરી કરતી વખતે, સ્થાનિક રિવાજોને જાણવું મહત્વપૂર્ણ છે. તેમાં કોઈને કેવી રીતે અભિવાદન કરવું, કઈ ભેટો યોગ્ય છે અને કેવી રીતે પોશાક પહેરવો તે બધું શામેલ છે.4. [દેશ] માં ક્યાં અને શું ખાવુંદેશોની મુસાફરી કરતી વખતે, તમે કદાચ જાણતા ન હોવ કે કયા ખોરાક અને ક્યાં અજમાવવા જોઈએ. તેથી, પ્રવાસીઓ રેન્ડમ સ્થાનો પર સમય અને નાણાં બગાડવા માંગતા નથી - તેઓ સામાન્ય રીતે સૌથી વધુ ભલામણ કરેલ રેસ્ટોરન્ટ્સ અને વાનગીઓનું સંશોધન કરે છે.5. મિત્રો માટે કઈ ભેટો પાછા લાવવાતમારા મિત્રો માટે કઈ ભેટો પાછી લાવવી તે નક્કી કરવું અઘરું છે. તમે કંઈક અનન્ય અને યાદગાર શોધવા માંગો છો. પરંતુ સ્થાનિક ટીપ્સ વિના, તમે ક્યારેય સફળ થઈ શકશો નહીં.6. રહેવા માટે શ્રેષ્ઠ પડોશીઓઘણાને રહેવા માટે સ્થાનો પસંદ કરવાનું જબરજસ્ત લાગે છે. તેથી, તમારા પ્રેક્ષકો માટે હાજર રહો અને તેમને આ સમસ્યા હલ કરવામાં મદદ કરો.7. માં કરવા માટે મફત વસ્તુઓપ્રવાસીઓ એક પણ પૈસો ખર્ચ્યા વિના કોઈપણ શહેરમાં રોમાંચક દિવસો પસાર કરી શકે છે. તેથી, તમારા વાચકો ચોક્કસ સાઇટની આસપાસ શ્રેષ્ઠ મફત પ્રવૃત્તિઓ શેર કરતા લેખનો આનંદ માણશે.8. શું ન ખાવુંએવા ખોરાક છે જે તમારે ટાળવા જોઈએ, કારણ કે તે સ્વાસ્થ્ય માટે જોખમ ઊભું કરી શકે છે. આમાં બિનપાશ્ચરાઇઝ્ડ ડેરી ઉત્પાદનો, કાચું માંસ અને માછલી અને અમુક ફળો અને શાકભાજીનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.9. [દેશ] માં શ્રેષ્ઠ ચલણ વિનિમયચલણ વિનિમયની શોધ કરતી વખતે, શ્રેષ્ઠ દર ઓફર કરતી અને સારી પ્રતિષ્ઠા ધરાવતી એક શોધો. તેથી, તમારે ચલણ વિનિમય પસંદ કરતી વખતે જોવા માટે કેટલીક બાબતો સમજાવવી જોઈએ:"},{"question":"How does role-based access control enhance database security?","answer":"Role-based access control restricts database access based on predefined roles, ensuring that users have appropriate permissions for their responsibilities."},{"question":"Inona no afaka manidina tsy misy elatra?","answer":"Ny fotoana no afaka manidina tsy misy elatra"},{"question":"Apakah Instagram? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 340 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Instagram (kebiasaannya dipanggil IG) merupakan sebuah perkhidmatan rangkaian sosial perkongsian gambar dan video secara dalam talian yang dimiliki oleh Facebook, Inc. Aplikasi ini dicipta oleh Kevin Systrom dan Mike Krieger, dan dilancarkan pada bulan Oktober 2010 di iOS. Versi untuk peranti Android dilancarkan pada bulan April 2012, diikuti oleh aplikasi sesawang pada bulan November 2012, aplikasi Fire OS pada 15 Jun 2014 dan aplikasi untuk tablet dan komputer Windows 10 pada bulan Oktober 2016. Instagram membolehkan pengguna memuat naik gambar yang boleh diubah menggunakan penapis gambar dan menyebarkannya ke dalam pelbagai bentuk perkhidmatan rangkaian sosial termasuklah laman yang mendahuluinya seperti Facebook atau Twitter. Pengguna dapat melihat kandungan pengguna lain dengan hasil daripada teg dan maklumat lokasi, serta melihat kandungan yang menjadi gaya terkini. Pengguna juga boleh menyukai gambar dan mengikuti pengguna lain untuk menambah senarai ke dalam kandungannya.Instagram pada mulanya hanya membenarkan kandungan dibingkai dalam nisbah bidang gambar segiempat sama (1:1) dengan 640 piksel agar sepadan dengan lebar paparan iPhone pada masa itu. Pada tahun 2015, terdapat kemas kini yang dilakukan dengan peningkatan menjadi 1080 piksel. Perkhidmatan ini juga menambahkan ciri pemesejan, kemampuan untuk menyertakan banyak gambar atau video dalam sekali hantar, serta \\"Cerita\\" - sama seperti Snapchat penentang utamanya - yang membolehkan pengguna menyiarkan gambar dan video ke kandungannya secara berurutan, dengan setiap gambar dihantar akan diakses oleh pengguna lain selama 24 jam setiap satu. Sehingga Januari 2019, ciri cerita ini digunakan oleh 500 juta pengguna pada setiap hari. Setelah dilancarkan pada tahun 2010, Instagram dengan cepatnya mendapat populariti, dengan satu juta pengguna berdaftar dalam masa dua bulan, 10 juta dalam setahun, dan 1 bilion pada Mei 2019. Pada bulan April 2012, Facebook memperoleh perkhidmatan dengan wang tunai kira-kira AS  1 bilion dan stok. Sehingga bulan Oktober 2015, lebih dari 40 biion gambar telah dimuat naik. Walaupun terkenal dengan populariti dalam penggunaan aplikasi, Instagram turut menjadi bahan kritikan, terutama kandungan haram yang tidak wajar dimuat naik oleh pengguna.Instagram menjadi aplikasi mudah alih ke-4 yang paling banyak dimuat turun pada tahun 2010"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന പ്രസ്താവനയിൽ \\"അവൻ\\" എന്ന സർവ്വനാമം എന്താണ് സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നത്? \\"ഞാൻ നാദറിന് വോട്ട് ചെയ്തു, കാരണം അവൻ എന്റെ മൂല്യങ്ങളുമായി ഏറ്റവും യോജിക്കുന്നു\\"","answer":"ഈ വാക്യത്തിലെ \\"അവൻ\\" എന്നത് നാദിറിനെ സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നു"},{"question":"時計の短針が１時間に動く角度は何度でしょうか？","answer":"３０度です。"},{"question":"¿En qué consiste la programación competitiva?","answer":"La programación competitiva es una especie de deporte mental, en el que los participantes deben resolver un conjunto de problemas de clase algorítimica y matemática, usualmente en un tiempo determinado. Para esto se require tener dominio de algún lenguaje de programación (como C++, Java o Python), de resolución de problemas, y conocimiento profundo de ciertos algortimos y estructuras de datos que aparecen en cursos avanzados de algoritmos a nivel universitario.Estas competencias son financiadas por compañías como Google, Acer, Jetbrains, Jane Street, Huawei, y otras, debido a que de esa manera pueden atraer programadores talentosos.Algunas de estas competencias son: ICPC (para estudiantes universitarios), IOI (para estudiantes pre-universitarios), Meta Hackercup, Huawei Challenge.También existen plataformas en las "},{"question":"Hadi ilmahada aad ku argto calamadahan mid kamida geey dhaqtar?","answer":"HADII ILMAHADA AAD KU ARAGTO MID KAMIDA CALAMADAHAN GEEY DHQTAR Waxey noqon karaan astaamo leh walwal tahayna inaadan yareysan dhaqtar caruur laxariir:-1= Matag/ mataq Hadii ilmaha yar sidaran u matagayo mrki uu jaqo naaska kadib ama sacado badan matago ama shuban iyo qandho leyahay wa muhim inaad laxarirto dhaqtar.2= Calool fadhi Hadii ilmahada uu saxaronayo waxkayar intii caadiga ahayd dhowr malmood hdna eey kamuqto raaxo daro laxariir dhaqtar.3= qaleel/ engagnaan Hadii ilmaha yari ooynayo hadana ilmo uusan lahayn ama aad ku aragto afka oo qalalan wax dhareera lahyn laxariir dhaqtar.4= Dhibaato dhagaha ah Hadii ilmahaada yar uusan uga dareen celin codadka si caadiya dhaqtar laxariir 5= indhaha Hadii indhaha midkamida ama labadodba eey gaduut ama wax kasocdan dhaqtar wa umuhim ilmahada.6= hargab/ duray Ilmahada yar hadii duray kudhaco amaba hergab sda utaqan sido kalna curan yahy ama uu lasocda qufac daran geey dhqtar.7= isbadal nuugista Hadii ilmahada yar uu diido jaqda nasaha ee isxigxigta dhaqtar geey.8= isbadal niyada ah Hadii ilmaha yar uu noqdo mid daal iyo inuusan hurdada katoseyn sidii cadiga ahyd kuna adag thy sidhaqsi ah dhaqtar laxariir sido kale haduu ooynayo waliba sidaran dhaqtar geey.9= Qandho Kama hadleyno qandho yar ee waxan kwdnaa qandho saida markasta lasoco oo cabir qandhda ilmahada hduu yeesho qandho saida dhaqtar geey.10= Shuban Hadii ilmahada yar saxardisa noqoto dareere saaida ama shuban dhaqtar geey.11= Xanuun xundhurta iyo xubinka Hadii xundhurta ama xubinka taranka uu noqdan gaduud sikadis ah wainaad dhaqtar laado."},{"question":"Ekologiaren ikuspegitik, nola eragiten du klima-aldaketak itsasoen biodibertsitatean eta ekosistema marinoan?","answer":"Klima-aldaketak itsasoen tenperatura eta pH maila aldatzen ditu, horrek biodibertsitatea eta ekosistema marinoen egonkortasuna kaltetuz. Hau eragin dezake espezieen desplazamenduak eta ekosistema berrien sorrera."},{"question":"Inona no teny ilazana ny iray tampo amin’ny ray aman-drenin’ny olona iray sy ny zanany?","answer":"Ny teny ilazana ny iray tampo amin’ny ray aman-drenin’ny olona iray sy ny zanany dia fianakaviana akaiky."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ॥ਕਾਲਬੂਤ ਕੀ ਹਸਤਨੀ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਚਲਤੁ ਰਚਿਓ ਜਗਦੀਸ ॥ਕਾਮ ਸੁਆਇ ਗਜ ਬਸਿ ਪਰੇ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਅੰਕਸੁ ਸਹਿਓ ਸੀਸ ॥੧॥ਬਿਖੈ ਬਾਚੁ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਚੁ ਸਮਝੁ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ॥ਨਿਰਭੈ ਹੋਇ ਨ ਹਰਿ ਭਜੇ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਗਹਿਓ ਨ ਰਾਮ ਜਹਾਜੁ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਮਰਕਟ ਮੁਸਟੀ ਅਨਾਜ ਕੀ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਲੀਨੀ ਹਾਥੁ ਪਸਾਰਿ ॥ਛੂਟਨ ਕੋ ਸਹਸਾ ਪਰਿਆ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਨਾਚਿਓ ਘਰ ਘਰ ਬਾਰਿ ॥੨॥ਜਿਉ ਨਲਨੀ ਸੂਅਟਾ ਗਹਿਓ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਮਾਯਾ ਇਹੁ ਬਿਉਹਾਰੁ ॥ਜੈਸਾ ਰੰਗੁ ਕਸੁੰਭ ਕਾ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਤਿਉ ਪਸਰਿਓ ਪਾਸਾਰੁ ॥੩॥ਨਾਵਨ ਕਉ ਤੀਰਥ ਘਨੇ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਪੂਜਨ ਕਉ ਬਹੁ ਦੇਵ ॥ਕਹੁ ਕਬੀਰ ਛੂਟਨੁ ਨਹੀ ਮਨ ਬਉਰਾ ਰੇ ਛੂਟਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਸੇਵ ॥੪॥੧॥੬॥੫੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 335 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਕਮਲੇ ਮਨਾ! (ਇਹ ਜਗਤ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਰੁੱਝੇ ਰੱਖਣ ਲਈ) ਇਕ ਖੇਡ ਬਣਾਈ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ (ਲੋਕ ਹਾਥੀ ਨੂੰ ਫੜਨ ਲਈ) ਕਲਬੂਤ ਦੀ ਹਥਣੀ (ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ);(ਉਸ ਹਥਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ) ਕਾਮ ਦੀ ਵਾਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਹਾਥੀ ਫੜਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ (ਸਦਾ ਮਹਾਉਤ ਦਾ) ਅੰਕਸ ਸਹਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਤਿਵੇਂ) ਹੇ ਝੱਲੇ ਮਨ! (ਤੂੰ ਭੀ ਮਨ-ਮੋਹਨੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ ਫਸ ਕੇ ਦੁੱਖ ਸਹਾਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ) ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੂਰਖ ਮਨ! ਅਕਲ ਕਰ, ਵਿਸ਼ਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਿਆ ਰਹੁ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਕਰ । ਤੂੰ ਸਹਿਮ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਕਿਉਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਤੇ ਕਿਉਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ? ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ ਕਮਲੇ ਮਨ! ਬਾਂਦਰ ਨੇ ਹੱਥ ਖਿਲਾਰ ਕੇ ਦਾਣਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਠ ਭਰ ਲਈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਹਿਮ ਪੈ ਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਕੈਦ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਨਿਕਲੇ । (ਉਸ ਲਾਲਚ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੁਣ) ਹਰੇਕ ਘਰ ਦੇ ਬੂਹੇ ਤੇ ਨੱਚਦਾ ਫਿਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਹੇ ਝੱਲੇ ਮਨਾਂ! ਜਗਤ ਦੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਇਉਂ ਹੀ ਵਰਤਾਰਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਮਾਇਆ ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਇਉਂ ਹੀ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ) ਜਿਵੇਂ ਤੋਤਾ ਨਲਨੀ (ਤੇ ਬੈਠ ਕੇ) ਫਸ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਕਮਲੇ ਮਨ! ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਸੁੰਭੇ ਦਾ ਰੰਗ (ਥੋੜੇ ਹੀ ਦਿਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ) ਹੈ, ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਖਿਲਾਰਾ (ਚਾਰ ਦਿਨ ਲਈ ਹੀ) ਖਿਲਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਝੱਲੇ ਮਨਾਂ! (ਭਾਵੇਂ) ਇਸ਼ਨਾਨ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਬਥੇਰੇ ਤੀਰਥ ਹਨ, ਤੇ ਪੂਜਣ ਲਈ ਬਥੇਰੇ ਦੇਵਤੇ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਭਾਵੇਂ ਲੋਕ ਕਈ ਤੀਰਥਾਂ ਤੇ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਇਸ਼ਨਾਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਕਈ ਦੇਵਤਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਪੂਜਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ) ਹੇ ਕਬੀਰ! ਆਖ—ਪਰ (ਇਸ ਸਹਿਮ ਤੋਂ ਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਤੋਂ) ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ । ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।੪।੧।੬।੫੭।\\""},{"question":"अधिक बर्ष ३६६ दिनको हुन्छ भने यस्तो बर्षमा थप भएको एक दिन कुन महिनामा जोडिन्छ ?","answer":"अधिक बर्षमा थप भएको एक दिन फेब्रुअरी महिनामा जोडिन्छ ।"},{"question":"نيشيمورا يا اولڊينڊورف؟ پوئين سوال کي نظر ۾ رکندي ، هڪ تناظر لکو جنهن ۾ جواب شامل آهي. اهو 1 - 20 جملا ٿي سگهي ٿو. پس منظر:","answer":"نيشيمورا جي فوج ۾ ٻه جنگي جهاز، هڪ ڪروزر ۽ چار تباهه ڪندڙ شامل هئا. ڇاڪاڻ ته اهي ريڊيو جي خاموشي جو مشاهدو ڪري رهيا هئا ، نيشيمورا شيما ۽ ڪوريتا سان هم وقت سازي ڪرڻ کان قاصر هو. نيشيمورا ۽ شيما حملن کان اڳ پنهنجن منصوبن کي همٿائڻ ۾ ناڪام ٿي ويا هئا  اهي ڊگهي وقت جا حريف هئا ۽ نه ئي هڪ ٻئي سان ڪجهه ڪرڻ چاهيندا هئا. جڏهن هو 2 بجي شام جو سوريگا اسٽريٽ ۾ داخل ٿيو ، شيما 22 ميل (40 ڪلوميٽر) هن جي پويان هو ، ۽ ڪوريتا اڃا تائين سيبوان سمنڊ ۾ هو ، ليٽي جي ساحل کان ڪيترائي ڪلاڪ پري. جيئن اهي پينون ٻيٽ کان گذري ويا ، نيشيمورا جي قوت انهن جي لاءِ يو ايس-آسٽريليا جي 7 هين فليٽ سپورٽ فورس طرفان قائم ڪيل هڪ تالا ۾ ڀ ranي وئي. آر. ايڊمرل جيسي اولڊينڊورف وٽ ڇهه جنگي ٻيڙيون، چار ڳري ڪروزر، چار هلڪي ڪروزر، 29 تباهه ڪندڙ ۽ 39 پي ٽي ٻيڙيون هيون. تنگي کي پار ڪرڻ ۽ لينڊنگ تائين پهچڻ لاءِ ، نيشيمورا کي گينٽليٽ هلائڻو هو. تقريبن 03:00 تي جاپاني جنگي جهاز فوسو ۽ ٽن تباهه ڪندڙن کي ٽارپيڊو سان ماريو ويو ۽ فوسو ٻن حصن ۾ ورهايو ويو. 03:50 تي آمريڪي جنگي جھازن فائرنگ شروع ڪئي. ريڊار فائر ڪنٽرول جو مطلب هو ته اهي جاپاني کان گهڻو وڌيڪ فاصلي کان نشانو بڻائي سگهن ٿا. جنگي جهاز ياماشيرو ، هڪ ڪروزر ۽ هڪ تباهه ڪندڙ 16 انچ (406 ملي ميٽر) شيلز کان معذور ٿي ويا ؛ ياماشيرو 04:19 تي ٻڏي ويو. نيشيمورا جي ستن جهازن مان صرف هڪ جهاز بچي ويو. 04:25 تي شيما جي ٻن ڪروزرن ۽ اٺن تباهه ڪندڙن جي قوت جنگ ۾ پهچي وئي. فوسو کي ڏسي ۽ هن کي ٻن جنگي جهازن جي برباد ٿيڻ تي يقين ڏياريندي ، شيما هڪ پوئتي هٽڻ جو حڪم ڏنو ، تاريخ ۾ آخري جنگي جهاز جي خلاف جنگي جهاز جي عمل کي ختم ڪيو."},{"question":"Араб мамлекеттеринде балдарды кантип тарбиялашат?","answer":"Башкалардан айырмаланып арабдарда балдарынын тарбиясына 7-10 жашка чейин энеси жооп берет. Эгер баласы эркек болсо, анда 10 жаштан кийин анын тарбиясын атасы өз көзөмөлүнө алып спортко кызыктырат же эркектер өзүн кандай алып жүрүү керектигин үйрөтөт. Арабдарда аялзатынын биринчи милдети бала тарбиялоо болгондуктан алар балдарын балдар бакчасына бербей, өздөрү үйдө тарбиялашат. Ошол себептен алардын балдары чыгармачылык, жаңы технологияны ойлоп табуу илиминен артта калышат. Эң жакшы жери - араб мамлекеттеринде жалгыз бой эне же атасыз жетим балдар деген түшүнүк жок."},{"question":"مفهوم «گراف» در حوزه ریاضیات را با ارائه چند مثال توضیح بده. ","answer":"گراف مدلی ریاضی برای یک مجموعه گسسته‌ است که اعضایش به گونه‌ای با هم پیوند دارند. اعضای این مجموعه می‌توانند چند انسان باشند و ارتباط میان آن‌ها دست دادن با یکدیگر باشد. اعضا می‌توانند اتم‌ها در یک مولکول باشند و ارتباطشان پیوندهای شیمیایی باشد یا این که اعضا می‌توانند بخش‌های گوناگون یک زمین و ارتباط میانشان، پل‌هایی باشد که آن‌ها را به هم می‌پیوندند."},{"question":"இந்த உரை என்ன முக்கியமான நிகழ்வைப் பற்றியது:இந்திய ஆயுத படைகள் 1947, 1965 மற்றும் 1971 ல் இந்திய-பாகிஸ்தான் போர், 1971, கோவா படையெடுப்பு, இந்திய சீன போர், கார்கில் போர் மற்றும் சியாச்சின் மோதல் உட்பட பல முக்கிய இராணுவ நடவடிக்கைளில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகின்றனர்.","answer":"இந்திய-பாகிஸ்தான் போர், 1971"},{"question":"Which of the following statements are INCORRECT?A. All the transition metals except scandium form MO oxides which are ionic.B. The highest oxidation number corresponding to the group number in transition metal oxides is attainedin Sc2O3 to Mn2O7.C. Basic character increases from V2O3 to V2O4 to V2O5.D. V2O4 dissolves in acids to give3– VO4salts.E. CrO is basic but Cr2O3 is amphoteric.Choose the correct answer from the options given below:(1) A and E only (2) B and D only(3) C and D only (4) B and C only","answer":"Answer (3)Sol. All transitions metals except Sc from MO oxides which are ionic.• The highest oxidation number corresponding to the group number in transition metal oxides inattained in Sc2O3 to Mn2O7.• Acidic character increases from V2O3 to V2O4 to V2O5.• V2O4 dissolves in acids to give VO2+.• CrO is basic but Cr2O3 is amphoteric"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"\\tBibilava vonoina, ka tsy tongotra hitsipaka, _ \\"","answer":"\\"tsy tanana handrangotra, tsy vava hiteny, fa todin' aina no andrasana.\\""},{"question":"ਆਦਮੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਰਾ 'ਤੇ ਮਾਣ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੋਇਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸ ਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਦੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਪਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਬਹਸ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਲਾਅ ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖ਼ਲਾ ਮਿਲ ਗਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਲਾਅ ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖ਼ਲਾ ਮਿਲ ਗਿਆ।"},{"question":"Wọn ti ju Oluṣọla Alọ sẹwọn gbere l’Akure, ọmọ ẹ lo fipa ba lo pọ","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ gíga kan niluu Àkúrẹ́ ti ni ki wọn lọọ ju ọkunrin kan, Alọ Oluṣọla, ṣewọn gbere lori ẹsun pe o fipa ba ọmọ ẹ lo pọ.Adajọ Samuel Bọla lo paṣẹ yii lẹyin ti wọn ti ro ẹjọ ọhun niwaju ẹ pe latigba ti ọmọ naa ti wa lọmọ ọdun mẹwaa ni baba ẹ ti n fipa ba a sun.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọmọ yii ko ju ọmọ oṣu mẹfa lọ ti iya ẹ ti binu gbe e ju silẹ, to sì ba tiẹ lọ.Ileewe awọn ọmọ yii laṣiiri ọrọ ọhun ti tu nigba ti ọmọ naa sọ pe o pẹ ti ẹnìkan ti n fipa ba oun lo pọ.O ni baba oun gan-an lẹni ti oun n sọ, ati pe oun ko ju ọmọ ọdun mẹwaa lọ to ti n ki oun mọlẹ.Ọmọ yii ni ti oun ba ti beere owo lọwọ baba oun, yala owo ileewe tabi awọn owo pẹẹpẹẹpẹ mi-in toun fẹẹ fi tọju ara oun, kinni ẹ lo maa n sare fa yọ soun, ti baba oun yoo sì fipa ba oun sun.Ọga ileewe ti ọmọ yii n lọ lo fọrọ ọhun to awọn ọlọpaa leti, loju ẹsẹ ni wọn si ti gbe e lọ s’ile-ẹjọ lori ẹsun onikoko kan, bẹẹ loun paapaa ti sọ pe oun ko jẹbi.Ni bayii, Adajọ Bọla Samuel ti sọ ọ ṣewọn gbere nitori ti ọkunrin naa ko ni ẹri kankan lati fi gbe ọrọ ẹ lẹsẹ pe oun kò jẹbi ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an."},{"question":"సరైన సమాధానాన్ని ఎన్నుకోండి.పద్మశ్రీ అవార్డు పొందిన మొట్టమొదటి మహిళా శాస్త్రవేత్త.ఎ) జానకీ అమ్మాళ్బి) నందిని హరినాథ్సి) కాదంబరి గంగూలీడి) అన్నా మణి","answer":"జానకీ అమ్మాళ్"},{"question":"Ahoana ny fizotron' ny fifidianana?","answer":"Mandeha any amin’ny birao fandatsaham-bato ny mpifidy hifidy ny kandidà tiany."},{"question":"السؤال: اذكر دعاء دعا به نبي الله زكريا؟","answer":"الجواب: رب لا تذرني فردًا وأنت خير الوارثين."},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Polonina? ","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Polonina dia Varsovie."},{"question":"Тортту шам менен кооздоонун кимдер ойлоп тапкан?","answer":"Кооздоо байыркы гректерден башталган. Гректер толгон ай кудайы Артемида атына деп, таттууларды шам менен кооздоп күйгүзүп коюшчу."},{"question":"Apakah peribahasa yang bermaksud \\"Melaga-lagakan seseorang atau kumpulan dengan seseorang atau kumpulan yang lain.\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah adu domba"},{"question":"පිරිපත යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"උවදුර, අපල"},{"question":"次の段落を完成させなさい： トルコで6日、大きな地震がありました。トルコとその隣のシリアでは、8日の昼までに8300人以上が亡くなりました。被害があった所では、倒れた建物から出ることができない人たちを助けています。","answer":"地震が起こった場所から約200kmの町で、大学の先生をしている日本人は「被害がひどい所から逃げてきた人のために、大学が避難の場所になっています。トルコは今寒いので、家が壊れて避難している人のために暖かい服などが必要です」と話しています。 東京に住んでいるクルド人は、トルコにいる家族が無事だとわかりました。家族の話を聞いて「トルコでは雪が降っています。家族は、家が壊れて住む所がないので、早く助けてあげたいです」と話しています。"},{"question":"درج ذیل جملے کا اردو میں ترجمہ کریں:Most people think that health and fitness are the same thing but there is a difference","answer":"اکثر لوگ سوچتے ہیں کہ صحت اور تندرستی ایک ہی چیز ہیں لیکن ان میں فرق ہے۔"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kasihkan anak tangan-tangankan, kasihkan isteri tinggal-tinggalkan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud anak yang dimanjakan akan rosak dan isteri yang diuliti selalu akan mendatangkan kedukacitaan"},{"question":"Parliament of India is called by what name?","answer":"The Parliament of India is commonly known as the Sansad. It is the supreme legislative body in India and is composed of two houses: the Rajya Sabha (Council of States) and the Lok Sabha (House of the People). The President of India is also considered a part of the Parliament, although they do not attend the sessions. The Sansad plays a crucial role in the governance and legislative process of India, operating under the framework of the Constitution of India."},{"question":"માર્ક ઇલિયટ ઝુકરબર્ગ કોણ છે?","answer":"માર્ક ઇલિયટ ઝુકરબર્ગ એ અમેરિકન બિઝનેસ મેગ્નેટ, કમ્પ્યુટર પ્રોગ્રામર, ઇન્ટરનેટ ઉદ્યોગસાહસિક અને પરોપકારી છે.તેમણે સોશિયલ મીડિયા સર્વિસ ફેસબુક અને તેની પેરેંટ કંપની મેટા પ્લેટફોર્મ (અગાઉ ફેસબુક, ઇન્ક.) ની સહ-સ્થાપના કરી, જેમાં તે એક્ઝિક્યુટિવ ચેરમેન, ચીફ એક્ઝિક્યુટિવ ઓફિસર અને કંટ્રોલિંગ શેરહોલ્ડર છે.ઝુકરબર્ગે હાર્વર્ડ યુનિવર્સિટીમાં ભાગ લીધો, જ્યાં તેણે ફેબ્રુઆરી 2004 માં તેના રૂમમેટ્સ એડ્યુઆર્ડો સેવરિન, એન્ડ્રુ મેકકોલમ, ડસ્ટિન મોસ્કોવિટ્ઝ અને ક્રિસ હ્યુજીસ સાથે ફેસબુક શરૂ કર્યું.મૂળરૂપે ફક્ત સિલેક્ટ ક College લેજ કેમ્પસમાં શરૂ કરવામાં આવ્યું હતું, આ સાઇટ ઝડપથી વિસ્તૃત થઈ હતી અને આખરે કોલેજોથી આગળ, 2012 માં એક અબજ વપરાશકર્તાઓ સુધી પહોંચી હતી. ઝુકરબર્ગે મે 2012 માં બહુમતી શેર સાથે કંપનીને જાહેરમાં લીધી હતી.2007 માં, 23 વર્ષની ઉંમરે, તે વિશ્વનો સૌથી નાનો સ્વ-નિર્મિત અબજોપતિ બન્યો.ત્યારબાદ તેમણે ચાન ઝુકરબર્ગ પહેલની સ્થાપના સહિતના અનેક પરોપકારી પ્રયત્નોનું આયોજન કરવા માટે તેમના ભંડોળનો ઉપયોગ કર્યો છે.\\""},{"question":" Firy ny lafiny misy ny nonagon ?","answer":"Misy lafiny sivy ny nonagon "},{"question":"පහත අර්ථයට ගැලපෙන ගීතය කුමක්ද?ගීතය නොඇසුව සවනක් නොමැති තරම්ය.. එක් අසම්මත ආදරයක හැගීම් වචන බවට පත් වන්නේ අජන්තා රණසිංහයන්ගේ අතිනි.. සමාජයේ සම්මත යැයි සම්මත කර ගත් කරුණු අබියස තවත් එක් මිනිස් සිතක අසරණ වීමක් පිළිබඳව ගීතය රචිතයි. රන් කෙන්දන් බැඳඅතැඟිලි එක්කළ ආදරයයිපෙම් රැහැනෙන් බැඳසිතුම් වසඟ කළ ආදරයයි.......ඇය විවාහකයි. නමුත් සිය සැමියාට ඇයගේ සිත තුල ඇති කැමැත්ත කුමක් හෝ හේතුවක් නිසාවෙන් සීමා සහිතයි. එය යෝජිත විවාහයක් වන්නට හැකියි. එසේත් නැතිනම් දෙදෙනා තේරුම් ගැනීමේ අර්බුදයක් හෝ ආදරය හඳුනා ගැනීමේ වරදක් ද විය හැකියි. දෙදෙනාගේ අතැඟිලි එක වූවත් ඇගේ සිත තුල වුවේ මහා හිස් බවක්. මේ අතරතුර ඇයට හමු වූ තවත් තරුණයෙකු කෙරෙහි ඇගේ සිත ඇදී යනවා. ඔවුන් එකිනෙකා හා නිරායාසයෙන්ම ප්‍රේමයෙන් බැඳුනා. විවාහය තුල මෙන් නොව මේ තරුණයාට හැකි වී තිබෙනවා ඇයගේ සිතුම් වසඟ කර ගන්නට.ඇගේ හැගීම් නිසා ඇය කොතරම් අසරණ වී සිටිනවා ඇතිද..! කිසිවෙකු සර්ව සම්පූර්ණ නොවූ ලෝකයක ඇය වැරදි හෝ නිවැරදි බව කවරෙකුට කිව හැකිද..? කිරිලිය සේ දුර පියාසලාලාඅත්තටු රිදුණා පමණයිදෑල විදාහළ දෑත මගේඔබටත් ඔහුටත් උරුමයිහිරු සඳු එකවර දෙපස නැඟේකළුවර ඇයි විජිතයම මගේ....සම්මතය තුල එක වරක ප්‍රේමයෙන් බැඳීමට ඉඩ ඇත්තේ එක අයෙකු හා පමණයි. එය එසේ ව්වුවත් දැන් මැය විවාහකයි. එයින් එපිට ලෝකයක් පිලිබඳ තව දුරටත් සිහින මැවීමට කොතෙකුත් වුවමනා කම් තිබුනද එය සමාජය ඉදිරියේ වරදක්. ඉතින් තව දුරටත් සිහින මැවීමෙන් සිදු වන්නේ වෙහෙසට පත්වීම පමණයි. සිය සැමියාගේ සහ පෙර කී තරුණයාගේ එකිනෙකාට වෙනස් සුදුසුකම් දකින මැය ඒ දෙදෙනාටම සිය ආදරය පුද කිරීමට සැරසෙනවා. දිවා කල ලොව එලිය කරන්නේ හිරුයි. රාත්‍රියේ එය භාර වන්නේ සඳුටයි. එසේ දිවා රෑ එලිය කරන හිරු සඳු එක වර පැයුවොත් ඉන් කෙතරම් එළියක් ලෝකයට ලැබේවිද... එලෙස ඇගේ දිවියට හිරු සඳු එක වර පායා ඇති මුත් ඇගේ ලෝකය වසා පැතිරී ගොස් ඇත්තේ අඳුරයි. එය ඇයට පවා වටහා ගත නොහැකි සංකීර්ණ හැගීම් සමුදායක්.කණාටු සුළඟේ දුහුළු මලකි අදවල්මත් වී පාවෙන්නේඔබගෙන් දෝඔහුගෙන් දෝමා හෙට දින සමුගන්නේ.....සිහින් සුලඟක පාවී ඈතට ඇදී යන දුහුල් මලක් සේ කිසිඳු අරමුණක් නොමැතිව ඇගේ හිත ඔහේ පා වෙනවා. පිළිතුරක් සොයා ගත නොහැකි මේ පැනය ඉදිරියේ ඇගේ සිතට දැන් හොදටම වෙහෙසයි.. නැවත ඇගේ සිතට වැටහෙනවා මේ වේදනාවෙන් මිදීමටනම් ඇය කාගෙන් හෝ සමුගත යුතු බව. නමුත් ඒ ඇගේ සිත දිනා ගත් ඇය ආදරය කරන තරුනාගෙන්ද නැතිනම් ඇයට ආදරය කරන විවාහක ස්වාමියාගෙන්ද තව දුරටත් මෙය ඇයට පැනයක්.. ගීයේ අරුත විමසා බැලීමේදී පුදුමයට පත් කරවන සුළු කරුණක් වේනම් ඒ අජන්තා රණසිංහයන් කොයි ලෙසකින් මෙම අතිශය සංකීර්ණ සිතුවිලි ගී පද බවට පත් කලේද යන්නයි. ගීතයේ ඇතුලත සිටින කාන්තා චරිතයට සපුරාම ආරූඩ වන ඔහු මෙහිදී දකින්නේ ස්ත්‍රියක් තුල සමාජය විසින් දකින්නාවූ චපලත්වය නොවේ. ඇයද හැගීම් අභියස අසරණ වන එක් මනුෂ්‍යයෙක්ම බව ඔහු ගීතයෙන් මනාව හුවා දක්වන්නේ රසිකයාටද පැනයක් ඉතිරි කරමින්..","answer":"රන් කෙන්දන් බැඳ අතැඟිලි එක්කළ ආදරයයි...පෙම් රැහැනෙන් බැඳසිතුම් වසඟ කළ ආදරයයි.....පෙම් රැහැනෙන් බැඳසිතුම් වසඟ කළ ආදරයයි.......කිරිලිය සේ දුර පියාසලාලාඅත්තටු රිදුණා පමණයිදෑල විදාහළ දෑත මගේඔබටත් ඔහුටත් උරුමයිහිරු සඳු එකවර දෙපස නැඟේකළුවර ඇයි විජිතයම මගේ....කණාටු සුළඟේ දුහුළු මලකි අදවල්මත් වී පාවෙන්නේඔබගෙන් දෝඔහුගෙන් දෝමා හෙට දින සමුගන්නේ..... ගායනය - විශාරද නන්දා මාලනීගීපද - අජන්තා රණසිංහසංගීතය - සරත් දසනායකචිත්‍රපටය - දුහුළු මලක්"},{"question":"Làm sao để lựa chọn từ ngữ và cấu trúc câu khi viết 1 văn bản?","answer":"- Sử dụng từ ngữ phù hợp với đề tài của văn bản; phù hợp với tính chất của loại văn bản; phù hợp với bạn đọc.- Đặt câu phù hợp với tính chất của loại văn bản, phù hợp với ngữ cảnh để tạo thành một mạch văn thống nhất, đồng thời không lặp cấu trúc, gây nhàm chán."},{"question":"سوال: ایک شخص کو سونے کا ہنس تحفے کے طور پر ملا، لیکن اس نے اسے رکھنے کے بجائے اس کے سونے کے انڈے پورے گاؤں کے ساتھ بانٹنے کا فیصلہ کیا۔ اس نے اپنے لیے سونے کے انڈے رکھنے کے بجائے بانٹنے کا انتخاب کیوں کیا؟","answer":"جواب: اس شخص کا خیال تھا کہ مال بانٹنے سے پوری برادری کے لیے زیادہ خوشی اور خوشحالی آئے گی۔اخلاق: سخاوت اور اشتراک اجتماعی بھلائی اور خوشی کا باعث بن سکتا ہے۔"},{"question":"ගෝරතර යනුවෙන් වචනයක් තිබේද එසේනම් එහි තේරුම කුමක්ද?","answer":"දන්නා තරමින්, එසේ වචන නැත. නිවැරදි වචනය \\"ඝෝර\\" යන්නයි. තේරුම \\"බිය දැනෙන\\" යන්නයිඝෝරතර (घोरतर):වඩා භයානක, ඉතා  බිහිසුණු,"},{"question":"فين كاين كهف العهود؟","answer":" المغرب "},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ පළමු පුරවැසියා කවුද?","answer":" ඉන්දියාවේ ජනාධිපති"},{"question":"ලෝක ජල දිනය සමරනු ලබන්නේ","answer":"මර්තු 22"},{"question":"ஹிப்பாலஸ் பருவக்காற்று குறிப்பு வரைக.","answer":"• கி.பி. முதல் நூற்றாண்டில் வாழ்ந்த கிரேக்க மாலுமி ஹிப்பாலஸ்.• இவர் பருவக்காற்றின் உதவியால் முசிறித் துறைமுகத்திற்குப் புதிய வழியைக் கண்டுபிடித்தார்.• விரைவான பயணத்திற்கு இப்புதிய வழி உதவியதால் யவனக் கப்பல்கள் சேரர்களின் முசிறித் துறைமுகத்திற்கு அதிகமாக வந்தன. (கிரேக்கரும் உரோமானியரும் யவனர் ஆவர்) ‘• யவனர் இப்பருவக்காற்றிற்கு அதைக் கண்டுபிடித்த ஹிப்பாலஸ் பெயரையே சூட்டினர்."},{"question":"Maxaa Keena Baruurta badan?","answer":"Baruurta badan ee ninka jirkiisa buuxisa, weliba midda gasha dhexda ee sameysa caloosha weyni waxa ay soo deysaa insaaym (enzyme) la dhaho Aromatase, kaas oo hormoon ka Testosterone ka oo ah hormoon ay shaqadiisu tahay in uu caawiyo soo saaridda dhiiga cas, tayeynta iyo awoodsiinta shahwada, xoojinta iyo weyneynta murqaha ninka, badinta xajmiga iyo culayska lafaha, maareyna baruurta jirka, iyo kor u qaadidda baahida ragannimo (libido/sexual drive) ee ninka, u beddela hormoon kale oo la dhaho Estrogen, Kaas oo marka uu ragga ku bato yareeya awoodda galmada, badiya baruurta iyo cayilka jirka, yareeya damac shahweedka ninka, weyneeya naasaha ninka, badiya daalka jireed ee qofka, keena niyadjab (depression) iyo tash aan dhammaan, sidoo kalena baabi’iya ama dhulka la gala murqaha kala duwan ee ninka, arrintaas oo dhaawacda ad’adeyga iyo xoogga waxqabad ee qofka."},{"question":"Cuál es la respuesta a la siguiente pregunta: ¿Dónde nació el vocalista de Led Zeppelin?","answer":"La ciudad donde nació el vocalista de Led Zepelling, Robert Anthony Plant es West Bromwich, United Kingdom"},{"question":"Awọn akẹkọọ ti wọn ji gbe royin: Omi tawọn maaluu n mu ni wọn fun wa mu, ojoojumọ la n jẹ kumọ","answer":"Yoruba bọ, wọn ni, ‘aja to ba re’le ẹkun to bọ, niṣe lo yẹ ka ki i ku ewu’. Bọrọ awọn ọmọleewe ijọba Government Science College, to wa ni Kagara, nipinlẹ Niger, ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ bọ kuro lahaamọ awọn agbebọn lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide yii, ṣe ri gẹlẹ niyi, wọn loju awọn ri mabo ninu igbo ti wọn ji wọn gbe si.Ọjọ mẹsan-an gbako lawọn ọmọleewe naa fi wa lakata awọn ọdaran agbebọn naa, ọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu keji yii, lawọn janduku agbebọn naa ya bo ilegbee (hostel) awọn ọmọ yii ninu ọgba ileewe wọn, wọn yinbọn pa ọkan lara awọn ọmọ naa, wọn ji mejidinlọgbọn lara wọn gbe, wọn tun ji awọn tiṣa wọn mẹrin, ati mọlẹbi awọn tiṣa naa mẹfa. Aropọ gbogbo wọn jẹ mejidinlogoji ti wọn tu silẹ lọjọ Satide.Gomina ipinlẹ Niger, Abubakar Sani Bello lo kọkọ royin ohun toju awọn ọmọ naa ri nigba ti wọn n dari bọ wale, o ni irin a-rin-wọ-dii lawọn majeṣin yii rin ninu igbo kijikiji fun wakati mẹjọ, lati aago mẹrin idaji ti wọn ti yọnda wọn, ki wọn too rin jade si gbangba.O lawọn oniṣẹ ọba ti wọn lọọ pade wọn sọ foun pe omi tun fẹẹ tẹyin wọ’gbin lẹnu, latari bawọn ẹgbẹ agbebọn mi-in tun ṣe rẹburu awọn ọmọ naa lọna, ti wọn lawọn o ni i jẹ ki wọn lọ, afi tawọn ba rowo. Gomina ko sọ boya wọn fun wọn lowo ati iye ti wọn gba, ṣugbọn o ni wọn da wọn gunlẹ fungba diẹ, ẹbẹ si pọ gidi ki wọn too yọnda wọn lati maa lọ.Ṣugbọn kekere leyi jẹ lara ohun tawọn ọmọ naa royin pe oju awọn ri ninu aginju ti wọn ko wọn pamọ si.Ọkan lara wọn, Abubakar Sidi, to wa nipele ẹkọ SS3, sọ pe niṣe ni wọn to awọn bii ẹni to sori ila, ti wọn si n fun awọn lẹgba lọkọọkan kari-kari. O ni kumọ kan bayii ni wọn fi n lu awọn, ojoojumọ si ni.O ni ẹwa ni wọn n se fawọn jẹ, ẹwa nikan ni, ẹẹkan lojumọ si lawọn n jẹun, o lẹwa ọhun ko ni i jinna nigba mi-in, ṣugbọn ko sẹni to le sọrọ laarin awọn, tori wọn ti sọ fawọn pe ẹni to ba ṣaroye maa fiku ṣefa jẹ ni.O lomi o si ninu igbo naa, awọn o tiẹ mọ ibi ti wọn ti lọọ wa omi wa, omi rukuruku kan ti wọn bu kalẹ fawọn maaluu ninu basia kan ti wọn gbe sibẹ lawọn maa n bu mu. O lawọn ni wọn maa bu omi naa fawọn, ẹẹkan lojumọ naa si ni. O loriṣiiriṣii iya bayii ni wọn fi jẹ awọn.Ọmọ SS3 mi-in, Suleiman Lawal, sọ pe awọn jiya mọ pọnmọ-pọnmọ ete lọdọ awọn agbebọn ọhun, o ni lilu buruku buruku ni wọn fi tawọn ṣe, kumọ ti wọn fi n lu awọn maaluu ni wọn fi n lu awọn. O ni wọn o bikita bawọn ba ku.“Iya gidi ni wọn fi jẹ wa o, mi o ri iru nnkan bayii ri laye mi, wọn mu wa rin bii ẹṣin ni, a kan n rin ọna jinjin lai mọ ibi ti a n lọ, irin ojoojumọ lati ibi kan si ibi kan ni, ninu igbo. Ko rọrun rara.Ọrọ naa ka akẹkọọ-binrin Sarat Isah lara debii pe ko sọ ju gbolohun meji lọ to fi bu sẹkun. O ni o dun oun gan-an, iya toun ko jẹ ri laye ni wọn fi jẹ oun. O ni niṣe ni wọn ṣe awọn bii ọmọ ẹran.Ohun toju awọn ogo-wẹẹrẹ yii ri buru debii pe niṣe ni ọkan ninu wọn bẹrẹ si i seeemi nigba ti wọn fi ko wọn jade. Gomina Abubakar lawọn ti sare gbe ọmọ naa lọ sileewosan ijọba ki wọn le doola ẹmi ẹ. O lawọn tun ti pese itọju pajawiri ati ayẹwo iṣegun fun gbogbo wọn. Ọkunrin naa ni akata ijọba lawọn ọmọ naa ṣi maa wa fọjọ meji si mẹta kan, ti wọn ba ti ri i pe ara wọn ti balẹ, ilera wọn si ti sunwọn lawọn maa da wọn pada fawọn obi wọn.Ọmọ SS2 kan, Mahmood Mohammed, sọ pe oun o le sọ boya oun tun maa pada sileewe. O lọwọ awọn obi oun niyẹn wa, ṣugbọn iya ti wọn fi jẹ awọn yii ko mu kileewe wu oun lati lọ mọ.Iṣẹlẹ yii, atawọn mi-in to tun waye lẹyin eyi lagbegbe naa ti ko ipaya bawọn obi pẹlu, ọpọ wọn lo sọ fawọn oniroyin pe awọn o le yọnda ọmọ wọn lati lọ sileewe ti ko si aabo mọ.Abilekọ Hafsat Abdullahi sọ pe meji lara awọn ọmọ oun lo kagbako iṣẹlẹ yii, o dupẹ lọwọ Ọlọrun pe wọn ti pada. O loun ati baba wọn ti pinnu pe tawọn ba tiẹ maa fi ọmọ sileewe ijọba, awọn ko ni i yọnda ki wọn maa gbe inu ọgba ileewe mọ, ki wọn maa lọ, ki wọn si ma pada lojumọ ni.Bẹẹ lawọn obi mi-in kọminu gidi lori iṣẹlẹ yii."},{"question":"Maxay tahay faa’idada Karootada Iyo Cabitaankeeda & Xanuunada ay Ka Hortag u yihiin?","answer":"Karootadu waa khudrad ay Soomaalidu si fiican u taqaanno oo dhulkooda laga helo. Karootada waxaa lagu tiriyaa khudradaha ugu caafimaadka badan, waxa ay xambaarsan tahay nafaqo kala duwan iyo walxo kale oo caafimaadka faaido ugu jirto. Haddaba Daryeel Magazine waxa u warbixintan ku soo gudbinayaa faaidooyinka karootada ama dabacasaha ee cilmi baadhis ahaan la xaqiijiyay.1. Awood siinta diifaca jidhka:Karootadu waxa ay kaalin mug leh ka qaadataa xoojinta habdhiska difaaca ee jidhka ee aadamaha, sida oo kalana waxa ay hodan ku tahay Faytamiinnada A iyo C oo jidhka muhiim u ah. 2. Caafimaadka wadnaha:Karootadu waxa ay yareysaa xaddiga Kolestaroolka dhibaatada leh ee jidhka ku urura waxayna sare u qaadaa kolestaroolka fiican, tani waxay ka hortagtaa xanuunnada ku dhaca wadnaha. 3. Xoojinta aragga:Faytamiinka A oo jidhka ku yaraada waxa ay kordhisaa halista indho beelka habeenkii ama waxa ay Soomaalidu u taqaanno “habeenada”. Karootada waxa ka buuxa maado la dhaho “beta-carotene” taas oo jidhku u beddelo faytmiin A.Faytamiinkani waxa uu siyaadiyaa awoodda aragga wuxuuna ka hortagaa indho beelka habeenkii, caadka indhaha fuula iyo xanuunka “macular degeneration” oo ah cillad ay badanaa duqnimadu keento. 4. Caafimaadka afka:Karootadu waxay siyaadisaa calyada, waxayna la dagaallantaa bakteeriyada afka ku dhalata, sidaasna waxa ay ku yareysaa bololka ilkaha iyo suuska.5. Kobcinta caafimaadka maqaarka iyo timaha:Karootadu waxa ay u fiican caafimaad maqaarka. Faytamiinnada A iyo C ee ka buuxa kaarootada waxa ay jidhka ka ilaaliyaan dhaawaca fallaadhaha qorraxda, waxayna dib u dhigaan calaamadaha duqnimada sida in maqaarku uu yeesho laalaab ama duuduub. Karootadu waxay kaloo uroon tahay timaha, waxa ay wanaajisaa habsami u wareegga dhiigga si uu u gaadho timaha jirriddooda, sidaa awgeedna timaha ayaa xoogeysta si fiicanna u baxa. Karootada faa’idadeedu waxa ay badan tahay inta aan la karin, sideeda ayaa loo cuni karaa ama cabbitaan ahaan ayaa loo shiidan karaa.6. Dheefshiidka:Karootada waxaa ku badan ganka loo yaqaanno “dietary fiber” kaas oo wanaajiya dheefshiidka, calool istaaggana ka hortaga.7.Xakamaynta xanuunka macaanka: Karootadu waxa ay nidaamisaa heerka sonkorta dhiigga, waxayna ka hortagtaa firfircooni yarida ama howlgabka unugyada soo saara insulinta. Dadka qaba xanuunka macaanka waxaa lagula dardaarmaa inay ku dedaalaan cunista kaarootada, cabitaan ahaanna ay u cabbaan iyadoo aan lagu darin sonkor."},{"question":"వరదలు కరవుల వల్ల మొక్కలకు ఏమి జరుగుతుంది?","answer":"పంటల వేళ్లు ఉండే ప్రాంతంలోకి నీరు వర్షపాతం ద్వారాగానీ, సాగునీటి ద్వారాగానీ చేరుతుంది. నేలకి తేమని నిల్వ చేసుకునే సామర్థ్యం ఉంటుంది. వరద వంటి పరిస్థితుల్లో ఎక్కువ నీళ్లు ఉండి, అది నేల లోపలి పొరల్లోకి ఇంకకపోతే మొక్కల వేళ్లు దెబ్బతింటాయి. ఇంకొకవైపు కరవు పరిస్థితులలో వేళ్ల ప్రాంతంలో తగినంత తేమ లేకపోతే పంటలు వడిలిపోతాయి."},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 日本では3年前の1月15日に、新型コロナウイルスがうつった人が初めて見つかりました。国によると、今までにうつった人は、何回もうつった人を入れて3100万人になりました。亡くなった人は6万2000人です。去年はうつりやすいオミクロン株が広がりました。1年でうつった人は約2700万人で、亡くなった人は約3万9000人でした。3年の間で、ワクチンを受けた人は増えました。亡くなったり病気がひどくなったりする人の割合は低くなりました。国は、新型コロナウイルスの厳しいルールをどうするか専門家と話をしています。しかし、去年の秋からコロナウイルスがうつった人が増えて、亡くなる人も今まででいちばん多くなっています。このため、コロナウイルスが広がらないようにして、社会や経済の活動をしていくことが必要です。","answer":"日本で新型コロナウイルスがうつった人が見つかってから3年"},{"question":"Dime el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿En cuántas películas ha estado Chris Evans?","answer":"El tema de la pregunta es cine."},{"question":"පාසැල් සිසුන්ගේ ඉදිරි දියුණුවට අවහිර වන මාර බලවේග පැමිණිය හැකි ස්වරූප කිහිපයක් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"පාසැල් සිසුන්ගේ ඉදිරි දියුණුවට අවහිර වන මාර බලවේග පැමිණිය හැකි ස්වරූප කිහිපයක් පහත පරිදි වේ.- තරුණ මදය- කුසගින්න- කුසීතකම- දඩබ්බර ගතිය- ප්‍රචණ්ඩ සිතුවිලි- කාමුක හැඟීම්- ඊර්ෂ්‍යාව- පළිගැනීම"},{"question":"すごろくの「あがり」はゴールのことですが、お寿司屋さんの「あがり」は何のことでしょう？","answer":"お茶です。"},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Менин дүйнөмдүн ушунчалык шайыр болушунун көптөгөн себептеринин бири сенсиң. Ал ортодо, сендей дос өмүрдүн байлыгы. Туулган кунуңуз менен куттуктайм!"},{"question":"مثال عن العبارة البادئة:\\"تحقق معي من أهمية القراءة في حياتنا.\\"","answer":"مثال عن التوجيه:\\"اكتب خطابًا قصيرًا للطلاب في مدرستك يشجعهم على القراءة ويوضح لهم فوائدها. استخدم أمثلة من الحياة الواقعية وقصص شخصية لإلهام الطلاب. قدم نصائح عملية حول كيفية تنظيم وقت القراءة واختيار الكتب المناسبة. يجب أن يكون الخطاب واضحًا وملهمًا، وأن يتضمن فكرة رئيسية ومقدمة وخاتمة قوية.\\""},{"question":"ਭਾਰਤੀ ਦੀਪ ਸਮੂਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਗੀਕਰਨ ਕਰੋ ਅਤੇ ਟਾਪੂਆਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਲਿਖੋ ।","answer":"ਭਾਰਤੀ ਦੀਪਾਂ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਲ ਸੰਖਿਆ 267 ਹੈ । ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਲਿਖੇ ਦੋ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ1. ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੀ ਖਾੜੀ ਵਿਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਅੰਡੇਮਾਨ-ਨਿਕੋਬਾਰ ਦੀਪ ਸਮੂਹ-ਇਹ ਦੀਪ ਉੱਤਰ-ਪੂਰਬੀ ਪਰਬਤ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ | ਅਰਾਕਾਨ ਯੋੜ (ਮਯਾਂਮਾਰ ਵਿਚ) ਦਾ ਵੀ ਵਿਸਤਾਰ ਹੈ । ਇਸਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆ 204 ਹੈ । ਸੈਡਲ (Saddle Peak) ਅੰਡੇਮਾਨ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੀ ਚੋਟੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸਦੀ ਉੱਚਾਈ 737 ਮੀਟਰ ਹੈ । ਨਿਕੋਬਾਰ ਵਿਚ 19 ਦੀਪ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਗ੍ਰੇਟਰ ਨਿਕੋਬਾਰ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਦੀਪ ਹੈ ।2. ਅਰਬ ਸਾਗਰ ਵਿਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਲਕਸ਼ਦੀਪ ਸਮੂਹ-ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਪਾਂ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਲ ਸੰਖਿਆ 34 ਹੈ । ਇਸਦੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਵਿਚ ਅਮੀਨਦੀਵੀ (Amindivi) ਅਤੇ ਦੱਖਣ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਨੀਕੋਟਾ (Minicoy) ਦੀਪ ਸਥਿਤ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਦਵੀਯੋ ਦਾ ਮੱਧਵਰਤੀ ਭਾਗ ਲਕਾਇਵ (Laccadive) ਕਹਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"I. K. Dairo","answer":"Isaiah Kehinde Dairo MBE (1930–1996) je olorin ara Naijiria.I.K. A bi Dairo ni ilu Offa, ti o wa ni ode oni Ipinle Kwara; idile rẹ jẹ akọkọ lati Ijebu-Jesa ṣaaju ṣiṣi lọ si Offa. O lọ si ile -iwe alakọbẹrẹ Kristiẹni Ihinrere ni Offa, sibẹsibẹ, o kọ awọn ẹkọ rẹ silẹ nigbamii nitori ọdun rirọ ninu awọn inawo idile rẹ. O kuro ni Offa o rin irin ajo lọ si Ijebu-Jesa nibiti o ti yan lati ṣiṣẹ bi barber. Ni irin -ajo rẹ, o mu ilu pẹlu rẹ ti ilu kọ nigbati o jẹ ọdun meje. Ni akoko ti o n gbe ni Ijebu-Jesa, o ti jẹ olufẹ ti nlu ilu. Ellison, Jen. Dairo Mu Ohun Juju wa si UW, '' The Skanner ''. Nigbati ko gba iṣẹ lọwọ, o lo akoko lati tẹtisi awọn aṣaaju -ọna ibẹrẹ ti orin juju ni agbegbe naa o si ṣe idanwo pẹlu ìlù. Ifẹ rẹ si orin jùju pọ si ni akoko pupọ, ati ni 1942, o darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ kan ti Taiwo Igese dari ṣugbọn laarin awọn ọdun diẹ, ẹgbẹ naa fọ. Ni ọdun 1948, o lọ si Ẹdẹ, Nigeria. Ẹdẹ ilu kan ni ode oni Ipinle Osun nibi ti o ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ nibẹ gẹgẹ bi oniṣowo asọ ẹlẹsẹ ati ṣe orin pẹlu ẹgbẹ agbegbe kan ni ẹgbẹ. Ni ọjọ kan, lakoko ti ọga rẹ ti rin irin -ajo, I.K. Dairo pinnu lati darapọ mọ awọn ọrẹ ẹlẹgbẹ rẹ lati ṣere ni ibi ayẹyẹ agbegbe kan, ti ko mọ fun un, ọga rẹ n pada wa ni ọjọ kanna, ọga naa binu si iṣe naa o si yọ kuro ninu iṣẹ rẹ nitori abajade. Christopher Alan Waterman. Juju: Itan Awujọ ati Itanilẹkọ ti Orin Gbajumo Afirika, University of Chicago Press, 1990. p 101.I.K. Dairo lepa ọpọlọpọ awọn iṣẹ afọwọkọ lẹhin ibọn rẹ ati pe o ni anfani lati ṣafipamọ owo to lati lọ si Ibadan, nibiti Daniel Ojoge, akọrin Jùjú aṣaaju -ọna kan ti nṣere nigbagbogbo. O gba isinmi lati darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ kan pẹlu Daniel Ojoge o si ṣere fun igba diẹ ṣaaju ki o to pada si Ijebu-Ijesa, pupọ julọ awọn ere orin ti o ṣe pẹlu ẹgbẹ Ojoge wa ni alẹ. Abala MT111 - lati Awọn aṣa Musical No 1, Mid 1983: \\"irawọ gbigbasilẹ Afirika pataki\\" Ti gba pada 6 Oṣu Kini 2012Iṣẹ orin Dairo wọ inu ọna iyara nigbati o da ẹgbẹ orin mẹwa ti a pe ni Orilẹ -ede Morning Star ni ọdun 1957. Ni ọdun 1960, lakoko ayẹyẹ ominira Naijiria, a pe ẹgbẹ naa lati ṣere nibi ayẹyẹ ti gbajugbaja kan Ibadan agbẹjọro ati oloṣelu Oloye DOA Oguntoye. Pẹlu ọpọlọpọ awọn olokiki Yoruba awọn alabojuto ni ibi isere, I.K. Dairo ṣe afihan ara rẹ ti orin jùjú ati gba akiyesi ati iwunilori lati ọdọ awọn alabojuto Yoruba miiran ti o wa, ọpọlọpọ ninu wọn nigbamii pe e si awọn ere orin lakoko awọn ayẹyẹ aṣa tabi awọn ayẹyẹ lasan. Ni ibẹrẹ awọn ọdun 1960, o yi orukọ ẹgbẹ naa pada si Blue Spots ati pe o tun bori idije kan ti a tẹlifisiọnu ni Western Nigeria lati ṣe afihan ọpọlọpọ awọn talenti ninu orin jùjú. Lakoko asiko naa, o ni anfani lati ṣe aami igbasilẹ tirẹ ni ifowosowopo pẹlu Haruna Ishola ati ṣaṣeyọri pataki ati olokiki olokiki ati olokiki.IK Dairo farahan ni ipari awọn ọdun 1950 ni ibamu pẹlu euphoria ti nyara si ominira. O rii nigba naa gẹgẹ bi akọrin akoko kan ti o le gba akoko moriwu ti o ṣaju ominira orilẹ -ede naa ati ni ṣoki lẹhin ominira. Ohun itọwo orin lakoko akoko naa ti pari lati mọrírì orin mimọ si ọpọlọpọ awọn ohun ti o pọ sii. Akoko naa tun jẹ ọkan ninu awọn ayẹyẹ lavish pẹlu awọn akọrin bi ifamọra ẹgbẹ.Aṣeyọri ere orin Dairo ni awọn ọdun 1960, ni ipa nipasẹ awọn ifosiwewe oriṣiriṣi pẹlu ibi -iṣere kan lati pẹlu awọn ohun ibile, igbesi aye iṣelu ti awọn ọdun 1950, eyiti o fun ni atilẹyin ati idojukọ lori Rhythm, lu ati tẹmpo ti o ṣe afihan awọn ohun oriṣiriṣi ẹya ati ninu ilana ti o yori si afilọ rẹ ti o ga ju ẹgbẹ akọkọ ẹya rẹ lọ. [6] Ẹgbẹ rẹ ṣe idanwo ati dun pẹlu awọn ọna orin ti ipilẹṣẹ lati oriṣiriṣi awọn agbegbe Yoruba ati tun lo Edo , Urhobo, Itsekiri ati Hausa ede ni diẹ ninu awọn orin wọn. Eto ti ẹgbẹ ti o ṣeto daradara ati sisọ, Yorùbá ati Latin America ni ipa lori ilu ijó ati awọn orin itagbangba lori awọn ile -iṣowo ti awọn alabojuto jẹ awọn nkan ti o ṣe alabapin ni igbega rẹ si giga ti Juju ati gbagede orin ni orilẹ -ede naa. O tun lo iṣiṣẹpọ orin, o dapọ Ijebu-Ijesa choral ohun pupọ-pupọ pẹlu awọn orin aladun ati ọrọ lati awọn orisun Kristiẹni."},{"question":"යුරෝපයේ ප්‍රබලම ආර්ථිකයට හිමිකම් කියන රට ","answer":"ජර්මනිය"},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Rwizi rweCugir rwizi rwizi rweGhiaag muRomania. Mutsara 2: Rwizi rweGhișag rwizi rwizi rweCugir muRomania. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hongu kana kuti kwete?","answer":"Kwete, mutsara wekutanga nemutsara wechipiri hazvireve chinhu chimwe chete. Musiyano uri mukuzivikanwa kwerwizi rukuru uye rwizi rwarwo:Mumutsara wekutanga, inotaura kuti  Rwizi rweCugir  irwo rutsva rwe  Ghiaag River  muRomania.Mumutsara wechipiri, inotaura kuti  Rwizi rweGhișag  irwizi rwe Cugir Rwizi muRomania.Mitsara miviri iyi inotsanangura nzizi dzakasiyana uye hukama hwadzo semikova kune imwe neimwe."},{"question":"අපගේ සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලය අයත් වන චක්‍රාවාටය,","answer":"ක්ෂීරපථය"},{"question":"س225- كم يستغرق وصول ضوء الشمس إلى الأرض ؟","answer":"ج225- ثمان دقائق وثلاث ثوان"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: Η ορεινή περιοχή ήταν επίσης διαμέρισμα της Γαλλικής Αλγερίας κατά τη διάρκεια αλλά και μετά τον","answer":"Αλγερινό Πόλεμο της Ανεξαρτησίας από το 1954 έως το 1962. Σε αυτήν την περιοχή ξεκίνησε ο Αλγερινός Πόλεμος της Ανεξαρτησίας από τους Βέρβερους μαχητές της ελευθερίας. Το τραχύ έδαφος της περιοχής Ωρές, την καθιστά ακόμη μια από τις λιγότερο ανεπτυγμένες περιοχές στο Μαγκρέμπ."},{"question":"Мурас деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Атадан балага берилчү дүнүйө ( атанын жашоодо тапкан баардык байлыгы) . Өлгөн кишинин мураскерлерине (балдарына) өтүүчү мүлк."},{"question":"ＡＢＯ式の血液型で、日本人で最も多いのは何型でしょう？","answer":"Ａ型です。"},{"question":"قم بالإجابة على السؤال من هي المُحدِثة المُلقبة بـ مسندة أصبهان ؟ من النص التالي: سمعت الحديث من والدها، وسمعت حضوراً من العالمة والمُحدِثة المُلقبة بـ مسندة أصبهان فاطمة بنت عبد الله اُلجوزْدانَّيِة، وسمعت من فاطمة بنت محمد بن أحمد البغدادي ، وسمعت كثيراً من أبو القاسم زاهر بن طاهر بن محمد الشحامي، وسمعت كتاب \\"مسند أبي يعلى الموصلي\\" من سعيد بن أبي الرجاء الصيرفي، وغيرهم..","answer":"المُحدِثة المُلقبة بـ \\"مسندة أصبهان\\" هي فاطمة بنت عبد الله الجوزدانية."},{"question":"Geef me een samenvatting van het artikel: Misdaad slachtoffers die noodhulp zoeken, wachten tot 50 procent langer op hulp dan drie jaar geleden, waarbij de reactietijden met een paar extra minuten toenemen. Uit de analyse van cijfers van het ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken blijkt dat in gebieden als Bedfordshire, Devon en Cornwall de reactietijden nu ten minste 50 procent langer zijn dan drie jaar geleden. In Essex en Kent wachten slachtoffers van misdrijven tot een derde langer op een antwoord. De reactietijden van de politie zijn in sommige gebieden met 50% verhoogd vanwege bezuinigingen. De schaduwminister van Binnenlandse Zaken van Labour, Yvette Cooper, op de foto, beweerde dat de slachtoffers van misdaad in gevaar werden gebracht. Volgens cijfers die aan de Labour Party zijn verstrekt op grond van de Freedom of Information Act, zijn in Engeland en Wales de gemiddelde 999 responstijden met 17 procent toegenomen. In Bedfordshire is de gemiddelde responstijd gestegen van zeven naar elf minuten. Misdaad slachtoffers in Cambridgeshire en Zuid-Wales wachten gemiddeld 14 minuten. De schaduwminister van Binnenlandse Zaken Yvette Cooper zei: \\"999 wachttijden zijn aanzienlijk toegenomen voor de meest ernstige noodsituaties en dat betekent dat slachtoffers in gevaar worden gebracht. 'Dit is het directe gevolg van de bezuinigingen van de Tory politie, maar nu willen ze nog verder gaan.' In een poging de druk op het 999-systeem te verminderen, introduceerde de regering een 101-nummer om minder dringende misdrijven zoals antisociaal gedrag, drugshandel, autodiefstal en klein vandalisme te melden. Het aantal politieagenten in Engeland en Wales is sinds 2009 met 17.000 gedaald, met verschillende krachten die nog meer extreme reducties plannen. De Metropolitan Police is een van de weinige krachten in het land die in staat is geweest om het aantal frontlinie officieren op het vorige niveau te houden. Steve White, voorzitter van de Politiefederatie van Engeland en Wales, zei: \\"Wat we zien, zijn de gevaren van het feit dat de regering de afgelopen vijf jaar de politiebudgetten zo hard heeft geknipt. Het is dan ook geen verrassing dat slachtoffers van misdaad nu aanzienlijk langer moeten wachten op hulp van de politie....","answer":"Sommige slachtoffers wachten tot twee minuten langer op een reactie. Er zijn nu 17.000 minder politieagenten in het hele land dan in 2009. Bellers worden aangemoedigd om contact op te nemen met de niet-noodsituatie 101 service. Labour's Yvette Cooper geeft de schuld van de verhoging van de wachttijd aan de Tory bezuinigingen."},{"question":"Koronafairọọsi pa ọga agba kan nileewe Yaba Tech","answer":"Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii nileewe gíga Yaba Tech, l’Ekoo, paṣẹ pe ki gbogbo awọn akẹkọọ fi ileewe naa silẹ pẹlu bi wọn ṣe kede pe àrùn koronafairọọsi ti pa ọkan lara awọn ọga agba níbẹ̀.Ọgbẹni M.A.O Omoighe.Loju-ẹsẹ ti iṣẹlẹ ọhun waye ni wọn ti kede ki wọn  ti ẹka ti olóògbé yìí ti jẹ adari pa fun ọsẹ meji, bẹẹ ni wọn tun sọ pe ki awọn ti wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ lọọ ṣayẹwo ara wọn, ki wọn si para mọ titi ti wọn yóò fi ri aridaju pe wọn kò ní arun ọhun lara.Ṣiwaju si i, awọn alaṣẹ ileewe naa ti sọ pe ki awọn omọleewe maa gba ikẹkọọ wọn lori ayelujara, ati pe gbogbo ipade to ba ti ju eeyan mẹ́wàá lọ, ori ẹrọ ayelujara ni ki iru ẹ ti máa wáyé."},{"question":"Hasbiyallahu adetliyken okunur mu?","answer":"Adetli kadınlar namaz kılamasalar da zikir çekebilir, dua edebilir. Bunlara bir mani yoktur."},{"question":"Wọn ti dana sun too geeti Lekki-Ikoyi","answer":"Iroyin to tẹ ALAROYE lọwọ bayii ni pe wọn ti dana sun too geeti Ikoyi.Ko ti i sẹni to mọ awọn to ṣiṣẹ naa, ṣugbọn awọn kan ni o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ awọn ọdọ ti inu n bi pelu bi awọn ṣọja ṣe yinbọn pa awọn kan ninu wọn lo ṣiṣẹ naa. Ṣugbọn a ko ti i le fidi eleyii mulẹ."},{"question":"Firy no isan'ny rantsantananan' ny olona amin'ny tanana?","answer":"Dimy no isan'ny rantsantananan' ny olona amin'ny tanana. "},{"question":"2016年の流行語大賞の年間大賞に選ばれた言葉で、その年のプロ野球セリーグチャンピオンの広島東洋カープの緒方監督が鈴木選手に対して言った言葉は何？","answer":"神ってるです。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'memakuk dengan punggung lading'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud membuat permintaan atau pertanyaan yang menyakiti hati orang"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Bu ñu leen waxee ne: \\"Gëmleen li Yàlla wàcce\\", Ñu ne: \\"Gëm nañu li ñu wàcce ci nun\\". Te ñoom weddi nañu la ñëw ginnaawam te muy dëggal la ñu yore. - Neel: \\"Lu taxoon ngeen rey ay Yonentiy Yàlla, ca bu jëkk ndegam gëm ngeen? \\".","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Bu ñu léen wàxee ne: \\"Gëmléen li Yàlla wàcce\\", Ñu ne: \\"Gëm na ñu li ñu wàcce ci nun\\". Te ñoom weddi na ñu la ñëw ginnaawam te mu'y dëggal la ñu yore. - Neel: \\"Lu tàxoon ngéen ray ay Yonent i Yàlla, ca bu njëkk ndegam gëm ngéen?\\"."},{"question":"Awọn mẹta ti wọn fẹsun ipaniyan kan l’Oṣogbo ti dero ẹwọn","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti wọ awọn mẹta lọ sile-ẹjọ lori ẹsun ipaniyan.Awọn afurasi naa ni: Aishat Mutiu, ẹni ọdun mọkanlelogun, Oyewale Ṣẹgun, ẹni ọdun mejilelogun ati Ijaye Shọla, ẹni ọdun mejilelogun atawọn mi-in ti wọn ti sa lọ bayii ni wọn fi ẹsun mẹrin kan.Awọn ẹsun mẹrẹẹrin naa ni igbimọ-pọ huwa buburu, idigunjale ati ipaniyan. Agbefọba, ASP Idoko John, sọ fun kootu pe lọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun 2020, ni wọn huwa naa laago mọkanla aarọ nileeṣẹ TUNS International Holding Limited, niluu Oṣogbo.Idoko fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe pẹlu ibọn, ada, irin, igi atawọn nnkan ija mi-in ni wọn ko lọ sibẹ. Wọn ja Taofeek Ọlakunle lole awọn nnkan bii kọmputa, tẹlifiṣan, baagi iyọ, baagi fulawa, masinni ti wọn fi n ge burẹdi, maṣinni ti wọn fi n ṣe guguru ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.O ni awọn olujẹjọ yii yinbọn fun ẹnikan to n jẹ Abdulrasheed Ọlawale, to si pada yọri si iku rẹ.Idoko ni awọn iwa naa lodi si abala ikẹfa, ikeji, okoolelọọọdunrun-un o le mẹrin (324) ati okoolelọọọdunrun-un o din ẹyọ kan (319) ofin iwa idigunjale ati gbigbe nnkan ija oloro rin ti orileede Naijiria ati abala kẹrinlelọgbọn ofin iwa ọdaran tipinlẹ Ọṣun n lo.Lẹyin ti awọn mẹtẹẹta sọ pe awọn ko jẹbi ni awọn agbẹjọro wọn, Taiwo Awokunle, Oloye Bọla Abimbọla Ige, A. A. Adelowo ati A. O. Olodo bẹbẹ fun beeli wọn lọna irọrun.Adajọ Modupẹ Awodele paṣẹ pe ki wọn ko awọn olujẹjọ lọ si ọgba ẹwọn Ileṣa. O ni ki agbefọba gbe faili wọn lọ si ẹka eto idajọ l’Ọṣun.O waa sun igbẹjọ si ọjọ kẹsan-an, oṣu kejila, ọdun yii, bẹẹ lo taari ẹjọ wọn si Majisreeti Kẹta."},{"question":"Sağ kaburga kemiğinin altında hangi organ var?","answer":"Vücudun sol tarafında kaburgalara yakın bölgelerde kalp, akciğer, dalak, pankreas, mide ve böbrek gibi organlar yer alırken sağ tarafta karaciğer bulunur."},{"question":"Chantal Youdum","answer":"Chantal Youdum jẹ́ olùdarí eré àti agbéréjáde ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè KamẹrúùnùNí ọdún 2011, Youdum ṣẹ̀dá eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Au coeur de l'amour, èyítí wọ́n gbé sáfẹ́fẹ́ lóri ìkànnì TV5 àti Canal 2. Eré náà dá lóri ọ̀dọ́mọbìnrin kan tí kò mọ bàbá rẹ̀, ó sì ṣàfihàn àwọn òṣèré bíi Valérie Duval, ẹnití ó rọ́pò òṣèrébìnrin Rouène. Youdum darí fíìmù ti ọdún 2014 kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Sweet Dance, èyí tí n ṣàfihàn Pélagie Nguiateu àti Alain Bomo Bomo.Ní ọdún 2016, wọ́n yan Youdum gẹ́gẹ́bi ọ̀kan nínu àwọn obìnrin méje tí wọ́n mú ìdàgbàsókẹ̀ bá ìwé-ìtàn kíkọ ní ilé Áfríkà. Ó ṣiṣẹ́ gẹ́gẹ́ olùṣàkóso ìpele fún ti eré Aissa ní ọdún 2017, èyítí Jean Roke Patoudem darí. Eré náà dá lóri ìtàn ọ̀dọ́mọbìnrin kan tí ó ní láti lọ gbé pẹ̀lú bàbá rẹ̀ ní abúlé míràn. Wọ́n kọ́kọ́ gbé eré Aissa jáde níbi ayẹyẹ Panafrican Film and Television Festival of Ouagadougou àti Vues d'Afrique Festival. Ní ọdún 2017 yìí bákan náà, Youdum darí eré Rêve corrompu. Eré náà dá lóri ọ̀dọ́mọkùnrin kan tí ó fi abúlé rẹ̀ sílẹ̀ láti lọ gbé ní ààrin ìlú nírètí láti ṣóríire níbẹ̀. Eré náà gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ níbi ayẹyẹ Écrans Noirs Festival ti ọdún 2018.Ní ọdún 2018, Youdum lọ́wọ́sí ṣíṣẹ̀dá eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Mimi la Bobonne, pẹ̀lú àjọṣepọ̀ Francis Tene. Wọ́n ṣe ìfihàn eré náà níbi ayẹyẹ Festival International de Films de Femmes ní ìlú Yaoundé."},{"question":"Sheeg Bariiska ka baxo magaalada Jowhar magaca loo yaqaano?","answer":"Waxaa loo yaqaanaa Bariis Baarow."},{"question":"次の段落の内容を書き続けてください： 東京都は杉の花粉を12の場所で調べていて、3つの場所で花粉が飛び始めたことがわかりました。このため、「10日から杉の花粉が飛び始めました」と発表しました。去年より5日早く飛び始めました。","answer":"今年の春は、杉やひのきの花粉が去年の2.7倍になりそうです。10年間で2番目に多くなりそうです。東京都は、花粉を調べた結果をインターネットで知らせていて、花粉が多い日に外に行くときはマスクや眼鏡をしてほしいと言っています。 医者は「体の中に入る花粉が多いと、花粉症の症状がひどくなります。今まで症状がなかった人も、花粉症になるかもしれないので、気をつけてください」と言っています。"},{"question":"இந்த உரை என்ன முக்கியமான நிகழ்வைப் பற்றியது:ஆடிக் கலவரத்தில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு இவர் 1983 இல் ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தில் குடியேறினார். அங்கு அவர் 2000 மார்ச் 6 இல் காலமானார். இவருக்கு திரு, சிறீ, சக்தி என மூன்று மகன்களும், சுசீலா, விமலா, பிரேமளா, அகிலா என நான்கு மகள்களும் உள்ளனர்.","answer":"ஆடிக் கலவரத்தில்"},{"question":"Inona ny hevitry ny teny hoe \\"skyscraper\\" talohan'ny hoe trano avo ? ","answer":"Ny dikan'ny teny hoe \\"skyscraper\\" talohan'ny hoe trano avo dia andrin-tsambo avo. "},{"question":"Ity misy toe-java-niseho: “Nahita poketra very an’i Mark mpiara-mianatra aminy i Samantha.” Raha mamorona fanontaniana avy amin'io toe-java-niseho io isika, ary ny valin'io fanontaniana io dia \\"Marka\\", inona no fanontaniana?","answer":"Ny poketra very an'iza no hitan'i Samantha?"},{"question":"උදාසීන යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"උදාසීන යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය උනන්දු වේ. "},{"question":"ماأسم الغدد التي تقوم بتنقيه الدم وتطهيره ؟","answer":"الغدد التي تقوم بتنقية الدم وتطهيره هي الغدد الليمفاوية. وهي عبارة عن شبكة من الغدد المنتشرة في جميع أنحاء الجسم، وهي مسؤولة عن إنتاج الخلايا الليمفاوية، وهي خلايا مناعية تساعد على محاربة العدوى."},{"question":" வினாபுற்று நோயை ஆரம்ப நிலையில் குணப்படுத்த உதவும் சிகிச்சை  முறைகள்  யாவை  ?","answer":"புற்றுநோய் சிகிச்சை விருப்பங்களில் பின்வருவன அடங்கும்:அறுவை சிகிச்சை. (அறுவை சிகிச்சையின் குறிக்கோள் புற்றுநோயை அகற்றுவது அல்லது முடிந்தவரை புற்றுநோயை அகற்றுவது.)கீமோதெரபி.( கீமோதெரபி புற்றுநோய் செல்களை அழிக்க மருந்துகளைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது.)கதிர்வீச்சு சிகிச்சை. எலும்பு மஜ்ஜை மாற்று அறுவை சிகிச்சை. இம்யூனோதெரபி. ஹார்மோன் சிகிச்சை. இலக்கு மருந்து சிகிச்சை. "},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk kerepek sengkuang cina lemak masin dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: Ngaku/ Arrowhead/Sengkuang Cina secukupnya, minyak masak, air bancuhan garamCara memasak:1. Kupas kulit ngaku dan rendam dengan air garam.2. Kemudian basuh bersih dan toskan ngaku hingga kering dan tiada air menitik.3. Panaskan minyak dalam jumlah yang banyak.4. Ambil ngaku tadi dan sagat ke dalam minyak.5. Bila ngaku sudah kekuningan, angkat dan toskan minyak.6. Sedia untuk dihidangkan begitu sahaja atau boleh digaul dengan sedikit garam."},{"question":"வினா:பச்சைக் கீரை பொரிக்க உதவுவது,வழுக்க உவுதவும் . அது என்ன ?","answer":"விடை:பாசி."},{"question":"அடித்தாலும், உதைத்தாலும் அழ மாட்டான் அவன் யார்?","answer":"பந்து. பந்துகள், பொதுவாக விளையாட்டுகளுக்கு பெரிதும் பயன்படும் பொருட்கள் ஆகும். இவை பொதுவாக கோள வடிவிலும் காற்றை அடக்கியும் இருக்கும். எனினும், சில சமயம் முட்டை போன்ற பிற வடிவங்களிலும் திண்மமாகவும் இருப்பதும் உண்டு. பந்துகளை பயன்படுத்தும் பெரும்பாலான ஆட்டங்களில், பந்தின் இருப்பையும் போக்கையும் பின்பற்றியே ஆட்டமும் அமைந்திருக்கும்."},{"question":"اذكر موضوع النص التالي: كانت ألمانيا واحدة من أوائل الدول في أوروبا التي أقامت علاقات دبلوماسية مع بنغلاديش. سرعان ما أصبح واضحًا أن العلاقة بين البلدين كانت مهمة لإعادة الإعمار، حيث أن حرب الاستقلال في بنغلاديش قد خلفت دمارًا شديدًا. تلعب التجارة بين البلدين اليوم دوراً هاماً وتمثل أكبر فرصة للتنمية المستدامة لبنجلاديش.","answer":"علاقة ألمانيا مع بنغلاديش ودورها في إعادة الإعمار."},{"question":"Zou je me kunnen helpen. Geef me een aantal manieren waarop ik mijn huis koel kan houden in de zomer.","answer":"Dit zijn een aantal opties:- Installeer een centraal airconditioningsysteem dat geïntegreerd is met je verwarmingssysteem - Koop een raamairconditioner om een individuele kamer koel te houden - Installeer een ventilator die koele lucht van open ramen 's nachts naar de woonruimte trekt en de warme lucht in de zolder afvoert - Plaats ventilatoren door het hele huis, maar plaats ze voor open ramen 's nachts om koele lucht binnen te halen - Installeer een luchtkoeler, het is soms goedkoper dan het installeren van een volledig airconditioningsysteem - Zorg ervoor dat je 's ochtends na het afkoelen van het huis 's nachts de ramen en gordijnen sluit - Neem een koeler gevuld met ijs en plaats er een ventilator in die koude lucht in de kamer blaast. Het ijs zal snel smelten, dus wees klaar om vaak bij te vullen. Niet de meest efficiënte manier, maar in geval van nood kan het helpen."},{"question":"Me kalmar: \\"fish\\" ke nufi a harshen Hausa? ","answer":"Kalmar \\"fish\\" na nufin kifi a harshen Hausa"},{"question":"Berikan penerangan pendek tentang Perang Dunia I dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 590 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Perang Dunia I (PD1) adalah sebuah perang global terpusat di Eropa yang dimulai pada tanggal 28 Juli 1914 sampai 11 November 1918. Perang ini sering disebut Perang Dunia atau Perang Besar sejak terjadi sampai dimulainya Perang Dunia II pada tahun 1939, dan Perang Dunia Pertama atau Perang Dunia I setelah itu. Perang ini melibatkan semua kekuatan besar dunia, yang terbagi menjadi dua aliansi bertentangan, yaitu Sekutu (berdasarkan Entente Tiga yang terdiri dari Britania Raya, Prancis, dan Rusia) dan Blok Sentral (terpusat pada Aliansi Tiga yang terdiri dari Jerman, Austria-Hungaria, dan Italia; namun saat Austria-Hungaria melakukan serangan sementara persekutuan ini bersifat defensif, Italia tidak ikut berperang). Kedua aliansi ini melakukan reorganisasi (Italia berada di pihak Sekutu) dan memperluas diri saat banyak negara ikut serta dalam perang. Lebih dari 70 juta tentara militer, termasuk 60 juta orang Eropa, dimobilisasi dalam salah satu perang terbesar dalam sejarah. Lebih dari 9 juta prajurit gugur, terutamanya akibat kemajuan teknologi yang meningkatkan keberkesanan suatu senjata tanpa mempertimbangkan perbaikan perlindungan atau mobilitas. Perang Dunia I adalah konflik paling mematikan keenam dalam sejarah dunia, sehingga membuka jalan untuk berbagai perubahan politik seperti revolusi di beberapa negara yang terlibat.Penyebab jangka panjang perang ini mencakup kebijakan luar negeri imperialis kekuatan besar Eropa, termasuk Kekaisaran Jerman, Kekaisaran Austria-Hungaria, Kesultanan Utsmaniyah, Kekaisaran Rusia, Imperium Britania, Republik Prancis, dan Italia. Pembunuhan tanggal 28 Juni 1914 terhadap Adipati Agung Franz Ferdinand dari Austria, pewaris takhta Austria-Hungaria, oleh seorang nasionalis Yugoslavia di Sarajevo, Bosnia dan Herzegovina adalah pencetus perang ini. Pembunuhan tersebut berujung pada ultimatum Habsburg terhadap Kerajaan Serbia. Sejumlah aliansi yang dibentuk selama beberapa dasawarsa sebelumnya terguncang, sehingga dalam hitungan minggu semua kekuatan besar terlibat dalam perang; melalui koloni mereka, konflik ini segera menyebar ke seluruh dunia.Pada tanggal 28 Juli, konflik ini dibuka dengan invasi ke Serbia oleh Austria-Hungaria, diikuti invasi Jerman ke Belgia, Luksemburg, dan Prancis; dan serangan Rusia ke Jerman. Setelah pawai Jerman di Paris tersendat, Front Barat melakukan pertempuran atrisi statis dengan jalur parit yang mengubah sedikit suasana sampai tahun 1917. Di Timur, angkatan darat Rusia berhasil mengalahkan pasukan Kesultanan Utsmaniyah, namun dipaksa mundur dari Prusia Timur dan Polandia oleh angkatan darat Jerman. Front lainnya dibuka setelah Kesultanan Utsmaniyah ikut serta dalam perang tahun 1914, Italia dan Bulgaria tahun 1915, dan Rumania tahun 1916. Kekaisaran Rusia runtuh bulan Maret 1917, dan Rusia menarik diri dari perang setelah Revolusi Oktober pada akhir tahun itu. Setelah serangan Jerman di sepanjang front barat tahun 1918, Sekutu memaksa pasukan Jerman mundur dalam serangkaian serangan yang sukses dan pasukan Amerika Serikat mulai memasuki parit. Jerman, yang bermasalah dengan revolusi pada saat itu, setuju melakukan gencatan senjata pada tanggal 11 November 1918 yang kelak dikenal sebagai Hari Gencatan Senjata. Perang ini berakhir dengan kemenangan di pihak Sekutu.Peristiwa di front Britania sama rusuhnya seperti front depan, kerana para pihak terlibat berusaha memobilisasi tenaga manusia dan sumber daya ekonomi mereka untuk melakukan perang total. Pada akhir perang, empat kekuatan imperial besar—Kekaisaran Jerman, Rusia, Austria-Hungaria, dan Utsmaniyah—bubar. Negara pengganti dua kekaisaran yang disebutkan pertama tadi kehilangan banyak sekali wilayah, sementara dua terakhir bubar sepenuhnya. Eropa Tengah terpecah menjadi beberapa negara kecil. Liga Bangsa-Bangsa dibentuk dengan harapan mencegah konflik seperti ini selanjutnya. Nasionalisme Eropa yang muncul akibat perang dan pembubaran kekaisaran, dampak kekalahan Jerman dan masalah dengan Traktat Versailles diyakini menjadi faktor penyebab pecahnya Perang Dunia II."},{"question":"Kodi ulimi wa nsomba uli ndi phindu ku Malawi?","answer":"Mafamu ambiri ansomba ali ndi eni ake ndipo amayendetsedwa ndi anthu omwe ali pafamu pawokha, ngakhale mafamu omwe ndi anthu ammudzi aliponso. Ulimi wapamadzi waung'ono umapezeka kuti ndi wopindulitsa, ngakhale kuti malire ake ndi ochepa."},{"question":"Bada Rabe-raben Adabin Zamani?","answer":"Ɗangambo (1984), Zarruƙ, Kafin Hausa, da Al-Hassan (1987), Yahaya, Zariya, Gusau, da ‘Yar’aduwa (1992), da kuma Junaidu, da ‘Yar’aduwa (2002), duk sun haɗu a kan cewa adabin zamani ko rubutaccen adabi ya kasu zuwa gida uku kamar haka:Rubutattun Waƙoƙi.Rubutun Zube.Rubutattun Wasannin Kwaikwayo."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe tempo?","answer":"Tempo dia ny hafainganam-pandehan'ny mozika iray, aseho amin'ny teny toy ny \\"allegro\\" na \\"adagio\\"."},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ 日本では、暑い夏に元気になるように、うなぎを食べる習慣があります。食べ物を作る会社が、大豆からできた原料などで「うなぎのかば焼き」を作りました。植物から作った原料を使っていて、動物から作った原料は使っていません。3つの部分に分けて作って、本当のうなぎのかば焼きを食べたときの感じになるようにしました。たれをつけて焼いてあります。1セット1500円で、インターネットで売りました。会社は「これからうなぎを食べることができなくなるかもしれないと心配して、このうなぎの料理を作りました」と話しています。世界では、食べ物が足りなくなっている問題などがあって、植物の原料から作る肉や魚が増えています。日本でも、店で売ったりレストランで出したりすることが多くなっています。","answer":"「うなぎのかば焼き」を植物からできた原料で作る"},{"question":"ప్రజాస్వామ్యం వివిధ దృక్కోణాలేవి ?","answer":"ప్రజాస్వామ్యం వివిధ దృక్కోణాలను కలిగి ఉంది. వాటిలో ముఖ్యమైనవి స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం, రాజకీయ పార్టీలు, సమన్యాయ పాలన, అధికార వికేంద్రీకరణ మొదలగునవి. వాటిని గురించి ఈ క్రింది పేర్కొన్న విధంగా భావించవచ్చు. అవి:1) స్వేచ్ఛ: ప్రజాస్వామ్యం యొక్క ముఖ్య దృక్కోణంగా స్వేచ్ఛను పేర్కొనవచ్చు. ఈ వ్యవస్థ అమలులో ఉన్న రాజ్యాలలో నివసించే పౌరులు సంపూర్ణ స్వేచ్ఛా, స్వాతంత్ర్యాలను కలిగి ఉంటారు.2) సమానత్వం: ప్రజాస్వామ్య ప్రభుత్వానికి ప్రధాన ప్రాతిపదిక సమానత్వం. ఈ వ్యవస్థ అమలులో ఉన్న రాజ్యాలలో నివసించే ప్రజలంతా ఎటువంటి తారతమ్యాలు, వ్యత్యాసాలు లేకుండా ఆర్థిక, రాజకీయ, సాంఘిక, పౌర సమానత్వాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటారు.3) రాజకీయ పార్టీలు: రాజకీయ పార్టీలను ప్రజాస్వామ్య వ్యవస్థ యొక్క మరొక దృక్కోణంగా మనం భావించవచ్చు. ఈ వ్యవస్థలో నిర్ణీత కాలంలో ఎన్నికలు జరుగుతాయి. ఈ ఎన్నికలలో మెజారిటీ నియోజక వర్గాలలో గెలుపొందిన రాజకీయ పార్టీ అధికారంలోకి వస్తుంది. రెండవ పార్టీ ప్రతిపక్ష పార్టీగా వ్యవహరిస్తుంది. ఇది ద్విరాజకీయ పార్టీ విధానం అమలులో ఉన్న రాజ్యాలలో జరిగే సాధారణ లేదా సహజ ప్రక్రియ.4) సమన్యాయ పాలన: ప్రజాస్వామ్య వ్యవస్థలో ప్రజలంతా చట్టం ముందు సమానులే. చట్టాలను అమలు పరచే విషయంలో రాజ్యం, ప్రభుత్వం, జాతి, మత, కుల, వర్గ, వర్ణ, లింగ ప్రాతిపదికన ఏ వ్యక్తిని ఎటువంటి వివక్షతకు, పక్షపాతానికి గురి చేయకూడదు.5) అధికార వికేంద్రీకరణ: అధికార వికేంద్రీకరణను ప్రజాస్వామ్య ప్రభుత్వం యొక్క ముఖ్యమైన దృక్కోణంగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు. రాజ్యము యొక్క సర్వ అధికారములు ప్రభుత్వ శాఖల మధ్య వికేంద్రీకరించబడతాయి."},{"question":"Berikan saya resipi untuk nasi lemak tumis dengan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 3 cawan beras,  santan, agak-agak, 3 biji bawang merah, 1 sudu kecil halba, 1 inci halia (hiris nipis), 1 batang halia (ketuk), 1 helai daun pandan (carik dan simpul), sedikit minyak untuk menumis, garam secukup rasaCara Penyediaan:1. Basuh beras dan toskan.2. Panaskan minyak di atas dapur dan tumis bawang, halia, halba, serai dan daun pandan sehingga bawang lembut dan naik bau.3. Masukkan beras dan kacau seketika.4. Masukkan santan anggaran sehingga air satu ruas jari.5. Masukkan garam secukup rasa dan kacau sedikit supaya garam larut sekata.6. Tutup penutup dan pindah ke periuk nasi elektrik. Jika tidak, anda boleh teruskan masak di atas api sehingga masak."},{"question":"指责潘石屹“卖国贼”，节目被紧急叫停，金星究竟动了谁的蛋糕？(I don;'t understand the prompt)","answer":"金星被叫停，是由于金星的“毒舌”得罪了太多明星，金星时常会调侃参加节目的一些明星。为了节目效果，难免会提及明星隐私的问题。一些明星可能会怀恨在心，所以这么人才会搞点小动作使得金星的节目惨被停播。"},{"question":"గుత్తి వంకాయ","answer":"వంకాయలను నాలుగు భాగాలుగా కోసి, వీటిలో పల్లీలు, ఎండుమిర్చి, ధనియాలు, కొబ్బరి కొర్రలతో చేసిన మసాలాను నింపి, నూనెలో వేపాలి."},{"question":"O yẹ kinu ọmọ Naijiria maa dun pe ijọba fẹẹ maa ra epo bẹntiroolu lati orileede Nijee- Sylva","answer":"“Emi o ri nnkan itiju kankan ninu iyẹn o. Ko tiẹ si nnkan to buru nibẹ rara. Orileede to tobi ni Naijiria, a si nilo epo rẹpẹtẹ. Koda, bi awọn ibudo ifọpo wa ba tiẹ n ṣiṣẹ paapaa, a ṣi nilo lati ra epo si i, ka le ni anito ati aniṣẹku. Niṣe lo yẹ ka gboriyin fun ijọba apapọ bi wọn ṣe fẹẹ bẹrẹ eto lati maa ra epo bẹntiroolu wọlu lati orileede Nijee (Niger), ko si abuku kan ninu ẹ rara.”Minisita fun ọrọ epo rọbi, to tun jẹ gomina ipinlẹ Bayelsa tẹlẹ ri, Timipre Sylva, lo ṣe bayii sọrọ nipa igbesẹ tijọba apapọ lawọn fẹẹ gbe lati maa ko epo wọle lati orileede alaamulegbe wa, Niger Republic. Ori eto tẹlifiṣan Channels kan lo ti sọrọ naa lalẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii.Sylva ni dipo ti awọn eeyan fi n tẹmbẹlu igbesẹ tijọba fẹẹ gbe naa, ti wọn n wo o bii nnkan itiju fun Naijiria, niṣe lo yẹ ki wọn ri i bi anfaani lati mu ki ajọṣe olokoowo ati ọrọ-aje laarin orileede Iwọ-Oorun Afrika kan si omi-in tubọ fidi mulẹ daadaa si i.O ni ko sọgbọn ti orileede wa le da si i lọwọ yii, tori epo ta a nilo lojumọ kan pọ ju ohun ti agbara wa le ka lati pese labẹle lọ.Ṣe l’Ọjọruu, Tọsidee, to kọja yii, ni ẹka ileeṣẹ ijọba to n ri si ọrọ epo rọbi fi iwe kan lede pe ajọsọ ati adehun ti duro laarin orileede wa ati Nijee lati maa ra epo rọbi wa silẹ wa. Ileeṣẹ ifọpo Soraz Refinery, to wa ni Zinder, lorileede Nijee, ni wọn ti fẹẹ maa ra epo bẹntiroolu naa wọle.Igbesẹ yii ti da awuyewuye pupọ silẹ, pẹlu bawọn eeyan ṣe n bẹnu atẹ lu ijọba apapọ pe igbesẹ ainitiju ni, wọn ni ko sohun to yẹ ko mu awọn ibudo ifọpo nla nla ta a ni lati ma ṣiṣẹ. Ọrọ ọhun si ṣi n ja ranyin di ba a ṣe n sọ yii."},{"question":"கேள்வி: சிறுநீரகத்தின் அடிப்படை அலகு என்ன? விடை:","answer":"நெப்ரான். சிறுநீரகம் நம் உடலின் முக்கிய உறுப்பு. இரத்தத்தை சுத்தம் செய்வது, உடலில் கழிவுப் பொருட்களை வெளியேற்றுவது, உடம்பில் எவ்வளவு நீர், எவ்வளவு உப்பு, எவ்வளவு எலக்ட்ரோலைட் வேண்டும் என்பது போன்ற ஏராளமான பணிகளை செய்கிறது. ஒவ்வொரு சிறுநீரகத்துக்கு உள்ளேயும், சுமார் 1,00,000-1,250,000 நெப்ரான்கள் உள்ளன. இவைகள்தான் சிறுநீர் வடிகட்டிகள். ஆனால் ஒவ்வொரு நெப்ரானும் தனித்தனியாய் இயங்கி சிறுநீரை வடிகட்டுகின்றன. ஒன்றுடன் ஒன்று இணைத்து செயல்படாது. இவை ஒவ்வொன்றின் உள்ளேயும் ஏராளமான இரத்த தந்துகி முடிச்சுக்கள் உள்ளன. ஒரு நெப்ரானின் அளவு 50 மி.மீ மட்டுமே!"},{"question":"Ingubo ka Yesu imhlophe qhwa.","answer":"Jesus rope is pure white."},{"question":"  வினா  :  கவிஞர்கள்  குறித்து எழுதுக.","answer":"விடை : கவிஞர்  என்பவர் கவிதையை உருவாக்கும் நபர் ஆவார். இவர்கள் புலவர்கள் என்றும் அழைக்கப்பட்டனர். முந்தைய கால கவிஞர்கள் பெரும்பாலும் நன்கு படித்தவர்களாகவும், உயர் கல்வி கற்றவர்களாகவும் இருந்தனர். மற்றவர்கள் பெரும்அளவில் சுயகல்வி கற்றவர்களாக இருந்தனர். கோவர், மில்டன் போன்ற ஒரு சில கவிஞர்கள் ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட மொழிகளில் கவிதைகள் எழுதினர். சில போர்த்துகீசிய கவிஞர்கள் போர்த்துக்கீசியம் மட்டுமின்றி எசுப்பானிய மொழியிலும் கவிதை படைத்தனர். கவிஞர்களில் பலர் மொழிபெயர்ப்பாளர்களாகவும் இருந்தனர்."},{"question":"من هو المهندس الفرنسي الذي قام بحفر قناة السويس ؟","answer":"دوليسيبس."},{"question":"Ìwúlò èdè Yorùbá","answer":"Èdè wúlò fún kí a le bá ara sọ ọ̀rọ̀ léyìí tí gbédìí fún ẹwà akéwì náà. A kò le ṣe kí a má kí ara wa ní orísirísi ọ̀nà bóyá ọ̀rẹ́ sí ọ̀rẹ́, pẹ̀lú orísirísi ẹwà èdè.Èdè wúlò fún fífi sọ èrò ọkàn wa àti fífi ìtara hàn sí ohun tí a gbọ́ rí tàbí tí ó ṣelẹ̀ sí wa. "},{"question":"Asa si Jesus natawo?","answer":"Si Jesus natawo sa Bethlehem."},{"question":"السؤال: حدد وقت الصيام للمسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: من طلوع الفجر الصادق إلى غروب الشمس"},{"question":"Tany amin’ny tanàna inona no nahaterahan’i Jesosy, araka ny Testamenta Vaovao ao amin’ny Baiboly?","answer":"Teraka tao Betlehema i Jesosy, araka ny Testamenta Vaovao."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Kasar Benin kasa ce ta yammacin Afirka da ta shahara da alakar tarihi da cinikin bayi na Afirka. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੩ ਪੰ. ੧ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਨਮ ਦੀ ਉੱਤਮਤਾਚਉਰਾਸੀਹ ਲਖ ਜੋਨਿ ਵਿਚਿ ਉਤਮੁ ਜਨਮੁ ਸੁ ਮਾਣਸਿ ਦੇਹੀ।ਅਖੀ ਵੇਖਣੁ ਕਰਨਿ ਸੁਣਿ ਮੁਖਿ ਸੁਭ ਬੋਲਣੁ ਬਚਨ ਸਨੇਹੀ।ਹਥੀ ਕਾਰ ਕਮਾਵਣੀ ਪੈਰੀ ਚਲਿ ਸਤਿਸੰਗਿ ਮਿਲੇਹੀ।ਕਿਰਤਿ ਵਿਰਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਧਰਮ ਦੀ ਖਟਿ ਖਵਾਲਣੁ ਕਾਰਿ ਕਰੇਹੀ।ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਨਮੁ ਸਕਾਰਥਾ ਗੁਰਬਾਣੀ ਪੜਿ ਸਮਝਿ ਸੁਣੇਹੀ।ਗੁਰ ਭਾਈ ਸੰਤੁਸਟਿ ਕਰਿ ਚਰਣਾਮਿਤੁ ਲੈ ਮੁਖਿ ਪਿਵੇਹੀ।ਪੈਰੀ ਪਵਣੁ ਨ ਛੋਡੀਐ ਕਲੀ ਕਾਲਿ ਰਹਰਾਸਿ ਕਰੇਹੀ।ਆਪਿ ਤਰੇ ਗੁਰ ਸਿਖ ਤਰੇਹੀ ॥੩॥","answer":"ਚੌਰਾਸੀ ਲੱਖ ਜੂਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਰੀਰ ਉੱਤਮ ਜਨਮ ਹੈ;(ਕਿਉਂ ਜੋ) ਅੱਖਾਂ (ਸ਼ੁਭ) ਵੇਖਦੀਆਂ, ਕਰਣ (ਸ਼ੁਭ ਬਚਨ) ਸੁਣਦੇ, ਮੁਖ (ਅਰਥਾਤ ਜੀਭਾ) ਸ਼ੁਭ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਦੇ ਵਾਕ ਬੋਲਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। (ਭਾਵ ਇਹ ਕਿ ਪਸ਼ੂ ਪੰਛੀ ਭੀ ਵੇਖਣ ਆਦਿ ਕ੍ਰਿਆ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪਰੰਤੂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਖੇ ਸ਼ੁਭ ਅਸ਼ੁਭ ਦਾ ਗਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਸੇ ਲਈ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ “ਕਬੀਰ ਮਾਨਸ ਜਨਮੁ ਦੁਲੰਭੁ ਹੈਹੱਥਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਕਾਰ ਕਰੋ, ਪੈਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਤੁਰਕੇ ਸਤਿਸੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲੇ।ਧਰਮ ਦੀ ਬਿਰਤੀ (ਉਪਜੀਵਕ) ਦੀ ਕਿਰਤ (ਕਾਰ) ਕਰ ਕੇ ਖੱਟ ਕੇ ਖਾਵੇ ਤੇ ਖਵਾਲੇ। (ਭਾਵ ਚੋਰੀ ਯਾਰੀ ਦੀ ਉਪਜੀਵਕਾ ਨਾ ਬਣਾਵੇ। ਯਥਾ:-ਘਾਲਿ ਖਾਇ ਕਿਛੁ ਹਥਹੁ ਦੇਇ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਰਾਹੁ ਪਛਾਣਹਿ ਸੇਇ॥ [ਸਾਰੰਗ ਦੀ ਵਾਰ ਸਲੋਕ ਮ: ੧-੨੨](ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ) ਗੁਰਮੁਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਸਫਲ ਹੈ (ਜੋ) ਗੁਰੂ ਜੀ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ (ਆਪ) ਪੜ੍ਹਕੇ ਤੇ ਸਮਝਕੇ ਸੁਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ; (ਭਾਵ ਦੀਵਾ ਬਾਲਕੇ ਪੜੋਪੇ ਹੇਠ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੁਕਾਉਂਦੇ, ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਚਾਨਣ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ)।ਗੁਰ ਭਾਈਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਕਰਦੇ, (ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਚਰਣ ਧੋਕੇ) ਚਰਨ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪੀਂਦੇ ਹਨ। (ਭਾਵ ਅੰਗੂਠਾ ਧੋਕੇ ਕਿੰਚਤ ਚਰਣਾਂਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਪਾਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਯਥਾ:-’ਚਰਨ ਸਾਧ ਕੇ ਧੋਇ ਧੋਇ ਪੀਉ॥ ਅਰਪਿ ਸਾਧ ਕਉ ਅਪਨਾ ਜੀਉ॥’ ਦਸਮੇਂ ਜਾਮੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਤਿਗੁਰਾਂ ਨੇ ਖੰਡੇ ਦੇ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਦੀ ਮ੍ਰਿਯਾਦਾ ਬੰਨ੍ਹਕੇ ਇਸ ਮ(ਇਸ ਉਕਤ ਪੌੜੀ ਦਾ ਸਿੱਟਾ ਇਹ ਹੈ-ਕਿ) ਪੈਰੀ ਪੈਣਾ ਨਾ ਛੱਡੀਏ, ਕਲਜੁਗ ਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਖੇ (ਨਿੰਮ੍ਰਤਾ ਹੀ) ਸੱਚਾ ਰਾਹ ਹੈ।(ਕਿ ਓਹ) ਗੁਰਸਿਖ (ਜੋ ਇਸ ਰਸਤੇ ਚੱਲਣਗੇ) ਆਪ ਤਰਨਗੇ (ਤੇ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬੀ) ਤਾਰਨਗੇ। (ਯਥਾ:-’ਮੰਨੈ ਤਰੈ ਤਾਰੈ ਗੁਰ ਸਿਖ॥ ਮੰਨੈ ਨਾਨਕ ਭਵਹਿ ਨ ਭਿਖ॥’ ਦਸਮੇਂ ਜਾਮੇ ਵਿਚ ਗੁਰੂ ਜੀ ਨੇ ‘ਵਾਹਿਗੁਰੂ ਜੀ ਕੀ ਫਤਹਿ ਦੀ ਮ੍ਰਿਯਾਦਾ ਬੰਨ੍ਹੀ।"},{"question":"Кадыр түн тосуу дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Кадыр түн (араб тилинде:‎ لَيْلَةِ الْقَدْرِ — лайлату-ль-кадр дининде күчтүү) – ислам дининде белгиленүүчү рамазан (орозо) айынын 27-түнү. Мусулмандардын түшүнүгү боюнча Алла Мухаммедге курандын алгачкы «фаатиха» «Ачуучу сүрөөсүн» рамазан айынын 27-түнү түшүргөн. Ал «Духан» (44) жана «Кадр» (97) сүрөөлөрүндө кадырлуу, кайталангыс «куттуу түн» катары каралып, ошол түндүн артыкчылыктары жөнүндө айтылат. Бул түнү чыныгы мусулмандар таң аткыча уктабастан, Кудайга кулчулук кылып, жакшылыктарды тилеп, куран окуп өткөрөт. Аллага ыраазычылыгын билдирип, алкыш айтуу менен көңүлүндөгү ыйык сакталган сырларын кабыл кылуусун тилешип, мечитте же үйлөрүндө тосушат, бул тилектер сөзсүз кабыл болоруна жана бул түн «миң айлык ибадаттан» да жогору турарына ишенишет. Мусулмандардын ишениминде Алла тарабынан адамдын тагдыры белгиленип, бакытка, байлыкка жолугат."},{"question":"ما هو الجهاز الذي يستخدم لقياس مقدار مقاومة المعدن للخدش؟","answer":"جهاز مومس"},{"question":"Akẹkọọ-jade Fasiti KWASU to lu jibiti yoo ṣẹwọn oṣu mẹfa","answer":"Adajọ Sikiru Oyinloye tile-ẹjọ giga ipinlẹ Kwara, ti ju akẹkọọ-jade ileewe Fasiti KWASU,  Ahmed Bọlaji, sẹwọn oṣu mẹfa gbako fun ṣiṣe jibiti ori ẹrọ ayelujara.Ọmọ ọdun mọkanlelogun naa lajọ to n gbogun ti iwa jibiti ati ṣiṣe owo ilu baṣbaṣu, EFCC, wọ lọ sile-ẹjọ fẹsun pe o tan oyinbo alawọ funfun kan lati le gba owo lọwọ ẹ.Bọlaji to n pe ara rẹ ni Rosemary, to si n lo foto obinrin lori ẹrọ ayelujara lati maa fi lu awọn ọkunrin ni jibiti lọwọ tẹ loṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021.Nigba ti wọn ka ẹsun yii si i leti, akẹkọọ-jade nipa imọ ibaraalu sọrọ ati igbohun-safẹfẹ (Mass Communication) naa ni loootọ loun jẹbi.Ọkan lara awọn oṣiṣẹ EFCC to mu ọdaran naa, Loveday Godwin, ṣalaye pe ọjọ kẹtala, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021 lọwọ tẹ Bọlaji lẹyin tawọn kan ta ileeṣẹ awọn lolobo.Onitọhun tẹsiwaju pe ọdaran naa gbiyanju lati lu ọkunrin oyinbo kan, Shawn Smith, ni jibiti owo ko too di pe ọwọ tẹ ẹ.Agbẹjọro EFCC, Ọgbẹni Sẹsan Ọla, ko foonu meji ti Bọlaji fi n ṣe jibiti atawọn ẹri mi-in to fi han pe o hu iwa naa siwaju ile-ẹjọ, adajọ si tẹwọ gba a gẹgẹ bii ẹri.Ọgbẹni Ọla ni niwọn igba ti Bọlaji ti jẹwọ pe loootọ loun jẹbi, ki ile-ẹjọ dajọ rẹ kiakia.Adajọ Oyinloye ni niwọn igba ti agbefọba ti fidii ẹjọ naa mulẹ, ko si ariyanjiyan rara pe ọdaran naa gbọdọ jiya ẹṣẹ rẹ.O ni ki ọdaran naa san ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un kan naira owo itanran, tabi ko lọọ ṣẹwọn oṣu mẹfa."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Mới đây, Bộ Tài chính vừa ban hành thông tư 45/2022/TT-BTC với nội dung sửa đổi, bổ sung một số điều tại Thông tư 143/2015/TT-BTC quy định thủ tục hải quan và quản lý xe ô tô, xe gắn máy của các đối tượng được phép nhập khẩu, tạm nhập khẩu không nhằm mục đích thương mại. Trong đó, hồ sơ, trình tự thủ tục nhập khẩu, tạm nhập khẩu phương tiện được quy định cụ thể, chi tiết hơn và kèm theo các chế tài xử lý nếu vi phạm về quá thời hạn khai bổ sung xác định giá trị hải quan, vi phạm về bảo quản hàng hóa, thời hạn nộp giấy chứng nhận đăng kiểm... Cụ thể, hồ sơ nhập khẩu, tạm nhập khẩu phương tiện gồm các giấy tờ như tờ khai, vận đơn hoặc chứng từ, giấy đăng ký kiểm định, giấy ủy quyền… bản giấy hoặc nộp qua phương thức điện tử theo mẫu quy định. Bên cạnh đó, người làm thủ tục thực hiện khai hải quan tại Chi cục Hải quan qua hình thức điện tử hoặc trực tiếp và chịu trách nhiệm bảo quản xe tại địa điểm được phép đưa về bảo quản 30 ngày để chờ kết quả kiểm tra xe của cơ quan kiểm tra chuyên ngành (cơ quan đăng kiểm). Trong 8 giờ làm việc kể từ thời điểm hoàn thành kiểm tra thực tế hàng hóa, nếu đủ cơ sở xác định hàng kê khai chưa phù hợp thực tế, cơ quan hải quan ban hành thông báo giá trị hải quan. Trong thời hạn 5 ngày làm việc, kể từ ngày ban hành thông báo trị giá hải quan, nếu người kê khai không bổ sung, Hải quan ban hành quyết định ấn định thuế và xử lý vi phạm (nếu có). Trường hợp người khai hải quan đủ điều kiện để được đưa hàng về bảo quản theo quy định thì trong thời hạn 30 ngày kể từ ngày đưa hàng về bảo quản, , Chi cục Hải quan phải theo dõi kiểm tra. Khi có kết quả đăng kiểm phương tiện, Chi cục Hải quan yêu cầu người kê khai hải quan thực hiện khai bổ sung (nếu có) và thông quan hàng hóa theo quy định. Trường hợp quá thời hạn 30 ngày kể từ ngày đưa hàng về bảo quản, người khai hải quan không tiến hành tiếp thủ tục hoặc cơ quan hải quan có thông tin về việc người khai hải quan không chấp hành quy định về bảo quản hàng hóa…Chi cục Hải quan nơi đăng ký tờ khai thực hiện kiểm tra việc mang hàng về bảo quản. Nếu người khai hải quan không lưu giữ xe tại địa điểm đã đăng ký bảo quản thì thực hiện xử lý vi phạm theo quy định của pháp luật. Bên cạnh đó, Chi cục Hải quan làm thủ tục nhập khẩu, tạm nhập khẩu chỉ thông quan khi có giấy chứng nhận chất lượng an toàn kỹ thuật và bảo vệ môi trường xe cơ giới nhập khẩu (đối với xe ô tô) và giấy kiểm tra chất lượng xe gắn máy nhập khẩu (đối với xe gắn máy ) của cơ quan kiểm tra chuyên ngành (Cơ quan đăng kiểm - PV). Khi nhận được giấy chứng nhận đăng kiểm (bản điện tử, bản giấy), cơ quan hải quan sẽ kiểm tra đối chiếu với thực tế. Trường hợp có sự khác biệt dẫn đến làm thay đổi trị giá hàng hóa thì cơ quan hải quan xác định lại trị giá hải quan và thông báo cho người khai thủ tục. Trong thời hạn 5 ngày làm việc kể từ ngày ban hành thông báo trị giá hải quan, nếu người khai không kê khai bổ sung, cơ quan hải quan ban hành quyết định ấn định thuế theo quy định của Luật Quản lý thuế, xử lý vi phạm (nếu có). Trường hợp người khai hải quan nộp giấy chứng nhận chất lượng an toàn kỹ thuật và bảo vệ môi trường không đúng thời hạn quy định (quá 30 ngày kể từ ngày đưa hàng về bảo quản), cơ quan hải quan sẽ tiến hành lập biên bản vi phạm, trừ trường hợp người khai hải quan có lý do khách quan được cơ quan kiểm tra chuyên ngành xác nhận. Trường hợp bị hải quan xử lý, sau khi người khai hải quan chấp hành quyết định xử lý, mới tiếp tục thực hiện các thủ tục hải quan theo quy định của pháp luật. Đối tượng áp dụng của Thông tư số 45/2022 là người Việt Nam định cư tại nước ngoài, là trí thức, chuyên gia, công nhân lành nghề về nước làm việc trong thời gian từ một năm trở lên theo lời mời của cơ quan nhà nước Việt Nam. Thông tư 45/2022/TT-BTC do Bộ Tài chính ban hành sẽ có hiệu lực từ ngày 10.9.2022.","answer":"Từ 10.9, áp dụng quy định mới về nhập khẩu ô tô mục đích phi thương mại"},{"question":"Qual a resposta correcta para esta pergunta: Qual foi o filme mais recente pelo qual Glenn Close não ganhou um Oscar apesar de ter sido indicada?","answer":"A resposta correcta para a questão é: Até 2022, o último filme em que Glenn Close foi nomeada, mas não ganhou o Oscar, foi \\"Lamento de uma América em Ruínas\\" (\\"Era uma Vez um Sonho\\" no Brasil)."},{"question":"ලොව වේගවත්ම සුපිරි පරිගණකය වන \\"ෆුගාකු\\" නිෂ්පාදිත රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ලොව වේගවත්ම සුපිරි පරිගණකය \\"ෆුගාකු\\" (\\"Fugaku\\") ජපානයේ පිහිටා  ඇත. එය  රිකෙන් (RIKEN) සහ ෆුජිට්සු (Fujitsu) ආයතන විසින් වැඩි දියුණු කරන ලද අතර ජපානයේ කොබේහි පරිගණක විද්‍යාව සඳහා  වූ රිකෙන්(RIKEN) මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ ස්ථාපනය කර ඇත."},{"question":"Ndege","answer":"Viumbe wanao paa angani"},{"question":"第1句: 佛蒙特州的边界是北边的米切姆,西边的努纳瓦丁和森林山,南边的佛蒙特州南边和东边的沃特尔纳和林伍德. 文2: 佛蒙特州的边界是北边的米切姆,西边的努纳瓦丁和森林山,南边的佛蒙特州和东边的沃特尔纳和林伍德. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"相同"},{"question":"كم مرة حج رسول الله؟\\t","answer":"\\tمرة واحدة"},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన సినిమా పాటలోని ఒక భాగం యొక్క సాహిత్యంపై విశ్లేషణ చెయ్యండి:పెళ్ళిచూపులలో బిగుసుకొనిపేరేమి,  చదువేమినను ప్రేమిస్తావా వయసెంతా?అని అడిగారా అసలొచ్చారానాలో వారు ఏం చూశారో నావారయ్యారునాలో వారు ఏం చూశారో నావారయ్యారుఅందులకే మా ఇద్దరి జంట అపురూపం అంటానీ ఎదుట నేను వారెదుట నీవుమా ఎదుట ఓ మామా ఎప్పుడుంటావుచల్లని వెన్నెల దొరవంటారు తీయని నవ్వుల సిరివంటారుఆ వెన్నెలలోని వేడిగాడ్పులు నవ్వులలోని నిప్పురవ్వలుఅనుభవించి అనమంటానువయసుకు వైరివి నీవంటానునీ ఎదుట నేను వారెదుట నీవుమా ఎదుట ఓ మామా ఎప్పుడుంటావు","answer":"పెళ్లిచూపులను కలుసుకొని ఊరేది? పేరేది? నను ప్రేమిస్తావా వయసెంత?’లాంటి పదాలు చందమామ ముందు ఆ అమ్మాయి చూ చూపించిన భావప్రకటన ఎంతో ముచ్చటగా ఉంటుంది. ‘‘నాలో వారు ఏం చూశారో నావారయ్యారూ అందుకనే మా ఇద్దరి జంట అపురూపం అంట’’ లాంటి మాటల్లో అంతటి గొప్పవాడు. నాలాంటి సామాన్యురాలిని ఇష్టపడటం ఏ జన్మపుణ్యమో కదా అన్న ఆలోచన బయటపడుతుంది. ఇది పాటో, మాటల మూటో అర్ధంకాని అద్భుతమే ఈ పాట! చిన్ని మాటలతో పాటలల్లే ప్రేమ సాహితీ సుగంధం ఆత్రేయ కలంనుండి జాలువారిన మంచిముత్యం ఈ పాట! తెరపై సంధ్యారాణిపై చిత్రీకరించిన ఈ పాట‘చందమామ.. అందాల మామా’అన్న సాకీతో ప్రారంభమవుతుంది. థియేటర్ అంతా నిశ్శబ్దం అయిపోతుంది. నాకెంతో ఇష్టం!  మామ మహదేవన్ ఏ పూనకం వచ్చి స్వరసమర్పణ చేసాడో తెలియదు కాని, అంత మధురాతి మధురం ఈ పాట! తన గొంతు కండరాల్లో ఏ అమృతం నింపుకుని పుట్టిందో తెలియదు కాని ఆ సుశీలమ్మ గానం ఈ పాటకు ఊపిరిపోసింది. అంతా కొత్తవారైనా గాని ఈ చిత్రం ఆదుర్తి, మామ, సుశీల, ఘంటసాల, ఆత్రేయల సాహితీ సంగీతాల సంగమానికి ఒక అపురూపమైన ఉదాహరణగా నిలిచింది. కొత్త నటిని అన్న జంకు లేకుండా సంధ్యారాణి సిగ్గు ఒలకబోసే అభినయం ఈ పాటకు మరింత అందాన్నిచ్చింది. అందుకే ఈ పాటంటే నాకు చాలా ఇష్టం.  మీకు ఇష్టమని అనుకుంటాను."},{"question":"什麼是三個宇宙速度？","answer":"根據科學計算，物體只要獲得每秒7.9米的速度，並且以水平方向拋出，就能繞地球運行，這個速度叫第一宇宙速度。如果物體獲得每秒11.2千米的速度，就能克服地球的引力，飛向太陽系的其他星球，這個速度叫第二宇宙速度。　　如果物體的運行速度達到每秒16.7千米的速度，就能飛出太陽系，到其他恆星世界去，這個速度叫第三宇宙速度。 "},{"question":"ලංකාව  යටත් කර ගෙන සිටි රටවල් මොනවාද​?","answer":"ඓතිහාසික වශයෙන් ලංකාව ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉතිහාසය විදේශීය ආක්‍රමණ කිහිපයක් සහ යටත් විජිත පාලන කාල වකවානු කිහිපයකින් සනිටුහන් වේ. විවිධ කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රදේශ යටත් කර ගත් හෝ පාලනය කළ ප්‍රධාන රටවල් වන්නේ:1. පෘතුගීසි අධිරාජ්‍යය (1505–1658): ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ පාදක වූ පළමු යුරෝපීය බලවතා පෘතුගීසීන් ය. ඔවුන් වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශ පාලනය කළ අතර බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් ක්‍රිස්තියානි ආගමට හරවා ගත්හ.2. ලන්දේසි අධිරාජ්‍යය (1658-1796): ලන්දේසීන් පෘතුගීසීන්ගෙන් අත්පත් කරගෙන දිවයිනේ සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රදේශ, විශේෂයෙන් වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශ පාලනය කළහ.3. බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අධිරාජ්‍යය (1796-1948): බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යටත් විජිත බලය ලෙස ලන්දේසීන් ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය කරන ලදී. ඔවුන් මුළු දිවයිනම එක්සත් කර පාලනය කළ අතර, මුළු දිවයිනම විදේශ බලවේගයක් විසින් පාලනය කරන ලද පළමු අවස්ථාව සනිටුහන් කළේය. බි‍්‍රතාන්‍ය පාලනය යටතේ සිලෝන් ලෙස හැඳින්වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 1948 දී නිදහස ලබා ගත්තේය.යුරෝපීය යටත් විජිත සමයට පෙර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අසල්වැසි දකුණු ආසියානු බලවතුන්ගේ ආක්‍රමණවලට මුහුණ දුන්නේය.1. චෝල අධිරාජ්‍යය: මධ්‍යතන යුගයේදී, දකුණු ඉන්දියාවේ සිට පැමිණි චෝල රාජවංශය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රදේශ ආක්‍රමණය කර පාලනය කළේය.2. පාණ්ඩ්‍ය සහ අනෙකුත් දකුණු ඉන්දීය රාජධානි: විවිධ කාලවලදී, අනෙකුත් දකුණු ඉන්දීය රාජධානි ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රදේශ කෙරෙහි බලපෑම් හෝ පාලනය සිදු කළහ.මෙම විදේශීය බලපෑම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංස්කෘතිය, භාෂාව සහ ඉතිහාසය කෙරෙහි සැලකිය යුතු බලපෑමක් ඇති කර ඇත."},{"question":"(- sin 45°, cos 0°) బిందువును కలిగిన పాదము ఏది ?","answer":"Q2"},{"question":"एयरोस्पेस इन्जिनियरहरूले सुपरसोनिक र हाइपरसोनिक उडानका चुनौतीहरूलाई कसरी सम्बोधन गर्छन्?","answer":"सुपरसोनिक र हाइपरसोनिक उडान ठेगानामा काम गर्ने एयरोस्पेस इन्जिनियरहरू वायुगतिकी, गर्मी व्यवस्थापन, र सामग्रीसँग सम्बन्धित चुनौतीहरू। नवप्रवर्तनहरूले उच्च गति हासिल गर्न उन्नत प्रोपल्सन प्रणाली र एरोडायनामिक डिजाइनहरू समावेश गर्दछ।"},{"question":"‘గిరిజన నృత్యం’ గురించి మీ సొంతమాటల్లో చెప్పండి.","answer":"అరకులోయలో కొండదొర, భగత, ఖ్యోద్, బోండీ అనే తెగల గిరిజనులున్నారు. ఉత్సవాల సమయంలో ఒక – గ్రామం వారు, మరో గ్రామానికి వెళ్లి, ‘థింసా’ నృత్యం. చేస్తారు. వివాహం సమయంలోనూ, చైత్రమాసంలో ఇటికల పండుగ రోజుల్లోనూ, గిరిజనులు ఈ నృత్యం చేస్తారు.థింసా జట్టుకు ఒక నాయకుడు ఉంటాడు. 20 మంది స్త్రీలు నృత్యం చేస్తారు. వాయిద్యాలు, మగవారు వాయిస్తారు. థింసాలో సన్నాయి, తుడుము, కిరిడి, డప్పు, బాకా, పిన్నలగర్ర, జోడి కొమ్ములు అనే ఆరు వాయిద్యాలు పురుషులు వాయిస్తారు. తమ గ్రామదేవత ‘నిసాని దేవత’ ను ఆరాధిస్తూ చేసే నృత్యాన్ని, “బోడి థింసా” అంటారు.ఈ నృత్యంలో ఒకవైపు మగవారు, మరొకవైపు స్త్రీలు, చేతులు పట్టుకొని వరుసగా నిలబడతారు. వీరు బృంద నాయకుడిని అనుసరిస్తూ లయబద్ధంగా అడుగులు వేస్తారు. ఈ నృత్యంలో పొంగిబుల్లమ్మ, కొర్రరాజమ్మ, కిలోల్ల లక్ష్మమ్మ మొదలయిన థింసా నృత్యబృందాలు. దేశమంతా ప్రదర్శనలు ఇస్తూ పేరుపొందాయి."},{"question":"أكمل هذه الجملة: شارك المنتخب السّعُوديّ في بطولة كأس القارات 1997 ","answer":"والتي نُظّمت في السعودية خلال الفترة ما بين 12 و21 أكتوبر من عام 1997."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : పంట విధానాలలో మార్పులు రావడానికి కారణమేమిటి?","answer":"మైదాన ప్రాంతాల్లో పంట విధానాలలో మార్పు రావడానికి కారణాలు :ఆహార పంటల నుండి నగదు/వ్యాపార పంటల వైపు మొగ్గు చూపుతున్నారు.పెట్టుబడి పెరుగుతున్న నేపథ్యంలో ఇవి లాభదాయకంగా ఉంటున్నాయి.వీటికి మార్కెటింగ్ సౌకర్యం బాగా ఉంది.కాలువలు, బోరుబావుల ద్వారా నీటి సౌకర్యము అందుబాటులో ఉంటుంది.యాంత్రీకరణ పెరగటం."},{"question":"De maneira concisa, defina a palavra \\"responsabilidade\\".","answer":"Responsabilidade significa cumprir obrigações e deveres."},{"question":"ප්‍රතිරෝධක න්‍යායන්  ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"ප්‍රතිරෝධය පිළිබද විද්‍යාත්මක න්‍යායන් අතර වඩාත් ප්‍රචලිත න්‍යාය වන්නේ ජර්මන් ජාතික විද්‍යාඥයෙකුවන ජී.එස් ඕම් නැමැති විද්‍යාඥයා ඉදිරිපත්කල න්‍යායයි.මෙම න්‍යායට අනුව ˘උෂ්ණත්වය නියතව පවත්නාවිට සන්නායකයක් තුලින් ගලායන විද්‍යුත් ධාරාව එම සන්නායකයේ අග්‍ර අතර පවතින විභව අන්තරයට සමානුපාතිකවේ.එනම් උස්ණත්වය නියතව පවත්නාකල් කිසියම් සන්නායකයක ප්‍රතිරෝධය නියතවේ."},{"question":"Maak een enquêtevraag om klanttevredenheid te meten.","answer":"Op een schaal van 1-5, hoe tevreden bent u met onze diensten?"},{"question":"The largest living lizard can't breathe fire, but it does have a venomous bite that inhibits blood clotting. What kind of creature is this?","answer":"Komodo dragon"},{"question":"Inona ny fiantraikan'ny Revolisiona Indostrialy teo amin'ny fiaraha-monina sy ny toekarena tamin'ny taonjato faha-19?","answer":"La Révolution industrielle a transformé la société en favorisant l'urbanisation, en créant de nouvelles classes sociales, en améliorant les moyens de transport et de communication, et en stimulant la croissance économique. Elle a également entraîné des conditions de travail difficiles pour les ouvriers, donnant naissance au mouvement ouvrier."},{"question":"හොඳම ෆෝමියුලා 1 ධාවකය කවුද?","answer":"\\tහොඳම ෆෝමියුලා 1 රියදුරු කවුද යන්න දශක ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ තීරණාත්මක ජයග්‍රාහකයෙකු නොමැතිව දැඩි ලෙස විවාදයට ලක් වූ මාතෘකාවකි. වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා මයිකල් ෂූමාකර්, අයර්ටන් සෙන්නා සහ ලුවිස් හැමිල්ටන් වැනි බොහෝ ප්‍රමුඛ රියදුරන් සිටි නමුත් අවසානයේ හොඳම කවුද යන්න තීරණය කිරීමට අපහසුය. ෆෝමියුලා 1 මෝටර් රථ යනු සැබවින්ම ප්‍රබලම රියදුරා කවුරුන්ද යන්න විකෘති කරන තරඟයක් ජය ගන්නේ හෝ පරාජය කරන්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න පිළිබඳ තීරණාත්මක කොටසකි. හොඳම ෆෝමියුලා 1 ධාවකයා කවුද යන ප්‍රශ්නය ක්‍රීඩාවට ඇතුළු වන සෑම නව පරම්පරාවේ රියදුරන් සමඟම නොනැවතී පවතිනු ඇත, කෙසේ වෙතත් පැහැදිලිවම අයර්ටන් සෙනා හොඳම ය."},{"question":"ලොව විශාලතම විල් 10 නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ලොව විශාලතම විල් 10 පහල සනිටුහන් කර ඇත.කැස්පියන් විලසුපීරියර් විලඒරල් විලවික්ටෝරියා විලහ්‍යුරන් විලමිචිගන් විලබයිකල් විලටැංගනිකා විලග්‍රේට් බෙයාර් විලග්‍රේට් ස්ලේව් විල"},{"question":"தஞ்சையில் பொறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அரசாணையால் அறியப்படும் செய்தி யாது?","answer":"தஞ்சாவூரில் வாழ்ந்த ஆகம சாஸ்திர பண்டிதராகிய சர்வசிவ பண்டிதரிடத்தில் பல நாட்டைச் : சார்ந்த மாணாக்கர்கள் கல்விக் கற்க வந்திருந்தார்கள் என்ற செய்தி, முதல் இராஜராஜ சோழன் காலத்தில் தஞ்சையில் பொறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Anjing yang panas dipanggil?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah hotdog."},{"question":"لاندې شرایطو ته په پام سره  \\"هو، ما فکر کاوه چې زه به ماشوم له لاسه ورکړم.\\" هغه وویل: \\"زه هم ډاریدم،\\" هغه وویل، د اخلاص له سترګو یې سیلاب راووت. \\"تاسووو؟ \\"هو البته. ته ولې پوښتنه کوې؟\\" \\"دا ماشوم په سمه توګه پلان شوی نه و.\\" او هدف جمله:\\"ایا تاسو په صادقانه توګه فکر کوئ چې زه غواړم تاسو یو _ ولرئ؟\\" د هدف کلمه وړاندوینه","answer":"ورکه شوې کلمه اسقاط دی"},{"question":"Gözlem yoluyla öğrenmeye ne ad verilir?","answer":"Toplumda bireyler diğer insanları seyrederek ve gözlem yaparak, onların yap- tığı davranışın pekiştirildiğini veya cezalandırıldığını gözlemleyerek öğrenirler. Bu nedenle sosyal öğrenme “başkalarını seyrederek çevreden öğrenme” veya “toplum içinde ve toplum için öğrenme” olarak da tanımlanabilir."},{"question":"사스(SaaS)의 뜻이 뭔가요? ","answer":"사스(SaaS)는 서비스로서의 소프트웨어(Software-as-a-Service, SaaS)의 약자로, 클라우드 애플리케이션과 기본 IT 인프라 및 플랫폼을 인터넷 브라우저를 통해 최종 사용자에게 제공하는 클라우드 컴퓨팅 형태입니다. SaaS를 사용하면 소프트웨어를 영구 구매하거나 강력한 온프레미스 IT 인프라에 투자할 필요가 없기 때문에 사용자의 초기 비용이 줄어듭니다. 기업이 인프라, 플랫폼, 온프레미스 소프트웨어의 구매나 유지관리 책임을 맡고 싶지 않은 경우나, 자본 비용(CAPEX) 투자가 아닌 운영 비용(OPEX)을 통해 비용 관리를 간소화하고자 하는 경우에 유용합니다. "},{"question":"திருவள்ளுவரின் சிறு குறிப்பு தருக ","answer":"திருவள்ளுவர் (சுருக்கமாக வள்ளுவர்) பழந்தமிழ் இலக்கியமான திருக்குறளை இயற்றிய தமிழ்ப்புலவர் ஆவார். கடைச் சங்க காலமான பொ.ஊ.மு 400க்கும் பொ.ஊ. 100க்கும் இடைப்பட்ட காலத்தில் வாழ்ந்த புலவரான மாமூலனார் மற்றும் மதுரையை, ஆரியப்படை கடந்த நெடுஞ்செழியன் எனும் பாண்டிய மன்னன் ஆண்ட பொழுது வள்ளுவர் பற்றிய குறிப்புகள் ஓலைச்சுவடிகளில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.கன்னியாகுமரியில் நிறுவப்பட்டுள்ள திருவள்ளுவர் சிலைதிருவள்ளுவர், திருக்குறளை தமிழ்ச்சங்கத்தில் அரங்கேற்றம் செய்ய மிகவும் சிரமப்பட்டதாகவும், முடிவில் ஒளவையாரின் துணையோடு, மதுரையில் அரங்கேற்றியதாகவும் நம்பப்படுகிறது.சங்க காலப் புலவரான ஔவையார், அதியமான் மற்றும் பரணர் மூவரும் சமகாலத்தவராக இருக்கலாம் என்ற கருத்தும் உள்ளது. இதன் மூலம் சங்க காலப் புலவர் மாமூலனாரே முதன் முதலில் திருவள்ளுவரைப் பற்றிய செய்தியைத் தருகிறார். ஆகையால் மாமூலனாருக்கு முன்பே ஔவையார் என்ற பெயருடைய மற்றொரு புலவர் இருந்திருக்கலாம் என்றே தெரியவருகிறது. மாமூலனார் பொ.ஊ.மு. 4 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு செய்தியைக் கூறுவதால், திருவள்ளுவர் பொ.ஊ.மு. 5 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுக்கு முற்பட்டவராக இருக்க வேண்டும். ஆனாலும் மாமூலனார் பாடல் இடம்பெற்றுள்ள திருவள்ளுவமாலை தொகுக்கப்பட்ட காலம் (பொ.ஊ. 11ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு) மிகவும் பிந்தையது என்பதால், சங்க கால மாமூலனாரும் திருவள்ளுவமாலையில் இடம் பெறும் மாமூலனாரும் ஒருவர் அல்லர் என்னும் கருத்து நிலவுகிறது. திருவள்ளுவர், அனைத்துத் தமிழர்களாலும் அறிந்து போற்றப்படுபவராகவும் தமிழர்களின் பண்பாட்டுச் செறிவின் அடையாளமாகவும் திகழ்கிறார்."},{"question":" मर्कटस्य सुरापानं मध्ये वृश्चिक दम्शनम् ।  तन्मध्ये भूतसञ्चारो यद्वा तद्वा भविष्यति ","answer":"एखाद्या माकडाला जर प्रथम दारू पाजली व त्यांत त्याला आणखी विंचू चावला व नंतर त्यास भूतबाधा झाली तर तो केवढा प्रचंड धिंगाणा घालेल त्याचे वर्णनहि करतां येणार नाही. एखाद्या कुचेष्टेखोर अथवा खोड्याळ मनुष्याला जर अनुकूल संधि मिळाली तर त्याच्या माकडचेष्टांना किती ऊत येईल?"},{"question":"Lẹyin ti Taoreed gbowo ni banki, wọn yinbọn pa a, wọn tun gbe owo ẹ sa lọ n’Ibadan","answer":"Ẹkun lawọn ti ko le mu iṣẹlẹ naa mọra bu si nigba ti wọn ri oku ọkunrin kan, Taoreed Oluṣọla, nilẹẹlẹ lẹyin ti awọn adigunjale yinbọn pa a ti wọn si ja a lole owo to ṣẹṣẹ gba ni banki.Ni nnkan bii aago kan aabọ ọsan ana, Mọnde, ọjọ Aje niṣẹlẹ ọhun waye nitosi sẹkiteriati ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ to wa laduugbo Agodi n’Ibadan.Ileefowopamọ kan ni Bodija la gbọ pe ọkunrin to n gun ọkada lọ naa ti gbowo ki awọn adigunjale meji ọhun ti awọn naa wa lori ọkada too tẹ le e debi ti wọn pa a si ti wọn si ja owo ọwọ ẹ gba.Gẹgẹ bi awọn tiṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju wọn ṣe sọ, bi Taoreed ṣe de itosi Sẹkiteriati lo ya bara sọna ileejọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ (Government House) lAgodi, nigba lo fura pe oun lawọn meji to wa lori ọkada to n bọ lẹyin oun n tẹ le.Nigba naa lawọn ẹruuku yinbọn lu u, ti wọn si gbe baagi owo ọwọ ẹ lọ nibi to ti n pọkaka iku lọwọ, ko too pada gbẹmi-in mi.Iwe akọsilẹ owo ti oloogbe yii gba, eyi ti wọn ba lara ẹ lẹyin to ku tan fi han pe ẹgbẹrun lọna ojilenirinwo Naira o le mẹfa (N446,000) lowo to ṣẹṣẹ gba nileefowopamọ.Awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ lẹka eto imọtoto ayika ni wọn gbe oku ẹ lọ si UCH, iyẹn ileewosan ijọba apapọ, to wa nitosi Agodi n’Ibadan.Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, SP Olugbenga Fadeyi, ti fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ fakọroyin wa.O ni ọga agba awọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, CP Joe Nwachukwu Enwonwu, ti paṣẹ pe ki awọn agbofinro bẹrẹ iwadii lati ri ọdaju eeyan to huwa ika ọhun mu laipẹ jọjọ."},{"question":"Euskal mitologiako Lamia nola deskribatzen da eta zer harreman du basoekin eta itsasoarekin?","answer":"Euskal mitologiako Lamiak emakume antzinakoak dira, sagar batzuk dituztenak eta askotan ile luzea eta oina arrain modukoak. Lamiak basoetan edo itsasertzean bizi izan ohi dira, eta askotan, zubien azpian kantatzen edo ilea orrazten aurkitu daitezke. Hainbat kondairetan, lamiak gizakiarekin harremanak izan ditu, batzuetan laguntasuna eskainiz eta besteetan tentatzen edo engainatzen. Lamiak Euskal Herriko paisaiaren eta naturaren misterioa adierazten du."},{"question":"Completa la siguientefrase:  Ganó dos medallas en el Campeonato Mundial de Yudo en los años...","answer":"2010 y 2011, y tres medallas en el Campeonato Panamericano de Yudo entre los años 2009 y 2012."},{"question":"Escriba un correo, para un cliente potencial de la empresa que he conocido en persona.","answer":"Hola, [nombre del cliente]:Espero que siga bien desde [evento, lugar y/o momento cuando se encontraron anteriormente].Quería saber ver si todavía estaba interesado en saber más sobre [su empresa] y cómo podemos ayudarlo con [necesidad/problema]. ¿Sigue buscando a alguien que lo ayude con [su servicio]?De ser así, ¡me encantaría que habláramos! Podemos tomar un café o hacer una llamada rápida para hablar más al respecto, lo que sea más conveniente para usted.¡Gracias y que tenga un excelente día!"},{"question":"Which city is the capital of Uzbekistan?","answer":"The capital of Uzbekistan is Tashkent. It has been the capital since 1930 and remains the country's most populous and economically significant city.Tashkent is a vibrant metropolis with a rich history, dating back to the 2nd century B.C. It offers a fascinating blend of ancient and modern architecture, with stunning mosques and madrasas from the Silk Road era alongside modern skyscrapers and bustling markets."},{"question":"¿Quién inventó el teléfono?","answer":"El inventor del teléfono fue Alexander Graham Bell en 1876. Fue el primero en obtener una patente de los Estados Unidos para un dispositivo que produjo una réplica claramente inteligible de la voz humana en un segundo dispositivo. Una resolución aprobada por la Cámara de Representantes de los Estados Unidos el 11 de junio de 2002 pidió el reconocimiento de la obra de Antonio Meucci y sus contribuciones para la invención del teléfono."},{"question":"Sheeg Buurta Ugu Dheer Somaliya Magaceedd?","answer":"Buurta Somaliya Ugu Dheer Waxa Ladhahaa Suurad."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Là một trong số ít quốc gia liên tục đáp ứng mục tiêu ngân sách quốc phòng thường niên của NATO là 2% GPD, Romania năm nay tăng ngân sách quốc phòng của nước này lên 7,5 tỷ USD, chiếm khoảng 2,5% GDP, trong bối cảnh xung đột ở Ukraine kéo dài.Quốc gia này chuẩn bị mở trung tâm đào tạo phi công F-16 cho Ukraine, đồng thời mua thêm máy bay, xe tăng, lựu pháo và UAV do Mỹ sản xuất để trang bị cho lực lượng Ukraine.","answer":"Trước đây, ngân sách quốc phòng này là quá mức cần thiết với Romania. Song với cuộc xung đột đang diễn ra gần biên giới, khoản tiền này là hợp lý, theo Sandu-Valentin Mateiu, sĩ quan tình báo Romania về hưu. \\"Chúng tôi đang ở tiền tuyến\\", ông nói."},{"question":"Ano ang kaugaliang Filipino na pagmamano?","answer":"Ang pagmamano ay isang kaugaliang Filipino sa pagbibigay galang ng mga mas nakakabata sa mga nakakatanda. Ginagawa ito sa pamamagitan ng paghawak ng kamay ng nakakatanda at  pagdikit sa noo. Madalas itong ginagawa kapag binabati ang matanda o nagpapaalam bago umalis."},{"question":"\\"වන සිව්පාවුන් වැනි මිනිසුන් මැද\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ","answer":"වන සිව්පාවුන් වැනි මිනිසුන් මැදදෙවි දේවතාවුන් වැනි මිනිසුන් ඇතඒ දේවතාවන් දිව්‍යාංගනාවන්මනු ලෝ තලයේ වාසනාවන්වල්මත් වූවන් දැක මහ වන මැදයා යුතු මාවත පෙන්වාඒ දෙස බලමින් සැනසෙන මිනිසුන්ඉටු දෙවියන් ලොව සිටිනාකඳුළු සලන්නන් කඳුළින් ගොඩ ගෙනමුවගේ හසරැළි රඳවාතුටු කඳුළින් නෙතු සරසන දෙවියන්පුද දෙමු දෙවොලට කැඳවාචන්ද්‍රලේඛා පෙරේරාසුනිල් ආරියරත්නරෝහණ වීරසිංහ(රේඛා ටෙලි නාට්‍යය)"},{"question":"Kodi ku Malawi kuli madokotala angati opanga opaleshoni?","answer":"phunzitsa m'modzi. kuchiza ambiri.Dziko la Malawi lili ndi maopaleshoni 65 okha komanso ogonetsa 7 m’dziko muno. ku chipatala cha Queen Elizabeth Central ku Blantyre, ndikupereka maphunziro a opaleshoni/yogonetsa kwa anthu azachipatala."},{"question":" ඉතාලියේ ජනගහනය කොපමණ වේද?","answer":"ඉතාලියේ ජනගහනය දළ වශයෙන් මිලියන 60කි."},{"question":"ගුවන්විදුලිය සොයාගත්තේ කවුද?","answer":"ඉතාලි ජාතික නව නිපැයුම්කරුවෙකු වන ගුග්ලියෙල්මෝ මාකෝනි විසින් 1890 දී ගුවන්විදුලිය නිපදවනු ලැබීය."},{"question":"làm sao để tạo ra 1 prompt template để tạo ra một đoạn hội thoại bằng tiếng Nhật theo chủ đề (ví dụ thể thao, văn hóa, ẩm thực) và theo trình độ (N5, N4, N3)","answer":"Để tạo ra một prompt template để tạo ra một đoạn hội thoại bằng tiếng Nhật theo chủ đề và trình độ (N5, N4, N3), bạn cần xác định rõ yêu cầu về chủ đề và mức độ ngôn ngữ. Dưới đây là một template mẫu bạn có thể sử dụng và thay đổi tùy theo nhu cầu cụ thể.Tiêu đề: Yêu cầu tạo đoạn hội thoại bằng tiếng NhậtNội dung yêu cầu:Xin chào,Tôi đang học tiếng Nhật và muốn luyện kỹ năng đối thoại. Bạn có thể giúp tôi tạo ra một đoạn hội thoại ngắn bằng tiếng Nhật không?Chủ đề: [Thể thao/Văn hóa/Ẩm thực/...]Trình độ: [N5/N4/N3]Xin lưu ý rằng tôi muốn hội thoại phản ánh trình độ ngôn ngữ tương ứng với JLPT [N5/N4/N3], nghĩa là sử dụng từ vựng và ngữ pháp phù hợp với trình độ đó.Cảm ơn bạn!Sau khi bạn gửi template như trên, tôi sẽ tạo ra một đoạn hội thoại dựa trên thông tin bạn cung cấp. Hãy thử nghiệm với mẫu template này để xem kết quả như thế nào."},{"question":"Bart verdient €16,- per uur. Op maandag, dinsdag en donderdag werkt hij 8 uur per dag. Op vrijdag werkt hij de helft van de werkdag. Eén keer in de 2 weken werkt hij ook een halve werkdag op zaterdag; hij krijgt dan wel 150% uitbetaald.Hoeveel verdient Bart gemiddeld per week?    A. € 544    B. € 496    C. € 472    D. € 432","answer":" Het antwoord is B. 496."},{"question":"* ما هي السورة التي تعادل قراءتها ثلث القرآن؟","answer":"سورة الإخلاص."},{"question":"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਬੂਝ ਨ ਪਾਇ ॥ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਦਾ ਮੁਖ ਊਜਲੇ ਹਰਿ ਵਸਿਆ ਮਨਿ ਆਇ ॥ ਸਹਜੇ ਹੀ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਸਹਜੇ ਰਹੈ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਭਾਈ ਰੇ ਦਾਸਨਿ ਦਾਸਾ ਹੋਇ ॥ ਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਗੁਰ ਭਗਤਿ ਹੈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਪਾਏ ਕੋਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਹਾਗੁ ਸੁਹਾਗਣੀ ਜੇ ਚਲਹਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਭਾਇ ॥ ਸਦਾ ਪਿਰੁ ਨਿਹਚਲੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਨਾ ਓਹੁ ਮਰੈ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਸਬਦਿ ਮਿਲੀ ਨਾ ਵੀਛੁੜੈ ਪਿਰ ਕੈ ਅੰਕਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੨॥ ਹਰਿ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਅਤਿ ਊਜਲਾ ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਪਾਇਆ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਪਾਠੁ ਪੜੈ ਨਾ ਬੂਝਈ ਭੇਖੀ ਭਰਮਿ ਭੁਲਾਇ ॥ ਗੁਰਮਤੀ ਹਰਿ ਸਦਾ ਪਾਇਆ ਰਸਨਾ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੩॥ ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹੁ ਚੁਕਾਇਆ ਗੁਰਮਤੀ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਸਬਦੈ ਜਗੁ ਦੁਖੀਆ ਫਿਰੈ ਮਨਮੁਖਾ ਨੋ ਗਈ ਖਾਇ ॥ ਸਬਦੇ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਸਬਦੇ ਸਚਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੪॥ ਮਾਇਆ ਭੂਲੇ ਸਿਧ ਫਿਰਹਿ ਸਮਾਧਿ ਨ ਲਗੈ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥ ਤੀਨੇ ਲੋਅ ਵਿਆਪਤ ਹੈ ਅਧਿਕ ਰਹੀ ਲਪਟਾਇ ॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਮੁਕਤਿ ਨ ਪਾਈਐ ਨਾ ਦੁਬਿਧਾ ਮਾਇਆ ਜਾਇ ॥੫॥ ਮਾਇਆ ਕਿਸ ਨੋ ਆਖੀਐ ਕਿਆ ਮਾਇਆ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਇ ॥ ਦੁਖਿ ਸੁਖਿ ਏਹੁ ਜੀਉ ਬਧੁ ਹੈ ਹਉਮੈ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਇ ॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਸਬਦੈ ਭਰਮੁ ਨ ਚੂਕਈ ਨਾ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਹਉਮੈ ਜਾਇ ॥੬॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਪ੍ਰੀਤੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਵਈ ਬਿਨੁ ਸਬਦੈ ਥਾਇ ਨ ਪਾਇ ॥ ਸਬਦੇ ਹਉਮੈ ਮਾਰੀਐ ਮਾਇਆ ਕਾ ਭ੍ਰਮੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਨਾਮੁ ਪਦਾਰਥੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥੭॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਗੁਣ ਨ ਜਾਪਨੀ ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਣ ਭਗਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ ਭਗਤਿ ਵਛਲੁ ਹਰਿ ਮਨਿ ਵਸਿਆ ਸਹਜਿ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸੋਇ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਸਬਦੇ ਹਰਿ ਸਾਲਾਹੀਐ ਕਰਮਿ ਪਰਾਪਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥੮॥੪॥੨੧॥","answer":" ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੇਵਕ ਬਣ = ਇਹੀ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ (ਦੱਸੀ) ਸੇਵਾ, ਇਹ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ (ਦੱਸੀ) ਭਗਤੀ। (ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ) ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ (ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ) ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ।1। ਰਹਾਉ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ (ਹੀ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਿਆਂ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ) ਸੂਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ। ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਸਦਾ ਸੁਰਖ਼ਰੂ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ) । ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ। (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ) ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।1।ਜੇਹੜੀਆਂ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀਆਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ (ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਜੀਵਨ-ਰਾਹ ਤੇ) ਤੁਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ-ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨਤਾ ਦੀ ਸੁਭਾਗਤਾ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਸੁਭਾਗਤਾ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ। (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ) ਉਹ ਪਤੀ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਸਦਾ ਅਟੱਲ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਨਾਹ ਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਨਾਹ ਕਦੇ ਜੰਮਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜੇਹੜੀ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮੁੜ ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਵਿੱਛੁੜਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਗੋਦ ਵਿਚ ਸਮਾਈ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ।2।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ-ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ, ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ-ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ। (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਪੁਸਤਕਾਂ ਦਾ) ਨਿਰਾ ਪਾਠ (ਹੀ) ਪੜ੍ਹਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਉਹ ਇਸ ਭੇਤ ਨੂੰ) ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝਦਾ, (ਨਿਰੇ) ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਭੇਖਾਂ ਨਾਲ (ਸਗੋਂ) ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪੈ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਤੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ) ਜੀਭ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।3।(ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ (ਤੁਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਮੁਕਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਹ) ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ (ਟਿਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ (ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿਂਦਾ ਹੈ) । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਜਗਤ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ) ਦੁਖੀ ਫਿਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਗ੍ਰਸੀ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ।4।(ਸਾਧਾਰਨ ਬੰਦੇ ਤਾਂ ਕਿਤੇ ਰਹੇ, ਜੋਗ-ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਪੁੱਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਜੋਗੀ ਭੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਹੇਠ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪਏ ਭਟਕਦੇ ਫਿਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਨਹੀਂ ਜੁੜਦੀ। ਇਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਭਵਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਗ਼ਲਬਾ ਪਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ, (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ) ਬਹੁਤ ਚੰਬੜੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ (ਮਾਇਆ ਤੋਂ) ਖਲਾਸੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦੀ, ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਵਿਤਕਰਾ ਭੀ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ।5।(ਜੇ ਪੁੱਛੋ ਕਿ) ਮਾਇਆ ਕਿਸ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੈ? (ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਕੀਹ ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ? ਜੀਵਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ) ਮਾਇਆ ਕੇਹੜੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ? (ਤਾਂ ਉੱਤਰ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਹੇਠ) ਇਹ ਜੀਵ ਦੁੱਖ (ਦੀ ਨਿਵਿਰਤੀ) ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਸੁਖ (ਦੀ ਲਾਲਸਾ) ਵਿਚ ਬੱਝਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ 'ਮੈਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਵਾਂ' ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਨਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਸਾਰੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਜੀਵ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਮੁੱਕਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ, ਨਾਹ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮੈਂ-ਮੇਰੀ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਨਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ।6।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ, ਤੇ) ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ (ਜੀਵ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ, (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ) ਜੀਵ ਕਬੂਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਹਉਮੈ (ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਮਾਰੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਨਾ ਤੋਂ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਈ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਕੀਮਤੀ ਪਦਾਰਥ) ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਸਮਾਈ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ।7।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉੱਚੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ, ਤੇ, ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ। (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ) ਭਗਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ) ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆਂ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ। (ਪਰ ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ) ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ।8।4। 21।"},{"question":"भारतातील सर्वात मोठे कॉफी उत्पादन करणारे राज्य कोणते आहे?(A) उत्तर प्रदेश(B) महाराष्ट्र(C) गुजरात(D) कर्नाटक=> ","answer":"(D) कर्नाटक"},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、最大500語の段落を書いてください： インターネットで服などを売るZOZOが初めての店を出す","answer":"インターネットで服などを売っているZOZOが12月16日、初めての店を東京に出します。インターネットだけでは、客が自分に似合うサイズやデザインの服などを見つけにくいと考えたためです。店を出して、新しい客を増やしたいとも考えています。店には、インターネットで売っている700ぐらいの服や靴などを置きます。予約した客が店に行くと、店の人やAIが似合う服などを無料で教えます。しかし店では品物を売りません。会社の人は「どんな服などが似合うかは店で目で見たほうがわかります。将来は店で集めるデータを品物を売るための役に立てたいです」と話しています。品物を買うのではなくて見たり使ってみたりするための店は、デパートなどでも増えています。"},{"question":"Mene amfanin Ƙugiya a Su?","answer":"Ana kafa ta a cikin ruwa a lanƙaya wani abu da kifi zai ci a jikinta, sai a baza ta a cikin wani yanki na ruwan da ake son kama kifin a ciki."},{"question":"Wangsulana pitakonan nganggo konteks artikel ing ngisor iki.Artikel: Kuning minangka warna ing antarane oranye lan ijo ing spektrum cahya sing katon. Warna iki dibangkitake dening cahya sing dhawa gelombang dominane kira-kira 570 - 590 nm. Warna kuning iki minangka warna utama ing sistem warna subtraktif, digunakake ing lukisan utawa cetakan warna. Ing model warna RGB, warna iki uga digunakake kanggo nggawe warna ing televisi lan layar komputer, kuning minangka warna sekunder sing digawe kanthi nggabungake abang lan ijo kanthi intensitas sing padha. Karotenoid menehi warna kuning sing khas kanggo godhong musim gugur, jagung, manuk kanari, narcis, lan lemon, uga kuning endhog, buttercup, lan pisang. Dheweke nyerep energi cahaya lan nglindhungi tanduran saka kerusakan marga sinar matahari (radiasi UV). Cahaya srengenge duwe warna kuning nalika srengenge cedhak karo cakrawala, amarga atmosfer nyebar dawa gelombang sing luwih cendhek (ijo, biru, lan violet).  Pitakonan: Pira dhawa gelombange cahaya sing mbangkitake warna kuning?Jawaban:","answer":"Gelombange cahaya sing mbangkitake warna kuning kuwi dhawane antara 570-590 nm."},{"question":"Apakah bunga terbesar di dunia?","answer":"Bunga terbesar di dunia ialah pakma raksasa. Ia juga dikenali sebagai padma raksasa, kerubut, pelimun atau bunga bangkai (nama botani: Rafflesia arnoldii)"},{"question":"Àjàkáyé-àrùn èrànkòrónà ọdún 2019-2020","answer":"Àjàkáyé-àrùn èrànkòrónà ọdún 2019-2020 tàbí Àjàkáyé-àrùn COVID-19 ni àjàkáyé-àrùn tí ó ṣẹlẹ̀ ní ààrin ọdún 2019 àti 2020 tí ò ń tàn káàkiri orílẹ̀ èdè gbogbo àgbáyé lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́. Kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn kòrónà tí ó ń ṣàkóbá fún èémí ọ̀wọ́ kejì (SARS-CoV-2) ló ṣokùnfà àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà. Àgbègbè Wuhan, ní ìlú Hubei, lórílẹ̀-èdè China ní àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí tí kọ́kọ́ farahàn lóṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2019, tí ó sìn ti di nǹkan tí àjọ tí ó ń rí sì ètò ìlera ní àgbáyé, World Health Organization tí kéde rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí àrùn pàjáwìrì gbogboògbò lágbàáyé tí wọ́n gbọdọ̀ mójú tó. Titi di ọjọ́ kẹwàá oṣù ó ti ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 118,000 tí ó ti kó àrùn yìí káàkiri gbogbo àgbáyé, tí 5,800 nínú wọn jẹ èyí tí wọ́n kà sí pé àrùn náà tí wọ̀ wọ́n lára jù. Ó ti ju orílẹ̀-èdè àádọ́fà (115) tó ti kàgbákó ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún yìí, pàápàá jùlọ àárín gbùngbùn orílẹ̀-èdè China, Italy, South Korea àti Iran. Ó ti ju ènìyàn ìgbàlélẹ́gbẹ̀rúnmẹ́rin, 4,200 tí àrùn yìí ti pa ní ìfọnnáfòṣu, ó tó ènìyàn ọgọ́rùn-ún-lé-lẹ́gbẹ̀ta, (3100) tí wọ́n kú ní orílẹ̀ èdè China nìkan, àti ẹgbẹ̀rún kan ènìyàn káàkiri àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè op kù káàkiri àgbáyé. Bẹ́ẹ̀ náà, ó ti ju ènìyàn mẹ́rìnlélọ́gọ́ta ẹgbẹ̀rún (64,000) tí wọ́n ti mórí bọ́ nínú àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí. Ẹ̀rà yìí máa ń ràn láti ara enikan sí ẹlòmíràn nípa èémí ìpọ̀jáde bí a bá ń wúkọ̀ tàbí bí a bá ń sín.Àkókò tí ènìyàn bá kó àrùn yìí àti ìgbà tí ó máa farahàn ma ń sábà máa ń tó Ọjọ́ márùn-ún, ṣùgbọ́n nígbà mìíràn ẹ̀wẹ̀, ó lè tó nǹkan bí ọjọ́ méjì sí mẹ́rìnlá. Àwọn àmìn ìfarahàn rẹ̀ sáà a máa ń wá bí, àìsàn ibà, ikọ́ wúwú, àti àìlèmí kánlẹ̀. Ìpeléke àrùn yìí máa ń fà àrùn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró, àti ìnira èémí. Lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ báyìí, àrùn yìí kò gbóògùn kankan. Ṣùgbọ́n ìwádìí ìjìnlẹ̀ ń lọ lórí rẹ̀ lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́. Ìgbìyànjú láti mójú tó àwọn àmìn ìfarahàn rẹ̀ ni àwọn oníṣẹ́ ìwòsàn ń ṣe. Àwọn ọ̀nà tí wọ́n là kalẹ̀ láti dẹ́kun àrùn yìí fífọwọ́ déédé, jíjìnnà sí ara ẹni, pàápàá jùlọ ẹni tí ó bá ń ṣàìsàn tàbí fura sí pé wọ́n ní àrùn yìí àti ìyaraẹnisọ́tọ̀ ẹni tí ó fura pé òun ní àrùn yìí.Lára àwọn ọ̀nà ìdẹ́kun mìíràn tí wọ́n ń gbà láti dẹ́kun jíjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí káàkiri àgbáyé ni dídẹ́kun ìrìn-àjò, ìyà sọ́tọ̀ ẹni-afurasí, òfin kónílé-ó-gbélé, àti títi àwọn ilé-ìwé pa. Àwọn ìlú bíi Hubei lórílẹ̀ èdè China àti gbogbo orílẹ̀ èdè Italy ló wà ní ìyàsọ́tọ̀-àmójútó lọ́wọ́ báyìí, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà òfin kónílé-ó-gbélé ń lọ lọ́wọ́ lórílẹ̀ èdè China àti South Korea; bẹ́ẹ̀ náà, àyẹ̀wò fínnífínní ní pápákọ̀-òfuurufú àti ìdíkọ̀ ọkọ̀ ojúrìn;àti ìmọ̀ràn ìrìn-àjò ní ìlú tàbí àgbègbè tí àrùn yìí bá ti ń jàkálẹ̀. Ilé-ìwé títìpa pátápátá ní gbogbo orílẹ̀-èdè tàbí àgbègbè tí àrùn yìí ti ṣẹ́yọ ní àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn, èyí tí ṣe àkóbá fún ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ọ̀ọ́dúnrún mílíọ́nù (300 million) àwọn akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ jákèjádò àgbáyé. Àkóbá ńlá mìíràn tí Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 yìí ni ìfàsẹ́yìn ètò ọ̀rọ̀-aje àti ìbágbépọ̀, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 ti fa ẹlẹ́yàmẹ̀yà àti ìjà-aòfẹ́-ọ-nílùú wá sí àwọn ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè China àti àwọn ọmọ ìran ìlà oòrùn Asia, bákan náà ìròyìn òfegè lórí ìkànnì ayélujára nípa Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 àti àwọn aríjẹ-nídìí ìbàjé lórí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà kò gbẹ́yìn.Titi di ọjọ́ Kejìlá oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 126000 tí ó ti kó àrùn yìí káàkiri gbogbo àgbáyé, Ìwòye wà pé wọn kò jábọ̀ tó bí àrùn yìí ṣe ń ṣọsẹ́ pàápàá jùlọ àwọn tí àmìn ìfarahàn ṣì ṣẹ̀pẹ̀rẹ̀.Ní àtiparí oṣù Kejìlá lọ́dún 2019, àwọn onímọ̀ ìlera kéde pé àìsàn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró ṣẹ́yọ sí àwọn ènìyàn ní Wuhan, lágbègbè Hubei, lórílẹ̀-èdè China ṣùgbọ́n tí wọn kò mọ ohun tí ó ṣòkùnfà rẹ̀. Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn yìí, wọ́n tọpinpin rẹ̀ ọjà kan tí wọ́n ti wọ́n ń pè ní Huanan Seafood Wholesale Market, wọ́n sìn ṣàkíyèsí pé láti ara zoonotic ní kòkòrò àìfojúrí tí ó ń fa àìsàn náà ti ṢẸ̀ wá. Kòkòrò Àìfojúrí yìí tí ó fa àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn ni wọ́n ń pè ní SARS-CoV-2, kòkòrò àìfojúrí tuntun tí ó fara pẹ́ kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà láti ara àdán, pangolin coronaviruses àti SARS-CoV. Ìgbàgbọ́ wà pé, ó ṣeé ṣe kí kòkòrò àìfojúrí yìí wá láti ara àwọn ẹ̀yà àdán tí wọ́n pè ní Rhinolophus.Àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn yìí kọ́kọ́ ṣẹ́yọ ní Ọjọ́ kìíní Oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2019, láti ara ẹnìkan tí kò dé ọjà oúnjẹ òkun, (Huanan Seafood Wholesale Market) tàbí ní ìbáṣepọ̀ kankan pẹ̀lú àwọn ogójì àwọn mìíràn tí àyẹ̀wò ọ̀wọ́ àkọ́kọ́ fihàn pé wọ́n ní kòkòrò àìfojúrí náà. Nínú àyẹ̀wò ọ̀wọ́ àkọ́kọ́, ìpín méjì nínú mẹ́ta ni àyẹ̀wò fihàn pé wọ́n ìbáṣepọ̀ pẹ̀lú wet (wet market), tí ó máa ń ẹran lóòyẹ̀.Àjọ ìlera àgbáyé World Health Organization (WHO) kéde àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn náà gẹ́gẹ́ bí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn gbogboògbò tí ó nílò ìmójútó pàjáwìrì ní ọgbọ̀njọ́ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020. Olùdarí àjọ ìlera àgbáyé, Who, Ọ̀gbẹ́ni Tedros Adhanom, gbóríyìn fún ìjọba orílẹ̀ èdè China fún akitiyan àti ìgbésẹ̀ wọ́n láti rí i pé àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn tí kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà ń fà kò tàn kálẹ̀ ju bó ṣe yẹ lọ lórílẹ̀-èdè naa, bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé ó ń jà rànyìnrànyìn ní àwọn àgbègbè orílẹ̀-èdè mìíràn.Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ àrùn yìí, iye àwọn ènìyàn tí ó ń lùgbàdì àìsàn yìí tó ìlọ́po méjì láàárín Ọjọ́ méje àti àbọ̀. Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020, kòkòrò àìfojúrí yìí ti jàkálẹ̀ dé àwọn àgbègbè China, ọdún Chunyun, tí ó jẹ́ ayẹyẹ àìsùn ọdún tuntun ní China, tí wọ́n ṣe ní ìlú Wuhan lo ṣe àkóbá fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì àìsàn yìí, nítorí pé ìlú Wuhan ni ìlú tí ìgbòkègbodò ọkọ́ tí gbòde jù ní China. Àsìkò yìí ni ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ fara kàṣà àrùn náà. Lógúnjọ́ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020, orílẹ̀-èdè China kéde ogóje ènìyàn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì àrùn yìí lọ́jọ́ kan ṣoṣo, àti ènìyàn méjì mìíràn ní Beijing, pẹ̀lú enikan ní Shenzhen.Lọ́jọ́ kẹrìndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kejì ọdún 2020, àjọ ìlera àgbáyé, WHO kéde ìdí kù nínú àwọn tí ó ń kó àrùn yìí ní China, ṣùgbọ́n tí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà gbìnàyá ní orílẹ̀-èdè Italy, Iran àti South Korea. Iye àwọn ènìyàn tuntun tí ó ń kó àrùn náà ní orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn tí ju ti China lọ.Pínníṣín ni iye àwọn ọmọdé tí àyẹ̀wò ti fihàn pé wọ́n ní àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí títí di ọjọ́ kẹrìndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kejì ọdún 2020. Ìkéde kan láti ọwọ́ àjọ ìlera àgbáyé WHO fihàn pé ìdá 2.4 ni àwọn ọmọdé tí ọjọ́ orí wọn kò ju mọ́kàndínlógún lọ ló ní àrùn COVID-19 yìí káàkiri àgbáyé.Láàárín Ọjọ́ mẹ́fà sí mọ́kànlélógójì, tí àmìn àrùn náà ṣẹ́yọ àti àsìkò tí àrùn COVID-19 hànde ni àwọn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì rẹ̀ ń kú, àgbálògbábọ̀, ọjọ́ mẹ́rìnlá .Titi di ọjọ́ Mẹ́rìnlélogun oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 800,000 tí àrùn COVID-19 tí pá. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí NHC tí orílẹ̀ èdè China tí sọ, àgbàlagbà ni ó pọ̀jù nínú àwọn tí àrùn náà pa. Ó tó ìdá ọgọ́rin, 80% àwọn àgbàlagbà tí ọjọ́-orí ti kọjá ọgọ́ta tó kú, àti ìdá márùndínlọ́gọ́rin àwọn tí wọ́n ti ní àìsàn mìíràn lára tẹ́lẹ̀, pàápàá jùlọ àìsàn ọkàn, cardiovascular diseases àti itọ̀ ṣúgà, diabetes.Ẹni àkọ́kọ́ tí àìsàn yìí pa kú lọ́jọ́ kẹsàn-án oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020 ní ìlú Wuhan. Ẹlòmíràn tó kú ní orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn yàtọ̀ sí China kú ní orílẹ̀-èdè Philippines, ẹlòmíràn tí ó tún kú, tí kì í ṣe láti ilẹ̀ Asia kú ní Faransé. Lẹ́yìn China, ó ti ju ènìyàn méjìlá. Mẹ́jìlá lọ tí wọ́n ti kú ní Iran, South Korea, àti Italy. Bákan náà, ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ènìyàn ìròyìn tí fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ pé wọ́n tí kú ikú àrùn kòrónà apá àríwá Amẹ́ríkà (North America), Australia, San Marino, Spain, Iraq, àti United Kingdom. Ìwé ìròyìn Daily NK jábọ̀ pé àwọn ọmọ-ogun tó ti ju igba (200) ni àrùn kòrónà ti pa lórílẹ̀-èdè North Korea.Kòsí àmìn kan pàtó tí kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà, COVID-19 máa ń gbé yọ lára ẹni tí ó bá kó o. Àwọn tí ó bá kó o lè máa ní àmìn kankan tàbí kí ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní ṣàìléra bí i ikọ́, ibà, àìlèmí kanlẹ̀, ara riro, àìlókun, àwọn àmìn àti ìfarahàn rẹ̀ ló wà nínú tábìlì yìí.l.Bí àrùn yìí bá ti ń peléke, ó máa ń fà àrùn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró, ìnira láti mí, ìjayà àti ikú. Ìwádìí tí fihàn gbangba pé àwọn mìíràn lè ní àrùn yìí láìsí àmìn tàbí Ìfarahàn kankan, nítorí ìdí èyí ni àwọn onímọ̀ ìlera gbà á ní lmọ̀ràn pé ẹnikẹ́ni tí ó bá ti sún mọ́ enití àyẹ̀wò fihàn pé ó ní àrùn náà gbọ́dọ̀ wà ní ìmójútó láti ríi dájú pé kò lùgbàdì àrùn náà.Àsìkò ìyàsọ́tọ̀ fún ẹni tí ó bá kó àrùn náà àti ìgbà tí àwọn àmìn rẹ̀ máa bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní jáde máa ń tó ọjọ́ kan sí mẹ́rìnlá, ọjọ́ márùn-ún ló sáà à máa ń jẹyọ jù. In one case, it had an incubation period of 27 days. Nígbà mìíràn ẹ̀wẹ̀, àrùn COVID-19 kìí ní àmìn ìfarahàn lára ẹlòmíràn."},{"question":"\\"Ny mpampianatra dia manana anjara toerana lehibe amin'ny fizotran'ny fampianarana, mitarika sy manentana ny mpianatra. Manomana lesona izy ireo, manombana ny fivoaran'ny mpianatra ary mamorona tontolo fianarana manohana.\\" Manomeza lohahevitra ho an'io lahatsoratra ambony io","answer":"- Ny anjara asan'ny mpampianatra- ny mpampianatra"},{"question":"Develop an intricately layered narrative that weaves together the lives of characters from different cultural backgrounds, each facing unique challenges, against the backdrop of a rapidly changing global landscape.","answer":" एक जटिलता से भरी कथा बनाएं जो विभिन्न सांस्कृतिक पृष्ठभूमियों से आए कथाओं को मिलाती है, प्रत्येक व्यक्ति अद्वितीय चुनौतियों का सामना करते हैं, एक तेजी से बदलते वैश्विक परिदृश्य के सामने।"},{"question":"\\"බුහුටි\\" යන වචනය පහදන්න","answer":"දක්ෂයම් කාර්යයක් කාර්යක්ෂමව හොඳින් සහ සිත් ඇදගන්නා ලෙසින් නිම කිරීම හෝ ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට හැකි.උදාහරණ:ඔහු ඉදිරියේ බුහුටීපන්සිළු ද නොසිටී(ගුත්තිලය)"},{"question":"உணவு விடுதியொன்றில் வழங்கப்பட்ட உணவு தரமற்றதாகவும் விலை கூடுதலாகவும் இருந்தது குறித்து உரிய சான்றுகளுடன் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையருக்குக் கடிதம் எழுதுக.","answer":"உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையருக்குக் கடிதம்:அனுப்புநர்கண்ணன்,25, வள்ளல் தெரு,அண்ணாநகர்,திருநெல்வேலி – 11.பெறுநர்உணவு பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையர் அவர்கள்,உணவு பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையம், திருநெல்வேலி.மதிப்பிற்குரிய ஐயா,பொருள் : தரமற்ற உணவு வழங்கிய உணவு விடுதியின் மீது நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு வேண்டுதல் – தொடர்பாக.வணக்கம்.இன்று காலை பேருந்துநிலையத்திற்கு வெளியில் உள்ள “சுவையகம்” என்ற உணவகத்திற்குச் சென்றோம். நானும் என் நண்பனும் உணவு உண்டோம். உணவில் கல்லும், குழம்பில் பூச்சியும் கிடந்தது. உணவக மேலாளரிடம் முறையிட்டோம். அதற்குச் சரியான காரணத்தை அவர் அளிக்கவில்லை. மேலும் அங்கு வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த உணவு விலைப்பட்டியல் பலகையில் எழுதி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த தொகையை வாங்காமல் கூடுதலாக இருபது ரூபாயைக் காசாளர் வாங்கினார்.எனவே, தரமற்ற உணவையும், விலை கூடுதலாகவும் விற்பனை செய்த, அந்த உணவகத்தின் மீது நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு பணிவுடன் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன். மேலும் இதற்கான தக்க சான்றுகள் (புகைப்படம்) இத்துடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.                                                                                                    நன்றி!திருநெல்வேலி.14.03.2022.                                                                                                                                                                                 இப்படிக்கு,                                                                                                                                                                        தங்கள்                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        உண்மையுள்ள,                                                                                                                                                                                     கண்ணன்."},{"question":"¿Qué lenguas se hablan en Guinea Ecuatorial?","answer":"Los idiomas oficiales de Guinea Ecuatorial son: en primer lugar el español, en segundo el francés, en tercero, recientemente incorporado, el portugués.​ Guinea Ecuatorial es el primer país independiente donde el español y el francés son idiomas oficiales. Es el único país de África subsahariana donde el español es lengua oficial."},{"question":"2 log 3 – 3 log 2 ను ఒకే సంవర్గమానంగా రాయండి.","answer":"2 log 3 – 3 log 2 = log 3^2 – log 2^3= log 9 – log 8 = log 9/8[∵ log x^m = m log x, log x/y = log x -logy]"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Ninkii afhayeenka u ahaa asxaabtii u hijrootay ardul xabash?","answer":"Jawaab: Wuxu ahaa jacfar bin abii daalib Rc."},{"question":"What is p-value in statistical testing?","answer":"The p-value is the probability of obtaining results as extreme as the observed results, assuming the null hypothesis is true. A smaller p-value suggests stronger evidence against the null hypothesis."},{"question":"O que é glossário do movimento 'Decisão ou Despacho Admissão'?","answer":"O glossário desse movimento explica que ele representa a decisão que admite o recurso de terceiro nível e que outros recursos devem ser registrados em 'Decisão ou Despacho'."},{"question":"问题：什么是最常见的节日乐器？","answer":"答案：其中一件最常见的节日乐器是锣。属于金属类的打击乐器，它的锣声常用于表现一种紧张的气氛和不祥的预兆，具有十分独特的艺术效果。"},{"question":" Dhig Sumadda hakadka? ","answer":" Sumadda hakadka (,) "},{"question":"\\"Эр Семетей баяны\\" аттуу китептин автору ким, качан жарык көргөн?а) Б. Максүтов, 2000-жылы б) А. Жакыпбеков, 2004-жылыв) С. Байгазиев, 2001-жылы г) К. Жусупов, 2004-жылы","answer":"а) Б. Максүтов, 2000-жылы"},{"question":"छोटो नेपाली कथा लेख्नुहोस् ।","answer":"उसको थरको कारणले होस् वा उसको निरन्तर चर्को, खरोंच र काटिएको कारण, कसैलाई ठ्याक्कै थाहा थिएन, तर गाउँको स्कुलका अरू केटाहरूले उसलाई इट्टा भनेर बोलाए। उसको बुबा थिएनन्। जब उसको आमा स्कूलमा आउनुभयो, सबै त्यहा भएपनि उनी बेकार र प्रायः अलमलमा देखिइन्।अधिकांश शिक्षकहरूले ईंट्टाको बारेमा राम्रो मानेका थिएनन्। तिनीहरूले औंल्याए कि उ तेस्रो कक्षादेखि धुम्रपान गर्दै थियो, र प्रायः अन्य केटाहरूसँग झगडा गर्थो। तिनीहरूले उसलाई चोरीको आरोप लगाए, र प्रायः सबै प्रकारका समस्याहरूको लागि उसलाई नै दोष दिए।तथापि, एक जना शिक्षकले उसलाई फरक नजरले हेरे। उनले याद गरे कि ईंट्टालाइ पढ्न मनपर्छ । कक्षा पछि, ईंट्टालाले शिक्षकलाई भन्यो कि उसले टम सावयरलाई सात पटक पढेको थियो – अरू कसैले यसलाई एक पटक पनि पढेका थिएनन्। उनी डन क्विक्सोट पनि पढ्न उत्सुक थिए, तर पुस्तकालयले उनलाई उधारो दिएन। भास्युकोभ्का को टोरेडरहरू को एक अंश तिनीहरूको पाठ्यपुस्तकमा थियो, र ईंट्टा पूरै पुस्तक पढ्न चाहन्थ्यो। केही हिचकिचाहटसंग, शिक्षकले उसलाई आफूले व्यक्तिगतरुपमा लिएको पुस्तक दिए। यसलाई पढिसकेपछि, ईंट्टाले यसलाई सही अवस्थामा फिर्ता गर्यो।कक्षाका बिध्यार्थीले अम्बर्टो इकोले आफ्नो नातिलाई लेखेको पत्र पढे जसमा उसले कुनै पनि उमेरमा हप्तामा एउटा कविता कण्ठ गरेर आफ्नो स्मरणशक्तिलाई तालिम दिनु महत्त्वपूर्ण भएको बताए। शिक्षकले कक्षालाई यो चुनौती लिन सुझाव दिनुभयो, तर ईट्टाले मात्र त्यसो गरे, र कुनै अप्ठ्यारो नभई सम्पूर्ण कक्षाको अगाडि एउटा कविता सुनाए।.शिक्षक जानु भयो । त्यसपछि एक दिन फेसबुकमा उनीहरूले इँट्टालाई गाउँबाट झकेर बालगृहमा पठाइएको थाहा पाए । शिक्षकले ईंट्टा कसरी मिलेर रहेको छ भनेर थाहा पाउन घरमा सम्पर्क गरे। उनिहरुले थाहा पाए कि ईंट्टा दुई पटक घरबाट भागेको थियो। उसलाई चाहने कोही छैन भन्ने जान्न उ वास्तवमा यो गाउँ फर्केको थियो ।शिक्षकले उसलाई बालगृहमा भेट्ने निर्णय गरे। ईंट्टाको जिज्ञासु स्वभाव थाहा पाएर शिक्षकले ईंट्टालाई थियोडोर ड्रेइजरको द फाइनान्सर नामको पुस्तक ल्याए। यसले उसलाई पैसा कमाउने बारे सिक्न मद्दत गर्नेछ, जुन भविष्यमा धेरै उपयोगी हुन सक्छ भन्ने कुरा बताए । उनले ईंट्टालाई नभाग्न प्रोत्साहन दिए, ताकि तिनीहरू कडा अध्ययन गर्न र कलेज जान सकून्। त्यसपछि उसले व्यापार सिक्न सक्छ, र उसले चाहेको खण्डमा गाउँ फर्कन सक्छ। शिक्षकले फेरि भेट्न आउने वाचा गरेनन्। उहाँलाई वाचाहरू गर्न मन पर्दैन कि उनी पूरा गर्न सक्ने कुरा निश्चित थिएन। जे भए पनि ईंट्टालाई यो कुरा आवश्यक थिएन।जब शिक्षकले पुरानो गाउँको विद्यालयमा सम्पर्क गरे, उनले कक्षालाई इट्टाको बारेमा बताए। यो लगभग नयाँ वर्ष थियो, त्यसैले विद्यार्थीहरूले ईंट्टालाइ पठाउन मिठाईको प्याकेज सँगै राखे। एकजना केटाले व्यायाम पुस्तकबाट च्यातिएको पानामा एउटा चिठ्ठी लेख्यो, “कस्तो छ, ईंट्टा ? तिमि कहिले फर्किदै छौ? यदि तिमीलाई केहि चाहिन्छ भने हामीलाई कल गर्नु” र मोबाइल फोन नम्बर समावेश गरियो।ईंट्टाले सोचेको थियो कि कसैले उनको वास्ता गर्दैन। आफ्ना पूर्व शिक्षक र सहपाठीहरूको प्रोत्साहनको साथ, ईंट्टाले उत्साहको नयाँ भावना प्राप्त गर्यो। उसले कडा मेहनत गर्यो र कलेजमा भर्ना भयो। स्नातक गरेपछि उ गाउँ फर्कियो । उसले आफ्नो नाम कमाएको थियो – ऊ इँटा जस्तै बलियो, सवल र भरपर्दो थियो।"},{"question":"සිංහල ජන කතාවක් කියන්න ","answer":"ඌරු පැටවුන් තිදෙනාඑක ගමක, ඌරු අම්මෙක් සමඟ ඌරු පැටවුන් තිදෙනෙක් ජීවත් වුණා. මෙම පැටවුන් තිදෙනා වැඩිවියට පැමිණි පසු, \\"ළමයිනේ දැන් ඔයාලා වැඩිමහල්. මගේ අධාරයක් නැතුව වුණත් දැන් ඔයාලට හොඳින් ජීවත් වෙන්න පුළුවන් වෙන්න ඕනා. ඒනිසා දැන් තම තමන් තනිව ජීවත් වීමට අවශ්‍ය නිවාස තනා ගන්නා.\\" කියා ඌරු අම්මා පැටවුන්ට පැවසුවා.ඉතින් මේ ඌරු පැටවු තිදෙනා තම තමන්ට නිවාස සාදා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය සොයමින් ගියා. පලවෙනි ඌරු පැටියා හිතුවා, පිදුරු වලින් නිවසක් තනා ගැනීමට. \\"මන් පිදුරු වලින් නිවසක් තනා ගන්නවා. එතකොට මන් වෘකයෙක් ගෙන් වුවත් ආරක්ෂිතයි.\\"දෙවැනි ඌරු පැටියා නිවස තැනුවේ ලී වලින්. තුන් වැනි ඌරු පැටියා සිය නිවස ශක්තිමත් ගඩොලින් තැනුවා. තුන් දෙනාම සිතුවා තමන්ගේ නිවාස තුළ සිටින විට, ඔවුන් වෘකයගෙන් ආරක්‍ෂිත බව.ඔන්න ටික දිනක් ගත වුණා. එක නපුරු වෘකයෙක්ට මේ ඌරු පැටව් ගැන ඉව වැටුණා. වෘකයා පළමුව පිදුරු වලින් නිවස තැනූ ඌරු පැටියාගේ නිවසට ගියා. \\"පුංචි ඌරු පැටියෝ... ඔයාගේ ගේ ඇතුලට මට එන්න දොර අරින්න...!!\\" කියා වෘකයා චාටු බස් දෙඩුවා.\\"මම ඔබට දොර අරින්නේ නැහැ. ඔබ යන්න.\\" කියා ඌරු පැටියා පැවසුවා. \\"ආහ්..!! එහෙම බැහැ. මගේ කටින් හුස්ම බිඹලා, ඔබේ නිවස මන් විනාශ කරනවා...!!!\\" කියූ වෘකයා ඉතා විශාල හුස්මක් ගෙන පිදුරු සෙවිලි කළ නිවසට පිම්බා. නිවස සී සී කඩ විසිරී ගියා. පුංචි ඌරු පැටියාව අල්වා ගත් වෘකයා, ඌරු පැටියාව ගිල, බඩ කට පුරවා ගත්තා. ඊළඟ දිනයේ වෘකයා ලී වලින් තනන ලද නිවසට ගියා. ඌරු පැටවාව චාටුවෙන් රවටා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ තැන, වෘකයා විශාල හුස්මක් පිඹ, ලී ගෙයද විනාශ කළා. දෙවනි ඌරු පැටියාවත් අල්ලාගෙන කෑවා.ඊළඟ දිනයේ ඔහු ගඩොලින් තැනූ නිවස වෙතයි ගියේ. මේ ඌරු පැටියාවත් චාටුවෙන් රවටා ගත නොහැකි වුණා. එහෙයින්, සැඩ හුස්මක් බිඹ, නිවස විනාශ කිරීමට වෘකයා සැරසුණා. කිහිප වරක්ම උත්සාහ කළා. නමුත් අසාර්ථක වුණා. ගඩොල් ඉතාම ශක්තිමත් නිසා නිවසට කිසිම හානියක් වුණේ නැහැ. පැය ගණනාවක් ම වෙහෙසුණු වෘකයා අසාර්ථක වුණා. තුන් වැනි ඌරු පැටියා කෑමට නොහැකි වූ වෘකයා බොහෝ වෙහෙසට පත්වී යන්න ගියා. තම නිවාස ශක්තිමත් ව, තැනූ බුද්ධිමත් ඌරු පැටියා බේරුණා.   "},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--चालत्या गाडीला खीळ","answer":"व्यवस्थित चालणाऱ्या कार्यात अडचण निर्माण होणे."},{"question":"மனிதன்  \\" அம்னிஷியா \\" எனும் நோயினால் மனிதன் இழப்பது எது  ?","answer":"விடை: அம்னிஷியா எனும் நோயினால் மனிதன் இழப்பது நினைவிழப்பு.மறதி நோய்மறதிநினைவிழப்புமூளையில் காயம் ஏற்படுவதனாலோ, தீவிர உணர்ச்சிப் பெருக்கத்தினாலோ ஏற்படும் நினைவிழக்கும் நோய். "},{"question":"Qiimaynta Cabbiraadda jirka?","answer":"Jir cabbirku waa hab lagu cabiro xajmiga jirka waxaana loo isticmaalaa in lagu fahmo heerka nafaqo ee qofka. Cabiraadahan soo socda ayaa badanaaba la isticmaalaa. Culays: Isbeddelka kuyimaada culayska ilmaha wuxuu tilmaan muhiim ah u yahay caafimaadka guud iyo ladnaanta bulshada. Si kastaba ha ahaatee xilliyada duruufaha gaarka ah waxaa muhiim noqon kara in la cabiro da’aha kale. Jiif ama Joog: Dhererka ilmuhu wuxuu isla beddelaa wakhtiga isagoo ku xiran nafaqeeyayaalka la qaatay iyo sida jirku uga faa’iidaystay.Dhexroorka bartamaha cududda sare (MUAC): kani waa cabbir deg-deg ah waxtarna u leh in lasaadaaliyo carruurta dhimashada khatarta ugu jirata da’dooduna u dhexayso 12 –  59 bilood.MUAC waa aalad baaritaan oo muhiima u ah go’aaminta ilmaha khatarta ku jira xilligamasiibooyinku jiraan. Tusaha cufnaanta jirka (BMI): waa aalad muhiim ah marka la cabirayo heerka nafaqada dadka waaweyn. Cabbirka culayska iyo dhererka ayaa la qaadaa ka dibna waxaa lagu xisaabiyaa tusaha. Isticmaalka BMI ee dadka waaweyn waa mid aan lagu kalsoonaan karin waayo saxnaanta dhererka ayaa waxaa carqaladeeya arrimo da’da la xiriira sida soo godashada lafta dhabarka (spinal curvature).Sidaas awgeed MUAC-gu waa cabbiraadda ugu haboon maadaama ilaa xad aanu ku xirnayn da’da. Barar(oedama): Ururitaanka dheecaanada aan caadiga ahayn unugyada dhexdooda wuxuu tilmaamaa nafaqo-darro halis ah."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fandotoana rano?","answer":"Mitranga ny fahalotoan'ny rano rehefa ariana any amin'ny loharanon-drano ny akora manimba, ka mandoto ny rano ary mahatonga ny fampiasana azy ho tsy azo antoka ho an'ny fahasalaman'ny olombelona sy ny tontolo iainana."},{"question":"Ukuze akhuthaze ukuthuthukiswa komnotho, uRosellini wamisa umnyango wezohwebo futhi wasekela iSeattle World's Fair","answer":"wamisa umnyango ngo-1962."},{"question":"30 second bis isii.","answer":"30 second Bis iisiiii indhahaaga iyo maskaxdadaba#Tik_Tok waa calaamad muujinaysa in dunida ay diyaar u tahay soo dhoweynta Dajaal Cawar ==========================1️⃣Waa maxay Tiktok ? 2️⃣Yaa iska leh? 3️⃣Hadafka loo sameeyay waa maxay ? Sanadkii tagay waxaan daawaday Taxane uu cinwaankiisa ahaa “ The army of satan “ ciidamada sheydaanka kaasoo ka baxayay youtube channel-ka “ Rational beleivers “ Taxanahaas oo  ka koobnaa 18 xalqadood . Waan hubaa qofkii daawada 18-kaas xalqadood in uu wax badan ka fahmi doono is bedelka ku socda dunida. Linkiga hoose ayad ka heli kartaa taxanahaas.Tiktok haddii aan afsoomaliyeeyo waa goob cowrada dumarka lagu goobeeyo , heesahana lagu xifdiyo. Tiktok waxaa leh ururka daahsoon ee shayaadiinta caabuda “Illuminati “, qoladan waxad ku dhex baran doontaa 18ka xalqadood, Illuminati waxaa ku abtirsada dadka ugu caansan dunida oo ah fanaaniin iyo siyiisiyiin, waxa kaliya ay dadka u balnqaadayaanayaa ah nagu soo biir waxaanu kaa dhigeynaa qof caan ah hantina heysta . kolka aad ku biiraysana kaliya waxaad oran “ Naftayda waxaan ka iibiyay shaydaan “. Dadka aan ka xusi karo waxaa ka mida Rihanna, J zea , Angelina Joulie , Halla Berry , Beyonce , Madona , Kanye waste , Nicki Minaj , Barack Obama , Bush yare , Lada Gaga , justin bieber , Machiel Jackson , Bill Clinton , Dick cheney , Bill gates , Hillary Clinton , Lil wayne  iyo kuwo kaloo badan.Dadka aan taxay qaar badan oo ka mid qiraal ayay sameeyeen waad heli kartaa ayagoo leh “ Naftayda sheydaan baan ka iibiyay “Suaalihii  1️⃣ 2️⃣ iyo Tiktok halka uu u abtirsado waa taa .3️⃣Hadafka loo sameeyay waa maxay ? Dadka ugu folowers-ka badan TikTok waa dumar , dumar-kana waa halka target-ka u ah dajaal sida xadiiskii ibnu cumar rasuulka ka weriyay ku cad . عَنِ ابْنِ عُمَرَ قَالَ قَالَ رَسُولُ اللَّهِ صَلَّى اللَّهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ يَنْزِلُ الدَّجَّالُ فِي هَذِهِ السَّبَخَةِ بِمَرِّقَنَاةَ فَيَكُونُ أَكْثَرَ مَنْ يَخْرُجُ إِلَيْهِ النِّسَاءُ حَتَّى إِنَّ الرَّجُلَ لَيَرْجِعُ إِلَى حَمِيمِهِ وَإِلَى أُمِّهِ وَابْنَتِهِ وَأُخْتِهِ وَعَمَّتِهِ فَيُوثِقُهَا رِبَاطًا مَخَافَةَ أَنْ تَخْرُجَ إِلَيْهِDadka ugu badan ee dajaal raaci doona waa dumar , dumarka dadka followers-ka u ah waa rag.Ogow dunidan alle wax walba asbaab ayuu u yeelay waxaan aaminsanahay in tiktok uu qeyb ka yahay asbaabaha dadka u dhaweynaya in dad badan ay raacaan deception-ka uu la imaan doono.Tiktok waxa uu kaalinta kowaad uga jiraa aaladaha ahlul fisqiga lagumana ciriirin karoMarkii aan argay musuqiisa waxan ku cabiray gabay kaas oo aan ka hadlayo xumaantiisa kulana dardaarmayo waxan iri sidan 1. Tigtogan la falqaynayee faciin wada qaatay2. Fajac iyo Ama kaak  baa ku dhacay fayla suufigiiiye 3. Aduunyadu fashaad inay gaadhaa lasku farayaaye 4. Garshadu markay foorartay faalo dhimataaye 5. Waa furinta laga duule xuma ah lagu feegaraye 6. Waa meel fas haad moyee  khayr laga filanayne 7. Waa meel ay hablaha faydani fallow ku doonane 8. Waa meel xumaha lagu foobiyoo vaar dab taale 9. Wase kama filaayn meel xun buu faalkii haystaaye 10. Kuwa falanfalxada  malayow filiqday ceebtiine11. Waa meel lagu ficshtamo qabyalda lagu farfaaraye12. Ninka videoga soo dhigow  faashil baa tahye 13. Waa furaha shaydaanka iyo fingiryadiisiye 14. Dhalinyarda ficnadanbay fiirintiisa jooga 15. Diinteena furqaaniyo faralka xoog yeela 16. Fadli baa ilaah laga helaa filo midkii fiican 17. Fadxi baa inoo soo socdii farax ku nooladda"},{"question":"Sheeg Wadanka Caalamka Ugu Kulul?","answer":"Wadanka Caalamka Ugu Kulul Waa Wadanka Liibiya (LIBYA)"},{"question":"Khối than nguyên khối kỷ lục của Việt Nam nặng khoảng bao nhiêu tấn?","answer":"Trong khuôn viên của Bảo tàng Quảng Ninh hiện trưng bày một khối than kíp lê khổng lồ, lớn nhất Việt Nam.Khối than đá này nặng khoảng 28 tấn, kích thước 3,6 m x 2,8 m x 2,2 m (22,2 m3), được tốp công nhân mỏ của Công ty cổ phần Than Cọc Sáu - Vinacomin phát hiện và khai thác ngày 5/4/2012 ở độ sâu 176 mét.  "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kalau takut dilambung ombak, jangan berumah di tepi pantai'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud sekiranya takut kepada risiko, jangan dekati bahaya. Contoh ayat: \\"Janganlah main saham kalau tidak mampu menanggung keberatan hati, bahkan kalau takut dilambung ombak, jangan berumah di tepi pantai.\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bajak selalu di tanah yang lembut\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud yang selalu menderita ialah orang yang lemah."},{"question":"Боз үй деген эмне жана ал Кыргызстанда салттуу түрдө кандай колдонулат?","answer":"Боз үй – Борбордук Азиянын, анын ичинде Кыргызстандын көчмөн элдеринин салттуу көчмө үйү. Ал кийиз же кездеме менен капталган жыгачтан турат."},{"question":"විපත යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"විපත යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය සැපත වේ. "},{"question":"Formule uma resposta para esta pergunta elaborada: Que equipe de wrestling Mathew Thomas Rehwoldt faz parte?","answer":"Os Vaudevillains"},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Joe R. Campa Jr. aimbova muzvikepe weUnited States Navy, uyo akashanda se 11th Master Chief Petty Officer weU.S. Navy. Mutsara wechipiri: Joe R. Campa Jr. aimbova U.S. Navy Matrose uyo akashanda saMaster Chief Petty Officer wechi11 weUnited States Navy. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hongu kana kuti kwete?","answer":"Hongu"},{"question":"Fehezanteny voalohany: Misokatra isan'andro isan-kerinandro ny tranombakoka.Fehezanteny faharoa: Mikatona ny tranombakoka amin'ny alatsinainy. Mifanaraka ve ireo fehezanteny roa ireo?","answer":"Tsia, mifanohitra izy ireo."},{"question":"\\"Ny epinara ve no loharanon'ny vitamina C tsara indrindra?\\"","answer":"Tsy ny epinara no loharano tsara indrindra amin'ny vitamina C."},{"question":"سورة من القرآن الكريم سميت بسورة الحواريين ما هي؟","answer":"سورة الصف"},{"question":"مدينة تعرف بأنها مدينة التلال السبع؛ فما هي؟","answer":"هو : روما."},{"question":"旧ソ連における農業の形態で、国営農場はソフホーズといいますが、集団農場のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"コルホーズです。"},{"question":"ما هو الاسم الكامل للخوارزمي؟","answer":"أبو عَبد الله مُحَمَّد بن مُوسَى الخَوارِزمي"},{"question":"کوانټم فزیک په دریو کرښو کې تعریف کړئ","answer":"کوانټم فزیک د فزیک یوه څانګه ده چې د مادې او انرژي چلند په کوچنۍ پیمانه لټوي، د ذراتو لکه اتومونو او فرعي اټومي ذراتو سره معامله کوي. دا اصول شاملوي لکه د څپې ذرې دوه اړخیزه، سپرپوزیشن، او ښکیلتیا، د تعدیل کلاسیک نظریات ننګوي. د کوانټم میخانیک یو احتمالي چوکاټ چمتو کوي ترڅو د مایکروسکوپی نړۍ کې لیدل شوي اصلي ناڅرګندتیا او غیر شعوري پیښې تشریح کړي."},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Khi dùng vũ kế đơn giản dạng hình trụ để hứng nước mưa, lượng mưa được xác định là:A. Là chiều cao của cột nước (mm) thu được trong 1 giờ.B. Là chiều cao của cột nước (mm) thu được trong một khoảng thời gian.C. Là chiều cao cột nước (mm) với diện tích đáy 1 m2 thu được trong 1 giờ.","answer":"đáp án BDụng cụ, thiết bị để đo lượng mưa gọi là vũ kế. Có thể tạo ra vũ kế đơn giản bằng cách sử dụng các bình thủy tinh hình trụ, thành cao, có vạch chia mm, mỏng, thẳng đứng để hạn chế tối đa nước mưa bắn vào trong hoặc bắt ra khỏi bình; đáy phẳng, diện tích đáy càng lớn càng tốt.Bình được đặt thăng bằng tại nơi cần đo lượng mưa. Khi đó, chiều cao của cột nước (mm) trong bình chính là lượng mưa tại khu vực cần đo trong khoảng thời gian tính từ thời điểm đặt bình tới thời điểm đọc chiều cao cột nước.Thông thường, lượng mưa được đo trong khoảng thời gian một trận mưa. Nếu đợt mưa kéo dài vài ngày thì lượng mưa được đo cho cả đợt mưa (bình vũ kế để ở ngoài trời trong suốt khoảng thời gian của đợt mưa).Muốn tính lượng mưa trung bình hàng tháng, hàng năm phải cộng lượng mưa của tất cả đợt mưa trong tháng, trong năm...Tuy nhiên, do thời gian mưa thường chỉ tập trung vào một số tháng trong năm, thậm chí có những đợt mưa lớn mà tổng lượng mưa có thể bằng một nửa lượng mưa trung bình của cả năm, vì vậy việc thống kê lượng mưa trung bình hàng tháng, hàng năm chỉ mang tính chất tương đối."},{"question":"Việt Nam có bao nhiêu tỉnh, thành giáp biển?","answer":"Việt Nam hiện có 28 tỉnh, thành có biển với 125 huyện ven biển. Từ Bắc vào Nam, các tỉnh, thành có biển lần lượt là: Quảng Ninh, Hải Phòng, Thái Bình, Nam Định, Ninh Bình, Thanh Hóa, Nghệ An, Hà Tĩnh, Quảng Bình, Quảng Trị, Thừa Thiên Huế, Đà Nẵng, Quảng Nam, Quảng Ngãi, Bình Định, Phú Yên, Khánh Hòa, Ninh Thuận, Bình Thuận, Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu, TP HCM, Tiền Giang, Bến Tre, Trà Vinh, Sóc Trăng, Bạc Liêu, Cà Mau và Kiên Giang."},{"question":"Haz un hola mundo en el lenguaje de programación python","answer":"\`\`\`pythonprint(\\"Hola mundo\\")\`\`\`"},{"question":"Que cidade portuguesa é famosa pelo seu centro histórico e consta da lista da UNESCO como sendo Património da Humanidade?","answer":"A cidade famosa pelo seu centro histórico e parte do Património da Humanidade da UNESCO é a cidade do Porto."},{"question":"கேள்வி :ரஸியா சுல்தானைப் பற்றிய பின்வரும் தகவல்களில் எது சரி?அ. தில்லியை ஆண்ட ஒரே முஸ்லிம் பெண்மணிஆ. சதியால் கொல்லப்பட்டவர்இ. 1240ல் கைதாள் என்னும் இடத்தில் கொல்லப்பட்டார்ஈ. இவை அனைத்தும் சரி","answer":"பதில் :ஈ. இவை அனைத்தும் சரி"},{"question":"கேள்வி : பொது நூலகங்களுக்கு நூல் ஒப்படைக்கும் சட்டம் எப்போது நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது? ","answer":"பதில் : 1954"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన శ్లోకాలకు కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:చంద్రశేఖర చంద్రశేఖర చంద్రశేఖర పాహిమామ్ |చంద్రశేఖర చంద్రశేఖర చంద్రశేఖర రక్షమామ్ || 1 ||రత్నసానుశరాసనం రజతాద్రిశృంగనికేతనంశింజినీకృతపన్నగేశ్వరమచ్యుతానలసాయకమ్ |క్షిప్రదగ్ధపురత్రయం త్రిదివాలయైరభివందితంచంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 2 ||పంచపాదప పుష్పగంధ పదాంబుజ ద్వయ శోభితంఫాలలోచన జాతపావక దగ్ధమన్మథ విగ్రహమ్ |భస్మదిగ్ధకళేబరం భవనాశనం భవమవ్యయంచంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 3 ||మత్తవారణ ముఖ్యచర్మకృతోత్తరీయ మనోహరంపంకజాసన పద్మలోచన పుజితాంఘ్రి సరోరుహమ్ |దేవసింధు తరంగసీకర సిక్తశుభ్ర జటాధరంచంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 4 ||యక్షరాజ సఖం భగాక్షహరం భుజంగవిభూషణంశైలరాజసుతా పరిష్కృత చారువామకలేబరమ్ |క్ష్వేడ నీలగళం పరశ్వధధారిణం మృగధారిణంచంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 5 ||కుండలీకృత కుండలేశ్వర కుండలం వృషవాహనంనారదాది మునీశ్వరస్తుత వైభవం భువనేశ్వరమ్ |అంధకాంతకమాశ్రితా మరపాదపం శమనాంతకంచంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 6 ||భేషజం భవరోగిణామఖిలాపదామపహారిణందక్షయజ్ఞ వినాశనం త్రిగుణాత్మకం త్రివిలోచనమ్ |","answer":"భుక్తి ముక్తి ఫలప్రదం సకలాఘసంఘనిబర్హణంచంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 7 ||భక్తవత్సలమర్చితం నిధిమక్షయం హరిదంబరంసర్వభూతపతిం పరాత్పర మప్రమేయ మనుత్తమమ్సోమవారుణ భూహుతాశన సోమపానిఖిలాకృతించంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 8 ||విశ్వసృష్టివిధాయినం పునరేవపాలనతత్పరంసంహరంతమపి ప్రపంచమశేషలోకనివాసినమ్ |క్రిడయంతమహర్నిశం గణనాథయూథసమన్వితంచంద్రశేఖరమాశ్రయే మమ కిం కరిష్యతి వై యమః || 9 ||మృత్యుభీతమృకండుసూనుకృతస్తవం శివసన్నిధౌయత్ర కుత్ర చ యః పఠేన్నహి తస్య మృత్యుభయం భవేత్ |పూర్ణమాయురరోగితామఖిలార్థ సంపదమాదరంచంద్రశేఖర ఏవ తస్య దదాతి ముక్తిమయత్నతః || 10 ||"},{"question":"Manana teny mikorotana ianao : \\"ALAMHELO\\"Inona ny teny tena marina mifanaraka amin'io teny mikorontana io?","answer":"Ny teny marina mifanaraka amin'io teny mikorontana io dia \\"MALAHELO\\"."},{"question":"පළමු ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් තරඟය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහභාගී වූයේ ?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය පළමු ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් තරඟය සඳහා සහභාගී වූයේ 1982 දී ය."},{"question":"Cual es la categoría principal de esta pregunta : ¿Quién fue el presidente de EE. UU. durante menos tiempo?.","answer":"La categoría de la pregunta es : Historia "},{"question":"Qual o nome completo do artista chamado do Vulgo FK?","answer":"O nome completo dele é Filype Kaique da Silva."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buruk hati'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang jahat. Contoh ayat: Perempuan yang buruk hati itu tidak membenarkan anak saudaranya menumpang di rumahnya."},{"question":"Cho tập hợp:U = {x ∈ N | x chia hết cho 3}Trong các số 3, 5, 6, 0, 7 số nào thuộc và số nào không thuộc tập U?","answer":"Lời giải:Một số thuộc tập U nếu số đó chia hết cho 3.Các số có tổng các chữ số là một số chia hết cho 3 thì chia hết cho 3.Ta có: U = {x ∈ ℕ | x chia hết cho 3}Khi đó ta thấy U là tập hợp các số tự nhiên x, sao cho x chia hết cho 3.Vì x chia hết cho 3 nên các số chia hết cho 3 trong các số đã cho là: 3; 6; 0Do đó: 3 ∈ U; 5 ∉ U; 6 ∈ U; 0 ∈ U; 7 ∉ U."},{"question":"පහත අර්ථයට ගැලපෙන ගීතය කුමක්ද?කෙටි කාලීන ජනප්‍රියත්වයක් හිමි මෑත කාලීන ගීත කලාව තුල බිහි වූ ඉතාමත් අර්ථ හා භාව පූර්ණ වූ මෙන්ම රසික ආදරය එක සේ දිනා සිටින ඇරඹුමම කඳුළක්‌ වෙලා ගීතය රචනා වන්නේ ගීත රචනා කලාවට මහඟු සේවයක් ඉටු කල කරුණාරත්න අබේසේකරයන්ගේ පුත් දිලීප අබේසේකරයන් විසිනි. ගීතයේ පද තුල තිබෙන ගැඹුරු බව නිසාම මෙම ගීතයේ අරුත පිළිබඳව රසිකයින් බොහෝ සැලකිල්ලක් දැක්වූ අතර ඒ හරහා ගීතයට විවිධ අර්ථකතන ලැබී තිබෙනු කිහිප විටක්ම දැක අසා ගනටද හැකි විය. ඇතැමෙකුගේ අදහස වූවේ මෙය මව් ගුණ ගීයක් යනුවෙනි. කෙසේ වුවද ගීතයෙන් පැවසෙන්නේ අන් කිසිවක් පිළිබඳව නොව වර්තමානය තුල සුලභ තාවකාලික අරුත් සුන් ප්‍රේමය පිලිබඳවයි.මෙය පෙම්වතෙකුගේ අසරණ ප්‍රකාශනයක් ලෙස දිස් වෙයි. ප්‍රේමය ආරම්භයේදීම එහි ඉමක් නොදකින බව හඳුනා ගන්න නිසාවෙන්ම සැමටම සිතට සහනයක්, සතුටක් ගෙනෙන ප්‍රේමය මේ ප්‍රේම මවන්තයාට ගෙන දෙන්නේ දුකක්. කිසිවක් කර ගත නොහැකි පෙම්වතා හට බලා සිටිනවා. ආදරය නමැති මාතෘකාව තුල ඇය බොහෝ දුරක් ඇවිදින්. මේ ප්‍රේමය තවත් එක නවාතැනක් පමණයි. පෙම්වතා බලාපොරොත්තු වන අන්දමට මේ පෙම්වතියගේ ගමනාන්තය නොවෙයි. ඇය ඔහු වෙතින් නික්ම යන්නේ ඒ නිසයි.ඇය ලියූ ආදර කවිය පෙම්වතාට බොහෝ දුක්බර වූ කවියක්. එකී දුක්බර කවියේ පවා පද පෙළක් අඩුවෙනුයි ඇය ලියා යන්නේ. එවන් කවියක අරුතක් කෙසේ සොයන්නද.. පෙම්වතා බලාපොරොත්තු වන්නට ඇත්තේ අරුත් පූර්ණ වූ ප්‍රේමයක් මිස තාවකාලික පෙම් කතාවක් නොවේ.මෙවන් ප්‍රේමයක අරුත විමසන්න ඇයත් නොමැති තැන ඔහු තවත් අසරණයි.  කඳුලින් අරඹන මෙකී ප්‍රේමය කෙරේ යම් දිනක ශෝකාන්තයක් පැමිණෙන බව දෙදෙනාම දැන නොසිටියාම නොවෙයි. පෙම්වතා සිටියේ දිරිමත්ව එයට මුහුණ දීමට. නමුත් පෙම්වතිය තුල එයට දිරියක් ඇත්තේ නෑ. විසඳා ගත නොහැකි ඉමක් නොපෙනෙන ගැටළු ගොන්නක් ඉතිරි කර පෙම්වතා තනිකර පෙම්වතිය ඔහු කෙරෙන් නික්මී ගොසින් …! කසුන් කල්හාරයන් සිය හඬ තුල විවිධ හඬ හැඩතල මවන්නෙක්. මේ ගීයට අවැසි වන ශෝකී ස්වරූපය මුසු ඔහුගේ හඬත්. නාලක අංජන කුමාර සංගීතවේදියාගේ මිහිරි සංගීතයත් ඉහත පද රචනයට සිදු කොට ඇත්තේ වචනයෙක් කිව නොහැකි සාධාරණයක්. ගීතයේ සාර්ථකත්වය කෙරෙහි බල පා ඇත්තේද එයම විය යුතුයි. ","answer":"ඇරඹුමම කඳුළක්‌ වෙලා මා බලා ඉද්දී ඒ දිහාආ දුරත් දුර වැඩි නිසාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා…දුක්‌බරම කවියක්‌ ලියාඑහි පද පෙළක්‌ අඩුවෙන් තියා…//අරුත පසදින්නට කියාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා… ශෝකාන්තය එන තුරාඑහි රැඳෙන්නට සිත් නැති නිසා…//අනන්තය ළඟ මා දමාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා…"},{"question":"Indro misy lahatsoratra:Andro tsy toy ny mahazatra androany, injao misy zavatra mikapokapoka ao am-baravaran’ny sekoly fanabeazana fototra ao Ampefiloha ao Antananarivo, renivohitr’i Madagasikara. Vita ny fianarana maraina ho an’ny taona fahaefatra, ka navory tao amin’ny efitrano iray hafa efa nomanina handraisana azy ireo mpianatra.  Hagagana no nisoritra teny amin’ny endriky ny ankizy raha nahita ireo biriky Lego maro loko miparitaka eo ambony latabatra. Nazavain’i Lalaharindratana, mpampianatra, ny anton’izao atrikasa \\"LEGO mandrafitra ny fiovana\\" izao. Nihaino tamim-pahalinana ny taridalana ny ankizy, dodona haneho ny heviny mikasika amin’ny fiovana, ny faniriany sy ny ho aviny amin’ny alalan’ireto biriky Lego ireto. Sambany no hilalao toy izao izy ireo ary tsy isan’andro rahateo no angatahana azy haneho ny hevitra amin’ny alalan’ny kilalao toy izao.Aiza no misy ny tanànan'i Ampefiloha araky ny lahatsoratra esty ambony?","answer":"Ao Antananarivo, renivohitr'i Madagasikara no misy an'Ampefiloha."},{"question":"Naon ngaran gunung pangluhurna di Indonésia?","answer":"Gunung pangluhurna di Indonésia nyaéta Gunung Puncak Jaya Wijaya."},{"question":"బహుళజాతి సంస్థల లక్షణాలను పేర్కొనండి.","answer":"బహుళజాతి సంస్థల లక్షణాలు:1. అధిక పరిమాణము: బహుళజాతి సంస్థల ఆస్తులు, అమ్మకాలు, అధిక పరిమాణములో ఉంటాయి. ఈ సంస్థల అమ్మకాల టర్నోవర్ అభివృద్ధి చెందుతున్న దేశాల స్థూల జాతీయ ఉత్పత్తికంటే ఎక్కువ. ఉదా: IBM నిజ ఆస్తులు 8 బిలియన్ల డాలర్ల కంటే ఎక్కువ.2. ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తముగా కార్యకలాపాలు ప్రపంచములో వివిధ దేశాలలో బహుళజాతి సంస్థలు తమ ఉత్పత్తి, మార్కెటింగ్ కార్యకలాపాలను నిర్వహిస్తాయి. వీటికి ఎన్నో దేశాలలో బ్రాంచీలు, అనుబంధ సంస్థలు, కర్మాగారాలు, కార్యాలయాలు ఉంటాయి. ఉదా: కోకోకోలా, ఆపిల్ సంస్థలు, ఇన్ఫోసిస్, ఎయిర్టెల్, రెడ్డి లాబ్స్ వంటివి ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తముగా విస్తరించినవి.3. కేంద్రీకృత నియంత్రణ: వివిధ దేశాలలో ఉన్న బహుళజాతి సంస్థల బ్రాంచీలు లేదా అనుబంధ సంస్థలు ప్రధాన కార్యాలయం యొక్క పర్యవేక్షణ, మార్గదర్శకత్వం, నియంత్రణలో పనిచేస్తాయి.4. నిర్వహణలో నైపుణ్యము: బహుళజాతి సంస్థలు సమర్థవంతమైన మేనేజర్లు, అనుభవము కలవారి సేవలను ఉపయోగించుకుంటాయి. కాబట్టి ఈ సంస్థలు వృత్తిపరమైన నిర్వహణ ద్వారా తమ కార్యకలాపాలను మార్కెట్లో విజయవంతముగా నిర్వహిస్తాయి.5. అధునాతనమైన సాంకేతిక పరిజ్ఞానము: బహుళజాతి సంస్థలకు అధునాతన సాంకేతిక పరిజ్ఞానము అందుబాటులో ఉంటుంది కాబట్టి వినియోగదారులకు నాణ్యమైన వస్తుసేవలను అందించడం జరుగుతుంది. 6. ప్రముఖమైన స్థానము, హోదా: బహుళజాతి సంస్థల పరిమాణము, ఆస్తులు, అమ్మకాలు చాలా ఎక్కువగా ఉంటాయి. కాబట్టి వ్యాపారము కొనసాగిస్తున్న దేశాలలో మార్కెట్ను నియంత్రించడమే కాకుండా ప్రముఖమైన స్థానాన్ని, హోదాను కలిగి ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи","answer":"Албетте, мына сизге кызыктуу факты: Мурда сөйкөлөр негизи  эркектер үчүн жасалган жана эркектер гана сөйкө тагышкан."},{"question":"Encik Danish menonton rancangan ________ untuk mengetahui isu-isu semasa tentang penularan wabak Covid-19.","answer":"drama"},{"question":"Nyatakan peribahasa yang sesuai dengan maksud peribahasa tersebut:\\"Kedudukan tidak tetap atau tidak terjamin\\"","answer":"Seperti abu di atas tunggul"},{"question":"Jereo ity fanambarana ity :« Avendran’izay olona izany. Raha ianao no vadiko angamba efa ela isika no nisaraka. »Misarona fankahalana ve izany fanambarana izany ?","answer":"Eny, maneho fankahalana ilay olona mety tsy mahatakatra izay takatrao izany."},{"question":" नेपाली चुटकिला ","answer":"एउटा अमेरीकाबाट आएको खैरे नेपलाको गाँउमा बास बसेछ । त्यसलाई नेपालको दाल भात र तरकारी निकै मिठो लागेर थपी थपी खाएछ । पछि दिशा लागेर 🚽ट्वाइलेट नपाएसी घारी तिर गर्न जाँदा झुकेर सिस्नोको घारीमा गएर हगेछ । हग्न त हग्यो तर सिस्नोले निकैनै पोलेछ ।पछि अमेरीका फर्केर साथी भाइलाई आफ्नो भ्रमणको बारेमा भनेछ “यार नेपाल देशले त खुब प्रगती गरीसकेछ, नेपालमा बिजुली यती धेरै भइसकेछ की बढी भएर उनीहरुले त घाँस, अनि झाडीतिर नी बीजुली छाडेछ ।”"},{"question":"ජනකවියෙහි අංග ලක්ෂණ මොනවද?","answer":"සමස්ත සමාජය තුළම පැතිර සිටි උසස් පහත් භේදයක් නොමැතිව සමාජයේ රදළයාගේ සිට දුප්පතා දක්වාම පැතිර සිටි මාධ්‍යයක් වීම හා එමගින් සමස්ත සමාජයම ජනකවිය නම් වූ භාෂාංග භාවිත කිරීම.සරල සුගම බස්වහරක් මෙන්ම කටවහරක් බහුලව යොදා ගැනීම නිසා සමස්ත ජනයාට තේරුම් ගැනීමේ හැකියාව ලැබීම.වෘත්තය මට්ටමෙන් වෙනස් ආරක ජනකවි නිපදවීම හා එක් එක් වෘත්තිය අනුව තාලය රිද්මය හා භාෂා භාවිතය වෙනස්වීම.බොහෝ විට අව්‍යාජත්වය පිරි පැවතීම."},{"question":"విచ్ఛిన్నతను ప్రభావితం చేసే కారకాలను చర్చించండి.","answer":"విచ్ఛిన్నకారులు సంక్లిష్ట కర్బన పదార్థాలను కార్బన్ డైఆక్సైడ్, నీరు, పోషకాల లాంటి సరళ అకర్బన పదార్థాలుగా విడగొడతాయి. ఈ ప్రక్రియను విచ్ఛిన్నక్రియ అంటారు.విచ్ఛిన్నతను ప్రభావితం చేసే కారకాలు :డెట్రిటస్లోని రసాయన సంఘటన, శోతోష్ణస్థితి కారకాలు విచ్ఛిన్నక్రియ రేటును నియంత్రిస్తాయి.నిర్ణీత వాతావరణ పరిస్థితులలో డెట్రిటస్లో లిగ్నిన్, కైటిన్ అధికంగా ఉండే విచ్ఛిన్నక్రియా రేటు నెమ్మదిగా ఉంటుంది.అధిక నైట్రోజన్, నీటిలో కరిగే పదార్థాలైన చక్కెరలు ఉన్నట్లయితే డెట్రిటస్ విచ్ఛిన్నక్రియా రేటు వేగంగా ఉంటుంది.శీతోష్ణస్థితి కారకాలలో ఉష్ణోగ్రత, నేలలోని తేమ ప్రధానమైనవి. ఇవి నేలలోని సూక్ష్మజీవులపై ప్రభావం చూపి విచ్ఛిన్నక్రియను క్రమపరుస్తాయి.వేడిగా, తేమగా ఉన్న పరిసరాలు విచ్ఛిన్నక్రియకు ఉపకరిస్తాయి.తక్కువ ఉష్ణోగ్రత, అవాయు పరిసరాలు విచ్ఛిన్నక్రియను నిరోధించి కర్బనపదార్థాల నిర్మాణం జరుపుతాయి."},{"question":"足利義昭（よしあき）は室町幕府１５代将軍ですが、足利義詮（よしあきら）は第何代将軍でしょう？","answer":"２代です。"},{"question":"O jakim wydarzeniu mówi ten fragment: W maju 2010 wraz z Haddy N’jie i Nadią Hasnaoui poprowadził 55. Konkurs Piosenki Eurowizji organizowany w Oslo.","answer":"55. Konkurs Piosenki Eurowizji"},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir?: Sérgio Dutra Santos (d. 15 Ekim 1975-Diamante do Norte) Brezilyalı voleybolcu. İlk kulübü 1989 yılında oynanmaya başladığı Brasil Volei Clube’ydi. Ulusal takım formasını ilk kez 2001 yılında giydi. Ulusal takım formasıyla 2001 Dünya Ligi’nde, 2002 Dünya Şampiyonası’nda, 2003 Dünya Ligi’nde, 2003 Dünya Kupası’nda, 2004 Dünya Ligi’nde, 2004 Atina Olimpiyat Oyunları’nda, 2005 Dünya Ligi’nde, 2005 World Grand Champions Cup’ta, 2006 Dünya Ligi’nde, 2006 Dünya Şampiyonası’nda, 2007 Dünya Ligi’nde, 2007 Dünya Kupası’nda, 2009 Dünya Ligi’nde ve 2009 World Grand Champions Cup’ta şampiyonluk yaşadı. Copra Berni Piacenza formasıyla da 2006 Top Teams Kupası’nda şampiyonluğuna ulaştı. 2003 Dünya Ligi’nde “en iyi manşet”, 2003 Dünya Kupası’nda “en iyi libero”, 2004 Atina Olimpiyat Oyunları’nda “en iyi manşet” ve “en iyi libero”, 2007 Dünya Kupası’nda “en iyi manşet” ve “en iyi libero”, 2009 Dünya Ligi’nde “en değerli oyuncu”, 2009 World Grand Champions Cup’ta “en iyi libero” ödüllerinin sahibi oldu. Voleybol kariyerini Brasil Vôlei Clube’de sürdürüyor.","answer":"Bu metin 2003 Dünya Kupası ile ilgilidir."},{"question":"Forneça 2 alternativas ao Google como motor de busca.","answer":"Dois motores de busca que podem ser usados como alternativa ao Google Search são: Bing, desenvolvido pela Microsoft, e o DuckDuckGo. O segundo enfatiza a privacidade e não registra as informações do usuário"},{"question":"Òjò Nrọ̀ Si Kòtò, Gegele Mbinú – The Rain Is Filling Up The Gully To The Annoyance Of The Hill","answer":"As many are happy, so are many sad during the raining season.  Yoruba has various songs to depict, requesting for rain, or when the rain has just begun, or when the rain is affecting outdoor activities particularly for children or when the rain is too much.  Listen to some of the songs for the rain that Primary School children often sing."},{"question":"LoL kime satıldı?","answer":"19 Temmuz 2012'de Riot Games, League of Legends'ın Brezilya sunucularının kapalı beta testlerine başladı ve oyunu ilk günkü gelişim ivmesiyle büyütmeye devam ediyorlar. Aralık 2015 itibarıyla şirketin tamamı Çinli Tencent Holding'e aittir."},{"question":"தாழ்பூந்துறை- என்ற சொல்லுக்குரில் இலக்கண குறிப்பு தருக(1) ஏவல் வினைமுற்று                              (2) உரிச்சொல் தொடர்(3) பண்புத்தொகை                                  (4) வினைத்தொகை","answer":" (4) வினைத்தொகை"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أكبر صحراء غير قطبية في العالم؟","answer":"الإجابة: الصحراء الكبرى"},{"question":"قم بتحويل هذه الجملة إلى الصيغة النشطة: \\"تم تحليل البيانات من قبل الفريق\\" ","answer":"الجواب: \\"قام الفريق بتحليل البيانات\\". "},{"question":"வினா: நம் உடலில் பித்த நீரைச் சுரக்கும் சுரப்பி எது?","answer":"விடை :கல்லீரல்"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fanalalahana eo amin'ny sehatrin'ny asa?","answer":"Fialan’ny fanjakana amin’ireo orin’asa notantaniny no atao hoe fanalalahana.Amidy amin’ny olon-tsotra izay manam-bola ka afaka hitantana azy ny orin’asa, izany hoe, alain’ny fanjakana ny volany niasa tao ka izay tian’ilay olona nividy azy hitantanany ny orinasa no ataony, ka tsy afa-mitsabaka eo intsony ny fanjakana fa manara-maso fotsiny sisa azony atao."},{"question":"Wọn ju Ṣeun sẹwọn gbere l’Ekiti, ọmọleewe mẹta lo ji gbe","answer":"Adajọ ti ni ki wọn sọ Kayọde Ṣeun, ẹni ọdun mejidinlọgbọn to ji awọn ọmọleewe girama mẹta gbe l’Ekiti, sẹwọn gbere.Ile-ẹjọ giga kan niluu Ado Ekiti, lọkunrin yii ti gba idajọ ọhun. Ewọn gbere ni wọn sọ ọ si.Olupẹjọ ijọba, Wale Fapohunda, sọ pe awọn mẹta ni wọn jọ huwa buruku naa, ṣugbọn awọn meji ti salọ, ati pe ọjọ keji oṣu karun-un, ọdun 2018, gan-an ni wọn huwa ọhun niluu Ayetoro-Ekiti, nijọba ibilẹ Ido/Osi.Ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ọhun sọ pe lasiko ti awọn wa ni isinmi ranpẹ ninu ọgba ileewe awọn lawọn ọkunrin mẹta ọhun kọlu awọn, ti wọn si fi aṣo di awọn lẹnu ki awọn eeyan too waa gba awọn silẹ.Lẹyin ti Adajọ Abiọdun Adesọdun ti gbọ ọrọ lẹnu awọn agbẹjọro mejeeji, lo sọ pe pẹlu gbogbo ẹri to wa niwaju oun, loootọ ni awọn eeyan ọhun ji awọn ọmọleewe girama naa gbe."},{"question":"اشرح الفرق بين الانحدار غير الخطي والانحدار الخطي.","answer":"يشير الانحدار - في علم الإحصاء وعلم الرياضيات - إلى العلاقة بين متغير مستقل ومتغير تابع. يمكن توضيح الفرق بين الانحدار الخطي والانحدار غير الخطي كما يلي: 1. الانحدار الخطي: الانحدار الخطي هو عندما تكون العلاقة بين المتغيرات بسيطة وثابتة. يعني ذلك أنه كلما زاد أو نقص أحد المتغيرين ، زاد أو نقص المتغير الآخر بنفس النسبة. مثلا ، إذا كانت المتغيرات هي الوزن والطول ، فإن الانحدار الخطي سيحدث إذا كان كل متر إضافي في الطول يزيد الوزن بكيلوغرام واحد.2. الانحدار الغير خطي:الانحدار الغير خطي هو عندما تكون العلاقة بين المتغيرات معقدة ولا تتبع قاعدة بسيطة. في هذه الحالة ، لا يمكن تمثيل العلاقة بخط مستقيم أو معادلة خطية. بل يكون للعلاقة شكل منحني أو متغير أو غير منتظم. وهذا يعني أن تغيير صغير في أحد المتغيرات قد يسبب تغيير كبير أو صغير أو لا شيء في المتغير الآخر. ومن الأمثلة على الانحدار الغير خطي هو الانحدار اللوجستي ، الذي يصف كيفية نمو السكان أو انتشار الأمراض أو غيرها من الظواهر التي تتأثر بالعوامل المحددة."},{"question":"أعطني سؤال وجواب له عن الموسيقى.","answer":"سؤال: متى تم تأسيس فرقة أيروسميث؟ الإجابة: 1970"},{"question":"Berikan saya resipi untuk sup spaghetti, dengan langkah-langkah yang lengkap. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 1 peket spageti, 1 peket bebola ayam (yang ada sayur), 1 sup bunjut, 1 batang carrot, sawi, 4 ulas bawang putih, 1 biji bawang besarBahan-bahan sos kicap: Kicap manis cap kipas udang, sos cili, cili padi cincang, kicap sotong, serbuk asam limau, gula, garam Bahan-bahan sampingan lain: Sambal cili dan daun supCara-cara:1. Didihkan air. Kemudian letak sedikit minyak dan masukkan spageti. Rebus sehingga lembut.2. Bila spageti dah lembut, toskan. Ambil sedikit air rebusan spageti tadi.3. Tumis bawang putih dan bawang besar yang sudah dihiris sehingga naik bau. Kemudian masukkan air rebusan tadi.4. Masukkan juga sup bunjut dan biarkan sehingga mendidih. Kemudian masukkan sayur dan bebola ayam.5. Letakkan garam dan perasa secukupnya.6. Untuk  sos kicap, satukan semua bahan dan kacau sebati. 7. Sedia untuk dihidangkan. Selamat mencuba!"},{"question":"Na mitologia Romana quem é Diana?","answer":"Deusa da Lua, da caça, da castidade."},{"question":"Tarawa mooy péeyu ban réew ?","answer":"Tarawa mooy péeyu réewum Kiribati"},{"question":"英語で、「おととい」のことは「the day before yesterday」といいますが、「あさって」のことは何というでしょう？","answer":"the day after (tomorrow)"},{"question":"ਪੰਜਾਬ: ਮਾਨਸਾ ਦੀ ਡਿੰਪਲ ਤੇ ਬਠਿੰਡਾ ਦੀ ਮਨੀਸ਼ਾ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਹਾਣੀ, ਕਿਵੇਂ ਘਰਦਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾਮੰਦੀ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਵਿਆਹ।","answer":"27 ਸਾਲਾ ਡਿੰਪਲ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ 21 ਸਾਲਾ ਪ੍ਰੇਮਿਕਾ ਮਨੀਸ਼ਾ ਨੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਰੁਕਾਵਟਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤੋੜਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਡਿੰਪਲ ਤੇ ਮਨੀਸ਼ਾ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਇਸ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਹਿਮਤੀ ਇਸ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਲੱਖਣ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ’ਤੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਇਸ ਦਾ ਵਿਰੋਧ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ।ਡਿੰਪਲ ਮਾਨਸਾ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਦੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮਨੀਸ਼ਾ ਬਠਿੰਡਾ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਦੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ।ਡਿੰਪਲ ਅਤੇ ਮਨੀਸ਼ਾ ਨੇ 18 ਸਤੰਬਰ, 2023 ਨੂੰ ਬਠਿੰਡਾ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ   ਗੁਰਦੁਆਰੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੱਖ ਧਰਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਰਹੁ-ਰੀਤਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ। ਡਿੰਪਲ ਨੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਮਰਦ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਰੁਕਾਵਟ ਨੂੰ ਤੋੜਦਿਆਂ, ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਕੁੜੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਅੰਤਰ ਧਰਮ ਤੇ ਅੰਤਰ- ਜਾਤੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਹੈ।ਡਿੰਪਲ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਉੱਚ-ਜਾਤੀ ਜੱਟ ਸਿੱਖ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਹੈ, ਜਦਕਿ ਮਨੀਸ਼ਾ ਇੱਕ ਦਲਿਤ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਡਿੰਪਲ ਇਸ ਗੱਲ 'ਤੇ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਜਾਤ ਅਤੇ ਧਰਮ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਹੁਣ ਇਸ ਵਿਆਹ ’ਤੇ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਖੜ੍ਹਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਅਕਾਲ ਤਖ਼ਤ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਨੇ ਦੋ ਕੁੜੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਗ੍ਰੰਥੀ, ਰਾਗੀ ਜਥੇ ਤੇ ਗੁਰਦੁਆਰਾ ਕਮੇਟੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਕੰਮਕਾਜ ਲਈ ਪੂਰਨ ਰੋਕ ਲਗਾ ਦਿਤੀ ਹੈ।ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ। "},{"question":"\\" ટીડા જોશી \\" બાળવાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક હતો જોશી. એનું નામ ટીડા જોશી.એને જોશ જોતાં ન આવડે પણ ખોટો ખોટો દેખાવ કરી પૈસા કમાઈ લે.એક દિવસ ટીડા જોશી એક ગામથી બીજે ગામ જવા નીકળ્યા. રસ્તામાં બે ધોળા બળદને એક ખેતરમાં ચરતાં દીઠા. આ વાત એને યાદ રહી ગઈ.જોશીજી તો ગામમાં ગયા અને એક પટેલને ત્યાં ઉતારો કર્યો. ત્યાં એક કણબી-કણબણ આવ્યાં ને જોશીને કહે - જોશી મહારાજ! અમારા બે ધોળા બળદ ખોવાયા છે. તે કઈ દિશામાં ગયા હશે તેનું જોશ ઝટ ઝટ જોઈ આપો ને?જોશીએ તો હોઠ ફફડાવી એક જૂના સડી ગયેલા ટીપણામાં જોઈને કહ્યું - પટેલ! તમારા બળદ આથમણી સીમમાં ફલાણા ખેતરમાં છે, ત્યાંથી લઈ આવો. પટેલ તો બતાવેલા ખેતરે ગયો એટલે તેને બળદ મળી ગયા. તે ઘણો રાજી થયો અને તેણે ટીડા જોશીને સારી ભેટ ધરી ખુશ કર્યા.બીજે દિવસે રાત્રે ટીડા જોશીની પરીક્ષા કરવા ઘરધણીએ પૂછ્યું - મહારાજ! તમારું જોશ સાચું હોય તો કહો, આજે ઘરમાં કેટલા રોટલા થયા છે?બન્યું એવું કે ટીડા જોશીને કંઈ કામ ન હતું અને ઘરમાં નવરાધૂપ બેઠા હતા એટલે રોટલાના તાવડીમાં નાખતી વખતે થયેલા ટપાકા ગણતા હતા! જોશીએ તો એમ જ નવરા બેઠાં ટપાકા ઉપરથી ગણી રાખેલું હતું કે કુલ તેર રોટલા થયેલા છે. સવાલ સાંભળી તેમણે જોશ જોવાનો ડોળ કરી કહ્યું - પટેલ આજે તમારા ઘરમાં તેર રોટલા થયા હતા.પટેલે પટલાણીને પૂછી જોયું તો જોશીની વાત સાવ સાચી નીકળી. પટેલને તો બહુ નવાઈ લાગી.આ બે બનાવથી જોશી મહારાજની કીર્તિ આખા ગામમાં ફેલાઈ, ને સૌ જોશી મહારાજ પાસે જોશ જોવરાવવા આવવા લાગ્યા. એટલામાં ત્યાંના રાજાની રાણીનો નવલખો હાર ખોવાયો. રાજાએ જોશીની કીર્તિ સાંભળી હતી, એટલે તેણે તેને તેડાવ્યો.રાજાએ જોશીને કહ્યું - જુઓ, ટીડા મહારાજ! રાણીનો હાર ક્યાં છે અથવા તો કોણ લઈ ગયું છે તે જોશ જોઈને કહો. હાર જડશે તો તમને ઘણા રાજી કરીશું.જોશી મૂંઝાયા. જરા વિચારમાં પડ્યા. રાજાએ કહ્યું - આજની રાત તમે અહીં રહો, ને રાત આખી વિચાર કરીને સવારે કહેજો. પણ જોજો, જોશ ખોટું પડશે તો ઘાણીએ ઘાલીને તેલ કાઢીશ.ટીડા જોશી તો વાળુ કરીને પથારીમાં પડ્યા પણ ઊંઘ ન આવે. જોશીના મનમાં ભય હતો કે નક્કી સવારે રાજા ઘાણીએ ઘાલીને મારું તેલ કાઢશે. નીંદર નહોતી આવતી એટલે તે નીંદરને બોલાવવા લાગ્યા - નીંદરડી! આવ; નીંદરડી! આવ.હવે વાત એમ હતી કે રાજાની રાણી પાસે નીંદરડી નામની દાસી રહેતી હતી ને તેણે જ હાર ચોર્યો હતો. ટીડા જોશીને નીંદરડી! આવ; નીંદરડી! આવ, એવું બોલતાં એણે સાંભળ્યા એટલે તે એકદમ ગભરાઈ ગઈ. એને લાગ્યું કે ટીડા જોશી મારું નામ પોતાના જોશના બળે જાણી ગયા લાગે છે.નીંદરડીએ બચી જવાનો વિચાર કરી સંતાડેલો હાર બહાર કાઢ્યો અને જોશી પાસે છાનીછપની ગઈ અને બોલી - મહારાજ! લ્યો આ ખોવાયેલો હાર. હારનું ગમે તે કરજો પણ મારું નામ હવે લેશો નહિ.ટીડા જોશી મનમાં ખુશ થયા કે આ ઠીક થયું; નીંદરને બોલાવતાં આ નીંદરડી આવી અને સામેથી હાર આપી ગઈ! ટીડા જોશીએ નીંદરડીને કહ્યું - જો, આ હાર રાણીના ઓરડામાં તેના પલંગ નીચે મૂકી આવ.સવાર પડી એટલે રાજાએ ટીડા જોશીને બોલાવ્યા. ટીડા જોશીએ તો ઢોંગ કરી એક-બે સાચા ખોટા શ્લોક બોલ્યા અને પછી આંગળીના વેઢા ગણી હોઠ ફફડાવી, લાંબું ટીપણું ઉખેડી બોલ્યા - રાજા! રાણીનો હાર ક્યાંય ખોવાયો નથી. તપાસ કરાવો. રાણીના ઓરડામાં જ તેના પલંગની નીચે હાર પડ્યો છે, એમ મારા જોશમાં આવે છે.તપાસ કરાવતાં હાર પલંગ તળેથી જ મળ્યો. રાજા ટીડા પર ખુશ થયો અને તેને સારું ઈનામ આપ્યું.રાજાએ એક વાર ટીડા જોશીની વધારે પરીક્ષા કરવા એક યુક્તિ રચી. ટીડા જોશીને લઈને રાજા એક વાર જંગલમાં ગયો. જોશીની નજર બીજે હતી એટલી વારમાં રાજાએ પોતાની મૂઠીમાં એક ટીડળું પકડી લીધું, ને પછી પોતાની બંધ મૂઠી બતાવી ટીડાને કહ્યું - કહો ટીડાજી! આ મૂઠીમાં શું છે? જોજો, ખોટું પડશે તો માર્યા જશો!ટીડા જોશી હવે પૂરા ગભરાયા. તેમણે વિચાર કર્યો કે હવે ભરમ ઉઘાડો થશે. હવે તો રાજા જરૂર મારશે. બીકમાંને બીકમાં બધી સાચી વાત રાજાને કહી દેવાને રાજાની માફી માગવા માટે બોલ્યા -ટપટપ કરતાં તેર જ ગણ્યાવાટે આવતા ધોરી મળ્યા;નીંદરડીએ આપ્યો હારકાં રાજા ટીડાને માર?ટીડા જોશી જ્યાં, ‘કાં રાજા ટીડાને માર?’ એમ બોલ્યા ત્યાં તો રાજાના મનમાં થયું કે જોશી મહારાજ તો ખરેખરા સાચા જોશી છે. રાજાએ તો પોતાના હાથમાંથી ટીડળું ઉડાડી કહ્યું - વાહ, જોશીજી! તમે તો મારા હાથમાં ટીડળું હતું તે પણ જાણી ગયા!ટીડા જોશી મનમાં સમજી ગયા કે આ તો મરતાં મરતાં બચ્યા ને સાચા જોશી ઠર્યા! પછી રાજાએ જોશીને મોટું ઈનામ આપ્યું અને તેમને વિદાય કર્યા. ટીડા જોશીએ પણ તે દિવસ પછી જોશ જોવાનું બંધ કર્યું અને બીજા કામે વળગી, ખાઈ, પીને મજા કરી."},{"question":"Kor u qaadista jir difaaca Caruuta:","answer":"QAABAB AAD DIFAACA CARUURTA KOR UGU QAADI KARTO Ogow hooyo ama aabo in kor uqaadista difaca ilmaha uu bilawdo kahor inta aney dhalan.✅ Taloyin u muhima waalidiinta Kor uqadida difaaca cunuga waxey bilwta inta uu uurka kujiro waxa muhim ah hooyada uurka leh iney caafimaad keeda kor uqado Qaababka aad kor ugu qaadi krto difaaca cunigada waxa kamida:-1= Daryeelida cafimadka hoyda uurka leh Hooyo hadad uurey thy sidaan sameey 🚩  Uurey cun cunto caafimaad leh  sida qudaarta, miraha, si eey u xojiyan difacda iyo difaca ilmahada. 🚩 Saneey jimicsiga fudud ee lagu oglyhy intaad uurka sido 🚩 Iska yareey walwalka sido kale seexo hurdo kugu filan 2= Naas nuujin dabiici ah ( naaska kalya) Caanaha ugu horeya ee naaska hooyada markey dhasho ee dambarta waa muhim dhalanka yar waxey siiyan difac waxey xojiyan difacisa aygo jirkisa kailaliya ineey soweraran infection nada bisha kowaad Intaas waxsii dheer faidoyinka badan ee ilmahu kahelo naaska kligiis inlodayo.....3= Waqti badan kuhay guriga nuunaha 6 bilood ee ugu horeysa nuunaha wainad kuhysi guriga bananka ha ubixin wuxuu halis ugu jiraa ilma aragtada iyo cudurada nuunaha yar wali difacisa maxogeysan marka bananka kadaa 4= Kangaroo care Waxaa jira qaab daryeeleed looyaqaan Kangaroo care kaas oo micnihiisa yahay inu maqaarka ilmaha yar taabto maqarka hoyada ama aabaha walba malmaha hore ee uu dhasho wxu kahelayaa unaso gudbinyn noola yaal nacfi uleh dhalaanka yar xojiyana difaacisa. Waliba cunuga markuy horay kadhasho wain hoyada laabteda lagu jifyo.5= Nadafada caruurta 80% taabasho ayey kugudban infection nada mrka caruurtada bar ineey sabuun iyo biyo kudhaqan gacmahoda 6= Seexi hurdo kufilan caruurtada Hurdada caafimad ka leh waxay kor uqda difaca ilmaha walba sixogan Ilmaha anan helin hurdo kufilan jirkooda somadayo ( cytokines) kaas oo ladagala ilma aragtda yareyana."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : పక్షులలో చలనాన్ని మీరు ఎలా ప్రశంసిస్తారు?","answer":"పక్షుల ఎగిరే లక్షణం గురించి నేను ఆశ్చర్యపోతాను.వాటికి అద్భుతమైన రెక్కలు మరియు ఆకర్షణీయమైన ఈకలు ఉన్నాయి. వాటి శరీరం పడవ ఆకారంలో ఉంటుంది. ఎముకలు’ తేలికగా, బోలుగా ఉంటాయి. వాటి శరీరం గాలిలో ఎగరడానికి వీలుగా మార్పు చెంది ఉంటుంది.ఈ ఎగిరే లక్షణం వలన దూరపు ప్రాంతాలు వెళ్ళడానికి పక్షులకు సాధ్యమౌతుంది. నాకు ఎగరడానికి రెక్కలు ఉంటే బాగా ఉంటుందని అనిపిస్తుంది"},{"question":"\\"දිලිසෙන සියල්ල රත්තරන් නොවේ\\"","answer":"විලියම් ෂේක්ස්පියර්"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය ගයනා   කළේ  කවුද?වසන්තේ නිදා උන් යොවුන් කෝකිලාවන්ගයන්නේ සුපෙම් ගීත හේමන්තයේවසන්තේ ලපල්ලෙන් වැසි උන් කුසුම් කැන්නටන්නේ පිපි දැන් හේමන්තයේවිලාපෙන් විඩා වී රැදී මං තලාවේවැසි අන්ධකාරෙන් වැටි මං මුලාවේවලාවක් ලෙසින් මා ඇදෙද්දී අයාලේඔබෙන් නෙත් ලැබුවේ හේමන්ත කාලේසුසුම් ලා දිවා රෑ වෙලී හුදෙකලාවේඑපා වී සියල්ලන් පලා ආ වෙලාවේතුෂාරෙන් උදා වූ සඳක් සේ නිශාවේඔබයි නෙත් සැදුයේ හේමන්තකාලේ....","answer":"නන්දා  මාලිනි "},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هو الممثل اللي احتل المرتبة اللولى فمسلسل باتمان التلفزيوني فالستينيات؟","answer":"الإجابة: آدم ويست"},{"question":"સૌરમંડળ એટલે શું તેના વિશે વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"સૌરમંડળ એ સૂર્યની ગુરુત્વાકર્ષક રીતે બંધાયેલ સિસ્ટમ છે અને તે ભ્રમણકક્ષાની .બ્જેક્ટ્સ છે.સૌથી મોટી આઠ ઓબજેક્ટ્સ બ્જેક્ટ્સ, જે ગ્રહોની સિસ્ટમ બનાવે છે, તે સૂર્યથી અંતરની ક્રમમાં છે: ચાર પાર્થિવ ગ્રહો, બુધ, શુક્ર, પૃથ્વી અને મંગળ;અને ચાર વિશાળ ગ્રહો જેમાં બે ગેસ જાયન્ટ્સ, ગુરુ અને શનિ અને બે આઇસ જાયન્ટ્સ, યુરેનસ અને નેપ્ચ્યુન શામેલ છે.પાર્થિવ ગ્રહો, જે બધાની ચોક્કસ સપાટી હોય છે, તે મોટે ભાગે ખડક અને ધાતુથી બનેલા હોય છે.ગેસ જાયન્ટ્સ મોટે ભાગે હાઇડ્રોજન અને હિલીયમથી બનેલા હોય છે, જ્યારે બરફ જાયન્ટ્સ મોટે ભાગે પાણી, એમોનિયા અને મિથેન જેવા અસ્થિર પદાર્થોથી બનેલા હોય છે.પાર્થિવ ગ્રહોને આંતરિક સૌરમંડળ અને વિશાળ ગ્રહો બાહ્ય સૌરમંડળ પણ કહેવામાં આવે છે.એક વિશાળ આંતરરાષ્ટ્રીય મોલેક્યુલર વાદળના ગુરુત્વાકર્ષણ પતનથી 6.6 અબજ વર્ષ પહેલાં સૌરમંડળની રચના કરવામાં આવી હતી.સમય જતાં, વાદળ સૂર્ય અને પ્રોટોપ્લેનેટરી ડિસ્કની રચના કરે છે જે ધીરે ધીરે ગ્રહો અને અન્ય પદાર્થોની રચના માટે એકીકૃત થઈ હતી.આ જ કારણ છે કે બધા આઠ ગ્રહોની ભ્રમણકક્ષા હોય છે જે એક જ વિમાનની નજીક આવેલી છે.હાલના સમયમાં, સૌરમંડળના 99.86% સમૂહ સૂર્યમાં છે અને બાકીના મોટા ભાગના સમૂહ ગ્રહ ગુરુમાં સમાયેલ છે.છ ગ્રહો અને અન્ય ઘણા શરીરમાં કુદરતી ઉપગ્રહો અથવા ચંદ્ર હોય છે જે તેમની આસપાસ ફરતા હોય છે.બધા વિશાળ ગ્રહો અને થોડા નાના શરીર ગ્રહો, ધૂળ અને કેટલીકવાર મૂનલેટ્સથી બનેલા ગ્રહોની રિંગ્સ દ્વારા ઘેરાયેલા હોય છે.\\""},{"question":"औपनिवेशिक काल के दौरान भारत की कृषि स्थिरता के मुख्य कारण क्या थे?","answer":"औपनिवेशिक काल के दौरान भारतीय कृषि के ठहराव के कारण इस प्रकार हैं:1. अंग्रेजों ने 1793 में भू-राजस्व प्रणाली शुरू की। इस प्रणाली के अनुसार, जमींदारों (जमींदारों) को ब्रिटिश सरकार को बड़ी मात्रा में राजस्व देना पड़ता था और राजस्व संग्रह का स्रोत किसान थे। जमींदारों ने भूमि उत्पादकता में सुधार पर ध्यान केंद्रित नहीं किया, जिसके परिणामस्वरूप कृषि विकास कम हुआ और बाद में किसानों का जीवन बदतर हो गया।2. भारतीय किसान उपभोग के लिए चावल और गेहूं जैसी खाद्य फसलें उगाते थे। ब्रिटिश सरकार भारतीय किसानों को ब्रिटिश उद्योगों के लिए नील जैसी व्यावसायिक फसलें उगाने के लिए मजबूर कर रही थी, जिसके कारण कृषि व्यवसायिक हो गई और खाद्यान्न की कमी हो गई।3. सिंचाई सुविधाओं की कमी और उर्वरकों की अनुपलब्धता जैसे अन्य महत्वपूर्ण कारकों ने भी कृषि उद्योग को प्रभावित किया और इसे और अधिक कमजोर बना दिया।4. कुछ आधुनिक उद्योगों के नाम बताइए जो स्वतंत्रता के समय हमारे देश में चल रहे थे।स्वतंत्रता से पहले भारत में कुछ उद्योगों का विकास देखा गया, जिनमें से सबसे प्रमुख टाटा आयरन एंड स्टील कंपनी (टिस्को) है। भारत में कपड़ा मिलों और सहायक उत्पादों में भी वृद्धि देखी जा रही थी। महाराष्ट्र, गुजरात और बंगाल ऐसे क्षेत्र थे जहाँ कपास और जूट उद्योग स्थापित किए गए थे। इन उद्योगों के अलावा, कुछ अन्य उद्योग जो चालू हो गए हैं वे हैं चीनी, कागज और सीमेंट।"},{"question":"Ukuxabana kwezinsizwa ngasemakhaya ngoKhisimuzi kwenza ukuba impi ingapheleliemakhaya ngoba uxolo lwalungenzekanga. Ziphindela nje izinsizwa emsebenzini,izinhliziyo zibomvu akukhulunyiswana. Kufihlelwene induku emqubeni. Olunyeuhlangothi lwalwehla lwenyuka luthenga izibhamu zomgunyathi ngoba befunaukuziphindiselela ingcabha ingagcini kubona. Akutshelwana uma kukhonaabazohlasela, ngakho-ke abanye babona ngoba sebembozwa impi. Ngalelo langabehlaselwa, uManyoba wayesebenza ebusuku. Wafika ekuseni sekukhona ababesebefile, sekugcwele ezikadalawane emagcekeni ehostela. Uma ebuza ukuthikwenzenjani, bamtshela ngokwenzekile, washaqeka wacishe wawa phansi uvalolokuthi ngabe naye ungomunye mhlawumbe walaba abafile. Kwake kwaba muncuisikhathi eside kunohlevana kubahlali basehostela. Ngenhlanhla nje kwakungabangwaizwe, kwakungamagqubu nje ezinsizweni. Ezinye zezizathu ezamenza wafunaukushiya umsebenzi eGoli ayosebenza ePitoli. EGoli izinsizwa zokuhamba zazivamiseukuhamba ngambili noma ngantathu ngoba zazikhuthuzwa noma zigetshengweotsotsi. Ngesikhathi sabo kwakukhona amaqembu otsotsi anjengoMsomi namanyeayedume ngokubulala, umuntu atholakale edindilizile esefile emgwaqweni. Isikhaliesikhulu sokubulala kuqala, kwakuwummese noma kube untshumentshu. Into embikakhulu eyayenzeka emadolobheni, ukuthola umuntu enqunywe intamo kungaziwaukuthi ubulawe ubani.1. Lichazani leli gama elibhalwe ngokugqamile kulo musho olandelayo njengobalisetshenzisiwe kulesi siqeshana?Olunye uhlangothi lwalwehla lwenyuka luthenga izibhamu zomgunyathi ...","answer":"Izibhamu ezingekho emthethweni."},{"question":"Makungenziwa iphutha lokucabanga ukuthi ukuzimela kusho ukukhohlwaabazali. Akekho umuntu obaluleke ukwedlula umzali empilweni. Umzali usukeesakhombisa uthando oluyisimangaliso uma ekutshela ukuthi zifunele indawoyakho. Lena enye yezindlela zokubona ukuthi uphumelele yini ekukukhuliseningendlela efanele. Yimuphi umzali ongejabule ukuvakashela ingane yakhekwayo?Asikho isikhathi esiqoshiwe sokuphuma ekhaya. Ngokwama-Afrika umfanauma esekhulile wakhelwa ilawu ekhaya. Lokho kusuke kuyisiqalosokuphemba umuzi. Amantombazane wona ahamba uma eseyogana. Lokhukwakwenzeka ngezikhathi esezadlula. Ucabanga ukuthi kusengenzekanamanje? Kuhle ukuphuma ekhaya usulungisele abazali umuzi. Ikhaya lakiniselibukeka. Lokhu kwenza kunikeza iqholo lokukhomba ikhaya lakiningaphandle kokuzenyeza kanye nokwesaba. Ukuvakasha ekhaya kubalula,kube mnandi futhi nakubazali ukuvakashelwa ingane yabo eyaphuma kahleekhaya. Ukujabula akugcini kubazali kuphela. Izinyanya zakini kanye noMdalibahlale bekubhekile futhi bekulethela izinhlanhla.Kwesinye isikhathi akubi lula ukulungisa ikhaya lakini uma nibaningi. Inganikuba khona ukubhekana emehlweni, niqhubane ngamadolo. Isizathu salokhuukuthi ningaba ngabandawonye impela kodwa indlela enicabanga ngayonenenza ngayo izinto ingafani. Ezinye izingane ukukhuliswa nokunakekelwangabazali zikuthatha njengento okwakufanele bayenze abazali. Ngaleyondlela zona njengezingane azibakweleti lutho abazali bazo. Ezinye zize zenzeimicimbi emikhulu uma seziphuma ekhaya. Lokhu kusuke kuwukubongaukukhuliswa, nokuzicelela izinhlanhla lapho ziya khona. Kuya ngenkoleloyakho-ke ekutheni uzicelela izibusiso kuMdali noma uzicelela kwabakiniukuba bahambe nawe.Kukhona ezinye izizathu zokungaphumi kwezinye izingane emakhaya.Kanjalo nabazali kuyenzeka babe nezizathu zabo zokungafuni ukubaizingane zabo ziphume. Izingane ezikhubazekile nganoma iyiphi indlelazidinga ukunakekelwa. Umzali kuphela osuke eyazi kahle ingane yakhe. 1. Ngokucabanga kwakho yiziphi ezinye izizathu ezingekhoesiqeshini ezenza ukuthi izingane eziningi zikubona kunzimaukuphuma emakhaya nakuba sezikhulile? Nikeza kube KUBILI. ","answer":"Azifuni ukusebenzisa imali yazo.Zibheke amafa asemakubo. "},{"question":"Meslek Lisesi 12 sınıf staj kaç ay?","answer":"İşletmelerde mesleki eğitim dersini okulda yapan Anadolu meslek programı öğrencileri ile Anadolu teknik programı öğrencilerinin Millî Eğitim Bakanlığı Ortaöğretim Kurumları Yönetmeliğine göre mezun olabilmeleri için 40 iş günü staj çalışması yapmaları gerekmektedir."},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana ireto:\\"Mpilalao basikety mahay izy\\" sy \\"Mahavariana ny fahaizany basikety.\\" mitovy ve ny resahan'ireo?","answer":"Eny, samy miresaka momba ny fahaizany milalao basikety."},{"question":"السؤال: شنا هو نظام التشغيل؟","answer":"الإجابة: نظام التشغيل هو واحد البرنامج كايكون عبارة عن واجهة بين المستخدم النهائي واجهزة ديال الكمبيوتر. كل جهاز ديال الكمبيوتر فيه على الأقل نظام تشغيل واحد باش يخدم البرامج الاخرى."},{"question":"Ọjọgbọn Fọlaṣade Ogunṣọla di obinrin akọkọ ti yoo di Adele ọga agba Fasiti Eko","answer":"Ọjọgbọn Fọlaṣade Tolulọpẹ Ogunṣọla ti jawe olubori ninu ibo ti igbimọ alakooso Fasiti Eko, UNILAG, di lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii lati yan ẹni ti yoo jẹ adele ọga agba (Acting Vice-Chacellor) ileewe naa, wọn si ti bura fun un lẹyẹ-o-sọka.Igba akọkọ ree ti obinrin yoo di ipo ọga agba UNILAG mu.Nibi ipade pataki kan to waye lọjọ ọhun nibaamu pẹlu aṣẹ ti Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari pa ninu lẹta kan to kọ si igbimọ naa lori fa-a-ka-ja-a ti iyansipo adele ọga agba Ọjọgbọn Ṣoyọmbọ mu dani lo fa igbesẹ tuntun ti wọn fi yan akọni obinrin yii.Gẹgẹ bi ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, awọn igbimọ alaakoso yunifasiti naa ti wọn n pe ni Senate ni wọn pepade, ti awọn Purofẹsọ mẹtadinlaaadọsan-an si pesẹ sibi ipade naa. Lẹyin ijiroro, wọn dabaa ẹni meji lara wọn fun aaye to ṣi ṣilẹ ọhun, Abilekọ Fọlasade Ogunṣọla ati Ọjọgbọn Ben Ogbolafor.Eyi lo mu ki wọn dibo, ti Abilekọ Ọgunṣọla si ni ibo marundinlaaadoje, nigba ti ẹni keji rẹ ni ibo mọkanlelọgbọn pere. Alaga igbimọ alakooso naa, Ọjọgbọn Chioma Agomo, lo kede esi ibo, o si fidi ẹ mulẹ pe Abilekọ Ogunṣọla lo yege.Ṣaaju iyansipo rẹ yii, Ogunsọla ni igbakeji ọga agba (Deputy Vice-Chancellor) ni ẹka iṣẹ idagbasoke fasiti ọhun, lati ọdun 2017 lo si ti wa nipo naa.Ọdun 1958 ni wọn bi adele ọga agba tuntun yii, ọjọgbọn ninu ẹkọ nipa ilana iṣegun awọn kokoro aifoju ri (Professor of Medical Microbiology), oun ni obinrin akọkọ ti yoo wa nipo ọga agba kọlẹẹji ẹkọ nipa iṣegun fasiti ọhun  (University College of Medicine), Idi-Araba, l’Ekoo. Ọpọ iwadii imọ ijinlẹ lori didena awọn arun aṣekupani bii HIV, AIDS ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ lo ti ṣe.Ṣaaju ni gbọnmi-si-i omi-o-to ti waye lori iyọkuro ati iyansipo ọga agba fasiti ọhun, lẹyii to mu ki Aarẹ Buhari paṣẹ pe ki Alaga igbimọ apaṣẹ fasiti naa, Ọjọgbọn Wale Babalakin, ṣi yẹba diẹ na. Bakan naa ni wọn ni ki ọga agba ti wọn yọ nipo naa, Ọjọgbọn Oluwatoyin Ogundipẹ, ati ẹni tawọn igbimọ apaṣẹ naa lawọn yan rọpo, Ọjọgbọn Theophilus Ṣoyọmbọ, ṣi wa ibi kan jokoo si titi ti igbimọ oluwadii ti Aarẹ gbe kalẹ lati tu iṣu desalẹ ikoko ohun to n fa aigbọra-ẹni-ye to waye naa yoo fi jabọ iṣẹ wọn.Ireti wa pe iyansipo yii yoo mu ki omi alaafia fasiti to ti n daru tẹlẹ bẹrẹ si i toro bayii."},{"question":"เหตุการณ์สำคัญจากข้อความต่อไปนี้คืออะไร: เนดเวตเป็นผู้เล่นที่สำคัญคนหนึ่งของทีมชาติเช็กโกสโลวาเกีย เขาเคยพาทีมชาติเข้าชิงชนะเลิศในฟุตบอลชิงแชมป์แห่งชาติยุโรป 1996 และได้รับการแต่งตั้งเป็นกัปตันทีมในการแข่งขันฟุตบอลชิงแชมป์แห่งชาติยุโรป 2004 ที่เช็กโกสโลวาเกียตกรอบรองชนะเลิศด้วยการแพ้กรีซ แต่เนดเวตก็ติดทีมยอดเยี่ยมประจำการแข่งขัน หลังจากนั้น เขาพาทีมชาติผ่านเข้าไปเล่นรอบสุดท้ายของฟุตบอลโลก 2006 นับเป็นครั้งแรกหลังจากที่เชโกสโลวสเกียแยกประเทศ ในการแข่งขัน เนดเวตมีการเล่นที่ว่องไวและปราดเปรียว จนได้รับฉายาว่า \\"\\" (\\"Czech Fury\\") โดยแฟนชาวอิตาลี และฉายา \\"ปืนใหญ่แห่งเช็ก\\" โดยสื่อภาษาอังกฤษ ส่วนฉายาท้องถิ่นคือ \\"Méďa\\" (\\"หมีน้อย\\") เนื่องจากนามสกุลของเขาคล้ายคำว่า \\"Medvěd\\" ที่แปลว่าหมีในภาษาเช็ก","answer":"ฟุตบอลชิงแชมป์แห่งชาติยุโรป 2004"},{"question":"Cite um dos eventos abordados no trecho a seguir: A cantora e compositora americana Taylor Swift recebeu muitos prêmios e indicações por seu trabalho musical. Swift assinou com a gravadora Big Machine Records em 2005 e lançou seu álbum de estreia auto-intitulado em 2006, que foi nomeado para um \\"Academy of Country Music Award\\". Na 50ª edição do Grammy Awards, ela foi indicação na categoria Artista Revelação. Seu segundo álbum, \\"Fearless\\" (2008), teve cinco singles, incluindo \\"Love Story\\", \\"White Horse\\" e \\"You Belong with Me\\" que foi vencedora do MTV Video Music Award de Melhor Vídeo Feminino. Swift foi posteriormente indicada para oito categorias na 52ª edição do Grammy Awards, e ganhou quatro deles, incluindo Álbum do Ano. Aos vinte anos, ela se tornou a artista mais jovem recebedora do prêmio, um recorde que manteve por onze anos antes de ser superada por Billie Eilish (18 anos) em 2020. \\"Fearless\\" tornou-se o primeiro álbum a ganhar o \\"American Music Country Award\\", \\"Country Music Association\\", \\"Academy of Country Music Award\\" e o Grammy Award de Álbum do Ano.","answer":"52ª edição do Grammy Awards"},{"question":"Кайсы жылы Лондондогу үйлөрдү номерлөө башталган?","answer":"1764-жылдан тартып гана Лондондо үйлөрдү номерлөө башталды"},{"question":"Mubvunzo: firimu rinonzi Life of the Party rinobuda rini Mhinduro:","answer":"Musi waChivabvu 11, 2018"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'makan tanggung'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud hidup di bawah jagaan orang lain. Contoh ayat: Rasida makan tanggung di rumah ibu saudaranya."},{"question":"Yintoni isitshaba ?","answer":"Isitshaba ngumyobo owenziwe ngeedayimani oye athwalwe entloko ziiKumkani."},{"question":"Tokony hijanona ho mpinamana ve isika aorian’ny fisarahana ?","answer":"Miankina amin’ny sitrapo sy ny fifanarahan'ireo olon-droa nisaraka izany. Indraindray dia ilaina ny fisarahana alohan'ny handinihana ny fisakaizana mba hisorohana izany."},{"question":"‘पड़ोस में आग लगने की दुर्घटना की खबर तुरंत दिए जाने पर भी दमकल अधिकारी और पुलिस देर से पहुँचे जिससे आग ने भीषण रूप ले लिया। इसके बारे में विवरण सहित एक शिकायती पत्र अपने जिला अधिकारी को लिखिए। ","answer":"परीक्षा भवन,क, ख, ग, आगरा।सेवा में,जिलाधिकारी,अ, ब, सआगरादिनांक 25 मार्च 20XXविषय – दमकल अधिकारी और पुलिस की लापरवाही की शिकायत हेतु पत्र।महोदय,सविनय निवेदन है कि मैं च. छ. ज. क्षेत्र का निवासी इस पत्र के माध्यम से आपको दमकल विभाग और पुलिस की लापरवाही की शिकायत करना चाहता हूँ। कल मेरे पड़ोसी के यहाँ अचानक आग लग गयी, जिस कारण पड़ौसियों का घर पूरी तरह से जल कर स्वाहा हो गया।आग लगने की घटना की जानकारी तुरंत दमकल विभाग को दी गयी परन्तु कई घण्टे तक भी दमकल की कोई गाड़ी नहीं आयी और न ही पुलिस ने आकर घटना की जानकारी ली। इतनी देर में आग की लपटें दूसरे पड़ौसियों के घर तक आकर भी फैल गयी।दमकल विभाग के कर्मचारी समय पर आते तो इतने बड़े नुकसान को बचाया जा सकता था। आपसे अनुरोध है कि दमकल विभाग और पुलिसकर्मियों के प्रति सख्त कार्यवाही करें जो सूचना देने के बाद भी घटनास्थल पर नहीं आए।सधन्यवाद।भवदीयप. फ. ब."},{"question":"Ndipe rondedzero yevashanu vepamusoro vanoteedzerwa vanhu pa instagram.","answer":"\\"1. @cristiano2. @leomessi3. @selenagomez4. @kyliejenner5. @therock\\""},{"question":"Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa Eko ṣekilọ fawọn ọba alaye: Ẹ yee ṣonigbọwọ fawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun","answer":"Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, CP Hakeem Odumosu, ti fi aidunnu rẹ han si bawọn ọba alaye atawọn olori ilu kan ṣe sọ ara wọn di agbodegba fawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun nipinlẹ Eko, o ni iwa to le ta epo s’aṣọ aala awọn ori ade naa ni.Odumosu fẹdun ọkan rẹ han nibi ipade itagbangba lori eto aabo agbegbe Ikorodu fun ọdun 2021, eyi to waye ni gbọngan apero ilu naa l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, yii.Odumosu ni ta a ba wo o lapapọ, eto aabo nipinlẹ Eko ti gbe pẹẹli si i, ṣugbọn ti agbegbe Ikorodu yii lo n fojoojumọ buru si i, tori laarin oṣu mẹfa pere, ojilenirugba ati meji (242) awọn afurasi adigunjale atọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun lọwọ awọn agbofinro tẹ lagbegbe Ikorodu nikan, ibọn mejidinlọgbọn (28) ati katiriiji ọta ibọn ti wọn o ti i yin bii ọgọfa (120) ni wọn ri gba lọwọ wọn.Laarin oṣu mẹfa yii kan naa, igba o din mẹjọ (192) lawọn iṣẹlẹ idaluru latọwọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun to waye, mejidinlogun (18) ninu awọn iṣẹlẹ yii lo la itajẹsilẹ lọ, igba mẹẹẹdọgbọn (25) si lawọn ọlọpaa tu iṣẹlẹ idigunjale fo.Lati wa ojuutu si iṣoro yii, afi ki ijọba ibilẹ, awọn olori ilu, awọn ọba alaye atawọn baalẹ jọ fọwọsowọpọ lori ọrọ yii. O lo yẹ kawọn ori ade fi tinutinu dẹbi fun awọn ọmọ to n ṣẹgbẹ okunkun, dipo ti wọn aa fi maa ṣe koriya fun wọn, ti wọn aa maa bẹru wọn, tabi ki wọn fa wọn bọdi nigba mi-in, tabi ki wọn maa fi oye da wọn lọla.“Awọn oniṣẹṣe atawọn oloogun ibilẹ gbọdọ jawọ ninu ṣiṣe oogun abẹnugọngọ fawọn ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun, akoba nla ni aṣa naa n mu wa fun iṣẹ aabo ilu tawọn ọlọpaa n ṣe. Ọpọ igba lawọn ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun atawọn afurasi adigunjale n gboju le oriṣiiriṣii oogun abẹnugọngọ bii igbadi, ifunpa, onde, tira ti wọn so kọra lati ṣiṣẹ ibi wọn.“Ẹyin lanlọọdu ati lanledi, o yẹ kẹ ẹ ṣewadii gidi tawọn ọmọkọmọ wọnyi ba fẹẹ gba ile lọwọ yin. Ko yẹ kẹ ẹ da gbogbo ẹ da kiateka nikan. To ba si jẹ lẹyin ti wọn ti gba ile tan lẹ too fura, ki lo de tẹ o ki i jẹ kawọn agbofinro gbọ, ka si ran yin lọwọ nitori ibẹru?Ni ti awọn aṣaaju ẹsin, dipo ki iwaasu wọn da lori bawọn eeyan ṣe gbọdọ di olowo ati ọlọrọ, niṣe lo yẹ ki wọn kọ wọn lati jẹ eeyan alaafia, ki wọn si maa ṣi wọn leti nipa ibaṣepọ ati igbesi aye alaafia ati aabo.”Odumosu ni ko sẹni to mọ awọn agbegbe naa to awọn ọba alaye atawọn baalẹ adugbo, ati pe bi ina ko ba ni awo, ko le jo goke odo, bii owe Yoruba ṣe sọ.Lara awọn eeyan pataki to wa nikalẹ lọjọ naa ni Ayangburẹn tilu Ikorodu, Ọba Kabiru Shotobi, Adeboruwa ti ilu Igbogbo, Ọba Sẹmiudeen Kasali, Alaga ijọba ibilẹ Ikorodu, Ọnarebu Wasiu Adeṣina, atawọn ọba alaye mi-in."},{"question":"Wanene ya ƙirƙiri anime?","answer":"Wanda ya ƙirƙira shine Osamu Tezuka."},{"question":"Lẹyin ti adajọ sun igbẹjọ si ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, wọn ti da Sunday Igboho pada satimọle","answer":"Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu yii ni ireti wa pe wọn yoo da ẹjọ ajijagbara ọmọ Yoruba nni, Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho.Ni nnkan bii aago mẹrin kọja ni wọn gbe ajijagbara naa wọ kootu ile-ẹjọ kan ti wọn n pe ni Cour De’appal De Cotonou to wa ni orileede Benin.Lasiko igbẹjọ naa ni awọn agbẹjọro Oloye Adeyẹmọ ati ti ilẹ Benin ṣe alaye loriṣiiriṣii. ALAROYE gbọ pe ẹsun ti wọn n tori rẹ ba Igboho ṣẹjọ ni i ṣe pẹlu iwe irinna to fi wọ orileede naa, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ko si ẹnikẹni ninu igun mejeeji awọn agbẹjọro yii to ba oniroyin sọrọ lori ohun to ṣẹlẹ nile-ẹjọ.Ireti wa pe wọn yoo fi ori ẹjọ naa ti sibi kan ni ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, opin ọsẹ yii, ti i ṣe ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọkan ninu awọn agbẹjọro agba ti wọn fẹẹ lo fun ẹjọ naa lati ṣatilẹyin fun Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, Dokita Maliki Falọla, yoo balẹ si orileede Olominira Benin laaarọ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, yii lati orileede France to n gbe..ALAROYE gbọ pe ki ohun gbogbo le lọ bi wọn ṣe fẹ ni wọn fi gba agbẹjọro agba naa, ẹni ti wọn bi ni orileede Benin, ṣugbọn to jẹ ọmọ Yoruba. Ọkunrin yii la gbọ pe o wa ninu awọn ti wọn kọ iwe ofin ti orileede Benin n lo, o si jẹ gbajugbaja agbẹjọro ni orileede naa.Ẹni to yọ ọrọ naa sọ fun ALAROYE sọ pe oun ni yoo dari awọn agbẹjọro ti yoo tun pade ni kootu Benin lọjọ Ẹti yii lati ṣatilẹyin fun Igboho.ALAROYE gbọ pe wọn ti da Igboho pada si atimọle titi ọla ti igbẹjọ naa yoo tun waye."},{"question":"جسمانی درجہ حرارت کم کرنے کے کیا چیزیں اہم ہیں؟","answer":"1۔ ناریل کا پانییہ ایک قدرتی الیکٹرو لائٹ ڈرنک ہے جو پوٹاشیم سے بھی بھرپور ہے۔ یہ جسم کی نمی کو برقرار رکھنے اور جسم کے درجہ حرارت کو منظم کرنے میں مدد کرتا ہے۔2. پودینہاسے چٹنی یا مشروبات میں استعمال کیا جا سکتا ہے اور اس میں ٹھنڈک کی خصوصیات ہیں جو شدید گرمی کے دوران جسم کے درجہ حرارت کو ٹھنڈا کرتی ہیں۔3. تربوزاس میں تقریباً 92 فیصد پانی ہوتا ہے اور یہ اینٹی آکسیڈنٹس سے بھی بھرپور ہوتا ہے جو جسم کو ہائیڈریٹ کرنے اور ٹھنڈک کا اثر فراہم کرنے میں مدد کرتا ہے۔4. دہیاس میں اینٹی مائیکروبیل اور اینٹی آکسیڈنٹس خصوصیات ہیں ۔ یہ اپنی ٹھنڈک کی خصوصیات کے لیے بھی جانا جاتا ہے جو آنتوں کی صحت کو سکون بخشتی ہے۔5. دودھدودھ آنتوں کی صحت کو برقرار رکھتا ہے اور جسم کے درجہ حرارت کو کم کرتا ہے۔ اس کے علاوہ یہ پروبائیوٹکس سے بھرپور مشروب ہے۔6. کیلایہ غذائی اجزاء کا بھرپور ذریعہ ہے جو فوری توانائی حاصل کرنے میں مدد کرتا ہے۔ اسے ٹھنڈے پھلوں میں بھی شمار کیا جاتا ہے جو جسم کو ٹھنڈا کرنے میں مدد کرتا ہے۔ کیلا کھانے سے ٹشوز سکڑ جاتے ہیں جو زیادہ پانی جذب کرنے میں مدد کرتا ہے۔7. ایوکاڈوایوکاڈو میں مونو سیچوریٹڈ فیٹی ایسڈز کی اعلیٰ سطح موجود ہوتی ہے جو خون سے زہریلے مادوں اور اضافی گرمی کو دور کرنے میں مدد کرتی ہے۔8. پیازپیاز کھانا انسان کو ٹھنڈک کی خصوصیات فراہم کرتا ہے۔ پیاز ہیٹ سٹروک سے تحفظ فراہم کرتا ہے۔ ماہرین کے مطابق سرخ پیاز میں کوئیرسیٹن موجود ہوتا ہے جو قدرتی اینٹی الرجک ہے اور جلد کو الرجی کا شکار ہونے سے بچاتا ہے۔9. ترش پھلترش پھل وٹامن سی سے بھرپور ہوتے ہیں جو چکنائی والی غذاؤں کو توڑنے میں مدد دیتے ہیں۔ یہ ہاضمے میں بھی مدد کرتے ہیں۔ ان میں اینٹی آکسیڈنٹس بھی ہوتے ہیں جو ٹھنڈک کا اثر دیتے ہیں۔10. کھیراکھیرے میں پانی اور فائبر ہوتا ہے۔ اس لیے اس کے پانی کی مقدار جسم کو ہائیڈریٹ رکھتی ہے۔ اس میں موجود فائبر کی مقدار آنتوں کو صحت مند رکھتی ہے۔11. اجوائناجوائن میں پانی کی مقدار تقریباً 95 فیصد ہوتی ہے اور یہ جسم کو ضروری غذائی اجزاء فراہم کرتی ہے۔ یہ انسانی جسم کو گرم دن کے دوران توانائی بخش اور ٹھنڈا رکھنے میں مدد کرتی ہے۔12. ایلو ویراایلو ویرا میں سوزش کی خصوصیات ہوتی ہیں جو گرمی کے دنوں میں جسم کے درجہ حرارت کو کنٹرول کرنے میں مدد کرتی ہیں۔"},{"question":"كم عدد اللترات التي يحتاجها الدماغ البشري من الدماء يوميا لكي يعمل؟","answer":"-(1000 لتر)"},{"question":"Sooyaalka Qorista Farta somaliga.","answer":"Umad waliba waxay leedahay hido iyo dhaqan soo jireen ah, laakin waxa lagu kala hor maro waa xifdinta hidahaas, iyada oo qoran.Sida dastuurkan cusub ku qoran, dowladda  waa in ururisaa, ilaalisaa waxyaabaha taariikhiga ah ee dalka, iyadoo horumarinaysa aqoonta .Hadaba waa sidee Sooyaalka Qoraalka Farta Soomaaliga:1920-kii ayey ahayd markii la soo bilaabay hindisaha qorista rasmiga ah ee afka Soomaaliga, ilaa xilligaasna waxaa lagu taamayey in si rasmi ah loo qoro, Cusmaan Yusuf Keendiid oo ka mid ahaa dadkii xukumayey beelaha Soomaalida qaarkood, fadhigiisuna ahaa magaalada Hobyo ayaa waxa uu soo saaray far lagu magacaabi jirey Cusmaaniya sanadii  1922-kii, fartaasi meelo kooban ayay ka shaqaysay, mana ahayn mid dalka ku wada baahday.1950-1960-kii, waxaa socdey dood ah sidee loo qori lahaa af-Soomaaliga, waxaa jiray loona badan, rag badan ayaa dadaal sameeyay, waxaa lagu muran sanaa Ma Carabi mise  laatiin?Ragga dadaalka sameeyay waxaa ka mid ahaa Ibaahim Xaashi Maxamud iyo Xuseen Sheekh Axmed Kadare, dhamaan raggaasi waxaa ay soo saareen qoraalo farta ah intii u dhaxeysay sanadihii 1950-1961-dii. July 1,  1961-dii, markii dalka xuriyadda qaatay, Waxaa lasoo bandhigay dhowr qoraal waxaa ka mid ahaa farta Shire Jamaac Axmed oo Laatinahayd  iyo faro kale, tanina waxa ay ka dambeysey kadib markii dowladdii xiligaasi jirtey ee madaxweyne Aadan Cabdulle Cusmaan ay saartey guddi kasoo baaran dega qoraalka farta Soomaaliga.Gudiga ayaa waxaa xubno ka ahaa dadka kala ahMuuse Xaaji Ismaaciil Galaal, Guddoomiye,Yaasiin Cusmaan Yuusuf – xubinMaxamuud Saalex (Ladane)- XubinIbraahim Xaashi Maxamuud – xubinKhaliif Suudi- XubinMustaf Sheekh Xasan- xubinShire Jaamac Axmed- XubinXuseen Sheekh Axmed (Kaddare)- XubinYuusuf Maygaag Samatar- XoghaynGuddigaasi hawshooda waxa ay ka socon weysey isqabqabsi dhexdooda ah maadaamaa rag iyaga ka mid ah ay doonayeen in iyaga fartii ay soo jiniseen la qaato sida Muuse Xaaji Ismaaciil Galaal oo isaga soo saaray far ku qoran alifbeetaha Carabiga sanaddii 1951-diiWaxaa kaloo gudiga xubin ka ahaa Xuseen Sheekh Axmed Kadare oo far uu leeyahay soo saaray 1952-dii, waxay gudiga ku taliyeen in farta Laatiinka la qaato, taasi oo uu soo hindisey Shire Jaamac Axmed sanaddii 1961-dii .Si kartaba ha ahaatee, dowladda Soomaaliya ayaa  keensatay khubaro ka socdey UNESCO, si arintan wax uga qabtaan, taasina ma dhicin in laga miro dhaliyo oo weli waa sii socday is qabqabsi.Markii ay soo ifbaxday in Farta Laatin lagu qorayo Soomaliga Waxaa mudaharaadyo ka dhaceen Soomaaliya oo lagaga soo horjeedey in lagu qoro Laatiinka, waxaana dadka laga dhaadhiciyey in ay ka soo hor jeestaan in lagu qoro laatiinka, taas oo masaajidda laga iclaamiyey in shacabku ka soo hor jeestaan waayo, ayey yiraahdeen, “Laatiin waa Laa-diin” oo micnaheedu yahay “Farta Laatiinta waa Diin La’aan” iyada oo loo tiirinayay in farta Laatiinku tahay tan wadamada islaamka aan ahayd ay wax ku qortaan.October 21, 1969: Markii uu dalka la wareegay  Madaxweyne Maxamed Siyaad waxaa uu dib usoo nooleeyay fikradii qoraalka farta Soomaaliga.21 January 1971:  Waxaa la dhisay guddiga Af-Soomaaliga, gudigan waxaa dhisay golaha sare ee kacaanka si ay u sameeyaan xarfaha ugu haboon ee lagu qoraayo Soomaaliga.Guddigan waxaa uu ka koobnaa 21 oo ah xeeldheerayaal Afafka ah  iyo labo lataliye, Xubnaha Guddiga ayaa kala ahaaSharif Salah Mohamed Ali, GudoomiyeYaasin Cismaan KeenadiidMustaf Sheekh XasanAxmed Cali AbokarYuusuf Xirsi AxmedMsuse Xaaji Ismaaciil GalaalCabdidaahir Affey,Aw Jaamac Cumar CiiseDahabo Faarax XasanCabdulaahi Xaaji AbuubakarCabdullaahi ArdeeyeXasan Sheekh MuuminMaxamed Nuur CaalinMaxamed Xasan Aaden (Gaheyr)Xirsi Magan CiiseCumar Aw NuuxCabdullaahi Xaaji Maxamuud (Insaaniya)Iikar Bannaa XadaadAaqib CabdullaahiXuseen Sheekh Axmed KadareAxmed Cartan XaangeMaxamed Xaaji Xuseen Sheeko XariirCabdiraxmaan Nuur XirsiShire JaamacGuddigan waxaa uu lahaa guddi hoosaadyo sida mid qaabilsan qorista  Qaamuuska, kan Taariikhda ,  Juqiraafiga, Sayniska, diyaarinta kutubta dugsiyada iyo naxwaha.Guddiga Afka Soomaaliga ayaa farta Roman-ka ama Laatiinka in lagu qoro Afka Soomaaliga, sababtun waxay ahayd maadaamaa makiinadihii xafiisyada yiiley ee teebka ay ku qornaayeen fartaasi laatiinka,Mudo  22 Bilood gudahood ah ayaa waxaa lagu diyaariyey  Buugaagta Dugsiga dhexe, xarfaha higgaadda Af-Soomaaligu oo ka kooban 5 Shaqal  iyo 21 Shibbane.Si ka duwan sidii 1961-dii, Ma dhicin wax mudaaharaadyo ah ama cadaadis ku yimid guddigan si farihii tartamayey midkood loo sooco, sababtuna waxay ahayd xukunkii adkaa ee dowladdii Maxamed Siyaad Barre.Markii la sameeyey dhamaan waxyaabihii loogu diyaargaroobayay qorista Afka Soomaaliya, ayaa si rasmi ah loo shaaciyey qoraalka farta sanadii 1972-kii.Hawlaha la qabtay waxaa ka mid ah dajinta naxwaha Afka sida  Magac, fal, Fal-kaab, Magac u yaal, Sifo, laakiin sidaasi oo ay tahay wali naxwaha iyo ebyidda afka waa mid qabyo ah, una baahan hawl badan.Waxaa iyana la qorey qaamuus, hase yeeshee markii uu ku dhamaan waayay xiligii loogu talogalay ayaa wasiirkii hidaha iyo tacliinta sare  waxaa uu sii wadistiisa hawsha dhamaystirka qaamuuska u  xilsaaray Cabdiqaadir Farax Bootaan oo ahaa nin ka tirsan  Akaadeemiyada Fanka iyo Dhaqanka , hase yeeshee waxaa si weyn u caan baxay oo fidey Qaamuuskii uu qorey Yaasiin Cusmaan oo lasoo saaray sanadkii 1976-diiQaraar dowladda Soomaaliya kasoo baxay taariikhdu markii ay ahayd Jaanyi 21 1972-di in afka rasmiga ah ee Jamhuuriyadda Soomaaliya uu yahay Afka Soomaaliga ee “Maxaa Tiri”Markii fartii la dhamaystirey, lana diyaariyey dhamaan agabkii loo baahnaa haddii ay buugaag ahaan lahayd iyo haddii naxwe ahaan lahayd, ayaa waxaa loo baahday in dalka iyo dadka lagu baahiyo, waxaana sidaasi ku biloowdey ololihii Farta sanaddii 1972-dii , Ololahaas oo ay Dawladdii Siyaad Barre  markii dambe ku baahisay  dhammaan deegaamada dalka, dadka reer miyiga ah ama reer guuraagu aad ayey wax u barteen.Warbixino ay hay’ado diyaariyeen waxaa lagu sheegay in Ololahan uu kor u qaaday  aqoonta dadka min 2% ilaa 55%.Xiligii ay jirtay dowladdii kacaanka waxaa dugsiga lagu baran jiray farta Soomaaliya dhamaan maadooyinka manhajka ku jirey sida seyniska, xisaabta iyo wax kasta oo kale.Sanaddii 2012-kii waxaa dalka  Djabuti lagu qabtay xaflad lagu xusay 40-sanno guuraddii qoridda far Soomaaliga, Soomaaliya waxaa ay ku jirtaa marxaladii ugu xumeyd ee xaga midnimada, Qowmidda Soomaalida ayaa u midowday xuska maalintaas.Munaasabaddaas waxaa  lagu daah rogey qaamuuska ugu weyn ee af-Soomaali lagu qoro, kaas oo fikirkiisa uu lahaa madaxweynaha Jabuuti Ismaaciil Cumar Geelle, isla markaana ay wada-jir u diyaariyeen machadka Afafka ee Jabuuti iyo Naadiga Qalinlayda iyo Hal’abuurka Soomaaliyeed (Somali-Speaking PEN Club).January 21, 2015: Madaxweynaha Soomaaliya Xasan Sheekh Maxamuud ayaa  isaga oo ka hadlayay xuska 42 guurada kasoo wareegtey markii la qorey farta Soomaaliga  sheegey in laga bilaabo maalintaas ay mabnuuc tahay in far aan ahayn tan Soomaaliga lagu isticmaalo xafiisyada dowladda, haddii aanan markaasi xiriir lala samaynaynin cid dibadda ah.February 21, 2015: Madaxweynayaasha Soomaaliya iyo Djabuti Ismaciil Cumar Geelle ayaa Muqdisho ku dhagax dhigay xarun goboleed lagu hormarinayo luqadda iyo dhaqanka Somaliweyn, Waxaa loo loogu Magac daray Akaadimiyad Goboleedka Farta Soomalaiga, Xasan Sheekh ayaa maalintaas sheegay in arrintaas lagula tartami doono luqadaha caalamka.Amarka Madaxweynaha ee ahaa in xafiisyada dowladda ay ku shaqeeyaan qoraalka Soomaaliga waxba lagama soo qaadin oo wax walbo waa sidii hore xafiisyada dowladda, inta badan warsaxaafaeedka soo gaaro Goobjoog News waxaa u qoran af Ingiriis iyadoo taasi ay jirto ayaa todobaadkan, maalintii axaddii guddoomiyaha gobolka Banaadir waxaa uu soo saaray amar cusub oo sheegaya in boorarka xayeysiinta ee ku dheggan gobolka Banaadir loo bedelo Farta Soomaaliga, lama oga hadalkaas Yusuf Jimcaale uu dibad baxayaasha niyadda ugu dhisayey iyo si dhab ah loo hirgelin doono."},{"question":"Iza amin'ireo vondrona mozika no fantatra amin'ny hira \\"Imagine\\"?a) The Rolling Stoneb) Ny Beatlesc) Queen","answer":"Safidy 2 - \\"Imagine\\" dia mifandray amin'ny The Beatles."},{"question":"වින්ඩ්සර්ෆිං වලදී ටැක් ක්‍රියා කරන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"වින්ඩ්සර්ෆින් ක්‍රීඩාවේ මූලික හැරීම් උපාමාරු දෙකක් ඇත, ටැක් සහ ජිබ්. ටැක් එක උඩු අතට හැරී පුවරුවේ නාසය සුළඟ හරහා ගෙන යයි. ඇල්ලීම ආරම්භ කිරීමට, රුවල් පුවරුවේ පිටුපසට ගෙන යාමෙන් පුවරුව ඉහළට ගෙනයන්න. පුවරු වල නාසය නිවැරදිව සුළඟට යොමු වූ විට, රුවල් ඉදිරිපස වටා අනෙක් පැත්තට යන්න. ඉන්පසුව, පුවරුව පහළට හරවා යැවීමට රිග් එක ඉදිරියට ගෙන යන්න."},{"question":"كيتعتبر ميناء روتردام من اكبر الموانئ فاوروبا فأي بلاد كاين؟","answer":"هولندا"},{"question":"Escribe un poema de Gustavo Adolfo Bécquer.","answer":"Un poema de Bécquer es \\"Rima I: Yo sé un himno gigante y extraño\\".Yo sé un himno gigante y extrañoque anuncia en la noche del alma una aurora,y estas páginas son de ese himnocadencias que el aire dilata en las sombras.Yo quisiera escribirlo, del hombredomando el rebelde, mezquino idioma,con palabras que fuesen a un tiemposuspiros y risas, colores y notas.Pero en vano es luchar; que no hay cifracapaz de encerrarlo, y apenas ¡oh, hermosa!si, teniendo en mis manos las tuyas,pudiera, al oído, contártelo a solas."},{"question":"nguruve mwana wayo anonzii?","answer":"ngurwana"},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள்:  ராணுவ ரீதியில் வெற்றியில் முடிவடைந்தாலும் இந்த போர் நடவடிக்கை நேசநாட்டுத் தளபதிகளுக்குள் நிலவிய உட்பூசலை மேலும் அதிகரித்தது. முன்னரே மோண்ட்கோமரியின் நடத்தை அமெரிக்கத் தளபதிகளுக்கு பிடிக்காதிருந்தது.","answer":"மார்க்கெட் கார்டன் நடவடிக்கையிலும் பல்ஜ் சண்டையிலும் அவர் தன்னிச்சையாக நடந்து கொண்ட விதம் அவர்களைக் கோபப்படுத்தியிருந்தது. அவர் தனது புகழை நிலை நாட்டவும், அமெரிக்கப் படைகளை அவமானப் படுத்தவும் வேண்டுமென்றே சில காரியங்களைச் செய்ததாக அவர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டினர். பிளண்டர் நடவடிக்கையில் தேவையற்ற எச்சரிக்கையுடன் மெல்லச் செயல்பட்டதால், ஜெர்மானியப் பாதுகாப்புப் படைகள் சுதாரித்து தஙகளைத் தயார் செய்து கொள்ள அவகாசம் அளித்து விட்டார் என்று குற்றம் சாட்டினர். வேகமாக முன்னேறியிருந்தால், ஜெர்மானியர்க் ஆயத்தமாவதற்கு இடம் கொடுக்காமல் எளிதில் ரைன் ஆற்றைக் கடந்திருக்கலாம், இழப்புகளும் குறைவாக இருந்திருக்கும் என்பது அவர்களது கருத்து. நேச நாட்டுத் தலைமையகத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட இந்தப் பூசல் போரில் இறுதிவரை தொடர்ந்தது."},{"question":"பாரதியாரின் பன்முக ஆற்றல்கள் யாவை?","answer":"கவிஞர், எழுத்தாளர், இதழாளர், சமூகச் சீர்திருத்தச் சிந்தனையாளர், விடுதலைப் போராட்ட வீரர் எனப் பன்முக ஆற்றல் கொண்டவர் பாரதியார்."},{"question":"வினா : பாகிஸ்தான் நாட்டின் முதலாவது கவர்னர் ஜெனரல் யார்?","answer":"விடை: முகமது ஜின்னா"},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் தேசிய பாடல் எது?","answer":"ஜனவரி 24, 1950 அன்று, இந்திய அரசியலமைப்புச் சபை \\"வந்தே மாதரம்\\" பாடலை தேசிய பாடலாக ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது."},{"question":"அகர முதலியைப் பார்த்துப் பொருள் வேறுபாடு அறிக1. ஒலி\\t2. ஒளி\\t3. பள்ளி\\t4. பல்லி\\t5.காலை\\t6. காளை\\t","answer":"1) சத்தம்2) வெளிச்சம்3) கல்வி கற்கும் இடம்4) ஒரு சிறிய உயிரி5) சூரியன் உதிக்கும் நேரம்6) எருது"},{"question":"Cé hé Giuseppe Verdi? ","answer":"Giuseppe Verdi duine de mhór-chumadóirí Iodálacha an 19ú haois.Scríobh sé ceoldrámaí cáiliúla ar nós Rigoletto, La Traviata agus Il Trovatore, a scríobhadh idir 1850 agus 1853. Bhí sé beo ó 10 Deireadh Fómhair 1813 - 27 Eanáir 1901. "},{"question":"Quốc gia nào ở Đông Nam Á chưa từng là thuộc địa của châu Âu?","answer":"Thái Lan chưa từng là thuộc địa của châu Âu.Trong lịch sử lập quốc, Thái Lan từng là nước lớn, từng nhiều lần lấn át các quốc gia láng giềng. Tới giữa thế kỷ 19, Thái Lan vô tình trở thành vùng đệm địa lý giữa hai thế lực là Anh (đã chiếm Miến Điện - Myanmar ngày nay) và Pháp (đã chiếm ba nước Đông Dương).Vị trí vùng đệm cùng chính sách \\"ngoại giao cây sậy\\" - mềm dẻo, linh hoạt đã giúp Thái Lan là quốc gia Đông Nam Á duy nhất không bị chiếm làm thuộc địa của các nước châu Âu. Tên gọi Thái Lan, nghĩa là vùng đất của sự tự do, cũng thể hiện điều này."},{"question":" Chapter- 4 THUNDERSTORM","answer":"\\"You ain't going anywhere, young lady. You will stay in this house until you put to birth. We will go for a DNA test since you're accusing my husband,\\" Mrs Ikemike said locking the doors.Chika dropped her bag and sat on the floor crying.\\"Why does this woman want to implicate me?\\" she said to herself.\\"Let's go to bed, Diamond. Go to your room, Madam,\\" she said again and went upstairs.Chika rubbed her palms. She felt like stabbing herself. DNA test!! She thought. She stood up and staggered to her room weeping loudly. The next morning, Mr Ikemike left for work but went to meet Chika first.\\"Madam, get up from there and get me a cup of hot coffee,\\" he shouted whilst kicking her.Chika stood up. She sighed and went to the kitchen.\\"If you like, confess. If you like, don't confess. All I know is that you're lying. Only God knows who got you pregnant,\\" he said and stormed out almost stepping on his wife.Mrs Ikemike sighed and waved her hands. Within herself, she knew her husband is impotent. Why will Chika accuse her husband, she hissed and sat on the dinning room floor. \\"She wants my husband to make her his wife or what? My husband is impotent so how did he get her pregnant?We will know the truth after the DNA test. I pray he doesn't find out that those kids ain't his,\\" she sighed and relaxed her head. \\"Chika wants to destroy my marriage. Is she a sent or what?\\" She stood up and went to meet her in the kitchen.\\"Whose coffee is that?\\" She asked taking a seat.\\"Your husband asked me to do make it for him,\\" she replied not looking at her.Mrs Ikemike carried the coffee and sipped a bit then stared at her.\\"Chika, who's really the father of the child in your womb?\\" Mrs Ikemike asked scratching her hair.\\"Your husband is responsible, he got me pregnant,\\" She said harshly.\\"My husband, Chika? I know the reasons for my question, Chika. You will see hell if you don't tell me the truth,\\" she told her.\\"I'm saying the truth, Madam,\\" Chika replied.\\"It's okay. Make another coffee for him.\\""},{"question":"மரத்தின் மேலே தொங்குவது, ஆனால் மலைப் பாம்பல்ல. அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை:  விழுது"},{"question":"කුරවි නාදය කුමක්ද?","answer":"පුරාණ කාලයේ භාරතයේ හිමාල පර්වතය ආශ්‍රිතව කුරවී නම් පක්ෂියෙකු සිටි බවත් ඔහුට ඉතා මිහිරි නාද ඇති බවත් ,,,,බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේගේ හඬ කුරවි නාදය තරමක් සමාන බවත් කියැවේ"},{"question":"Atsakykite į klausimą: Kurias metais Rebeka Gilmor atstovavo Jungtinėms Valstijoms?","answer":"2015 m. ir 2016 m. IIHF pasaulio moterų U18 čempionate, iš viso 19 taškų per 15 rungtynių ir dvigubai aukso ir vieną kartą sidabro. 2015 m. ji baigė turnyrą kaip geriausias kulkas."},{"question":"திருப்பத்தூர் தாலுகா அலுவலகம் எதிரில் பெரியாரின் மார்பளவுச் சிலை ஒன்று உள்ளது. செவ்வாய்க்கிழமையன்று இரவு 9 மணியளிவில் அந்தச் சிலையை இருவர் சுத்தியல் கொண்டு தாக்கினர் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது. இதில் சிலையின் முகப் பகுதி சேதமடைந்தது. இதனைப் பார்த்த அந்த பகுதியில் இருந்த திராவிடர் கழகம், திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் சிலையை உடைக்க முயன்றவர்களை  பிடித்து , டவுன் காவல் நிலையத்தில் ஒப்படைத்தனர்.பிடிபட்ட இருவரில் முருகானந்தம் என்பவர் பா.ஜ.கவின் நகர பொதுச்செயலாளராக இருக்கிறார். மற்றொரு நபரின் பெயர் ஃப்ரான்சிஸ். இந்த விவகாரம் தொடர்பாக திராவிடர் கழகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த இளங்கோ என்பவர் காவல்துறையில் புகார் அளித்துள்ளதாகவும் பிடிபட்டவர்கள் குடிபோதையில் இருப்பதாக தெரிகிறது என்றும் மாவட்ட காவல்துறை கண்காணிப்பாளர் பகலவன் பிபிசி தமிழிடம் தெரிவித்தார். இருவரிடமும் காவல்துறை விசாரணை மேற்கொண்டுவருகிறது. வேலூர் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள 19 பெரியார் சிலைகளுக்கும் காவல்துறை பாதுகாப்பு அளிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.அதேபோல தமிழகத்தின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளிலும் உள்ள பெரியார் சிலைகளுக்கு காவல்துறை பாதுகாப்பு அளிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. பா.ஜ.கவின் தேசியச் செயலர் எச். ராஜா, திரிபுராவில் லெனின் சிலை உடைக்கப்பட்டதைப்போல, தமிழகத்தில் நாளை பெரியாரின் சிலையும் உடைக்கப்படும் என்று தன் ஃபேஸ்புக் பக்கத்தில் வெளியிட்ட கருத்து தமிழகத்தில் பெரும் சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்தியிருந்த நிலையில் இந்த சம்பவம் நிகழ்ந்துள்ளது.பிற செய்திகள்: சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பிபிசி தமிழ் : மேலே உள்ள கட்டுரைக்கு நல்ல தலைப்பைக் கொடுங்கள்.","answer":"வேலூரில் பெரியார் சிலை உடைப்பு; இருவர் கைது"},{"question":"ما هو متوسط وزن الأسد بالكيلو جرام؟","answer":"من 30 الى 70 كيلو جر"},{"question":"මට බළලෙකු ලබා ගත හැකි බව ඒත්තු ගැන්වීමට මගේ මවට ලිපියක් ලියන්න.","answer":"ආදරණීය අම්මේ, මම බළලෙකු ලබා ගැනීමට කැමතියි, මන්ද සහකාර සතෙකු සිටීම බළලුන් සිටින මිනිසුන්ගේ ආතතිය අඩු කිරීමට සහ ඉහළ සංවේදනයට හේතු වන බව පෙන්වා දී ඇත. බල්ලන්ට මෙන් බළලුන්ට ක්‍රියාශීලී දෛනික කළමනාකරණයක් අවශ්‍ය නොවේ (එබැවින් අපට දවසේ කොටසක් නිවසින් බැහැරව සිටීමට අවශ්‍ය වූ විට, බළලාට පැය ගණනක් තනිව සිටීමට හැකි වනු ඇත). මම කාලසටහනක් ලෑස්ති කරලා තියෙනවා මම පූසාට කවනවද පොඩි පෙට්ටිය හිස් කරන්නද කියලා. ඒ වගේම මම දැනටමත් මගේ මිතුරිය හැනාගෙන් අහලා තියෙනවා අපි නිවාඩුවට යනකොට ඇවිත් පූසා බලාගන්නවද කියලා. බළලෙකු ඇති කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය මිලදී ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් මුදලක් මම ඉතිරි කර ගෙන ඇති අතර මගේ දීමනාව බළලාට ආහාර මිලදී ගැනීමට භාවිතා කිරීමට මම සැලසුම් කරමි. මම හිතන්නේ ඔබත් බළලෙකු සිටීමෙන් සතුටක් ලබනු ඇත! ඔවුන් සමඟ සෙල්ලම් කිරීමට විනෝදජනකයි, ආදරය / සුරතල් සතුන් හා එවැනි විනෝදජනක පෞරුෂයන් ඇත."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકનુ એક લેખન નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે. આજ રીતની \\"માથાફોડ\\" પર આવુ જ બીજુ લેખન લખો. \\"રમેશ ઘરમાં આવીને દિલુને કહે : “અરે સાંભળ્યું કે ? આજે બે મહેમાન છે. હું શીખંડ લેવા જા‌ઉં છું. તું પૂરી કરી નાખ.”⁠દિલુ પાછળથી બબડે છે : “આજ સવારનું માથું ચડ્યું છે ને ઠીક નથી, ને વળી મહેમાન ક્યાં આણ્યા ? વળી બે વાગે જમીને રેલે જાવું છે.”⁠દિલુ ધૂંવાપૂંવા થતી ધમપછાડા કરતી લોટ ચાળે છે. નંદુ આવે છે; કહે છે : “બા, તને લોટ ચળાવું ? મને આંક આપને ?”​ દિલુ કહે : “કોરે ખસે છે કે નહિ ? મારી સમજજે. આ આટલી ઊતાવળ છે એમાં તું ડાહી થવા આવી ! ત્યાં તારા બાપને ક્યાં ખબર છે કે એમ તે ઝટપટ કેમ થતું હતું !”નંદુ હળવેક દઈને મોં પાડી બહાર ગઈ.\\"","answer":"આજે દુકાનના હિસાબ ગણવામાં છગનલાલની ભૂલ થઈ ને શેઠ તેને વઢ્યા. છગનલાલ ઘેર આવી ચિડાતા ચિડાતા ફરતા હતા. બબુ આવીને કહે : “બાપા, આજે પાગલો પા કરોને ?”બાપા કહે : “આજે તારી બા પાસે જા; હું કામમાં છું.”બબુ કહે: “કામમાં ક્યાં છો ? ફરો છો તે રમાડોને ?”છગનલાલ આંખ લાલ કરીને ઘૂરક્યા : “એલી બબુડી, શું બોલી ? બોલતાં આવડે છે કે નઈ ? ચાલ ચાલી જા, પાગલો પા નથી કરવો. જો એમ ફરી વાર બોલી છે તો !”બબુ ડરતી ડરતી ઘરમાં ભાગી ગઈ."},{"question":"“ప్రాచీన కాలంలో భారత సాంఘిక వ్యవస్థ ఏ రూపంలో ఉండేది? అప్పటి వృత్తులేవి? ఈ ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానాలు కోరితే అజంతా గుహలకు వెళ్ళాలి” ఇలా అనడం వెనుక నార్ల వేంకటేశ్వరరావు గారి భావం ఏమై ఉంటుందో రాయండి.","answer":"అజంతా చిత్రాలలో భారతీయ జీవితం, సంస్కృతి తొణికిసలాడుతున్నాయి. వాటి ద్వారా వివిధ భారతీయ జీవితాల్ని గురించి, సంస్కృతి గురించి, వారి వృత్తులు మొదలైన ఎన్నో విషయాల గురించి తెలుసుకోగలుగుతున్నాం. అజంతా చిత్రాల ద్వారా మన ప్రాచీన సాంఘిక వ్యవస్థ గురించి తెలుసుకోవచ్చు.ఆ అజంతా చిత్రాలలో ఒకప్పుడు మనదేశంలో రాజమందిరాలు ఏ విధంగా ఉండేవో, రాజులు, రాణులు వేషభాషలు ఎలా ఉండేవో, వారు రాజసభలను ఎలా తీర్చుకొనేవారో తెలుస్తుంది. రాజుల సైనిక బల నిర్మాణం, వారి ఆయుధాలు, ఎలా ఉండేవో ఆ చిత్రాల వల్ల తెలుసుకోవచ్చు. అక్కడ చిత్రాలలో మన భారత సాయుధ దళాలు సింహళ దండయాత్ర చేసిన నౌకాదళ చిత్రాలున్నాయి. వీరశివాజీ, రాజ్యానికై సముద్రాలు దాటి వెళ్ళిన భారతదేశ వ్యక్తుల చిత్రాలున్నాయి. పర్ష్యన్ రాయబారులకు దర్శనం ఇచ్చిన మన భారతీయ రాజుల చిత్రాలు ఉన్నాయి. అందువల్లనే, నార్లవారు అజంతా చిత్రాల ద్వారా ఆనాటి భారత సాంఘిక వ్యవస్థ రూపం వెల్లడి అవుతుందని చెప్పారు."},{"question":"O ma wa ga o, wọn tun pa ọmọ ọdun mẹrindinlogun mi-in l’Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan","answer":"Niṣe ni gbogbo eeyan ro pe iku ojiji tawọn olubi ẹda kan fi n pa awọn eeyan ni ijọba ibilẹ Akinyẹle, niluu Ibadan, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, yoo mọwọ duro pẹlu bi ọwọ ọlọpaa ṣe tẹ awọn kan ti wọn jẹwọ pe awọn lawọn wa nidii ọrọ naa, ti wọn si foju wọn han lọsẹ to kọja. Ṣugbọn ọrọ ko ri bẹẹ pẹlu bi awọn kan ṣe tun lọọ pa ọmọbinrin ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlogun kan ti wọn pe orukọ rẹ ni Tokẹ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, ni Akinyẹle yii kan naa.ALAROYE gbọ pe adugbo Onikoko, loju ọna Ibadan si Ọyọ, ni awọn ọlọpaa Moniya ti kan oku ọmọdebinrin naa ninu igbo lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Epo bẹntiroolu ni wọn ni awọn obi ọmọ yii ni ko lọọ ra wa lalẹ ọjọ Aje, ti wọn ko si ri i ko pada sile ki wọn too lọọ kan oku ẹ ninu igbo yii.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Chuks Enwonwu, ti ni ki iwadii bẹrẹ lori awọn to ṣiṣẹ buruku naa."},{"question":"Que língua é falada no país Eslovénia?","answer":"A língua oficial falada na Eslovênia é o esloveno."},{"question":"ＪＲＡの場外馬券売り場。カタカナ４文字で言うと何？","answer":"ウインズです。"},{"question":"સાનમ રે ફિલ્મ સારાંશ આપો .","answer":"સાનમ રે ફિલ્મ સારાંશસાનમ રે એ 2016 ની રોમેન્ટિક ડ્રામા ફિલ્મ છે જેનું નિર્દેશન દિવ્યા ખોસલા કુમાર દ્વારા કરવામાં આવ્યું છે અને તેમાં પલકી સિંહ અને યમી ગૌતમ છે. ફિલ્મ સ્વપ્નશીલ યુવા અભિનેતા અક્ષની વાર્તા પર આધારિત છે જે તેની ગામઠી પ્રેમિકા શ્રુતિ સાથે શહેરમાં આવે છે અને તેમના સપનાને પૂર્ણ કરવા માટે સંઘર્ષ કરે છે.ફિલ્મની શરૂઆત અક્ષના ગામથી શરૂ થાય છે જ્યાં તે શ્રુતિ સાથે પ્રેમમાં પડે છે. તેણી તેના સપનાઓને પૂર્ણ કરવા માટે શહેરમાં આવે છે અને તેના પરિવારને તેના નિર્ણય માટે માફી માંગે છે. શહેરમાં, અક્ષ તેની ગરીબી અને અજ્ઞાનતાને કારણે મુશ્કેલીઓનો સામનો કરે છે. તે એક રેસ્ટોરન્ટમાં ગેટ આઉટ બોય તરીકે નોકરી મેળવે છે અને તેના પ્રેમિકાને મળવા માટે હંમેશા ઉત્સાહી રહે છે.ફિલ્મમાં શ્રુતિની નાની દીકરીનું પણ પાત્ર છે જે તેના માતાના ગુમ થવાથી ગભરાયેલી છે. તે અક્ષને ગમે છે અને તેની સાથે સમય પસાર કરે છે.અક્ષ તેની ગરીબી અને અજ્ઞાનતાને કારણે ઘણી મુશ્કેલીઓનો સામનો કરે છે, પરંતુ તે તેના સપનાઓને અસ્વાધીન કરવાનું વચન આપે છે. તેની પ્રેમિકા શ્રુતિ તેની સાથે છે અને તેને તેના સપનાઓને પૂર્ણ કરવામાં મદદ કરવા માટે પ્રેરણા આપે છે.ફિલ્મનો અંત અક્ષની સફળતા સાથે થાય છે અને તે તેની પ્રેમિકા શ્રુતિ સાથે ખુશીથી જીવે છે.સાનમ રે એ એક રોમેન્ટિક ડ્રામા છે જે પ્રેમ, સપનાઓ અને સંઘર્ષ વિશે વાત કરે છે. તે શ્રેષ્ઠ ભારતીય ફિલ્મોમાંની એક છે જે તેના સુંદર સંગીત, અદભૂત દ્રશ્યો અને શક્તિશાળી પાત્રોને કારણે પ્રશંસા મેળવે છે."},{"question":"Nahoana no miposaka avy any atsinanana ny masoandro?","answer":"Miposaka any atsinanana ny masoandro noho ny fihodinan'ny Tany manodidina ny tenany avy any andrefana mankany atsinanana"},{"question":"Adikao amin'ny teny Malagasy ny teny hoe \\"montre\\".","answer":"Ny teny hoe \\"montre\\" dia azo adika amin'ny teny Malagasy hoe \\"famataran'andro\\"."},{"question":"Nitori ifẹhonu han lodi si SARS, awọn ọdọ ba teṣan ọlọpaa jẹ n’Ijẹbu-Ode","answer":"Bi ifẹhonu han ṣe n lọ kaakiri awọn ipinlẹ pe kijọba fagi le ikọ ọlọpaa adigboluja ti wọn n pe ni SARS, bẹẹ naa lo waye nipinlẹ Ogun, ṣugbọn janduku lawọn ọdọ to kopa ninu ẹ n’Ijẹbu-Ode fi tiwọn ṣe. Niṣe ni wọn wọ teṣan ọlọpaa Imoru lọ, ti wọn da ibẹ ru, ti wọn tun ji wọn lẹru lọ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọjọ kẹsan-an, oṣu kẹwaa yii.Ninu fidio kan to gun ori ayelujara lori rogbodiyan yii, awọn ọdọ kan ti wọn n fọ gilaasi oju ferese lo ṣafihan. Bi wọn ṣe n la igi mọ awọn ọkọ ti wọn paaki kalẹ ninu ọgba ọlọpaa naa ni wọn n fọ gilaasi ọkọ, bẹẹ ni wọn n ko awọn ohun tọwọ wọn ba nitosi lọ.Ọkan ninu wọn wa ọkada to ba ninu ọgba ọlọpaa naa lọ, bẹẹ ni omi-in n tu taya mọto ti wọn paaki silẹ jẹẹjẹ.Okuta nla atawọn nnkan ọṣẹ mi-in ni wọn tun n ju sinu ile lọdọ awọn ọlọpaa yii, bẹẹ ni wọn n ṣepe buruku fun wọn.Bi wọn ti n ṣe eyi ni wọn n sọ pe ọlọpaa ti wọn ba bi daadaa ko jade sita waa koju awọn, wọn ni tọhun yoo jẹ buruku iya.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ko sẹni to mọ ohun to fa a fi awọn ọdọ to n fẹhonu han nitori SARS naa ṣe tun sọ ọ di ohun ti wọn n ba nnkan jẹ ni teṣan bayii, kinni kan to daju ni pe iṣẹlẹ yii waye. Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun,  paapaa fidi ẹ mulẹ, o si binu gan-an si iwa ti awọn ọdọ naa hu.Oyeyẹmi ṣalaye pe rogbodiyan to fa fifi opin si SARS ti wọn n beere kiri yii ko waye nipinlẹ Ogun, ki lo waa de to jẹ ipinlẹ ti ko mọ nipa ẹ lawọn eeyan yii doju ija kọ.O ni awọn ti ṣeleri pe ẹnikẹni tọwọ ba tẹ lori eyi to ṣẹlẹ ni teṣan ọlọpaa yii yoo kabaamọ gidi.O fi kun un pe ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti pe awọn ọba atawọn baalẹ pe ki wọn kilọ fawọn ọmọ ilu wọn, ki wọn ma ṣe lọwọ si iwọde onijagidijagan, nitori ẹni tọwọ ba tẹ nibi ifẹhonuhan to mu wahala dani ko ni i le royin tan.Ọpọlọpọ eeyan lo fi aidunnu han si ohun ti awọn ọdọ wọnyi ṣe naa, wọn ni iwa arufin ni wọn hu, yoo si daa bawọn ọlọpaa ba ri mu ninu wọn lati fi wọn jofin."},{"question":"\\"Kekancan ora kena tukar padu. Kudu padha rukun. Mbiyantu kanca sing lagi kasusahan. Aja rumangsa kuwat pinter dhewe.\\"Miturut wacan ing dhuwur, Menawa ana kanca sing lagi kasusahan kudu ...A. Padha rukunB. RumangsaC. MbiyantuJawaban:","answer":"Jawaban: C. Mbiyantu"},{"question":"السؤال: شنو كايتسمى الشخص اللي كايكشر على النياب ديالو وهو معبس ؟","answer":"الإجابة: مجعور"},{"question":"Eemọ ree o: wọn ni gomina ilẹ Hausa kan ni olori awọn Boko Haram","answer":"Ọkunrin kan to ti fi igba kan jẹ igbakeji ọga pata ni ileefowopamọ apapọ ilẹ wa (Central Bank of Nigieria), Ọmọwe Obadiah Mailafiya, tun tẹnu mọ ọn lanaa pe gomina ilẹ Hausa kan to wa lori aga ijọba lọwọlọwọ bayii ni olori pata fun awọn Boko Haram. O ni nibi ti ọrọ de bayii, ki a ma jẹ ki ẹnikẹni pe aja ni ọbọ fun wa mọ o, ki gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria mọ pe gomina yii lo wa nidii aburu to n ba wọn.Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde ijẹrin, ni ọkunrin naa ti kọko sọrọ yii lori eto redio kan, to ni lara awọn ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ ronu piwada ninu awọn ọmọ ogun afẹmiṣofo Boko Haram yii sọ foun pe gomina naa ni olori awọn kaafata, ko si si ohun kan to n lọ to ṣẹyin ọkunrin gomina naa. Bi Mailafiya ti sọ bayii lawọn agbofinro DSS ranṣẹ si i, wọn ni ko waa ṣalaye ohun to mu un sọ bẹẹ. Ni wọn ba mu un lọ si agọ wọn to wa ni Kuba Road niluu Jos lanaa. Ṣugbọn wọn fi i silẹ nigbẹyin, bo si ti jade lo tun tẹnu mọ ọn pe oun ko le ko ọrọ oun jẹ, nitori ootọ pọnnbele ni.O jọ pe wọn ni ko bọ si gbangba ko ni oun ko sọ bẹẹ mọ ni, ṣugbọn Mailafiya loun ko ni i sọ bẹẹ, nitori ododo to fidi mulẹ ni ohun ti oun sọ. Awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa paapaa tilẹ ti kin Mailafiya lẹyin, wọn ni ki ẹnikẹni ma tori ọrọ to sọ yii pa ohùn mọ agogo rẹ lẹnu o, kaka bẹẹ, ki wọn jẹ ko wi tẹnu ẹ, ki ijọba si gbe iwadii to rinlẹ dide lori ọrọ naa, ki wọn le mọ eyi ti i ṣe ododo."},{"question":"ما هو اكثر الكواكب خطورة؟","answer":"المشتري هو أكثر الكواكب خطورة."},{"question":"Ọmọ Akunyili ti wọn pa ni: Emi ati baba mi ṣi sọrọ lo ku ọla to maa ku","answer":"Ọrọ idaro to n ti ẹnu Abilekọ Chidiogo Akunyili-Parr, ọkan lara awọn ọmọ oloogbe, Dokita Chike Akunyili, jade, lasiko yii fi bi ibanujẹ iku baba wọn to jade laye lojiji ṣe ka a lara to han.Dokita Akunyili, ọkọ Ọga agba ajọ NAFDAC tẹlẹ nilẹ wa, Ọjọgbọn Dora Akunyili, lawọn kan ṣeku pa lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee ọsẹ yii, lagbegbe Afor Nkpor, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Ndemili, ipinlẹ Anambra, bo ṣe n dari bọ lati ibi to ti lọọ gba ami-ẹyẹ kan ti wọn fi da iyawo rẹ to ti doloogbe naa lọla.Chidiogo lọ sori ikanni Instagiraamu rẹ, o si kọ awọn ọrọ wọnyi sibẹ, o ni:“Ubuntu (ọkan lara orukọ baba rẹ) tumọ si ‘bo ṣe n ṣe yin lo n jẹ ko ṣẹlẹ si mi’. To ba jẹ loootọ ni itumọ orukọ yii, a jẹ pe ọkunrin to tawọ si adọdọ ibọn rẹ, to si yin in lu ọ lẹẹmeji, bi aye ṣe ri, bi ayika rẹ si ṣe ri, lo fara han ninu ibinu rẹ, iwa aitọ ati iwa ọdaran to hu yẹn.Ani to ba jẹ loootọ ni itumọ orukọ yii, a jẹ pe gbogbo bi baba mi ṣe n pọkaka iku, ti ẹmi fẹẹ bọ lẹnu ẹ yẹn ṣẹlẹ lati fi bi ara ṣe n ni orileede wa to, bi orileede wa ṣe n pọkaka iku han ni.”Chidiogo, to gbe oriṣiiriṣii fọto toun ati baba rẹ ya papọ sori ikanni naa, sọ pe iku baba oun yii yẹ ko mu kawọn eeyan ji giri si iṣoro aabo to mẹhẹ lorileede yii, ki wọn si wo ọna to daa ju lati yanju ẹ.Ọmọ naa tun sọ pe oun ati oloogbe yii sọrọ ni alẹ ọjọ to ṣaaju iku rẹ, toun o si mọ pe ọrọ to maa ba oun sọ kẹyin niyẹn.O ni nigba toun ati oloogbe naa n sọrọ, o bi oun leere pe igba wo loun maa bimọ le ọmọ ọwọ oun yii, tori oun fẹẹ fun un lorukọ kan toun ti n tọju pamọ tipẹ. O ni baba oun lo sọ ọmọ toun n tọ lọwọ ni Mmesomma, eyi to tumọ si ‘ohun to rẹwa nikan l’Ọlọrun n ṣe, bẹẹ la sọrọ nipa ipo ti Naijiria wa bayii’.O pari ọrọ rẹ pe: “A le ti gba ọna ọtọọtọ bayii o… ṣugbọn ọna to mu iku oro bii eyi wa, to si n ṣẹlẹ si ọpọ eeyan, ko daa rara.”"},{"question":"د منجمنټ خصوصیات څه شی دي ؟ ","answer":"• سروې• پلانګذاری• تخصیص• استخدام• هماهنګي• رهبري• راپور ورکول• راپور اخيستل"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- አንደኛው የዓለም ጦርነት የጀመረው በየትኛው ዓመት ነው? መልስ፡- ","answer":"1914 ዓ.ም"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ayam bertelur di atas padi mati kelaparan\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahase tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang menderita kesusahan di tempat yang mewah. Contoh ayat: Walaupun negara ini kaya dengan pelbagai hasil bumi, namun kita akan menjadi seperti ayam bertelur di atas padi mati kelaparan jika kita malas berusaha dan belajar bersungguh-sungguh, kita pasti akan hidup susah."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Langkah-Langkah Menjaga Alam Sekitar.","answer":"Alam sekitar merupakan sumber kehidupan yang penting untuk manusia dan makhluk hidup lainnya di muka bumi ini. Namun, akibat kesilapan dan kecuaian manusia, alam sekitar kini mengalami masalah seperti pencemaran air, udara, dan tanah, serta penggundulan hutan dan kepupusan spesies. Oleh itu, langkah-langkah proaktif perlu diambil untuk melindungi dan menjaga alam sekitar agar generasi akan datang dapat menikmati keindahan dan kekayaan alam semula jadi. Dalam karangan ini, kita akan membincangkan empat langkah yang boleh diambil untuk menjaga alam sekitar.Salah satu langkah penting dalam menjaga alam sekitar adalah dengan mengamalkan konsep 3R, iaitu mengurangkan (reduce), menggunakan semula (reuse), dan mengitar semula (recycle). Mengurangkan bermaksud mengurangkan penggunaan sumber alam dan barang yang tidak diperlukan. Sebagai contoh, kita boleh mengurangkan penggunaan plastik sekali pakai dan menggunakan beg kain yang boleh digunakan berulang kali. Menggunakan semula pula bermaksud menggunakan barang yang telah digunakan untuk tujuan lain. Sebagai contoh, kita boleh menggunakan botol kaca yang telah digunakan untuk menyimpan makanan. Akhir sekali, mengitar semula bermaksud mengolah bahan buangan yang telah digunakan untuk dijadikan produk baru. Contohnya, kertas yang telah digunakan boleh diolah semula menjadi kertas baru.Penanaman pokok dan pemuliharaan hutan merupakan langkah yang penting dalam menjaga alam sekitar. Pokok berfungsi sebagai penyerap karbon dioksida, penghasil oksigen, dan pemelihara kestabilan tanah. Dengan menanam lebih banyak pokok, kita boleh membantu mengurangkan jumlah karbon dioksida dalam atmosfera dan melawan pemanasan global. Selain itu, pemuliharaan hutan juga penting dalam menjaga kepelbagaian spesies dan keseimbangan ekosistem. Oleh itu, kita harus memastikan hutan dilindungi daripada aktiviti penebangan dan pembalakan yang tidak terkawal.Pencemaran air, udara, dan tanah merupakan masalah utama yang dihadapi alam sekitar. Oleh itu, kita perlu mengambil langkah untuk mengurangkan pencemaran ini. Pertama, kita perlu memastikan bahan buangan dibuang dengan cara yang betul. Sebagai contoh, bahan buangan elektronik harus dibuang di tempat khas yang disediakan oleh pihak berkuasa. Kedua, kita harus menggunakan kenderaan yang lebih mesra alam, seperti kereta elektrik atau menggunakan pengangkutan awam. Ketiga, industri harus mematuhi peraturan pencemaran yang ditetapkan oleh pihak berkuasa dan menggunakan teknologi yang lebih mesra alam dalam proses pengeluaran mereka. Keempat, kita harus menjaga sumber air dengan tidak mencemarkan sungai, tasik, dan lautan dengan bahan kimia dan sampah.Pendidikan dan kesedaran alam sekitar merupakan salah satu langkah terpenting dalam menjaga alam sekitar. Masyarakat perlu diberi pengetahuan mengenai isu-isu alam sekitar dan cara-cara untuk menjaga kelestarian sumber alam semulajadi. Pendidikan alam sekitar boleh dimulakan di peringkat sekolah rendah dengan memasukkan topik seperti kepelbagaian biologi, keberkesanan sumber, dan isu-isu pencemaran dalam kurikulum. Selain itu, kempen dan program kesedaran alam sekitar boleh dianjurkan oleh pihak berkuasa, pertubuhan bukan kerajaan (NGO), dan komuniti setempat untuk menggalakkan masyarakat melibatkan diri dalam usaha menjaga alam sekitar.Kesimpulannya, langkah-langkah yang telah dinyatakan seperti mengamalkan konsep 3R, penanaman pokok dan pemuliharaan hutan, mengurangkan pencemaran, serta pendidikan dan kesedaran alam sekitar merupakan usaha yang penting untuk menjaga alam sekitar. Semua pihak perlu bekerjasama dan berusaha bersungguh-sungguh dalam melaksanakan langkah-langkah ini demi kelestarian alam sekitar untuk generasi akan datang. Hanya dengan usaha bersama, kita dapat memastikan keindahan dan kekayaan alam semulajadi dapat dinikmati oleh generasi masa depan."},{"question":"Jiiftadu maxay uga duwantahay mansooyinka kale ? ","answer":"Waxay kaga duwantahy dhanka iyo meeriska iyo habdhaceeda ookooban ."},{"question":"Patikrinkite žemiau pateiktą eilutę ir atsakykite į klausimą, pateiktą toje pačioje kalba, kaip ir eilutė:  Perėjimas: asociacijų taisyklių mokymasis (priklausomybės modeliavimas) - Variklių santykių paieškos. Pavyzdžiui, prekybos centras gali rinkti duomenis apie klientų pirkimo įpročius. Naudodamasis asociacijų taisyklių mokymu, prekybos centras gali nustatyti, kurie produktai dažnai yra perkami kartu, ir naudoti šią informaciją rinkodaros tikslais. Tai kartais vadinama rinkos krepšinio analize.  Klausimas: Kokį terminą naudojasi prekybos centrai, kad surinktų klientų pirkimo įpročius?","answer":"Asociacijos taisyklių mokymasis (eng. Association rule learning)"},{"question":"تقنیني اسناد څه شی دي ؟","answer":"ځواب تقنيني اسناد د (قانون ، فرمان ، مقررې او لایحې) څخه عبارت دي ."},{"question":"වායුගෝලයේ වැඩිපුර්රම අඩංගු වාතය","answer":"නයිට්‍රජන්(78.084%)"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de Belize?","answer":"0,683."},{"question":"අධික රාගය යටපත් කරමින් රහත් උනු රහතන් වහන්සේලාගෙ නම් සදහන් කරන්න පුලුවන්ද? එය රාගය යටපත් කිරීමට වීර්ය වැඩීමට උපකාර වෙයි කියල හිතෙනවා..","answer":"මෙහෙමයි, රාගය යටපත් කරලා පමණක් රහත් වෙන්න බැමුලින් සෝතාපන්න වෙන්න තියෙන්නේ ඔය කෙලෙස් වලට වඩා දැක්ම පිළිබඳ කතාවක්.හැබැයි සෝතාපන්න ඉඳලා අරිහත්වය දක්වා මාර්ගයේ නම් රාගය යටපත් කිරීමත් කරන්න වෙනවා"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe vintana?","answer":"Ny vintana dia fahatongavan-javatra kisendrasendra, zavatra tsy fanta-piaviana, tsy hita fototra. Ny vintana ihany koa dia hery napetraky ny Zanahary mba hifehy sy handrindra ny fiainan’izao rehetra izao."},{"question":"Magaalada Dhaa’if markuu aaday Nabiga (SCW), kadib ay ku soo dhagax yeeyeen saxaabigii la socday magaciis?","answer":"Waxa uu ahaa Zayd Ibnu Xaaritha    "},{"question":"milazà fiasana nentin'ny fandrosoana roa.","answer":"ireo fiasana nentin'ny fandrosoana roa: ny larozoara ary ny trakitera"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : «  Mahafinaritra izao, hoy ilay anankiray izay, mila olona toa anao izao indrindra ny firenena ankehitriny. »","answer":"Maneho hafaliana io fanambarana io. Finaritra ny manodidina nohon’ny fahavononana hanova"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai kelip-kelip terbang malam\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud \\"sesuatu rahsia yang tidak dapat disembunyikan.\\" Kisah Norli yang mengandungkan anak luar nikah bagai kelip-kelip terbang malam apabila perutnya semakin membesar."},{"question":"جنوبی ایشیا میں سکندر کی مہم کی دیرپا اہمیت کیا ہے؟","answer":"جنوبی ایشیا میں الیگزینڈر کی مہم تاریخ میں ایک قابل ذکر واقعہ بنی ہوئی ہے، جس میں قدیم ریسرچ اور فوجی فتوحات کی حد تک نمائش کی گئی ہے۔ اس عرصے کے دوران یونانی اور ہندوستانی ثقافتوں کے امتزاج نے منفرد فنکارانہ اور تعمیراتی تاثرات پیدا کیے، جس سے خطے کے ورثے کو تقویت ملی۔ مزید برآں، الیگزینڈر کی مہم نے بین الثقافتی بیداری کو زیادہ سے زیادہ سہولت فراہم کی، جس نے تاریخی اکاؤنٹس اور داستانوں میں حصہ ڈالا جن کا مطالعہ اور قدیم دنیا میں دلچسپی رکھنے والے اسکالرز اور شائقین کی طرف سے تعریف کی جاتی ہے۔"},{"question":"Lapho abantu bevivinya umzimba, ngokuvamile bazizwa bomile futhi baqale ukujuluka. Kubalulekile ukuba abantu bazizwe bomile lapho bevivinya umzimba ngoba kubenza baqaphele ukuthi kufanele bakhethe:  thathe ikhefu; sebenzisa uketshezi;  ukunciphisa ukuphefumula kwazo;  yeka ukudla okuthile; Impendulo yakho:","answer":"ukuphuza uketshezi"},{"question":"ஜெயமோகனின் பெற்ற  விருதுகள் யாவை ? ","answer":"விருதுகள்1990 ஆண்டு அகிலன் நினைவுப்போட்டிப் பரிசைப் பெற்றார்.1992 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான கதா[9] விருதைப் பெற்றார்.1994 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான சம்ஸ்கிருதி சம்மான்[10] தேசியவிருது பெற்றுள்ளார்.2008 ஆம் ஆண்டு பாவலர் விருது பெற்றார்[11]2010 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் இவரது படைப்பான விஷ்ணுபுரம் பெயரால் விஷ்ணுபுரம் இலக்கிய வட்டம் விருது ஒன்றை அளிக்கிறது.2011 ஆம் ஆண்டு அறம் சிறுகதைத் தொகுதிக்காக முகம் விருது பெற்றார்2012 சிறந்ததிரைக்கதைக்கான கேரளா பிலிம் கிரிட்டிக்ஸ் விருது ஒழிமுறி2012- சிறந்த திரைக்கதைக்கான டீ ஏ ஷாஹித் விருது ஒழிமுறி2014- கனடா தமிழ் இலக்கியத் தோட்டம் வழங்கிய இயல் விருது"},{"question":"\\"Arahabaina nahavita soa ny adidy e!\\"Inona no fihetseham-po asehon'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Maneho haravoana io fanambarana io satria miarahaba ilay olona miresaka eto ary maneho ny hafaliany sy ny fientanam-pony amin'ny alalan'ny fampiasana \\"!\\" ao anatin'ilay fanambarana."},{"question":"Frontier supercomputer හි MSU ප්‍රමුඛ කණ්ඩායමට එක්සත් ජනපද බලශක්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (DOE) කොපමණ ගණනය කිරීමේ කාලයක් ලබා දී තිබේද?","answer":"එක්සත් ජනපද බලශක්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (DOE) විසින් මිචිගන් රාජ්‍ය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය MSU ප්‍රමුඛ කණ්ඩායමට ෆ්‍රොන්ටියර් සුපිරි පරිගණකයේ නෝඩ් පැය මිලියන 1.3ක ගණනය කිරීමේ කාලය ප්‍රදානය කර ඇත."},{"question":"Ọmọ ìpínlẹ̀ wo ni Onídàájọ Ibrahim Tanko Muhammad?","answer":"Ọmọ Ìpínlẹ̀ Bauchi ni."},{"question":"Muhiimada uu Leeeyahay bini'adamka wadnaha ","answer":"Wadnaha waa mid kamid ah xubnaha ugu muhiimsan jirkeena, isagoo ka shaqeeya gaarsiinta oxygen ta iyo nafaqada dhamaan jirkeena oo ay ugu horeyso maskaxda. Maalin kasta wadnaheenu wuxuu garaacmaa 115Kun oo jeer;; sidoo kale wadnahaagu wuxuu pumb gareeyaa 200 galoon oo dhiig ah maalinweliba. Haddii ay shaqadaasi joogsato oo la qaban waayo nolashayda, nolahsaada, nolasheena oo dhan ayaa khatar gelayso, Haddaba.  Sow inalama gudboona inaan ilaahay ku mahdinno markasta xilli kasta iyo wakhti kasta."},{"question":"(ngezwi elinokuzithoba) Ngiyabonga ukungihlonipha kwenuzivakashi zami nafika lapho ebengicele ukuba niziveze khonangenhloso yokuzoxoxisana ngikhiphe lokhu okungaphakathi kimi.(kanye kanye.) Yebo baba.(athinte kancane isikhwehlela.) Lo mbiko engiqonde ukuwedlulisanamhlanje ngizoqala ngokuwubhekisa kini madodakazi amingomuzwa wokuzisola njengomuntu ozibona enecala phambikwamathongo ami naphambi kukaMvelinqangi ngenxa yesenzosodlame engasenza kini.(kanye kanye.) Yebo baba!(ujabhile.) Lo mbiko engiqonde ukuwedlulisa namhlanje lapha kiniingqikithi yawo isekutheni selokhu ngingenile lapha eselininjengomsolwa otokile osalindele ukuqulwa kwecala lakhe, angikazengikuthole neze ukuphumula emoyeni.Eqinisweni ngihlaselwa amaphupho amabi ephelekezelwa yizithunzizabadala abangamathongo omuzi. Bathi manginilande kuzo zonkeizinkalo enganichithela kuzo, khona lapho ngizicelele uxolo kiningiphinde ngihlawule ngembuzi yokugeza igceke lomuzi wabongenxa yokunihubha kwami ngesikhali emzini wabo. Sengicelaukuzwa kini-ke manje ukuthi ngabe niphawula nithini kuleli lamiloxolo. Ngabe niyangixolela zingane zami kumbe nisangibambeleinhliziyo namagqubu?(Esikhundleni sokuphawula avele abukane emehlweni amadodakaziyimbe.)1. Yini umsebenzi womlandi kulesi siqeshana? Nikeza isizathu sempenduloyakho. ","answer":"Umlandi usitshela ngemizwa yokuzehlisa nokuzithoba njengoba uMdaluliubonga izingane zakhe ukuba zifikile ukuzombona ejele. Uphinde asitshelengemicabango/izenzo zabalingiswa njengoba oLondiwe, noKhombephinoNenezi bebukana kuqala uma uMdaluli ebazisa ngephupho lokuthimakalande izingane azixosha. Umlandi usichazela ngemizwa yabalingiswanjengoba uMdaluli ejabula uma izingane zimxolela, baxhawulane bonkebejabula"},{"question":"Kaip vadinasi kasmet nuo 2013 m. Rumšiškėse vykstantis muzikos festivalis, kurio organizatoriai skelbia, kad tai didžiausias muzikos festivalis Lietuvoje?","answer":"Šis muzikos festivalis vadinasi \\"Granatos live\\". Tai, kiekvienų metų pirmąjį rugpjūčio savaitgalį, organizuojamas trijų dienų muzikos, pramogų ir laisvalaikio festivalis po atviru dangumi."},{"question":"ਸਵਾਲਃ  ਚੰਦਰਯਾਨ-3 ਚੰਦਰਮਾ 'ਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਖੋਜ ਕਰੇਗਾ ?","answer":"ਜਵਾਬਃ ਲੈਂਡਰ ਨੂੰ 70 ਡਿਗਰੀ ਅਕਸ਼ਾਂਸ਼ 'ਤੇ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਧਰੁਵ 'ਤੇ ਉਤਰਨ ਲਈ ਡਿਜ਼ਾਇਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਚੰਦਰਯਾਨ-3 ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਖੋਜ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਪ੍ਰੋਪਲਸ਼ਨ, ਲੈਂਡਰ ਅਤੇ ਰੋਵਰ ਮੌਡਿਊਲ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ, ਔਰਬਿਟਰ ਵੀ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਏਗਾ।ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਲੈਂਡਰ ਅਤੇ ਰੋਵਰ ਖੋਜ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਣਗੇ, ਪਰ ਡੇਟਾ ਨੂੰ ਭੇਜਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਔਰਬਿਟਰ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਹੈ।ਰੋਵਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਖਿੱਚੀਆਂ ਗਈਆਂ ਤਸਵੀਰਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਡੇਟਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੈਂਡਰ ਨੂੰ ਭੇਜ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਧਰਤੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਸਾਂਝੀਆਂ   ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਇੱਕ ਅੰਡਾਕਾਰ ਮਾਰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਚੰਦਰਮਾ ਦੀ ਪਰਿਕਰਮਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਪ੍ਰੋਪਲਸ਼ਨ ਮੌਡਿਊਲ ਪੁਲਾੜ ਵਿੱਚ ਐਕਸੋਪਲੈਨੇਟਸ (ਹੋਰ ਤਾਰਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਪਰਿਕਰਮਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਗ੍ਰਹਿ) ਦਾ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕਰੇਗਾ।ਇਸਰੋ ਨੇ ਭਵਿੱਖਬਾਣੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਤਿੰਨ ਤੋਂ ਛੇ ਮਹੀਨਿਆਂ ਤੱਕ ਚੰਦਰਮਾ ਦੀ ਪਰਿਕਰਮਾ ਕਰੇਗਾ।"},{"question":"menene maanar kalmar \\"war\\" a harshen hausa?","answer":"kalmar na nufin \\"yaki\\""},{"question":"GARASHADA GUUSHA!","answer":"Guushu way macne badan tahay, mana laha qeexitaan u gaar ah oo laysku raacay, waxayna dhacdaa xayndaabyada kala duwan ee nolosha sida qoyska, waxbarashada, ganacsiga, siyaasadda, shaqada, xiriirka bulshada, diinta iyo dhaqanka. Taasi waxay keentay in qof walba guusha uu u arko hadba sida ay ula muuqatay. Tusaale, qofka ganacsadaha ah guushu wuxuu u arkaa marka uu faa’iido badan sameeyo; qofka siyaasiga ah guushu wuxuu u arkaa marka uu ku guulaysto kursi madaxtinnimo; qofka ciyaartooyda ah guushu wuxuu u arkaa marka uu goolka dhaliyo."},{"question":"Sheeg Yaa Ugu Soo Hor Islaamay Reer Madiina?","answer":"Waxa Ugu Soo Hor Islaamay Reer Madiina Sacad Binu Suraaqa RC."},{"question":"« Tsy nahaloa-peo aho tamin’ny minitra iray nibitsihanao ny vetsom-pitiavanao teo an-tsofiko ». Inona no fihetseham-po fonosin’io fanambarana io ?","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho fihetseham-po miabo satria mankamamy ny fanambaram-pitiavana."},{"question":"السؤال: شحال عدد التكبيرات في صلاة الجنازة؟","answer":" الجواب: ربعه تكبيراتٍ مع تكبيرة الإحرام."},{"question":"கேள்வி: \\"ஒரு வன உலா\\" என்ற தலைப்பின் அடிப்படையில், ஒரு சிறுகதையை எழுதுங்கள்.","answer":"பதில்:மென்மையான காலை வெளிச்சத்தில் குளித்த காடு அதன் பழமையான கவர்ச்சியைக் காட்டியது. வளைந்து நெளிந்த பாதையில் ஒவ்வொரு அடியும் அமைதிக்கான பயணமாக இருந்தது. உயரமான மரங்கள் வழியாக சூரிய ஒளி வடிகட்டப்பட்டு, வெப்பத் திட்டுகளால் தரையைத் தட்டி எழுப்பியது.பறவைகள் தலைக்கு மேல் மெல்லிசைப் பாடல்களைப் பாடின, அவற்றின் குரல்கள் இலைகளின் சலசலப்புடன் இசைந்தன. பாசி படர்ந்த பாறைகள் காலப்போக்கில் கதைகளைச் சொன்னன, காட்டுப் பூக்கள் தங்கள் வண்ணமயமான தலையைத் தலையசைத்து வாழ்த்தின.நான் ஆழமாகச் சென்றபோது, காடு இயற்கையின் அழகு மற்றும் வாழ்க்கையின் மென்மையான சமநிலையின் ரகசியங்களை கிசுகிசுத்தது. காடுகளின் மையத்தில், நான் ஒரு அமைதியான புல்வெளியைக் கண்டேன்.காட்டில், இயற்கையின் வசீகரத்தை மட்டுமல்ல, என்னுடையதை விட மிகப் பெரிய உலகத்துடனான தொடர்பையும் நான் கண்டுபிடித்தேன். எனவே, வாழ்க்கையின் மாபெரும் திரைச்சீலையில் நமது தாய் பூமியின் காலமற்ற நினைவூட்டலை நான் உணர்ந்தேன்."},{"question":"चुप ।","answer":"तै चुप ।"},{"question":"Nitori ọmọ ilu kan to ku lojiji, awọn ọdọ fẹhonu han, wọn tun le ọba kuro laafin n’Ita-Ogbolu","answer":"Ọgọọrọ awọn ọdọ ni wọn jade niluu Ita-Ogbolu, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Akurẹ, lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, lati fẹhonu han ta ko iṣẹlẹ iku ọmọ ilu naa kan, Ayọ Oloyede.Ọna marosẹ kan ṣoṣo to gba aarin ilu Ita-Ogbolu kọja lọ si ipinlẹ Ekiti lawọn olufẹhonu han naa kọkọ di pa, ti wọn ko si fun awọn arinrin-ajo laaye lati kọja fun bii ọpọ wakati.Lẹyin eyi ni wọn ṣẹṣẹ mori le aafin, nibi ti wọn ti fagidi le Ọba Idowu Faborede ti i ṣe Ogbolu ti Ita-Ogbolu kuro laafin tipatipa.Ni ibamu pẹlu ohun ti akọroyin wa fidi rẹ mulẹ lati ẹnu ọkan lara awọn tinu n bi ọhun, o ni ọmọ bibi ilu awọn ni Oloyede, ati pe ọkan pataki ni i ṣe ninu awọn ti awọn gbẹkẹle pe yoo tun ọjọ ọla ilu naa ṣe nipasẹ iṣẹ ọlọpaa to n ṣe.O ni ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọsẹ to kọja, lo sare wa sile lati waa bẹ iya rẹ wo labule kan ti ko fi bẹẹ jinna siluu awọn.Asiko to n pada siluu Akurẹ, nibi to fi ṣebugbe, lo ku lojiji ninu ijamba ọkọ kan to waye nitosi abule kan ti wọn n pe ni Odudu, to wa laarin Akurẹ si ilu wọn.Ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ ti Oloyede wọ lo deedee takiti lojiji, lai si idi kan pato, ọkunrin ọhun ni ohun to ya awọn lẹnu ju ni bo ṣe jẹ pe Oloyede to jokoo si ijokoo ẹyin nikan lo ku ninu ijamba ọkọ naa, ti ko si ohun to ṣe awakọ to wa niwaju.O ni awọn fura si iku ọlọpaa kogbereegbe ọhun pe ki i ṣoju lasan, idi ree ti pupọ awọn ọdọ fi n binu, ti wọn si lọọ fipa le kabiyesi kuro laafin rẹ latari bi ko ṣe bikita nipa iṣẹlẹ naa."},{"question":"أين تقع ولاية عنابة؟","answer":"تقع ولاية عنابة في الشمال الشرقي للجزائر و تحمل الرقم 23 في الترتيب الولائي للولايات."},{"question":"Qual cor reflete todas as outras? ","answer":"O branco é a combinação entre a reflexão de todas as cores."},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර ටෙස්ට් තරඟවලදී කඩුළු රකින්නෙකු ලෙස වැඩිම දවාගැනීම් සංඛ්‍යාවක් සඳහා දායක වූ ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"ජාත්‍යන්තර ටෙස්ට් තරග වලදි කඩුළු රකින්නෙකු ලෙස වැඩිම දවාගැනීම් සංඛ්‍යාවක් සඳහා දායක වූ ක්‍රීඩකයා වන්නේ මාක් බවුච(ර්)ය."},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana : \\"Ny fitsangantsanganana dia fomba mahafinaritra hankafizana ny tendrombohitra.\\" sy \\"Mitombo be ny fankafizana ny tendrombohitra amin'ny fanaovana fitsangatsanganana.\\"Misy ifandraisany ve ireo fanambarana ireo?","answer":"Eny, samy miresaka momba ny mahafinaritra amin'ny fitsangatsanganana ireo fanambarana roa ireo."},{"question":"Me dê uma curiosidade do tipo histórica.","answer":"Qual rainha inglesa teve mais filhos? A Rainha Vitória."},{"question":"Idia Iya ayaba ti Benin","answer":"Idia ni ìyá Esigie, ẹni tí ó jẹ́ Oba àwọn ènìyàn Edo láàrin ọdún 1504 sí 1550. Àwọn onítàn mọ̀ pé Idia wà láyé nígbà Ogun Idah(ogun náà wáyé láàrin ọdún 1515 sí 1516) nítorí ó kópa ribiribi láti mú ìṣẹ́gun Benin wáyé. Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ sì gbàgbọ́ pé, òun ni igi lẹ́yìn ọgbà bí ọmọ rẹ̀ ṣe dé orí ìtẹ́. Ó jẹ́ akíkanjú tó jà gidigidi nígbà kí ọmọ rẹ̀ tó dé orí ìtẹ́ àti lẹ́yìn ìgbà tí ó di ọba Edo. Ó ran ọmọ rẹ̀ lọ́wọ́ láti di ọba lẹ́yìn ìgbà tí Baba rẹ̀ Oba Ozolua fi ayé sílè. Ó kó àwọn ajagun jọ láti bá arákùnrin Esigie, ẹni tí a mọ̀ sí Arhuaran jà. Arhuaran ni ẹni tí ó yẹ kó di Ọba ṣùgbọ́n wọ́n ségun rẹ̀. Idah di ìyá Oba kẹrindínlógún ti Benin.Idia dé Àfin torí Ozolua, ẹni tí ó jẹ́ ọba láàrin 1483 sí 1514, Ozolua pinu láti fi saya lẹ́yìn ìgbà tí ó ri kó jó. Idia àti Oba Ozolua fẹ́ ara wọn kí ó tó di ọdun 1504, ṣùgbọ́n àwọn onítàn ò ní ìdánilójú ìgbà tí wọ́n fẹ́ ara wọn. Nítorí ìpinnu ọba, àwọn òbí Idia pèsè rẹ̀ fún ìgbé ayé rẹ̀ ní ààfin nípa fífún ní àwọn àgbo kọ̀kan."},{"question":"الجملة الأولى: ولد في 23 يناير 1919 في تشيزويك ، لندن ، همفري ليستوك غيلبرت ، وتوفي في 29 يناير 1984 في لندن. الجملة الثانية: ولد (هامفري ليستوك غيلبرت) في 23 يناير 1919 في (تشيزويك) ، لندن ، إنجلترا. توفي في 29 يناير 1984 في لندن السؤال: هل تعبر الجملة الأولى والجملة الثانية عن نفس المعنى؟","answer":"نعم"},{"question":"\\"Tichifunga nezve 2019 Masters Tournament, ndiudze kuti ndiani akahwina makwikwi egorofu, kwakaitirwa makwikwi uye akahwina aive zera ripi? 2019 Masters Tournament yaive chinyorwa chechi83 cheMasters Tournament uye kekutanga pamakwikwi makuru mana egorofu. muna 2019, yakaitwa pakati paApril 11 na14 paAugusta National Golf Club muAugusta, Georgia.Tiger Woods akahwina bhachi rake reGreen rechishanu, uye regumi neshanu guru, nesitiroko imwe chete pamberi pevamhanyi vatatu. Zvakamusiya achinyara parekodhi yaJack Nicklaus matanhatu Masters anohwina, uye matatu ari mupfupi rekodhi yake gumi nesere makuru anohwina. Pazera re43, akave mutambi wechigumi nerimwe kuhwina hombe, uye wechipiri mukuru weMasters akahwina, zvakare akangoitwa nani naNicklaus uyo akahwina aine makore 46. Aive makore gumi nerimwe mushure mekukunda kwake kwekupedzisira kukuru, 2008 U.S. Open, uye 14 makore kubva pakahwina Masters ake ekupedzisira achirova rekodhi yapfuura yemakore gumi nematatu akabatwa naGary Player. Nekuda kwechimiro chepamusoro cheWoods, uye nekudonha kwake kubva pamusoro pemutambo nekuda kwenyaya dzemunhu pamwe nekukuvadzwa, kukunda kwakaunza kushambadza kukuru pasirese, uye kunoonekwa seimwe yemitambo mikuru inodzoka. \\"","answer":"Tiger Woods akahwina mutambo wegorofu kuAugusta National Golf Club muAugusta, GA uye aive nemakore makumi mana nematatu."},{"question":"මහාවංශය රචනා කරන ලද්දේ කවුරුන්ද? ","answer":"මහාවංශය රචනා කරන ලද්දේ මහානාම හිමි ය."},{"question":"من هم أشد الناس عداوه للمسلمين؟","answer":"اليهود."},{"question":"القصيدة التالية \\"وَمَنْ كانَ مِنْهُمْ مَاجداً مُتَقَدِّماً # فَهُمْ رَهْطَكُ الْغُرُّ الكِرَامُ وَمَعْشَرُكْ\\"\\tلها بحر الطويل أو الكامل أو الوافر أو الرجز؟","answer":"الطويل"},{"question":"Fesleğen soslu bir makarna tarifi verir misin?","answer":"Tabii ki! İşte lezzetli bir fesleğen soslu makarna tarifi:Malzemeler:350 gram makarna (spagetti, fettuccine, penne gibi tercih ettiğiniz türde)2 su bardağı taze fesleğen yaprakları2 diş sarımsak1/2 su bardağı ekstra sızma zeytinyağı1/2 su bardağı rendelenmiş parmesan peyniri1/2 su bardağı iri çekilmiş ceviz içi (isteğe bağlı)Tuz ve karabiberYapılışı:Büyük bir tencerede su kaynatın. Kaynar suya biraz tuz ekleyin ve makarnayı paketinde yazan talimatlara uygun şekilde haşlayın. Makarnanın al dente (hafif diri) olmasına dikkat edin. Haşlandıktan sonra süzün ve kenara alın.Bu sırada fesleğen sosunu hazırlamak için bir mutfak robotu veya blendır kullanın. Fesleğen yaprakları, soyulmuş sarımsak, zeytinyağı, rendelenmiş parmesan peyniri, tuz ve karabiberi ekleyin. İsteğe bağlı olarak ceviz içi de ekleyebilirsiniz. Tüm malzemeleri pürüzsüz bir kıvam alana kadar karıştırın.Haşlanmış makarnayı bir servis tabağına alın. Üzerine hazırladığınız fesleğen sosunu gezdirin ve iyice karıştırın.Makarnanızı sıcak servis yapın ve ekstra parmesan peyniri ve taze fesleğen yaprakları ile süsleyerek servis edebilirsiniz.Bu fesleğen soslu makarna tarifi, lezzetli ve hafif bir yemek seçeneğidir. Afiyet olsun!"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو اسم الغار الذي احتمى فيه الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم عند هجرته إلى المدينة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: غار ثور"},{"question":"Jawablah pertanyaan berikut berdasarkan informasi pada artikel yang diberikan.Ada berapa sila dalam Pancasila ?Artikel: Pancasila adalah ideologi dasar bagi negara Indonesia. Nama ini terdiri dari dua kata dari Sanskerta: panca berarti lima dan sila berarti prinsip atau asas. Pancasila merupakan rumusan dan pedoman kehidupan berbangsa dan bernegara bagi seluruh rakyat Indonesia.Isi kelima sila Pancasila tercantum dalam naskah pembukaan UUD 1945, yaitu:1. Ketuhanan Yang Maha Esa,2. Kemanusiaan yang adil dan beradab,3. Persatuan Indonesia,4. Kerakyatan yang dipimpin oleh hikmat kebijaksanaan dalam permusyawaratan/perwakilan,5. Keadilan sosial bagi seluruh rakyat Indonesia.","answer":"Pancasila disusun atas lima sila yang menjadi dasar dan ideologi negara Indonesia sejak Proklamasi Kemerdekaan 17 Agustus 1945, yaitu: 1. Ketuhanan Yang Maha Esa, 2. Kemanusiaan yang Adil dan Beradab, 3. Persatuan Indonesia, 4. Kerakyatan yang Dipimpin oleh Hikmat Kebijaksanaan dalam Permusyawaratan/Perwakilan, serta 5. Keadilan Sosial bagi seluruh rakyat Indonesia."},{"question":"Awọn adigunjale pa ọlọpaa kan lasiko ti wọn kọ lu ileefowopamọ ni Ọtun-Ekiti","answer":"Ọlọpaa kan ti wọn ko ti i darukọ rẹ lo gba ọrun lọ lojiji ninu akọlu kan tawọn janduku ṣe si banki igbalode kan  ni Ọtun-Ekiti, nijọba ibilẹ Mọba, nipinlẹ Ekiti. Ipo Inspẹkitọ ni wọn lọlọpaa yii wa, oun si ni ẹṣọ alaabo to wa lẹnu iṣẹ lasiko tawọn adigunjale yii ya bo banki naa.Akọlu ti wọn ṣe si banki si yii l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, ni yoo jẹ igba keji laarin ọdun kan ti iru akọlu bẹẹ yoo waye nileefowopamọ naa, eeyan mẹrin ni wọn fẹmi wọn ṣofo ninu akọlu ti iṣaaju.Ọkunrin kan to jẹ olugbe ilu naa, Ṣọla Atọlagbe, sọ nipa iṣẹlẹ yii fun wa pe awọn afurasi ọdaran wọlu ọhun ni deede aago marun-un aabọ irọlẹ, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i yinbọn soke lati le awọn eeyan ati awọn onibaara banki naa danu.Ṣọla ni ado oloro kan ni wọn fọ mọ ilẹkun igbalode to wọnu banki naa, bi ado oloro naa ṣe bu gbamu ni ilẹkun naa fa ya, wọn wọnu ile, wọn si ko ọpọ owo ti ẹnikẹni ko ti i mọ iye rẹ wọ inu ọkọ bọọsi alawọ funfun ti wọn gbe wa.Nigba to n sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ naa, Alukoro awọn ọlọpaa ni ipinlẹ Ekiti, Ọgbẹni Sunday Abutu, fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, o ṣalaye pe  loootọ ni awọn adigunjale naa fẹẹ fi ado oloro wọle sinu banki naa, ṣugbọn wọn ko raaye wọle.O ni iwadii ṣi n lọ lọwọ."},{"question":"Oración 1: Sacramento está ubicado en (38.651254, -121.259279), entre Fair Oaks y Folsom.Oración 2: Fair Oaks está ubicado entre Sacramento y Folsom (38.651254 , -121.259279).Pregunta : ¿podemos reescribir la oración 1 a la oración 2?","answer":"Si podemos reescribir la oración 1 a partir de la oración 2 de la siguiente manera: Fair Oaks está ubicado entre Sacramento y Folsom, en las coordenadas 38.651254 121.259279. "},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة قصيره من البحر البسيط.","answer":"إليك هذه القصيدة:دَعني أُفرق ما عِندي وَأَجمَع مايَجدى وَأَقضي مِن الأَفعال ما وَجبانَفسي الَّتي تَملك الأَشياء ذاهيةفَما أُبالي عَلى شَيء إِذا ذَهَبا"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe sombin-tantara?","answer":"Tantara fohy nefa feno mamerina ny ampaham-piainan’olona tena nisy na noforonin’ny saina fotsiny izay anasongadinana toe-javatra manokana tiana hampitaina ny sombin-tantara: mahaliana na azo tohizana ao an-tsaina na dia efa tapitra aza."},{"question":"دې پوښتنې ته ځواب ورکړئ چې دواړه ټاونسینډیا او ایکوچورډا څه دي؟","answer":"نباتات"},{"question":"اقلیم مدیترانه ای چگونه اقلیمی است ؟","answer":"اقلیم مدیترانه‌ای معمولاً در غرب قاره‌ها میان عرض جغرافیایی ۳۰ درجه تا ۴۵ درجه است. از ویژگی‌های این اقلیم دمای معتدل و متغیر، هوای بارانی، تابستان‌های داغ و خشک است که بستگی به سیستم پرفشار نیمه‌گرمسیری دارد، به غیر از مناطق ساحلی که تابستان‌ها به خاطر جریان سرد اقیانوسی ملایم‌تر است. این جریان سرد اقیانوسی بیشتر اوقات ایجاد مه کرده و از ریزش باران جلوگیری می‌کند."},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 「空飛ぶクルマ」は人が乗って空を飛ぶ乗り物です。国や会社などは、日本で空飛ぶクルマの利用を始めるための考え方の案を決めました。国などによると、電気で飛ぶことや自動で運転することができて、垂直に上がったり下りたりする乗り物を空飛ぶクルマと言います。プロペラや翼で3つのタイプに分けます。乗ったり降りたりする場所は「バーティポート」と呼んで、ビルの屋上などに作ります。空には、空飛ぶクルマだけが飛ぶ「コリドー」という道のような所を作ります。空飛ぶクルマは、人が多いまちとまちの間を飛んだり、山や島など交通が不便な所に行くのに使ったりします。災害のときにも使います。計画では、2025年ごろビジネスで使い始める予定です。","answer":"「空飛ぶクルマ」2025年ごろビジネスで使い始める計画"},{"question":"kuy Saartjie Baartman ?","answer":"Saartjie Baartman ab jaam la woon, fekkoon baax ca réewum Afrig bëj saalum. Moom nag, benn doomu Àngalteer lañu ko jaayoon. Gannaaw bi, tubaab yi dañu ko wutal ab dàkkental, tudde ko Venus Noire walla Venus Hottentote. Ci atum 1810 la àgg Tugal. Bi mu àggee nag, tubaab yi dañu ko wuññi , gàcc ko, làññi di ko wone ci ja yi ak luuma yi, diggante Àngalteer ak Frãs."},{"question":"ඉතාලියේ ජාතික වෘක්ෂය වන්නේ කුමන ශාකයද?","answer":"මධ්‍යධරණි කලාපය නිජභූමිය කරගත් කොළ පැහැ පත්‍ර, ධවල වර්ණ පුෂ්ප සහ රක්ත වර්ණ පලතුරු  සහිත ස්ට්‍රෝබෙරි ශාකය (Arbutus Unedo), ඉතාලියේ ජාතික වෘක්ෂයයි."},{"question":"问题：三星的公司文化是什么样的？","answer":"答案：三星的公司文化注重创新、团队合作和不断学习的精神。"},{"question":"Quel est le rôle de la narration dans la danse classique ?","answer":"Le spectacle chorégraphique a-t-il pour fonction de raconter, voire d'exprimer (un sentiment, un comportement, une émotion…), ou bien ne vise-t-il qu'à explorer du regard le seul mouvement ? C'est là un débat, qui, alors que se multiplient les interrogations sur la raison même du geste dansé, agite le monde des créateurs.Si, depuis le début du xxe s., l'ordre narratif a été remis en question, il n'en a pas pour autant disparu ; il a continué d'irriguer, dans une large mesure, le ballet néoclassique, notamment en Grande-Bretagne et dans l'ex-U.R.S.S., ainsi que la plus grande partie des ballets jazz. Cependant, en règle générale, l'enchaînement discursif a eu tendance à disparaître au profit d'une juxtaposition d'épisodes dont le sens varie en fonction du regard des spectateurs.Ainsi, les grands mythes et les œuvres littéraires offrent une source très abondante d'adaptations ou de transpositions. Des chorégraphes comme Neumeier et Roland Petit y puisent généreusement. Les créateurs de la nouvelle danse française n'y sont pas insensibles, qu'ils s'inspirent de l'univers de Beckett (Marin), de celui de Kafka (Verret, Nadj) ou de Choderlos de Laclos (Preljocaj). Quant à Martha Graham, poursuivant son exploration des méandres de l'âme féminine, elle a donné des mythes grecs une interprétation psychanalytique."},{"question":"Um alimento orgânico deve apresentar em sua embalagem o selo de uma instituição certificadora, garantindo ao consumidor que, além de ser um alimento isento de agrotóxicos, também é produzido com técnicas planejadas e controladas. A técnica de produção desses alimentos causa menor impacto aos recursos naturais, contribuindo para melhorar a qualidade de vida das pessoas.Nesse sistema de produção de alimentos vegetais, o controle de insetos é manejado por meio do(a):a) prática de adubação verde.b) emprego da compostagem.c) controle da irrigação do solo.d) utilização de predadores naturais.e) uso de sementes inoculadas com Rhizobium.","answer":"A resposta correcta é a alternativa: d) utilização de predadores naturais."},{"question":"ਪੰਜਾਬ ਬੰਦ ਅੱਜ 9 ਅਗਸਤ ਨੂੰ, ਕਈ ਥਾਈਂ ਸੜਕੀ ਆਵਾਜਾਈ ਠੱਪ।","answer":"ਲੰਬੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ 'ਤੇ ਕਲੰਕ ਬਣੀ ਹੋਈ ਮਨੀਪੁਰ ਹਿੰਸਾ ਪੰਜਾਬ 'ਚ ਵੀ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਪੰਜਾਬ ਅੱਜ 9 ਅਗਸਤ ਨੂੰ ਬੰਦ ਹੈ। ਮਨੀਪੁਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿੰਸਕ ਝੜਪਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਵਹਿਸ਼ੀ ਵਿਵਹਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਨਾਰਾਜ਼ ਦਲਿਤ ਅਤੇ ਈਸਾਈ ਭਾਈਚਾਰਿਆਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਬੰਦ ਦੇ ਸੱਦੇ ਦੇ ਮੱਦੇਨਜ਼ਰ ਸੂਬੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਈ ਸਕੂਲ ਬੰਦ ਹਨ। "},{"question":"VaMugabe Vanoshamisa Veruzhinji Vachiti Vasiya Basa","answer":"Vange vari mutungamiri wenyika, VaRobert Mugabe, vasiya basa rekutungamira hurumende mushure mekunge vazivisa paramende kuti vasiya basa semutungamiri wenyika. VaMugabe vatora danho iri panguva iyo paramende yanga ichitora matanho ekuvapomera mhosva sezviri mubumbiro remitemo yenyika, pachishandiswa nzira ye impeachment. Mutauriri wedare reparamende, VaJacob Mudenda, vaudza nhengo dzeparamende dzanga dzaungana kuHarare International Conference Centre, kuti hurongwa hwe impeachment hwava kumiswa sezvo VaMugabe vabvuma kubva pachigaro. Gurukota rezvemutemo, VaHappyton Bonyongwe, ndivo vanonzi vatura shoko rekusiya basa kwaVaMugabe kuna VaMudenda, izvo zvinonzi VaBonyongwe vatombopengerwa nedzimwe nhengo dzeparamende dzanga dzafunga kuti vari kuda kukanganisa hurongwa hwe impeachment hwanga hwatanga. VaMugabe vasiya basa zvichitevera kupindira kwakaita mauto nemusi weChipiri svondo rapera achiti zvinhu zvanga zvaipa munyika, kusanganisira kuparara kwehupfumi munyika. Bato reZanu PF rakatobuda nechisungo chekuti vakadzingwa semutevedzeri waVaMugabe muhurumende nemuZanu PF, VaEmmerson Mnangagwa, ndivo vari kutora basa raiitwa naVaMugabe. VaMugabe vakaberekwa musi wa 21 Kukadzi 1924 kwaKutama mudunhu reMashonaland West. Vakadzidza paKutama neku Fort Hare University kuSouth Africa, mushure vakazoshanda semurairidzi. Zanu PF yatosvitsa zita raVaMnangagwa kuti vatambirwe zviri pamutemo semutungamiri wenyika. Pasi pemitemo yenyika, VaMnangagwa vanofanirwa kutora mhiko yekuva mutungamiri wenyika achabata matomu kusvika panoitwa sarudzo gore rinouya. Muna 1963, VaMugabe vakasarudzwa semunyori mukuru webato idzva rakanga raumbwa reZimbabwe African National Union, Zanu. Vakazosarudzwa semutungamiri webato iri muna 1975, muna 1980 vakazosarudzwa kuve mutungamiri wehurumende yeZimbabwe zvichitevera kukunda kwebato ravo musarudzo. Muna 1987, vakazove mutungamiri wenyika kusvika kusiya kwavo basa neChipiri, Mbudzi 21, 2017. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ਘਰੁ ੧ ॥ਕਿਆ ਤੂ ਰਤਾ ਦੇਖਿ ਕੈ ਪੁਤ੍ਰ ਕਲਤ੍ਰ ਸੀਗਾਰ ॥ਰਸ ਭੋਗਹਿ ਖੁਸੀਆ ਕਰਹਿ ਮਾਣਹਿ ਰੰਗ ਅਪਾਰ ॥ਬਹੁਤੁ ਕਰਹਿ ਫੁਰਮਾਇਸੀ ਵਰਤਹਿ ਹੋਇ ਅਫਾਰ ॥ਕਰਤਾ ਚਿਤਿ ਨ ਆਵਈ ਮਨਮੁਖ ਅੰਧ ਗਵਾਰ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਸੁਖਦਾਤਾ ਹਰਿ ਸੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਪਾਈਐ ਕਰਮਿ ਪਰਾਪਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਕਪੜਿ ਭੋਗਿ ਲਪਟਾਇਆ ਸੁਇਨਾ ਰੁਪਾ ਖਾਕੁ ॥ਹੈਵਰ ਗੈਵਰ ਬਹੁ ਰੰਗੇ ਕੀਏ ਰਥ ਅਥਾਕ ॥ਕਿਸ ਹੀ ਚਿਤਿ ਨ ਪਾਵਹੀ ਬਿਸਰਿਆ ਸਭ ਸਾਕ ॥ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰਿ ਭੁਲਾਇਆ ਵਿਣੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਨਾਪਾਕ ॥੨॥ਲੈਦਾ ਬਦ ਦੁਆਇ ਤੂੰ ਮਾਇਆ ਕਰਹਿ ਇਕਤ ॥ਜਿਸ ਨੋ ਤੂੰ ਪਤੀਆਇਦਾ ਸੋ ਸਣੁ ਤੁਝੈ ਅਨਿਤ ॥ਅਹੰਕਾਰੁ ਕਰਹਿ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀਆ ਵਿਆਪਿਆ ਮਨ ਕੀ ਮਤਿ ॥ਤਿਨਿ ਪ੍ਰਭਿ ਆਪਿ ਭੁਲਾਇਆ ਨਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਜਾਤਿ ਨ ਪਤਿ ॥੩॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰਿ ਪੁਰਖਿ ਮਿਲਾਇਆ ਇਕੋ ਸਜਣੁ ਸੋਇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜਨ ਕਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਏਕੁ ਹੈ ਕਿਆ ਮਾਣਸ ਹਉਮੈ ਰੋਇ ॥ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਜਨ ਭਾਵੈ ਸੋ ਕਰੇ ਦਰਿ ਫੇਰੁ ਨ ਪਾਵੈ ਕੋਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਰਤਾ ਰੰਗਿ ਹਰਿ ਸਭ ਜਗ ਮਹਿ ਚਾਨਣੁ ਹੋਇ ॥੪॥੧॥੭੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 42 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ! ਹੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ) ਅੰਨੇ੍ਹ ਹੋਏ ਮਨੱੁਖ ! ਹੇ ਮੂਰਖ ! ਤੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਪੁੱਤਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੀ) ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦੇ ਹਾਵ-ਭਾਵ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਕਿਉਂ ਮਸਤ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ ? ਤੂੰ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਕਈ) ਰਸ ਭੋਗਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ (ਕਈ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ) ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀਆਂ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ (ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀਆਂ) ਮੌਜਾਂ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਤੂੰ ਬੜੇ ਹੁਕਮ (ਭੀ) ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀ ਹੋ ਕੇ (ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਵਾਲਾ) ਵਰਤਾਉ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਹੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ! ਹੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ) ਅੰਨੇ੍ਹ ਹੋਏ ਮਨੱੁਖ ! ਹੇ ਮੂਰਖ !ਤੈਨੂੰ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਚੇਤੇ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਿਹਾ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਪਣੀ ਹੀ) ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾੳੇੁ।(ਹੇ ਮੂਰਖ !) ਤੂੰ ਖਾਣ ਵਿਚ ਹੰਢਾਣ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਸੋਨਾ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਇਕੱਠੀ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂਤੂੰ ਕਈ ਕਿਸਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਧੀਆ ਘੋੜੇ, ਵਧੀਆ ਹਾਥੀ ਤੇ ਕਦੇ ਨਾਹ ਥੱਕਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਰਥ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਕਰ ਲਏ ਹਨ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਮਸਤੀ ਵਿਚ) ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਾਕ ਸਨਬੰਧੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ (ਭੀ) ਭੁਲਾ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈਂ, ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਿੱਤ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਿਆਉਂਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਤੂੰ (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿਚ) ਗੰਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਸਿਰਜਨਹਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ (ਤੈਨੂੰ) ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨੋਂ ਲਾਹ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਮੂਰਖ !) ਤੂੰ (ਧੱਕੇ ਧੋੜੇ ਕਰ ਕੇ) ਮਾਇਆ ਇਕੱਠੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ (ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ) ਬਦ‑ਅਸੀਸਾਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ (ਪਰ) ਜਿਸ (ਪਰਵਾਰ) ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ (ਇਸ ਮਾਇਆ ਨਾਲ) ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਉਹ ਤੇਰੇ ਸਮੇਤ ਹੀ ਨਾਸਵੰਤ ਹੈਹੇ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀ ! ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਦੇ ਦਬਾਉ ਹੇਠ ਆਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈਂ ਤੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ) ਮਾਣ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂਜਿਸ (ਮੰਦ ਭਾਗੀ ਜੀਵ) ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ) ਨਾਹ ਉਸ ਦੀ (ਉੱਚੀ) ਜਾਤਿ (ਮੁੱਲ ਪਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ) ਨਾਹ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਾਲੀ ਕੋਈ) ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ।੩।ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਸੱਜਣ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਉਸ ਸੇਵਕ ਦਾ ਰਾਖਾ (ਹਰ ਥਾਂ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ । ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਕੁਝ ਵਿਗਾੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੇ । (ਪਰ ਆਪਣੀ) ਹਉਮੈ ਵਿਚ (ਫਸਿਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਦੁਖੀ (ਹੀ) ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਨੂੰ ਜੋ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਉਹੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਮੋੜਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਚਾਨਣ(-ਮੁਨਾਰਾ) ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧।੭੧।\\""},{"question":": ماذا تسمى القواعد التي يتفق عليها مستخدمو المواقع والصفحات والانترنت ؟","answer":"الإجابة: Protocol"},{"question":"Takip eden paragrafı tamamlayınız: Dünya genelinde birçok ülke, iklim değişikliği ile mücadele için çeşitli önlemler ve politikalar benimsemektedir. Örneğin, Çin, yenilenebilir enerjiye yatırım yapmakta ve elektrik üretimini kömürden daha temiz kaynaklara kaydırmaktadır. ABD, Paris İklim Anlaşması'na geri dönme kararı almış ve yenilenebilir enerjiye geçiş için teşvikler sunmaktadır. Avrupa Birliği, karbon nötr olma hedefini benimsemiş ve yeşil enerji üretimi gibi politikaları uygulamaktadır. İskandinav ülkeleri, temiz enerji üretiminde liderdir ve hidroelektrik ve rüzgar enerjisi gibi ","answer":"yenilenebilir kaynaklara yatırım yapmışlardır. Bunlar sadece birkaç örnek olup, birçok ülke kendi koşullarına uygun stratejiler geliştirip uygulamaktadır. İklim değişikliği ile mücadele, uluslararası işbirliği ve çok taraflı çabaları gerektirir."},{"question":"Ity misy ampahan-dahatsoratra: \\"'Mampametra-panontaniana ny mpanara-baovao etsy ankilan’izay ny kalitaon’ireo karatra hoe tena mampiseho ny fahavononan’ny firenena hiatrika fifidianana tokoa ve ary tena manaraka ny fenitra mifandraika amin’izany?\\"Inona no mampametra-panontaniana ny mpanara-baovao?","answer":"Mampametra-panontaniana ny mpanara-baovao ny kalitaon’ireo karatra hoe tena mampiseho ny fahavononan’ny firenena hiatrika fifidianana tokoa ve ary tena manaraka ny fenitra mifandraika amin’izany?"},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Gambie nékk","answer":"Réwum Gambie mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Afrique"},{"question":"日本で、最高裁判所以外の裁判所を、総称して何と呼ぶでしょう？","answer":"下級裁判所"},{"question":"வினா: தொலைக்காட்சியில் ஒளிபரப்பப்படும் வானிலை படம் எவ்வுயரத்தில் இருந்து சுற்றி வரும் செயற்கை துணைக்கோளால் படம் பிடிக்கிறது?","answer":"விடை: 36,000 கி.மீ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud cakar ayam?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah tulisan sangat buruk. Contoh ayat: Doktor-doktor sering dianggap mempunyai tulisan cakar ayam."},{"question":"Nadine Ibrahim","answer":"Nadine Ibrahim (tí a bí ní ọdún 1993/1994 ) jẹ́ olùdarí eré ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà.A bí Ibrahim ní ìlú Kaduna ó sì dàgbà sí inú ẹ̀sìn Mùsùlùmí. Ìyá rẹ̀ tí orúkọ rẹ̀ n ṣe Amina J. Mohammed ti fìgbà kan jẹ́ òjíṣẹ́ ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà rìí fún ètò àyíká. Láti ìgbà tí ó ti wà lọ́mọdé ni ó ti ní ìfẹ́ sí ṣíṣe fíìmù. Ó kó lọ sí Ilẹ̀ọba Aṣọ̀kan nígbà tí ó wà lọ́mọ ọdún mẹ́rìnlá níbi tí ó ti kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ṣíṣe fíìmù láti ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga Gloucestershire University. Ó tún maá n ṣiṣẹ́ lóri àwọn iṣẹ́ àkànṣe fún Ajo Agbaye pẹ̀lú ṣíṣe àwọn fíìmù tó dá lóri ìrírí ayé. Ibrahim jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn tí wọ́n gbé eré tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Hakkunde jáde. Eré náà dá lóri ará Gúúsù Nàìjíríà kan tí ó ṣe alábàápàdé àṣà Ariwa fún ìgbà àkọ́kọ́.Ibrahim tọ́ka sí Tyler Perry, Alfred Hitchcock, Spike Lee àti Ang Lee gẹ́gẹ́bi àwọn àwòkọ́ṣe rẹ̀. Ó tún tọ́ka sí ìyá rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bi ẹni tí ó tún ní ipa pàtàkì lóri rẹ̀. Wọ́n dárúkọ rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bi ọ̀kan lára àwọn ọ̀dọ́ olùbéréjáde tí ó ní ìlérí jùlọ ní Nàìjíríà. Ibrahim ṣe ìgbeyàwó pẹ̀lú Nasir ní ìlú Àbújá ní ọdún 2014."},{"question":"Waxad Sheegtaa shinida imisa indhood ayay leedahay ?","answer":"Shinida waxay  shan(5) indhood.."},{"question":"An bhfuil an Páirtí polaitíochta Sinn Féin ag prapáil chun freastal ar Westminster?","answer":"Silím gur Scéal earraigh is ea é, dar le Lucht Oibre na Breataine agus Sinn Féin.Duairt an Lucht Oibre, go raibh siad ag iarraidh tacaíocht sa pharlaimint ó Shinn Féin tar éis an toghcháin sa Bhealtaine.Ach dar le Sinn Féin, dtabharfaidís droim láimhe le croípholasaí agus go nglacfaidís lena suíocháin i Westminster."},{"question":"世界上的“風車之國”是指哪個國家？","answer":"1229年,荷蘭人發明了第一座為人類提供動力的風車，從此風車成為荷蘭民族文化的象徵。"},{"question":"俗に、損な役回りをさせられるときに引くのは「貧乏くじ」ですが、見たい項目を探す時に引くのは「何くじ」でしょう？","answer":"もくじ（目次）です。"},{"question":"Welk belangrijke gebeurtenis gaat de volgende tekst over: Floto nam in 2016 deel aan de Olympische Spelen, hij won de eerste ronde van Samuli Piippo, de tweede ronde van Khairul Anuar Mohamad maar verloor in de derde ronde van Ku Bon-chan die later Olympisch kampioen werd.","answer":"De Olympische Spelen waar Floto aan deel nam."},{"question":"السؤال: الهجرة النبوية من أين كانت وإلى أين؟","answer":"الإجابة: هاجر النبي صلى الله عليه وسلم من مكة المكرمة إلى المدينة المنورة."},{"question":"Поясни, хто такі трилобіти","answer":"Трилобіти — найдавніші з відомих створінь. Не так давно було вивчено понад 10 тис. їх видів різноманітних форм і розмірів. Їхні закам’янілі останки виявили у всіх куточках світу, але тільки в гірських породах палеозойської ери. Трилобіти були схожі як на ракоподібних (мали тверді панцири), так і на комах. Ці істоти отримали свою назву через те, що їхній тулуб був захищений панциром, поділеним на три частини. Завдяки своїй особливості трилобіти могли у разі небезпеки згортатися в кульку. Численні ноги дозволяли їм пересуватися піщаним дном моря. Трилобітів вважають одними з перших живих істот."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Thời gian gần đây, pilates và nước hoa niche là hai cụm từ được giới trẻ dành nhiều sự quan tâm đặc biệt trên mạng xã hội. Nếu muốn dáng đẹp, dáng xinh thì lao tới phòng tập pilates, còn muốn vừa thơm vừa độc thì hội GenZ lại rủ tai nhau về nước hoa niche – những chai nước hoa được sản xuất với số lượng có hạn, pha thủ công và dĩ nhiên là… không rẻ. Thế thì một cửa hàng mới ngay giữa trung tâm Vincom Center Đồng Khởi, độc quyền phân phối 20 dòng nước hoa Niche ở Việt Nam, rộng gấp đôi so với phòng nước hoa như trong Vlog của Trấn Thành, tưởng quen thuộc với khách hàng nhờ phong cách retro như ViinRiic giờ lại mang tinh thần mới rất GenZ sẽ còn xịn xò thế nào hơn nữa? ViinRiic Galeries De Parfums ra đời vào năm 2015, là boutique nước hoa đầu tiên và duy nhất mang đúng tinh thần và trải nghiệm nước hoa niche-indie quốc tế, chuyên nghiệp và an toàn, cũng là nơi mà mang đến giá trị trải nghiệm mua sắm khác lạ độc đáo, lẫn sự đáng tin nhất tại Việt Nam. Giới sưu tầm nước hoa và người mua sắm văn minh ưu ái gọi ViinRiic là thánh địa mùi hương tại Việt Nam. Không dừng lại ở việc mang đến các sáng tạo thơm độc đáo, cao cấp, chính quy, ViinRiic tăng tính trải nghiệm bằng những ngôn ngữ thiết kế cửa hàng rất \\"lạ\\". Vượt qua những căn bản lối mòn là cửa hàng vật lí cao cấp với quầy \\"bar\\" hay \\"lab\\", ViinRiic đã đem đến cho khách hàng cảm giác mãn nhãn bằng các thiết kế phá bỏ định kiến về một cửa hàng. Mới đây, thánh địa mùi hương có mặt tại Vincom Center Đồng Khởi, địa điểm mua sắm cao cấp, nhộn nhịp và trẻ trung nhất Sài Gòn. Tại đây, một cửa hàng mang phong cách Avent Garde rất GenZ với tường gạch xám – xanh, ưu tiên những mùi hương GenZ tại vị trí trung tâm như EX NIHILO, Aterlier Materi, Histoires De Parfumes,… kèm theo đó là những nhà hương Niche đang được yêu mến bậc nhất như Roja, Amouage,.. vẫn được dành những góc riêng biệt rất sang trọng đậm màu ViinRiic. Chia sẻ về phong cách đậm chất GenZ trong cửa hàng mới này, anh Eric Trần – một trong hai người sáng lập nên ViinRiic chia sẻ: \\"Chúng ta thường hiểu rằng, GenZ là một cái gì đó bứt phá, vượt quá giới hạn, vượt qua các rào cản hay một chuẩn mực từ trước giờ mọi người vẫn cho rằng không hề thay đổi được. Thì ViinRiic - Vincom Đồng Khởi đã phá vỡ định kiến về một cửa hàng vật lí thông thường, quầy kệ chỉn chu mà mọi người hoặc những khách hàng cao cấp thường hay thấy. Chúng tôi lấy cảm hứng và sử dụng luôn chất liệu gạch block để phá vỡ những định kiến về loại vật liệu bình dân này và đặt nó đúng vào vị trí để nó trở nên hữu dụng, xinh đẹp, sang trọng. Cũng như các thương hiệu lớn, từ thời trang, trang sức… hiện nay, tệp khách hàng GenZ đã được quan tâm rất nhiều, thậm chí được nghiên cứu sâu sắc để khai thác mạnh. ViinRiic cũng thế, cũng đã thay đổi cách tiếp cận bằng ngôn ngữ thiết kế khác lạ cửa hàng, chill hơn, thời thượng hơn bắt kịp xu hướng hơn. GenZ và ViinRiic hướng tới, không chỉ là các thương hiệu được lựa chọn phân phối nữa, mà thay đổi luôn về mặt thị giác. GenZ rồi cũng sẽ lớn lên trở thành một \\"người lớn\\" vì vậy ViinRiic vẫn luôn giữ cái core cửa hàng đúng chuẩn mực luxury và tinh thần GenZ đó chính là cách tiếp cận, thiết kế, phong cách, trải nghiệm…\\". Và vẫn giữ nguyên tinh thần ViinRiic, người yêu mùi hương có thể đặt lịch hẹn trước cho những buổi trò chuyện về mùi hương riêng và chu đáo cùng những chuyên gia mùi hương của thánh địa thơm. Bên cạnh đó, bạn cũng có thể tự do ghé thăm hệ thống các cửa hàng nước hoa cao cấp của ViinRiic tại 2 đầu Sài Gòn và Hà Nội, tổng cộng 6 điểm đến, để chủ động tìm hiểu và khám phá cho mình những sáng tạo thơm mang dấu ấn \\"chữ kí\\" riêng biệt. Đầy đủ ngần ấy những tên tuổi thơm rạng danh thế giới tề tựu, song ở mỗi boutique ViinRiic, bạn sẽ có trải nghiệm khác biệt, bởi mỗi thánh địa thơm lại có một ngôn ngữ thiết kế độc đáo riêng. Nhiều người đặt câu hỏi, nếu đưa nước hoa niche vào trong một trung tâm thương mại đông đúc như Vincom: có khi nào phần thương mại sẽ đánh mất tinh thần niche hay không? Câu trả lời là không. Bởi dù rất GenZ hay tọa lạc ở nơi đông đúc giữa lòng Sài Gòn như Vincom Đồng Khởi thì ViinRiic vẫn có một góc rất riêng, kín đáo và riêng biệt. Tại không gian thơm độc đáo và chuyên nghiệp này, bỏ lại những khái niệm thơm lối mòn và \\"đồng phục\\", chúng ta có cơ hội thưởng thức các sáng tạo thơm thẩm mỹ từ các nghệ sĩ điều hương tài năng quốc tế như Atelier Materi, Pierre Guillaume, Jovoy Paris, Affinessence, Histoires De Parfums… Chắc chắn, cùng là mùi hương, song những lọ nước hoa ViinRiic sưu tầm và lựa chọn cho bạn sẽ rất khác. Ở thánh địa mùi hương, chúng ta sẽ đi từ bất ngờ này đến bất ngờ khác, không bao giờ cạn kiệt cảm hứng, bởi nước hoa không đơn thuần chỉ là thơm, mà còn là những câu chuyện giàu văn hoá và cảm xúc. Từ thời điểm mới ra đời cho tới hiện tại, 8 năm sau đó, những người sáng lập ra ViinRiic vẫn không ngừng dịch chuyển để trải nghiệm và kết nối các nghệ sĩ điều hương tài năng toàn cầu, mục đích sưu tầm những thương hiệu mùi hương giá trị như Roja Parfums, Clive Christian, Les Liquides Imaginaires, UNUM, Matiere Premiere…để làm giàu thêm bộ sưu tập nước hoa của người yêu hương nước Việt.","answer":"Giữa Vincom tấp nập có một \\"thánh địa\\" nước hoa niche mới cho GenZ: Liệu phần thương mại sẽ 'nuốt chửng' tinh thần niche?"},{"question":"Escribe un cuento para un niño de cinco años, tomando la idea del Principito, en una versión nueva y original en 500 palabras.","answer":"Nico y la odisea cósmica Había una vez un pequeño explorador llamado Nico, que vivía en un planeta diminuto muy lejano, llamado Pequeñolandia. En Pequeñolandia, todo era tan pequeño que las flores parecían estrellitas brillantes y las montañas se veían como suaves colinas verdes.Un día, mientras Nico jugaba entre las flores, vio algo reluciente entre los pétalos. ¡Era una estrellita dorada! La tomó en sus manos y la miró con asombro. La estrellita comenzó a brillar aún más y, de repente, habló: \\"Hola, Nico, soy Estela, una estrella viajera. He venido a Pequeñolandia para conocer tus maravillas\\".Nico se emocionó muchísimo y decidió mostrarle a Estela todos los rincones de su pequeño mundo. Juntos exploraron el bosquecito mágico, donde los árboles susurraban cuentos y los pájaros cantaban melodías encantadas. Después, subieron la Montaña Esmeralda, donde encontraron pequeños duendes risueños que les regalaron risas y alegrías.En su travesía, también conocieron a Nube, una nube risueña que flotaba por el cielo azul y los llevó a volar por las nubes esponjosas. Desde allí, Nico y Estela veían las estrellitas en el cielo, y Estela les contaba historias sobre otros planetas y lejanas galaxias.Un día, mientras caminaban cerca del río de agua cristalina, encontraron una extraña criaturita. Era redonda y tenía pequeñas alas. \\"¡Hola, soy Alita! Soy la última libélula de Pequeñolandia\\", dijo con tristeza. \\"Nadie se ha dado cuenta de que soy la última, todos están muy ocupados para notar mi existencia\\".Nico y Estela se sintieron tristes por Alita y decidieron ayudarla. Juntos construyeron un pequeño refugio para las libélulas, y poco a poco, más libélulas comenzaron a llegar a Pequeñolandia. Alita ya no se sentía sola, y las libélulas se convirtieron en las guardianas del bosquecito mágico.Con el tiempo, Nico y Estela se hicieron grandes amigos. Cada día, recorrían Pequeñolandia explorando y descubriendo nuevas maravillas. Un día, mientras estaban en la cima de la Montaña Esmeralda, Nico preguntó a Estela si quería quedarse en Pequeñolandia con él. \\"Me encantaría, Nico, pero soy una estrella viajera y debo seguir mi camino por el universo\\", respondió Estela con una sonrisa.Nico se puso un poco triste, pero sabía que siempre tendría los recuerdos de su aventura con Estela en su corazón. Y así, con un abrazo cálido y un brillo en los ojos, Estela se despidió de Nico y continuó su viaje.Desde aquel día, Nico nunca dejó de explorar Pequeñolandia. Siempre recordaba a Estela y miraba al cielo, sabiendo que, en alguna parte, su amiga estrella seguía brillando. Y aunque Nico nunca volvió a verla, la magia de su amistad hizo que Pequeñolandia fuera un lugar aún más especial y lleno de maravillas.Y así, este pequeño explorador aprendió que la amistad no tiene fronteras y que, aunque las estrellas puedan estar lejos, siempre brillarán en el corazón de quienes las aman.Fin."},{"question":"தமிழ் மொழி எந்த மொழி குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்தது?","answer":"தமிழ் மொழி திராவிட மொழி குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்தது. இது உலகின் மிகப் பழமையான மொழிகளில் ஒன்று. தமிழ் மொழி சுமார் 2000 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக பேசப்பட்டு வருகிறது. இது இந்தியாவின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ மொழிகளில் ஒன்று மற்றும் உலகெங்கிலும் 70 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மக்களால் பேசப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Sheeg aayada qur'aanka ku jirta wax dhibic ah aanan laheyn?","answer":"Waa1.wawaalidin wamaawalad(suuratul-balad),allaahu alsamadu(suuratul-ikhlaas)"},{"question":"Immisa gobol ayey ahaayeen tirada gobollada dalka Soomaaliya ka hor xukuumadii Kacaanka?","answer":"Waxa ay ahaayeen 8 gobol."},{"question":"Lẹyin ọjọ mẹrin to dawati, ileeṣẹ panapana ri oku Abdullateef ninu odo n’Ilọrin","answer":"Lẹyin ọjọ mẹrin ti wọn ti n wa Abdulwaheed Abdullateef, ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlọgbọn, ọjọ Abamẹta, (Satide), ana nileeṣẹ panapana ri oku rẹ ninu odo Moro, lagbegbe  Oko-Olowo, niluu Ilọrin.Atẹjade kan ti Alukoro ileeṣẹ naa, Hassan Hakeem Adekunle, gbe sita, ṣalaye pe ni nnkan bii aago mejila aabọ ọsan ọjọ naa lawọn lọọ wọ oku ọkunrin naa jade.O ṣalaye pe ẹnikan torukọ rẹ n jẹ Ọgbẹni Hassan lo ri oku naa nibi to le tente si leti odo naa, oun lo si fi to ileeṣẹ awọn leti.Adekunle ni awọn ti yọnda oku rẹ fawọn mọlẹbi rẹ.O waa gbadura ki Ọlọrun tu awọn ẹbi rẹ ninu."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Aza malahelo vaky vilany ..................................  \\"","answer":"\\"  Aza malahelo vaky vilany fa manakaiky an ' Ampanataovana \\""},{"question":"बौद्ध धर्माचे महत्वाचे धर्मग्रंथ कोणत्या भाषेत आहेत?","answer":"बौद्ध धर्माचे महत्वाचे धर्मग्रंथ पाली भाषेत आहेत ."},{"question":"వలసలు  మీద వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"జీవనోపాధి కొరకు ఒక ప్రాంతం నుండి మరొక ప్రాంతానికి తరలి వెళ్ళడాన్ని వలసలు అని అంటారు. ఇవి అనేక రకాలుగా ఉంటాయి. ఒక ఊరి నుండి మరొక ఊరికి; పల్లె నుండి పట్నానికి ; పట్నం నుండి పల్లెకు ; ఒక రాష్ట్రం నుండి మరొక రాష్ట్రానికి ; ఒక దేశం నుండి మరొక దేశానికి ; ఒక ఖండం నుండి మరొక ఖండానికి జీవనం కొరకు వలసలు వెడుతుంటారు. వలసలు వెళ్ళడానికి సైతం విభిన్న పరిస్థితులతో కూడుకొని ఉంటాయి. పెళ్ళిళ్ళరీత్యా మరియు చదువుల నిమిత్తం కొందరు ; బ్రతుకు దెరువుకై కొందరు ; వ్యాపార నిమిత్తం మరికొందరు వలసలు వెడుతుంటారు.వివిధ దినపత్రికలు, టీవీలలో, మాసపత్రికలలో వెలువడిన వ్యాసాలు, పరిశోధన పత్రం ద్వారా దీనిని విపులంగా వివరించిన మాట వాస్తవం. ప్రభుత్వం సైతం వాటిని నియంత్రించడానికి పలు పథకాల్ని ప్రవేశపెట్టినప్పటికీ అనుకున్నంత ప్రగతి సాధించలేదన్నది నిజం.ప్రపంచీకరణ నేపథ్యంలో ప్రపంచమే ఒక కుగ్రామంగా తయారయ్యింది. కేంద్ర, రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వాలు లక్షల కోట్లలో చేపట్టే అభివృద్ధి పథకాల్ని కాంట్రాక్టర్లకు అప్పగించడం ఆనవాయితీ. ప్రభుత్వం చేపట్టే అభివృద్ధి కార్యక్రమాల్లో పనిచేసే పనివారి గురించి తెలుసుకుంటే గుండె తరుక్కుమనక మానదు. రాష్ట్రంలోని పలు జిల్లాల నుండి పట్నాలకు వలసలు వెళ్ళే కార్మికులు భవనాల నిర్మాణంలో ఎక్కువగా పనిచేస్తూ, మిగతా చిన్న చితక పనులు చేయడానికి మొగ్గుచూపుచున్నారు. వారి సంపాదన తక్కువగా ఉండి ఖర్చులు అధికంగా ఉండటం మూలంగా నగరాల్లో దుర్భర పరిస్థితులు ఎదుర్కొంటూ కాలం గడుపుతుంటారు.బీహార్ రాష్ట్రం నుంచి వలస కార్మికులు కొంతమంది తెలంగాణాలోని జాతీయ రహదారులకు ఇరువైపుల ధనవంతులు వ్యసాయం భూమిని కొనుగోలు చేసి అక్కడ వివిధ పండ్లతోటల పెంపకం చేపడుతూ, అందులో పనిచేయడానికి ఈ రాష్ట్రం నుండి వచ్చిన వ్యక్తుల్ని నియమించుకోవడం జరుగుతోంది. అలాగే బడా కాంట్రాక్టర్లు వివిధ రహదారుల ఏర్పాటు నిమిత్తం రకరకాల బ్రిడ్జిలు, వంతెనలు, ప్రాజెక్టులు, డ్యాముల నిర్మాణంలో పనిచేసే కార్మికులు ఎక్కువగా ఈ ప్రాంతానికి చెందినవారు.బోర్ వెల్స్ లో పనిచేసే కార్మికుల్లో అత్యధికమంది ఛత్తీస్ డ్ కు చెందిన ఆదివాసులే ఉన్నారు. కుటుంబానికి దూరంగా ఉంటూ, ఎలాంటి లాభార్జన లేకుండా ఏదో మోటు కష్టానికి పరిమితమై పనిచేస్తూ ఎప్పుడు ఎక్కడ ఉంటారో వారికే తెలియకుండా పనిచేస్తూ కాలం గడుపుతుంటారు.భాగ్యనగరంలో ఇటుకల తయారీలో ఎక్కువగా ఒడిషా రాష్ట్రానికి చెందినవారే ఉన్నారు. వారు నామమాత్రపు డబ్బులు తీసుకొని యజమానుల క్రింద పనిచేస్తుంటారు. పేదరికంతో ముందుగానే వారి వద్ద డబ్బులు తీసికొని అప్పు తీర్చుటకు నెలలకొద్దీ పనిచేస్తున్నారు. ఉత్తరప్రదేశ్ నుండి తెలంగాణాకు వలసలు వచ్చి పండ్లతోటలలో పనిచేస్తున్నారు.“ఎన్నో కష్టాలు, మరెన్నో చీదరింపులు, వేధింపుల మధ్య పనిచేస్తూ పొట్టకూటి కోసం పనిచేస్తున్న వలసకూలీల బ్రతుకులను మార్చేవారే లేరు సరికదా! అన్ని రాష్ట్రాల్లో ప్రభుత్వాలు ఎన్ని సంక్షేమ, అభివృద్ధి పథకాలు చేపట్టినా ఆ ఫలాలు ఎవరికి వెళుతున్నాయో అర్థం కాని పరిస్థితి.దేశంలో రోజు రోజుకు నిరుద్యోగత పెరిగిపోతోంది. ఎలాంటి ఉన్నతమైన చదువులు చదివినా నేటికీ తల్లిదండ్రులపై ఆధారపడి జీవించే పరిస్థితులు నెలకొన్నాయి. ‘కనుక ముందు ప్రభుత్వాలు మేల్కొని పల్లెల్లో వ్యవసాయానికి తగిన పరిశ్రమలు నెలకొల్పాలి. అర్హత కలిగిన వారికి ఉద్యోగాలివ్వాలి. కూలీలకు శాశ్వతమైన వేతనంతో కూడిన పనిని కల్పించాలి. ప్రజలు వలసలు వెళ్ళకుండా ప్రభుత్వమే అరికట్టాలి.ఇప్పటికైనా కేంద్ర, రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వాలు వలసకూలీల పట్ల, శ్రామిక వర్గాల పట్ల అండగా ఉంటూ, రక్షణనిస్తూ, ఉద్యోగ భద్రతను కల్పిస్తూ, వారిని అన్ని విధాలుగా ఆదుకునేలా ప్రత్యక్ష చర్యలు తీసుకునే విధంగా చట్టాల్ని రూపొందించాలి. ఈ వలసల నియంత్రణను కావించాలి. వలసలు వెళ్ళేవారికి ఆర్థికపరమైన భరోసా ఇవ్వాలి. అప్పుడే మన భారతదేశం సర్వతోముఖాభివృద్ధి చెందుతుందనటంలో అతిశయోక్తి లేదు."},{"question":"दिइएको वाक्यलाई कोष्ठकमा बताएअनुसार परिवर्तन गर्नुहोस् :तिमी सबैलाई चिन्छौ । ( उच्च आदरार्थी )","answer":"हजुर सबैलाई चिन्नुहुन्छ । "},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Đường lên đỉnh Olympia - 31/7/2022Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Ngày 30-7, truyền thông Indonesia cho biết PSSI đã nhận được thư phúc đáp của AFF, xung quanh đề nghị xem xét trận U19 Việt Nam hoà U19 Thái Lan 1-1 tại vòng bảng giải Đông Nam Á kết thúc cách đây hai tuần. Theo PSSI, từ phút 80 tới hết trận, khi tỉ số đang là 1-1, hai đội U19 Việt Nam và U19 Thái Lan chỉ đá bóng qua lại chờ hết giờ, không có động thái tấn công. Kết quả, trận hoà này khiến chủ nhà U19 Indonesia (thắng U19 Myanmar 5-1 ở trận đấu cùng giờ) gián tiếp bị loại theo điều lệ AFF ban hành. Tức giận trước kết quả này, Chủ tịch PSSI - Mochamad Iriawan úp mở chuyện PSSI sẽ rời AFF, gia nhập Liên đoàn bóng đá Đông Á (EAFF). Chuyên gia bóng đá Đông Nam Á người Anh, cựu HLV trưởng đội tuyển Thái Lan - Steve Darby khi bình luận vụ việc trên truyền thông quốc tế đã cho rằng Chủ tịch PSSI hành xử trẻ con và khẳng định PSSI khó mà rời AFF được. Trong thư phúc đáp, AFF sau khi tham khảo ý kiến từ các đơn vị chuyên môn đã đi tới khẳng định trận U19 Việt Nam hoà U19 Thái Lan không phạm luật. Phía PSSI chấp nhận kết luận này và cho rằng vụ việc khép lại tại đây. Mới đây, Chủ tịch PSSI bất ngờ \\"quay xe\\", cho rằng phát biểu rời AFF chỉ là nói thay nguyện vọng của cư dân mạng, chứ không phải tuyên bố chính thức. Động thái này khiến truyền thông Indonesia \\"việt vị\\", chuyển sang truy vấn Tổng thư ký PSSI - Yunus Nusi. \\"Kế hoạch rời AFF vẫn đang được PSSI nghiên cứu. Chúng tôi sẽ thảo luận về ưu và nhược điểm của việc rời AFF hay không, trước khi ra quyết định. Hãy cho chúng tôi thời gian, khi có quyết định, PSSI sẽ công bố với công luận. Hiện tại PSSI vẫn là thành viên của AFF\\", ông Yunus Nusi nói. Theo truyền thông Indonesia, kịch bản PSSI rời AFF chắc chắn không xảy ra. Phát biểu của Tổng thư ký PSSI được cho là giữ thể diện cho tổ chức này, sau phát biểu hớ và tiền hậu bất nhất của Chủ tịch Mochamad Iriawan. Theo Băng Tâm (An Ninh Thủ Đô) https://www.anninhthudo.vn/so-mat-the-dien-pssi-noi-van-nghien-cuu-ke-hoach-roi-aff-post512339.antd Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS","answer":"Sợ mất thể diện, PSSI nói 'vẫn nghiên cứu kế hoạch rời AFF'"},{"question":"මහවැලි සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහනේ කොටසක් ලෙස ඉදිකරන ලද ජලාශ මොනවාද සහ එ​හි වැඩ ආරම්භ කළේ කවදා ද?","answer":"මහවැලි සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන කොත්මලේ, වික්ටෝරියා, රන්දෙණිගල, රන්ටැඹේ, සහ මාදුරුඔය වැනි ජලාශ ඉදිකිරීමට සම්බන්ධ විය. 1977 දී එ​හි වැඩ ආරම්භ විය."},{"question":"Бүткүл Орто Азиядагы жалгыз президент айым ким болгон?","answer":"Бүткүл Орто Азиядагы жалгыз президент айым деп Роза Отунбаеваны айтабыз.Ал Кыргыз Республикасынын башында 2010-2011 жылдар аралында турган жана тарыхта чоң из калтырган."},{"question":" Sheeg Wiilka Abii Lahab Ee Islaamay Markii Laga Reebo Cudba?","answer":"Waa Muctab Ibnu Lahab"},{"question":"Apakah maskud \\"bawa diri\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud menjaga dan menyesuaikan diri dengan keadaan, atau melarikan diri."},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي يطلق عليها سورة الفرائض؟","answer":"– سورة النساء."},{"question":" Em que ano o Rio de Janeiro sediou os Jogos Olímpicos?","answer":"Pelos jesuítas, forma como são conhecidos os religiosos membros da Companhia de Jesus."},{"question":"ખંડકાવ્ય એટલે શુ ?","answer":"ખંડકાવ્ય એ કાવ્યનો એક પ્રકાર છે. આ કાવ્ય પ્રકાર સંસ્કૃત સાહિત્ય પરથી ઉતરી આવ્યો છે. આ પ્રકાર જીવનની કોઈ એક ખાસ ઘટના કે ખંડને આવરી લે છે. આ કાવ્ય પ્રકારને કવિ નરસિંહરાવ દિવેટિયા ‘પરલક્ષી સંગીતકાવ્ય’ અને ઉમાશંકર જોશી તેને ‘કથનાત્મક ઊર્મિકાવ્ય’ કે ‘કથનોર્મિકાવ્ય’ તરીકે પણ ઓળખાવે છે. પરંતુ ખંડ કાવ્ય આ નામ વધુ પ્રચલિત બન્યું છે.ખંડકાવ્યમાં માનવજીવનના એકાદ વૃત્તાંતનું, એના જીવનના અમુક ખંડનું અને ચાર પુરુષાર્થોમાંથી એકાદ પુરુષાર્થનું નિરૂપણ થતું હોય છે. ખંડકાવ્ય એ નર્યા પ્રસંગને નિરૂપતું પ્રસંગકાવ્ય કે કથા-અંશને નિરૂપતું કથાકાવ્ય નથી; પરંતુ વૃત્તાંતનો ટેકો લઈને માનવસંવેદનને (પછી ભલે એ મૃગ કે ચક્રવાકનું કથાપ્રતિક બનીને આવતું હોય) ઉત્કટતાથી આલેખીને જીવનના ખંડપ્રદેશના નિરૂપણ દ્વારા જીવન સમગ્રને આલોકિત કરતું હોય છે."},{"question":"Төмөнкүнү эмодзилер менен көрсөтүп берчи: \\"Тоого чыгуу, чуркоо, сууда сүзүү -- бул менин сүйүктүү спорт түрлөрүм\\"","answer":"❤️⛰️🚶🏃🏊"},{"question":"மனித உடலில் மிகப்பெரிய எலும்பு எது?","answer":"விடை: தொடை எலும்பு"},{"question":"Apakah soalan untuk: \\"What Separates Me from You adalah album studio keempat oleh kumpulan metalcore / pop punk Amerika A Day to Remember.\\"? Topiknya adalah What Separates Me from You.","answer":"\\"What Separates Me from You\\"?"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"விடுதலை ஏடு பார்ப்பனரல்லாத தாழ்த்தப்பட்ட பிற்படுத்தப்பட்ட மக்களுக்கு அவர்களது விழிப்புக்கு நல்லதொரு துணைவனாக இருந்து வந்திருக்கிறது."},{"question":"सबैभन्दा बढि घरपालुवा जनावर भएको देश कुन हो?","answer":"भारत"},{"question":"How does the Doppler effect in physics explain the change in frequency or wavelength of a wave concerning an observer?","answer":"The Doppler effect describes the change in frequency or wavelength of a wave in relation to an observer moving relative to the source of the wave. When the source approaches the observer, the frequency increases (blue shift), and when it moves away, the frequency decreases (red shift). This phenomenon is evident in sound waves (change in pitch) and light waves (change in color)."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ ረጅሙን ዓለም አቀፍ ድንበር የሚጋሩት ሁለቱ አገሮች የትኞቹ ናቸው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"ካናዳ እና አሜሪካ"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഖണ്ഡിക പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക: കൊറിയൻ യുദ്ധത്തിലെ ചൈനയുടെ ഇടപെടൽ മൂലം അമേരിക്കൻ ഐക്യനാടുകൾ ചൈനക്കു മേൽ ഒരു വ്യാപാരം നിരോധനം നടപ്പിലാക്കിയിരുന്നു. എന്നാൽ പിന്നീട് അമേരിക്കൻ പ്രസിഡന്റായിരുന്ന റിച്ചാർഡ് നിക്സൺ ചൈനയുമായുള്ള ബന്ധങ്ങൾ പുനഃസ്ഥാപിച്ചു.","answer":"റഷ്യയുമായുള്ള ബന്ധത്തിൽ ചൈന ഒരു വലിയ സഹായമായിരിക്കും എന്നാണ് നിക്സൺ വിശ്വസിച്ചിരുന്നത്."},{"question":"What do you mean by Endurance Limit?","answer":"The highest stress a material can bear for an endless number of cycles before failing is known as the endurance limit. Another name for it is endurance stress. The material's yield strength and ultimate strength are more than the endurance limit. It is the stress range below which the material has an endless life under cyclic stressors and no fracture propagation occurs. Fatigue strength, or the highest stress a material can bear for a predetermined number of cycles before failing, is not the same as endurance limit. "},{"question":"තක්කඩි යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"තක්කඩි, යනු මාංශ හොද්දක් තුල තම්බාගත් තිරිඟු පිටි වලින් සෑදු ගුලි සමන්විත ආහාරයකි. මෙම ආහාරය, ශ්‍රී ලාංකික යෝනකවරුන්ට ආවේණික ආහාරයකි."},{"question":"ሳምሰንግ በዓመቱ ወደ ገበያ ይዟቸው የወጡት ሞዴሎች ምን ምን ናቸው?","answer":"ሳምሰንግ ጋላክሲ ኖት 10ጂ፣ 10+5ጂ፣ ኤ90 5ጂ እና የመተጣጠፍ ችሎታ ያለው ጋላክሲ 5ጂ"},{"question":"كم تبلغ مساحة قطر ؟","answer":"11437 كم مربع"},{"question":"Indro misy lahatsoratra:Misy ny hanin-kotrana, toy ny vary, vomanga, katsaka, mangahazo. Misy ny menaka, toy ny voanio, voanjo, ny dibera. Ireo no atao hoe sakafo enerjetika. Izany hoe ireo no sakafo mpanome hery mampandeha ny vatana; nefa mbola tsy ampy izany.Misy ny sakafo manome hery fanorenana izay miantoka ny fitomboana sy ny fikarakarana ny vatana. Ao ny voamaina : tsaramaso, voanjobory, tiasisa, soza, lojy, kabaro... Sy ny sakafo azo avy amin’ny biby toy ny ronono, lôko, henan’aomby, henan’akoho, makamba, trondro….Misy koa ny sakafo mitondra hery fiarovana izay miaro amin’ny aretina sady tsara ho an’ny faritra sasany amin’ny vatana : ny anana , ny legioma, nyvoan-kazo, ny karazana hanitra afangaro amin'ny sakafo (tamotamo, sakitany...).Miresaka momba ny inona io lahatsoratra io?","answer":"Miresaka momba ny karazan-tsakafo io lahatoratra io."},{"question":"Tóm tắt văn bản sau: Hãng AP dẫn lời một quan chức Thủy quân lục chiến giấu tên của Mỹ đưa tin phi công chiếc tiêm kích F-35B Lightning II trị giá 100 triệu USD (2.400 tỉ đồng) bị rơi ở bang South Carolina vào tuần trước, đã hạ cánh an toàn ở sân sau của một ngôi nhà gần đó.Theo nguồn tin, khi đang bay ở độ cao khoảng 304 m và chỉ cách sân bay quốc tế Charleston 1,6 km về phía bắc, phi công máy bay phản lực đã \\"gặp sự cố và buộc phải phóng ra\\". Người này vẫn chưa được xác định danh tính, không bị thương nặng và đã xuất viện sau khi được điều trị tại một trung tâm y tế địa phương.Hiện vẫn chưa rõ nguyên nhân khiến một chiếc F-35B của Thủy quân lục chiến Mỹ bị rơi ở bang South Carolina. Tuy nhiên, tờ Business Insider đưa tin vụ rơi máy bay F-35B của Anh 2 năm trước cho thấy, ngay cả một lỗi bảo trì đơn giản cũng có thể hạ gục một chiếc máy bay tối tân.Vào tháng 8, Bộ Quốc phòng Anh đã công bố báo cáo cuối cùng về sự mất tích của chiếc F-35B. Máy bay này đã rơi xuống biển Địa Trung Hải vào tháng 11.2021 khi đang cất cánh từ tàu sân bay HMS Queen Elizabeth.Phi công đã cố gắng nhảy dù an toàn và nhảy dù xuống sàn đáp, nhưng chiếc máy bay đã chìm xuống đáy biển, nơi nó được tìm thấy gần như nguyên vẹn ở độ sâu gần 2.000 m và cuối cùng đã được trục vớt.Các nhà điều tra xác định nguyên nhân vụ tai nạn là do nắp cửa hút gió bị kẹt trước khi cất cánh. F-35B cần lực đẩy 17,2 tấn để phóng từ sàn đáp của hàng không mẫu hạm Queen Elizabeth, nhưng cửa bị chặn có nghĩa là máy bay chỉ nhận được lực đẩy 14,2 tấn.Điều này không được phát hiện vì thiết kế ống dẫn khí vào của F-35B tạo ra một điểm mù mà chỉ có người trèo vào ống hút mới có thể phát hiện ra vật lạ trong ống dẫn.","answer":"Báo cáo từ Bộ Quốc phòng Anh cho thấy một lỗi kỹ thuật nhỏ cũng có thể khiến tiêm kích F-35B trị giá 100 triệu USD của Mỹ sản xuất rơi xuống biển."},{"question":"ગુજરાતી ભાષા વિષે પ્રાથમિક પરિચય આપો.","answer":"ગુજરાતી ‍ ભારત દેશના ગુજરાત રાજ્યની ઇન્ડો-આર્યન ભાષા છે અને મુખ્યત્વે ગુજરાતી લોકો દ્વારા બોલાય છે. તે બૃહદ ઇન્ડો-યુરોપિયન ભાષા કુટુંબનો ભાગ છે. તે ગુજરાત રાજ્ય અને દીવ, દમણ અને દાદરા-નગર હવેલી કેન્દ્રશાસિત પ્રદેશોની અધિકૃત ભાષા છે.૨૦૧૧ની વસ્તી ગણતરી મુજબ, ભારતમાં વક્તાઓની સંખ્યા પ્રમાણે ગુજરાતી છઠ્ઠા ક્રમે સૌથી વધુ બોલાતી ભાષા છે. ૫.૫૬ કરોડ લોકો ગુજરાતી ભાષા બોલે છે, જે ભારતની વસ્તીના લગભગ ૪.૫% જેટલા થાય છે. સમગ્ર વિશ્વમાં ગુજરાતી ભાષા બોલતા લોકોની સંખ્યા ૬.૫૫ કરોડ છે, જેથી ગુજરાતી ભાષા વિશ્વમાં ૨૦૦૭ મુજબ ૨૬મા ક્રમની સૌથી વધુ બોલાતી ભાષા છે.ગુજરાતી ૭૦૦ વર્ષ કરતા વધુ જૂની છે. ગુજરાત બહાર, ગુજરાતી લોકો દ્વારા દક્ષિણ એશિયાના ઘણા ભાગોમાં, ભારતનાં અન્ય રાજ્યો, ખાસ કરીને મુંબઈ તથા પાકિસ્તાન (મુખ્યત્વે કરાચી)માં ગુજરાતી બોલાય છે. ગુજરાતી વંશના લોકો દ્વારા દક્ષિણ એશિયાની બહાર પણ વિશ્વનાં અનેક દેશોમાં ગુજરાતી બોલાય છે. ઉત્તર અમેરિકા ખંડમાં ગુજરાતી ભાષા સૌથી ઝડપથી વિકસતી અને અમેરિકા અને કેનેડામાં સૌથી વધુ બોલાતી ભારતીય ભાષાઓમાંની એક છે. યુરોપમાં ગુજરાતીઓ બ્રિટિશ દક્ષિણ એશિયન ભાષાઓ બોલનારા લોકોમાં બીજા ક્રમે છે, અને યુ.કે.ના લંડનમાં ગુજરાતી ચોથા ક્રમે સૌથી વધુ બોલાતી ભાષા છે. ગુજરાતી ઉત્તર-પૂર્વીય આફ્રિકા, ખાસ કરીને કેન્યા, યુગાન્ડા, તાન્ઝાનિયા, ઝામ્બિયા તથા દક્ષિણ આફ્રિકા સહિત આફ્રિકાનાં અન્ય દેશોમાં પણ બોલાય છે. બીજે બધે, જેમ કે ચીન (ખાસ કરીને હોંગકોંગ), ઇન્ડોનેશિયા, સિંગાપુર, ઓસ્ટ્રેલિયા અને મધ્ય પૂર્વના દેશો જેમ કે બહેરીન વગેરેમાં ગુજરાતી ઓછા પ્રમાણમાં બોલાય છે.ભારતના \\"રાષ્ટ્રપિતા\\" મહાત્મા ગાંધી અને \\"લોખંડી પુરૂષ\\" સરદાર વલ્લભભાઈ પટેલની પ્રથમ ભાષા ગુજરાતી હતી. બીજા મહાનુભાવો કે જેમની પ્રથમ ભાષા ગુજરાતી છે અથવા હતી તેમાં નરસિંહ મહેતા, સ્વામી દયાનંદ સરસ્વતી, મોરારજી દેસાઈ, ધીરુભાઈ અંબાણી, જે.આર.ડી. ટાટા, નરેન્દ્ર મોદી અને મહમદ અલી ઝીણાનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.ગુજરાતી એ ભારતીય આર્ય કુટુંબની અને સંસ્કૃતમાંથી ઉદ્ભવેલી ભાષા છે, જે ગુજરાતમાં જ ઉદભવેલી અને ગુજરાત તથા દમણ અને દીવ , દાદરા અને નગર હવેલી જેવા કેન્દ્ર શાસિત પ્રદેશોમાં બોલાતી મુખ્ય ભાષા છે. આખા વિશ્વમાં ૫ કરોડ ૯૦ લાખ લોકો ગુજરાતી બોલે છે, જે તેને વિશ્વમાં ૨૬માં ક્રમની સૌથી વધુ બોલાતી ભાષા બનાવે છે. ભારત દેશના રાષ્ટ્રપિતા મોહનદાસ કરમચંદ ગાંધી તથા દેશના લોખંડી પુરુષ સરદાર વલ્લભભાઈ પટેલની માતૃભાષા છે. ગુજરાતી લેખનપધ્ધતિ નાગરી લેખનપધ્ધતિને અનુસરે છે. નાગરી પોતે દેવનાગરી હસ્તલિપિમાંથી પેદા થયેલી છે, આ બંને હસ્તલિપિ વચ્ચેનું મુખ્ય તફાવત એ છે કે નાગરી લિપિમાં મથાળું બાંધવામાં નથી આવતું."},{"question":"أريد إيجاد عنوان مناسب للنص التالي: التي شملها الاستطلاع شهدت عودة الى النشاط بصفة طبيعية منذ 11 ماي. الدراسة التي شملت 500 مؤسسة كان هدفها متابعة مدى تطور النشاط وتقييم وضع العمال وتحديد أولويات أصحاب URL رؤساء المؤسسات ارتفاعا في الإنتاج ب URL % وتطور ب URL % في التوزيع. وانخفض الطلب بنسبة URL %. وانخفضت الصادرات ب 11.4 % وسجل رقم المعاملات ارتفاعا ب 4.2 % وانخفاضا ب 5.2 % على مستوى السيولة النقدية. وفي ما يتعلق بالمشاكل التي واجهها أصحاب المؤسسات عند عودة النشاط ، كانت الصعوبات المالية الأعلى فيما أكد 23 % من أصحاب المؤسسات ان صعوبات أخرى اعترضتم أيضا على غرار صعوبات في التزود تعطل الإجراءات الجمركية والتأخير في الاستخلاص وصعوبات في URL كانت نسبة الصعوبات ذات العلاقة بالوضع المالي 70 % وهذه الإشكاليات تتمثل في التأخير في خلاص المزودين والحرفاء فيما اقتربت نسبة المشاكل المرتبطة بالرصيد البشري من 60 % والتي كانت أساسا هبوط في نسق العمل وتراجع الإنتاجية . ونسبة 31 % من المشاكل نتيجة تراجع الطلب . أما بخصوص خلاص رواتب الموظفين فقد أكد 78 % من أصحاب المؤسسات المستجوبين أنهم قاموا بدفع رواتب شهر ماي لموظفيهم. فيما بلغت نسبة أصحاب المؤسسات الذين قاموا بدفع رواتب شهر جوان 82 %.وباعتبار تأثير الحجر الصحي الشامل في التشغيل قال 69 % من المستجوبين أنهم لم يقوموا بتخفيض عدد الموظفين منذ تفشي الوباء في مارس الماضي فيما أكد 14 % تأثر 25 % من الوظائف والتقلص يعود اما الى البطالة الفنية أو إلى إنهاء التعاقد. وفي الأشهر الثلاثة القادمة يقول اصحاب المؤسسات أن أصحاب الوظائف المطلوبة اساسا هم المهندسون والممثلون التجاريون وعمال بناء وفنيون ومدققو الحسابات. وعبر أكثر من نصف اصحاب المؤسسات عن حاجتهم الى التمويل لعودة URL الإجراءات الحكومية التي ينتظرها أصحاب المؤسسات والمتعلقة بالجانب الضريبي تخفيض الضرائب وإعادة الحوافز الضربية وإلغاء الأقساط للعام 2020 وتخفيض الأداء على القيمة المضافة من 13 إلى 7 % وإعادة جدولة الديون الضريبية على 7 سنوات. أما انتظاراتهم على المستوى المالي فقد قال أصحاب المؤسسات انه لابد من تسهيل الحصول على قروض وتحمل الحكومة لجزء من نسب الفائدة وتقديم الدعم المالي للشركات على شكل إعانات. ضمان تنفيذ الاجراءات المتخذة بشان منح الاعتمادات التي تضمنها الدولة وحماية القدرة الشرائية لضمان دينامكية الشركات. اما عن انتظارات اصحاب المؤسسات في الجانب الاجتماعي فتتمثل في تحيين مجلة الشغل وتشجيع المؤسسات على المسؤولية الاجتماعية. بالاضافة الى تاملهم لمزيد من الاجراءات الديوانية والادارية والاستثمارية..","answer":"في دراسة للمعهد العربي لأصحاب المؤسسات: 14 % من أصحاب المؤسسات أكدوا تأثر 24 % من الوظائف لديهم."},{"question":"log 2 + log 3 ని ఒకే సంవర్గమానంగా రాయండి.","answer":"log 6 ( log x + log y = log xy)"},{"question":"Ajao ji jẹnẹretọ, ni wọn ba fẹẹ dana sun un l’Akurẹ","answer":"Diẹ lo ku ki wọn dana sun ole kan tọwọ tẹ lọsan-an gangan, nibi to ti fẹẹ ji jẹnẹreto gbe lẹgbẹẹ ṣọọbu itaja kan to wa nitosi South Gate, ni fasiti imọ ẹrọ to wa niluu Akurẹ, lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ to kọja.ALAROYE gbọ lati ẹnu ọkan lara awọn araadugbo tiṣẹlẹ naa ti waye pe ọmọkunrin ọhun to porukọ ara rẹ ni Ajao lawọn eeyan kọkọ lu ni alubami, lẹyin eyi lo ni awọn tinu n bi ọhun bẹrẹ si i ko taya ọkọ jọ eyi ti wọn fẹẹ fi dana sun un kawọn agbaagba kan too ba a bẹbẹ, ti wọn si rọ wọn ki wọn fa a le awọn ọlọpaa lọwọ.Ajao ni wọn ní kó niṣẹ meji tó n ṣe ju ko ja awọn eeyan lole lọ, ọjọ sì ti pẹ diẹ to tí ń ji ẹrọ amunawa awọn onisọọbu to to wa lagbegbe naa, ṣugbọn ti ko sẹni to ri i gba mu lọrun ọwọ ninu gbogbo awọn to n ṣọ ọ.Awọn agbaagba adugbo to gba a silẹ lọwọ iku ojiji la gbọ pe wọn ṣeto bi wọn ṣe gbe e lọ si tesan ọlọpaa to wa nitosi, nibi ti wọn ti n fọrọ wa a lẹnu wo lọwọ."},{"question":"மண்டேலாவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"எமது நாட்டில் முதலில் சிறைச்சாலைக்குச் சென்ற பின்னரே சனாதிபதியாகின்றோம்."},{"question":"Ceist: Cé hé guth an mháthair eile i Coraline. Freagra:","answer":"Is é Teri Hatcher guth an mháthair eile i Coraline. "},{"question":"ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਇਹ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਨਿਆਂਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਮ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਮਜਬੂਤ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ।\\" \\"ਸਾਡੇ ਦੇਸ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ਾਰਾਂ ਸਾਲ ਪੁਰਾਣੀ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਦੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਅਸੀਂ 130 ਕਰੋੜ ਭਾਰਤੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਬਰ ਦੀ ਮਿਸਾਲ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰਨੀ ਹੈ।\\"\\"ਦੇਸ ਦੀ ਸਰਬਉੱਚ ਅਦਾਲਤ ਨੇ ਅਯੁੱਧਿਆ ਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਫੈਸਲਾ ਸੁਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ਇਸ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਦੀ ਹਾਰ ਜਾਂ ਜਿੱਤ ਵਜੋਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਰਾਮਭਗਤੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਜਾਂ ਰਹੀਮ ਭਗਤੀ, ਇਹ ਵੇਲਾ ਅਸੀਂ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਭਾਰਤ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਜਬੂਤ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਹੈ। ਦੇਸ ਵਾਸੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਮੇਰੀ ਅਪੀਲ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ, ਸੁਹਾਰਦ ਅਤੇ ਏਕਤਾ ਬਣਾਏ ਰੱਖਣ।\\"ਮੋਦੀ ਨੇ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਦੇ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਦੀ ਅਹਿਮੀਅਤ ਕੁਝ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੱਸੀ:ਇਹ ਦੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਲਝਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਦਾ ਪਾਲਣ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਅਹਿਮ ਹੈ। ਹਰ ਪੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ-ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਦਲੀਲਾਂ ਰੱਖਣ ਦਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਵਕਤ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਇਨਸਾਫ਼ ਦੇ ਮੰਦਿਰ ਨੇ ਦਹਾਕਿਆਂ ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦਾ ਸੁਹਾਰਦਪੂਰਨ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੱਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਸੰਤੁਸ਼ਟ ਨਹੀਂ -ਸੂੰਨੀ ਵਕਫ਼ ਬੋਰਡ।ਸੁੰਨੀ ਵਕਫ਼ ਬੋਰਡ ਦੇ ਵਕੀਲ ਜ਼ਫ਼ਰਜਾਫ਼ ਗਿਲਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, “ਸੂੰਨੀ ਵਕਫ਼ ਬੋਰਡ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਸੰਤੁਸ਼ਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਅਸੀਂ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਬਣਾਈ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਅਪੀਲ ਕਰਨਗੇ। ਸਾਡੇ ਕੋਲ ਰਿਵਿਊ ਪਟੀਸ਼ਨ ਪਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਵਿਕਲਪ ਹੈ ਅਸੀਂ ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਲੜਾਈ ਲੜਾਂਗੇ।”“ਜਿਹੜੇ ਲੋਕ ਜਸ਼ਨ ਮਨਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਸੀਂ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਹਿ ਸਕਦੇ ਉਹ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਅਸੀਂ ਫੈਸਲੇ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਅਗਲੀ ਰਣਨੀਤੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਦਮ ਚੁੱਕਾਂਗੇ।”ਇਹ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਮੀਲ ਦਾ ਪੱਥਰ ਸਾਬਿਤ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ - ਅਮਿਤ ਸ਼ਾਹ।ਕੇਂਦਰੀ ਗ੍ਰਹਿ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਅਮਿਤ ਸ਼ਾਹ ਨੇ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਦੇ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ 'ਤੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਰਬਉੱਚ ਅਦਾਲਤ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਕ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੀਲ ਦਾ ਪੱਥਰ ਸਾਬਿਤ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਏਕਤਾ, ਅਖੰਡਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਮਹਾਨ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਤਾਕਤ ਪ੍ਰਦਾਨ ਕਰੇਗਾ।\\" \\"ਦਹਾਕਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਚੱਲੇ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਸ਼੍ਰੀ ਰਾਮ ਜਨਮਭੂਮੀ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਜ ਇਸ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਨਾਲ ਅੰਤਿਮ ਰੂਪ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਨਿਆਂ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੱਜਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਵਾਗਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ।\\"ਹੁਣ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਅਤੀਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਭੁਲਾ ਦੇਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ - ਆਰਐੱਸਐੱਸ ਮੁਖੀ।ਆਰਐੱਸਐੱਸ ਮੁਖੀ ਮੋਹਨ ਭਾਗਵਤ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਦਾ ਸਵਾਗਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਬਰ ਬਣਾਏ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਅਪੀਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ 'ਝਗੜਾ ਵਿਵਾਦ' ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਅਪੀਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹਾਰ-ਜਿੱਤ ਵਜੋ ਨਹੀਂ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।","answer":"ਅਯੁੱਧਿਆ ਫੈਸਲੇ ਦੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਨੇ ਕੀ ਅਹਿਮੀਅਤ ਦੱਸੀ?"},{"question":"Bireeki tanka epo feeli, lo ba tẹ awọn ọmọleewe mẹẹẹdogun pa","answer":"Iran buruku ni iran ọhun, iran ti ko dun un wo rara, tori teeyan ba jẹ ori awun, aanu abiyamọ aa ṣe e ni, pẹlu bi ijamba ọkọ tanka epo kan to waye l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii, ṣe sọ mẹẹẹdogun lara awọn ọmọ ileewe pamari ti wọn n pada lọ sile wọn jẹẹjẹ doloogbe lojiji, niṣe lọkọ naa lọ gbogbo wọn mọlẹ bii ẹran aijẹ. Wọn ni mẹta ninu awọn ọmọ ohun lo jẹ pe baba kan naa, iya kan naa, lo bi wọn.Yatọ sawọn to ku, ba a ṣe gbọ, awọn ọmọleewe bii marun-un mi-in tun fara pa gidi, ti wọn si wa lẹsẹ-kan-aye-ẹsẹ-kan-ọrun lọsibitu awọn ologun to wa ni Bareke David Ejoor, ni Effurun, ati ni ọsibitu Jẹnẹra Warri, ti wọn gbe wọn digbadigba lọ.Wọn ni ileewe Army Children Primary School, to wa lagbegbe Effurun, nipinlẹ Delta, lawọn ọmọ naa ti n kawe, wọn o si ṣẹṣẹ maa rin ẹgbẹ titi naa, ibẹ ni wọn n gba lojoojumọ ti wọn ba n lọ sileewe tabi dari sile.Nnkan bii aago meji aabọ ọsan ni tirela tanka ti epo bẹntiroolu kun inu rẹ bamu padanu ijanu rẹ, awakọ naa ko le ṣakoso ọkọ ọhun mọ, lo ba n ya barabara kaakiri, bo ṣe lọọ ya ba awọn ọmọleewe to n ṣeri pada lọ sile kaluku wọn niyẹn, o si pa wọn nifọnna ifọnṣu. Gẹrẹ tiṣẹlẹ yii waye ni dẹrẹba ọkọ naa ti fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ, o sa lọ rau.Ẹnikan tọrọ naa ṣoju ẹ sọ pe bireeki ọkọ ọhun lo feeli bo ṣe n da gẹrẹgẹrẹ ọna naa bọ, ti ko si le ṣakoso irin ọkọ naa, debi ti ijamba yii fi waye.A gbọ pe awọn ileeṣẹ panapana ati awọn agbofinro to tete de sibi iṣẹlẹ naa ni ko jẹ kawọn ọdọ tinu n bi dana sun ọkọ ọhun, tori epo bẹntiroolu kun inu rẹ tẹmutẹmu."},{"question":"Идиш аяк жууганда эмне үчүн калдыратпайт?","answer":"Идиш аяк жууганда калдыратпайт себеби ырыскы качат, үй ичиндеги адамдарга ыңгайсыздык жаратат , жактырбагандын белгисин бергендей болуп калат, анан да идиштер сынат."},{"question":"问题：三星公司在电视领域的发展如何？","answer":"答案：三星公司在电视领域取得了重要突破和市场份额的增长，推出了高清智能电视和曲面电视等产品。"},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng cho câu sau:Tổng (hiệu) chia hết cho 3 là:A. 562 – 123 B. 20 987 + 123 789  C. 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 – 12 D. 1 . 2. 3. 4 + 14 ","answer":"Lời giảiTa có: 3 chia hết cho 3 nên theo tính chất chia hết chủa một tích ta có 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 chia hết cho 3, lại có 12 chia hết cho 3 nên theo tính chất chia hết của một hiệu ta có 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 – 12 chia hết cho 3. Chọn đáp án C. "},{"question":"திருதராஷ்டிரன் தம்பிகள் யாரஂ?","answer":"திருதராஷ்டிரன் தம்பிகள் பாண்டு மற்றும்  விதுரன் ஆவாரஂகளஂ."},{"question":"Latari iyansẹlodi awọn oṣiṣẹ kootu to n lọ lọwọ, ẹgbẹ awọn agbẹjọro fẹhonu l’Akurẹ","answer":"Ọgọọrọ awọn agbẹjọro ni wọn tu yaayaa jade niluu Akurẹ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ ta a wa yii, lati fẹhonu han ta ko bi ijọba ṣe kuna lati dahun ohun tawọn oṣiṣẹ kootu n beere fun lati bii ọsẹ mẹta ti wọn ti bẹrẹ iyansẹlodi.Awọn lọọya ọhun pẹlu oriṣiiriṣii patako ti wọn gbe lọwọ ni wọn kọkọ pejọ siwaju ọgba ile-ẹjọ giga ipinlẹ Ondo to wa lagbegbe Oke-Ẹda, nibi ti wọn ti to lọwọọwọ lọ si ọfiisi gomina to wa ninu Alagbaka, niluu Akurẹ, lati fẹdun ọkan wọn han si Gomina Rotimi Akeredolu.Agbẹnusọ fun ẹgbẹ awọn agbẹjọro nijọba ibilẹ Guusu Akurẹ, Ọgbẹni Rotimi Ọlọrunfẹmi, akẹgbẹ rẹ lati ijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ondo, Amofin Thompson Akinyẹmi ati Orimisan Okorimisa lati ijọba ibilẹ Okitipupa ninu ifọrọwerọ wọn pẹlu akọroyin ALAROYE ni gbogbo ọna lawọn fi ṣatilẹyin fun iyansẹlodi ẹgbẹ awọn oṣiṣẹ kootu to n lọ lọwọ ti ijọba yoo fi ṣohun to tọ fun wọn.Wọn ni o ti to akoko to yẹ ki ileesẹ eto idajọ wa lominira ara wọn ninu ninu eto inawo, ki wọn le lanfaani ati ṣiṣẹ wọn bo ti tọ ati bo ti yẹ labẹ ofin lai bẹru ẹnikẹni.Wọn ni ẹbẹ lawọn n bẹ Akeredolu lati bọwọ fun abala ikọkanlelọgọfa (121), ila kẹta ninu iwe ofin orilẹ-ede yii."},{"question":"பொழுது எத்தனை வகைப்படும்?அ) இருஆ) மூன்றுஇ) நான்குஈ) ஆறு","answer":"அ) இரு"},{"question":"கேள்வி : குடியரசு தலைவர் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்ட முதல் பெண்மணி - ","answer":"பதில் : மனோகர நிர்மலா ஹோல்கர் (1967)"},{"question":"வினா: தமிழகத்தில் பண்டமாற்று முறை குறித்து எழுதுக. ","answer":"தமிழகத்தில் பண்டமாற்றுபழங்காலத்தில் வாழ்ந்த தமிழர் அன்றாட தேவையான அரிசி, பருப்பு, உப்பு, பால், தயிர், மீன், இறைச்சி முதலிய பொருள்களை காசு கொடுத்து வாங்காமல் பண்டமாற்று செய்துகொண்டார்கள்.ஒரு நாட்டின் வளர்ச்சி நிலையின் அடையாளங்களுள் ஒன்றாக அந் நாட்டின் உள்நாட்டு வாணிபமும் அயல்நாட்டு வாணிபமும் வரலாற்று நூல்களில் இடம் பெறுகின்றன. இவை வாணிபப் பொருள், வாணிபப்பாதை, பண்டங்களைச் சுமந்து செல்லப் பயன்படுத்திய வாகனங்கள், கால்நடைகள், நாணய முறை, அளவை முறை, வாணிபம் செய்வோர் என விரிவான முறையில் பல செய்திகளை உள்ளடக்கி இருக்கும்.tamilnadu fishermenகடல் கடந்த அயல்நாட்டு வாணிபம் உள்நாட்டு வாணிகத்தின் வளர்ச்சியாக உருவாகியது. இன்று கடல்சார் வரலாறு என்ற புதிய வரலாற்று வகைமையில் கடல் வாணிபம் சிறப்பான இடத்தைப் பெற்றுள்ளது. வாணிபத்தின் வளர்ச்சியானது வணிகக்குழுக்களையும் நகரங்களையும் மாநகரங்களையும் உருவாக்கியது. தமிழக வரலாற்றில் இவை இடம் பெற்றிருந்தமைக்கான சான்றுகள் தொல் தமிழ்க் கல்வெட்டுக்களிலும் (தமிழ் பிராமி) சங்க இலக்கியங்களிலும் காவியங்களிலும் அகழ் ஆய்வுகளிலும் பரவலாக வெளிப்பட்டுள்ளன. இவ்வளர்ச்சி நிலை உருவாகும் முன்பும் உருவான பின்பும் வளர்ச்சி அடையாத தொடக்ககால வாணிபமுறையான பண்டமாற்று முறையும் வழக்கில் இருந்துள்ளது. பொருளியல் வளர்ச்சியின் அடையாளங்களுள் ஒன்றான நாணய முறை சங்ககாலத்தில் வழக்கில் இருந்துள்ளது. இது குறித்த தெளிவான சான்றுகள் சங்க இலக்கியங்களில் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன (அகநானூறு 293: 6-7, 363:6-8). இந்த நாணயங்கள் பொன்னால் ஆகிய நாணயங்கள் என்றும் தெரியவருகிறது. இருப்பினும் நாணய அறிமுகத்திற்கு முன்னர் நடைமுறையில் இருந்த பண்டமாற்று முறை முற்றிலும் மறையவில்லை.இது குறித்த சங்க இலக்கியப் பதிவுகளைக் காணும் முன்னர் மானுட சமூகத்தின் வளர்ச்சியில் நிகழ்ந்த மூன்று வேலைப் பிரிவினைகள் குறித்து அறிந்து கொள்வது அவசியமாகிறது.முதல் வேலைப் பிரிவினை:ஒரு சமூகத்தின் வளர்ச்சிப் போக்கில் உழுதொழில் அறிமுகமாகி அது பரவலான பின்னர் அது வேளாண் சமூகம் என்றழைக்கப்படுகிறது. இச் சமூகத்திற்கு முந்தைய இனக்குழுச் சமூகமானது வேட்டையாடியும், காய்,கனி, கிழங்கு, தேன் ஆகிய காட்டு வளங்களைச் சேகரித்தும் வாழ்ந்தமையால் இங்கு நிலவிய வாழ்க்கை முறையை உணவு தேடி வாழும் வாழ்க்கை என்று மானுடவியலர் குறிப்பர். மார்க்சியம் இதனை வளர்ச்சி அடையாத பொருள் உற்பத்தி முறை என்று குறிக்கும்.இச்சேகரித்தலில் பயன்படுத்திய கருவிகளின் வழி தம் உழைப்பைச் செலுத்தியமையாலும் அவற்றின் துணையால் எதையும் உற்பத்தி செய்யாமையாலும் இக்கருவிகள் உழைப்புக் கருவிகள் என்று பெயர் பெற்றன. இதன் வளர்ச்சி நிலையாக புன்செய் வேளாண்மையை இச் சமூகம் மேற்கொண்டது. புன்புல வேளாண்மை என்று சங்க இலக்கியங்கள் இதனைக் குறிப்பிடும்.இதன் அடுத்த கட்டமாக கால்நடை வளர்ப்பு தோன்றியது. தொடக்கத்தில் கால்நடைகள் அவற்றின் ஊணுக்காகவே வளர்க்கப்பட்டன. அடுத்து அவற்றின் பாலும் பாலால் செய்யப்பட்ட பொருட்களும் உற்பத்திப் பொருளாகின. இச்சமூகம் குறித்து ‘இதுதான் சமுதாய ரீதியில் ஏற்பட்ட மாபெரும் முதல் வேலைப் பிரிவினையாகும்’ என்றும் இதன் தொடர்ச்சியாக அடிமை முறை உருவானது என்றும் எங்கெல்ஸ் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். இவ்வேலைப் பிரிவினையின் வளர்ச்சியில் கால்நடைகள் பண்டமாற்றின் வடிவமாகிவிட்டன. அத்துடன் அவை தனிச் சொத்தாகவும் மாறத்தொடங்கின. இது குறித்து எங்கெல்ஸ்: \\"கால்நடை வளர்த்த குலங்கள் அண்டைமக்களிடம் பண்டமாற்றுக்குத் தந்த முக்கியமான பொருள் கால்நடைகள்தாம். கால்நடை என்ற சரக்கே மற்ற எல்லா சரக்குகளையும் மதிப்பிடுவதற்குரிய சரக்காக ஆயிற்று; மற்ற சரக்குகளுக்கு மாற்றுப் பண்டமாக எங்கும் அட்டியின்றி அது பெற்றுக் கொள்ளப்பட்டது. சுருங்கச் சொன்னால், பணத்தின் பணியை அது மேற்கொண்டுவிட்டது. ஏற்கெனவே இந்தக் கட்டத்தில் அது பணம் மாதிரியே பயன்பட்டு வந்தது\\" என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். தமிழில் செல்வத்தைக் குறிக்கும் சொல்லாக ‘மாடு’ என்ற சொல் வழங்குகிறது என்பதும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது (திருக்குறள்:400).இரண்டாவது வேலைப் பிரிவினை:வேளாண்மைச் சமூகத்தில் கால்நடை வளர்ப்பு அறிமுகமானதை அடுத்து கைத்தொழில்கள் உருவாயின. இது வேளாண்மைச் சமூகத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட இரண்டாவது வேலைப்பிரிவினை ஆகும். நீரின் துணையால் வேளாண்மையை மேற்கொண்ட சமூகம் தன் தேவையை உழைப்பின் வாயிலாகப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டது. இதன் பொருட்டு உழைப்பிற்குத் துணைபுரியும் வகையில் கருவிகளையும் உருவாக்கிக் கொண்டது. இக்கருவிகள் பொருள் உற்பத்தியில் பங்களிப்புச் செய்தமையால் உற்பத்திக் கருவிகள் என்று அழைக்கப்படலாயிற்று.உற்பத்திக் கருவிகளின் வளர்ச்சியால் கைத்தொழில்கள் தோன்றி வளர்ந்தன. வேளாண் உற்பத்தியும் கைத்தொழிலும் தொடக்கத்தில் இணைந்திருந்த நிலையில் வேளாண்மையில் இருந்து கைத்தொழில் பிரிந்து இரண்டாவது வேலைப் பிரிவினை உருவாயிற்று.மூன்றாவது வேலைப் பிரிவினை:மூன்றாவது வேலைப்பிரிவினையாக வணிகர்கள் உருவாக்கம் அமைந்தது. இது குறித்து எங்கெல்ஸ் \\"உற்பத்தியில் பங்கெடுக்காமல் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்பட்ட பொருட்களைப் பரிவர்த்தனை செய்வதில் மட்டும் ஈடுபடும் ஒரு வர்க்கம் படைக்கப்பட்டது\\" என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். வணிகர்கள் உருவான பின்னர் கைத்தொழிலில் நிகழ்ந்த உற்பத்தியானது தேவைக்காக மட்டுமின்றி ‘பண்டமாற்றத்துக்காக உற்பத்தி செய்யும் முறையாக’ மாறியது. இது குறித்து கார்ல் மார்க்ஸ் மிகத் தெளிவாக ஆராய்ந்துள்ளார். அவரது கருத்து வருமாறு:\\"முன்பு வேளாண் வேலையில் ஓர் உபரி வேலையாக (பகுதி நேர வேலையாக) நூற்பையும் நெசவையும் மேற்கொண்டு வந்தவர்களை முழுமையாக நூற்பவர்களாகவும் நெசவு மேற்கொள்பவர்களாகவும் மாற்றிவிட்டார்கள். இதன் அடுத்தகட்டமாக வீடுகளில் இருந்த இவர்களை ஒரு தொழிற் கூடத்துக்குள் (பட்டறை) வேலை செய்பவர்களாக ஆக்கினர். இம் முறையில் மூலப் பொருள்களையோ தொழிற்கருவிகளையோ வணிகன் அவர்களுக்கு வழங்கவில்லை. அவன் செய்ததெல்லாம் படிப்படியாக அவர்களை ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட வேலையை மட்டும் செய்பவர்களாக்கிவிட்டான். அத்துடன் தாம் உற்பத்தி செய்யும் பொருளை வாங்குவோரை (வணிகர்களை) சார்ந்திருப்பவர்களாகவும் அவர்களுக்காக உழைப்பவனாகவும் நெசவாளி மாறிவிட்டான். அவர்கள் நெய்யும் ஆடைகளை வாங்குவதன்வழி அவரகளது உழைப்பை வணிகன் வாங்கி விட்டான்.இவ்வகையில் உற்பத்தியாளனுக்கும் நுகர்வோனுக்கும் இடையில் தவிர்க்க இயலாத ஒருவனாக வணிகன் தன்னை ஆக்கிக்கொண்டான். உற்பத்திப் பொருட்களை நுகர்வோரிடம் கொண்டு சேர்ப்பது மட்டும் வணிகரது பணியாயிற்று.\\"பண்டமாற்று:வேளாண்மையில் இருந்து உருவான முக்கிய வேலைப் பிரிவினையான கைத்தொழிலும் வாணிபமும் அவற்றின் வளர்ச்சிப் போக்கில் வேளாண்மையில் இருந்து தம்மைத் துண்டித்துக் கொண்டன. குறிப்பிட்ட பொருள்களை உற்பத்தி செய்பவர்களாக கைத்தொழிலாளர் விளங்கினர்.சேகரிக்கப்பட்ட இயற்கைப்பொருள்களையும், வேளாண் உற்பத்திப் பொருட்களையும், கைத் தொழிலில் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்பட்ட பொருள்களையும் மக்களிடம் (நுகர்வோரிடம்) கொண்டு சேர்ப்பவர்களாகவும் வணிகர்கள் இருந்தனர்.இவர்களது செயல்பாடுகள் வலுப்பெறு முன்னர் மக்களின் பண்டங்கள் தேவையை நிறைவேற்றும் ஒரு முறையாக பண்டமாற்று முறை விளங்கியது.பணத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தாமல் பொருள்களின் பரிமாற்றம் வழி நேரடியாக நிகழும் வாணிப முறையே பண்டமாற்று முறையாகும். இது தொன்மையான ஒன்றாகும். பணம் அறிமுகமான பின்னரும் கூட இது தொடர்ந்துள்ளது. உழைப்பிற்கான ஊதியம் கூட தானியவடிவில் வழங்கப்பட்டது. பிற்காலச் சோழர் ஆட்சியில் சமைத்த சோறு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. கொல்லர், தச்சர், குயவர், வண்ணார், முடிதிருத்துவோர். ஆகியோரின் பணியை வேளாண் உற்பத்தியில் கிடைக்கும் தானியங்களை வழங்கிப் பெற்றுக் கொள்ளும் முறை தமிழ்நாட்டுக் கிராமங்கள் சிலவற்றில் இன்றும் கூட நிலவுகிறது. (1968 கீழவெண்மணிக் கொடூரத்திற்கான காரணங்களில் ஒன்று நெல் வடிவில் அவர்கள் பெற்று வந்த ஊதியத்தில் கூடுதலாக அரைப்படி கேட்டதுதான்).பண்டைத் தமிழகத்தில் பண்டமாற்று:தமிழ்ச் சமூக வரலாற்றில் குறிப்பிடத் தக்க ஒன்றாகத் திணைச் சமூகம் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளது.பண்டையத் தமிழ்நாட்டின் நிலப்பகுதிகளை குறிஞ்சி, முல்லை, மருதம், நெய்தல், பாலை என ஐந்தாகப் பகுத்து, அவற்றின் நில அமைப்பு, அங்கு வாழும் மக்கள், அவர்களின் தொழில், உணவு, வழிபடும் தெய்வம் என்பனவற்றை தொல்காப்பியம் வரையறுத்துக் கூறுகிறது.மற்றொரு பக்கம் இத்திணை வாழ்க்கையையும் திணை சார்ந்த ஒழுக்க நெறியையும் குறித்த இலக்கியப் பதிவாக சங்க நூல்கள் விளங்குகின்றன. இவற்றிற்குப் பின்னால் உருவான காப்பியங்களிலும் இவற்றின் தாக்கம் காணப்படுகிறது. திணை சார்ந்த வாழ்க்கை முறையானது இலக்கிய முறையியலா? நடப்பியலின் பதிவா? ஐந்து திணைகளும் ஒரே காலத்தில் நடைமுறையில் இருந்தனவா அல்லது ஒரு திணை வாழ்க்கை முறையின் மறைவையடுத்து மற்றொரு திணை வாழ்க்கை முறை உருவானதா? என்பன போன்ற வினாக்கள் தமிழ் ஆய்வாளர்களிடம் உண்டு.இவற்றிற்குள் புகாமல் சிவத்தம்பியின் ஒரு கருத்துடன் மட்டும் நின்று கொள்வது இக் கட்டுரையின் அடிப்படை நோக்கத்தில் இருந்து விலகிச் செல்வதைத் தவிர்க்கும். ‘திணைக் கோட்பாட்டின் சமூக உள்ளடக்கம்' என்ற தமது கட்டுரையில் ஒரே காலகட்டத்தில் ஐந்திணை வாழ்க்கையும் நடைமுறையில் இருந்துள்ளது என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளதுடன் ‘சமச்சீரற்ற வளர்ச்சி’ என்று அவர் அடையாளப்படுத்தி உள்ளார். சிவத்தம்பி அடையாளம் காட்டும் சமச்சீரற்ற வளர்ச்சியை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் வகையில் சங்க இலக்கியங்களில் காணப்பெறும்  பண்டமாற்று குறித்த செய்திகள் சான்றாக அமைந்துள்ளன. இச்சான்றுகள் சிலவற்றை இனிக் காண்போம்.சான்று: 1 (நெல்லும் உப்பும்)உப்பின் பயன்பாட்டை சங்ககாலத் தமிழர்கள் அறிந்திருந்தனர். நெய்தல் நிலப்பகுதியில் பாத்திகள் அமைத்து உப்பை விளைவித்துள்ளனர். உப்பு உற்பத்தியாகும் இடத்தை ‘உப்புவிளை கழனி’ என்றே குறித்துள்ளனர் (குறுந்தொகை269:6). உணவுக்குச்; சுவை ஊட்டியதன் அடிப்படையில் ‘உப்பமுது' என்ற பெயரால் உப்பு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. தொடக்கத்தில் தாம் விளைவித்த உப்பை மாட்டு வண்டியில் ஏற்றிச் சென்று உள்நாட்டுப் பகுதியில் விற்றுள்ளனர். உமண்சாத்து என்று இவர்களைக் குறிப்பிடுவதால் ஒரு வணிகக் குழுவாக இவர்கள் இயங்கி உள்ளனர் என்று கூறமுடியும். தனிமனிதர்கள் மேற்கொண்ட உப்பு விற்பனையும் இருந்துள்ளது.‘நெல்லின் நேரே வெண்கல் உப்பு கொள்ளிரோ’ என்று உமணப்பெண் ஒருத்தி கூவி விற்றுள்ளமையால்   நெல்லும் உப்பும் சம அளவு மதிப்பில் பண்டமாற்றுப் பொருளாக இருந்தமை புலப்படுகிறது. இதே செய்தியை ‘நெல்லும் உப்பும் நேரே ,ஊரிர், கொள்ளிரோ’ எனச் சேரிதோறும் நுவலும் பெண்ணொருத்தியை மற்றொரு அகநானூற்றுச் செய்யுளும் அறிமுகம் செய்கிறது.நெல்லுக்கு இணையான மதிப்பை உப்பு பெற்றிருந்தமை இதனால் புலப்படுகிறது. ‘தம் நாட்டு விளைந்த வெண்ணெல் தந்து பிறநாட்டு உப்பின் கொள்ளை சாற்றி’ என்று நற்றிணை குறிப்பிடுகிறது. உப்பைக் கொடுத்து வெண்ணெல் வாங்கும் பொருட்டு உப்பளத்திற்குச் செல்லும் ஒரு தாயை குறுந்தொகை (269:5-6)குறிப்பிட உப்பைக் கொடுத்து வாங்கிய நெல்லைக் கொண்டு வெண்மையான சோறு சமைக்கப்பட்டதை அகநானூறு அறிமுகம் செய்கிறது.வேட்டைத் தொழிலை மேற் கொண்டு காட்டில் வாழும் வேடுவர் மான் இறைச்சிக்கு மாற்றாக நெல்லையும், ஆநிரை வளர்க்கும் ஆயர்குலப் பெண் தயிருக்கு மாற்றாக நெல்லையும் பெற்றுச் சென்றுள்ளனர் . கள்ளைப் பண்டமாற்றாகத் தந்தும் நெல்லைப் பெற்றுள்ளனர் .சான்று: 2 பண்டமாற்றில் மீன்உணவுப் பொருளான மீன் பண்டமாற்றில் உப்பைப் போன்று நெல்லுக்கு இணையான மதிப்பைக் கொண்டிருக்காமல் கூடுதல் மதிப்பைப் பெற்றிருந்து என்பதை ‘சில மீன் சொறிந்து பலநெல் பெறூஉம்’ என்ற ஐங்குறுநூற்றுச் செய்யுள் அடியால் (49:2) அறிய முடிகிறது.கடகப் பெட்டி அளவு கெளிற்று மீனுக்கு மாற்றாக பெரும்பயறு பெற்றதை ஐங்குறுநூற்றுச் செய்யுள்(7:1-2) குறிப்பிடுகிறது. காவிரி ஆற்றின் மடுவில் பிடித்த வாளை மீன்களுக்கு மாற்றாக செந்நெல்லைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்ளாது முத்துக்களையும் அணிகலன்களையும் வாங்கி வரும் பெண்ணை ‘பழஞ்செந் நெல்லின் முகவை கொள்ளாள், கழங்குஉறழ் முத்தமொடு நன்கலம் பெறூஉம்’ என்று அகநானூற்றுச் செய்யுள் (126:11-12) அறிமுகம் செய்கிறது. வரால் மீன் கொண்டு வந்த வட்டிலில் அதற்கு மாற்றாக வெண்ணெல் நிரப்பப்படுகிறது (ஐங்குறுநூறு48:2-3). இங்கு வரால் மீனும் நெல்லும் ஒரே சீரான மதிப்பில் உள்ளன.சான்று: 3 (மது)சங்ககாலத் தமிழர்களின் சிறப்பான நுகர் பொருளாக மது விளங்கியுள்ளது. கள் என்றழைக்கப்பட்ட மதுவானது தென்னை, பனை ஆகிய மரங்களில் இருந்து பெறப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன் வீட்டிலும் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இல்லத்தில் தயாரிக்கப் பட்டதன் அடிப்படையில் ‘இல்லடுகள்’ என்று அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இதற்கான மூலப்பொருளாக அரிசி பயன்பட்டுள்ளது. கள் தவிர தேறல், நறவு என்ற பெயரிலான மதுவும் பயன்பாட்டில் இருந்துள்ளன.பண்டமாற்றில் மதுவும் இடம்பெற்றிருந்தது. யானைக் கொம்பைக் கொடுத்து கள் வாங்கியுள்ளனர் (அகநானூறு 245:10-12). மீன் பிடித்தபோது கிடைத்த முத்தைக் கொடுத்து கள் வாங்கி உள்ளனர் (அகநானூறு 296:8-9).சான்று: 4 (பிற பொருள்கள்)ஆடு மேய்க்கும் ஆயர் ஒருவர் ஊருக்குப் புறத்தே உள்ள மேய்ச்சல் நிலத்தில் இருந்து ஊருக்குள் பாலுடன் வந்து கூழோடு திரும்புவதை ‘பாலொடு வந்து கூழொடு பெயரும், ஆடுடை இடை மகன்” என்று குறுந்தொகை (221:3-4) குறிப்பிடுகிறது. பாலைக் கொண்டு வந்து வீட்டில் கொடுத்துவிட்டு அங்கிருந்து கூழுடன் தொழிற்களத்துக்குத் திரும்புவதாக இதைக் கொள்ளலாம். கூழ் என்பதற்கு உணவு தானியம் எனப் பொருள்கொண்டு, ’பாலை விற்றுவிட்டு அதற்கு விலையாக உணவிற்குரிய தானியத்தைப் பெற்றுச் சென்றானெனலும் ஒன்று’ என்று குறுந்தொகைப் பதிப்பில் (2009:413) உ.வே.சா. எழுதியுள்ளார். அவரது உரையின் அடிப்படையில் பாலும் உணவு தானியமும் பண்டமாற்று செய்யப்பட்டன என்றும் கூறலாம். உணவு தேடி வாழும் வேடுவர்களும், மீன்பிடித்து வாழும் நெய்தல் நில மக்களும், நீரின் துணையால் நன்வேளாண்மை செய்வோரும் தமக்குள் நிகழ்த்திய பண்டமாற்று குறித்து பொருநராற்றுப்படை(214-217) பின்வருமாறு குறிப்பிடுகிறது.தேன் நெய்யொடு கிழங்கு மாறியோர்மீன் நெய்யொடு நறவு மறுகவும்தீம் கரும்போடு அவல் வகுத்தோர்மான் குறையொடு மது மறுகவும்.(குறிஞ்சி நில வேட்டுவர்கள் நெய்தல் நில மக்களிடம் தேன், கிழங்கு என்ற இரண்டு கானகப் பொருள்களைக் கொடுத்துவிட்டு மாற்றாக மீனையும் கள்ளையும் பெற்றுக் கொண்டனர். நன்செய் நில உழவர்கள் இனிமையான கரும்பையும், நெல்லில் இருந்து உருவாக்கிய அவலையும் கொடுத்து விட்டு அதற்கு மாற்றாக மான் இறைச்சியையும் மதுவையும் பெற்றனர்.)பண்டமாற்று வெளிப்படுத்தும் வரலாறுபண்டமாற்று முறை குறித்து மேலும் சில சான்றுகள் உள்ள நிலையில் தேர்வு செய்யப்பட்ட சான்றுகளை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டே இக்கட்டுரை எழுதப்பட்டுள்ளது. இருப்பினும் இங்கு இடம்பெற்றுள்ள சான்றுகளின் துணையுடன் சில முடிவுகளை முன்வைக்க இடமுண்டு.சங்க காலத்தை மாறுதல் நிகழும் காலம் (Transition period) என்பதற்கான அகச்சான்றுகள் சங்க இலக்கியத்தில் உள்ளன. மாறுதல் நிகழும் காலத்தில் பழையனவும் புதியனவும் ஒருசேர நிலவும். இவ்வகையில் நாணய முறையும், பண்டமாற்று முறையும் ஒரே நேரத்தில் வழக்கில் இருந்துள்ளன.வணிகர்களும் அவர்களது வணிகச் சாத்துக்களும் (குழுக்கள்) இயங்கிக் கொண்டிருந்த சமூகத்தில் பண்ட மாற்று முறையும் தொடர்ந்துள்ளது.தமிழக வரலாற்றின் தோற்ற காலத்திலேயே (பெருங்கற்காலம்-மெகலாத்திக்காலம்) நெற்பயிர் அறிமுகமாகி இருந்துள்ளது. ஆதிச்சநல்லூர், புதைகுழிகளில் கிடைத்த தாழிகளில் நெல் மணிகளும் உமிகளும் கிடைத்துள்ளன. குன்னத்தூர் அகழாய்வில் நெல்லரிசித் தவிடு கிடைத்துள்ளது. பண்டமாற்றில் மதிப்புறு பொருளாக நெல் இருந்துள்ளது. ‘நெல்உகுத்துப் பரவுங்கடவுள்' ‘நெல்லும் உயிரன்றே’ ‘நெல் பலபொலிக' என்ற சங்கப் பாடல் தொடர்களும்,வெறியாட்டு என்ற சடங்கில் நெல் பெறும் இடமும் இதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை உணர்த்துகின்றன. நெல் வேளாண்மை நிகழும் வளம் மிக்க மருத நிலத்தின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியும், கைத்தொழில்கள் உருவாக்கமும் அதைச் சார்ந்து உருவான அரசியல் மேலாண்மையும் இதன் பின்புலமாக இருந்துள்ளன. நெல்லுக்கு இணையான மதிப்பை உப்பு பெற்றிருந்ததானது (சான்று:1) அதுவும் ஒரு உற்பத்திப் பொருள் என்பதால்தான். அதன் கிடைப்பருமையும் மற்றொரு காரணமாக இருந்துள்ளது.பண்டமாற்றானது பெரும்பாலும் உணவுப் பொருளை மையமாகக் கொண்டே நிகழ்ந்துள்ளது. இங்கு எடுத்துக் காட்டாகக் காட்டப்பட்ட சான்றுகளில் பெரும்பாலானவை அடிப்படைத் தேவையான நெல், மீன், பயறு, கள் என்பவைதாம்.மதுரைக் காஞ்சி, பட்டினப்பாலை, ஆகிய நூல்களில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ள வாணிபப் பொருள்களுடன் இப் பண்டமாற்றுப் பொருள்களை ஒப்பிடும் போது இவை அன்றாட வாழ்வின் பயன்பாட்டிற்குரியன என்பதில் ஐயமில்லை.விதிவிலக்காக முத்துக்களும் அணிகலன்களும் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன.வணிகர்களும், வணிகக் குழுக்களும் நடத்திய வாணிபத்தில் விற்போர் விலையை முடிவு செய்வோராக விளங்கினர். பண்டமாற்று வாணிபத்தில் வாங்குவோர் விற்போர் என்ற பாகுபாடு இன்றி தேவையே முன் நிறுத்தப்பட்டது.இரு தரப்பினரும் தம்மிடம் இருந்த பொருட்களின் உரிமையாளராக இருந்தனர். அதன் மதிப்பை அவர்களே முடிவு செய்தனர். ஆயினும் உற்பத்திப் பொருட்களின் சுழற்சியில் பணத்தின் பங்களிப்புக்கு இணையாக பண்டமாற்று முறையால் செயல்பட முடியாது போனது. பண்டமாற்றில் இடம் பெற்றிருந்த பொருட்கள் குறித்து மேலும் விரிவாக ஆராய்ந்தால் அன்றையத் தமிழ்ச் சமூகத்தில் நிலவிய பொருளாதாரம் சார்ந்த சமூக வேறுபாடுகளை அறிய முடியும்."},{"question":"鯨為什麼“集體自殺”？","answer":"鯨生活在深海，要靠聲納定位系統來辨別方向，尋找食物。當它游到淺海時聲納定位系統來辨別方向、尋找食物。當它游到淺海時聲納定位系統就會失靈，衝上海灘。其他鯨淡了救它也紛紛上岸，結果引起集體死亡。　　還有一種原因認為鯨的耳朵里有一種寄生蟲，使它們的神經錯亂，游上海灘，究竟是什麼原因，還需小朋友們多學文化知識，等長大後作進一步研究。"},{"question":"කටාර් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හැඳින්වෙන නම කුමක්ද?","answer":"කටාර් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව 'ෂූරා කවුන්සිලය' යනුවෙන් හඳුන්වයි."},{"question":"සාදික්කා  ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රෝපණය ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"පරතරය – 20’x20’ ’හෝ මීටර් 6 x 6 (හෙක්ටයාරයකට පැල 250)මෝසම් වැසි ආරම්භ වීමත් සමඟ සිටුවීම සිදු කෙරේ. රෝපණ වල 21 / 2’x21 / 2 ’ප්‍රමාණයෙන් යුක්ත වන අතර මතුපිට පස් හා ගව පොහොර මිශ්‍රණයකින් පුරවා ඇත. ශාකයේ කොළරය පාංශු මට්ටමින් තිබිය යුතු අතර රෝපණයේදී මුදුන් මූලයට හානි නොවීමට හෝ නොනැමීමට වගබලා ගත යුතුය. පැළ සිටුවීමෙන් පසු පස ප්‍රමාණවත් ලෙස වසුන් යෙදිය යුතුය.සෘජු හිරු එළියෙන් ශාක ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා තාවකාලික සෙවන සැපයිය යුතුය. සිටුවීමට මාස 6-12 කට පෙර තාවකාලික සෙවන සහිත ගස් සිටුවන්නේ නම් වඩා සුදුසුය."},{"question":"දිය බෙරළිය යනු මොනවද?","answer":"මෙය තෙතමනය සහිත සාරවත් භූමිවල වැඩෙන පැලෑටියකි.ඇස් පෙනීමේ දුර්වලතා ඇති අයට වටිනා ඔසුවකි. එමෙන්ම ශරීරයේ ඉදිමුම් ඇති අයට මෙන්ම වකුගඩු රෝගීන්ටද ගුණදායකයි .මෙහිද තන්තු බහුලය.කාටිලේජ වර්ධනයටද ගුණදායකය. අනෙක් වර්ග මෙන්ම ආහාරයට සකසා ගතහැකිය ."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക: 1817-1864 ലെ","answer":"കൊക്കേഷ്യൻ യുദ്ധത്തിൽ, 1839 ൽ റഷ്യൻ സൈന്യം അക്തി പിടിച്ചെടുത്തു. അതേ വർഷം തന്നെ അഖ്തിൻസ്കോയ് കോട്ട ഈ സ്ഥലത്ത് സ്ഥാപിക്കപ്പെട്ടു. 1848 ൽ ആക്രമിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഷാമിൽ സൈനികർക്കെതിരായ പ്രതിരോധത്തിൽ കോട്ടയ്ക്ക് ഒരു പ്രധാന പങ്കുണ്ട്."},{"question":"问题：护手霜的功效有哪些？","answer":"回答：护手霜可以保持双手的水分平衡，滋润干燥的皮肤，改善粗糙和龟裂现象。"},{"question":"නිර්මාපකයෙකු වූ මොසාර්ට් උපත ලැබුවේ කුමන රටේද?","answer":"ඔස්ට්රියාව"},{"question":"Explique a piada a seguir Qual a fruta que anda de trem?R.: O kiwiiiii.","answer":"O humor da piada está em fazer um trocadilho entre a palavra kiwiiiii e a onomatopeia de som de trem piuí"},{"question":"විල්පත්තු ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානයේ ඇති තෙත් බිම්වල ඇති සුවිශේෂත්වය කුමක්ද සහ ඒවාට එම නම ලැබුණේ කෙසේද?","answer":"විල්පත්තු ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානයේ තෙත්බිම් සුවිශේෂී වන්නේ විල්ලු තෙත්බිම් පැවතීම නිසා ඒවා වැසි ජලය සහිත පැතලි, නොගැඹුරු අවපාතයන් වේ. ඔවුන්ට සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ඇතුල්වීමක් හෝ පිටවීමක් නොමැත. \\"විල්පත්තුව\\" යන නමේ තේරුම \\"විල් දේශය\\" යන්නයි, එය මෙම මිරිදිය විල්ලු වලින් ව්‍යුත්පන්න වී ඇත. ඔවුන් මී හරකුන්ගේ සහ මග්ගර්(Mugger) කිඹුලන්ගේ නිවහනයි. වෙරළ තීරයට ආසන්නව ඇති කිවුල් ජල විලස් මෝය කිඹුලන් වාසය කරයි, මෙම ප්‍රදේශය එකම ප්‍රදේශය තුළ කිඹුල් විශේෂ දෙකක් නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීම සඳහා සුවිශේෂී වේ."},{"question":"विश्वको सबैभन्दा बढि हुलाक भएको देश कुन हो?","answer":"भारत"},{"question":"Waze wasiyala uHulumeni ngale mithetho yakhe esikhwezaabafokazana emakhanda amakhosi.Uqinisile baba. ODuma abasazikhohliwe bengamakhosi. NgempelauDuma ungekhohlwe sekunguye inkosi kule ndawo. Kukhona nabantuasebemkhulekela. Eqinisweni nje, lo Hulumeni wayecabangeni nje azeashaye umthetho onje?(Ubuso buhwaqabala) Kwakunani nje ukuthi bavotiseabasemadolobheni kuphela? Thina makhosi basivikele ngokushayaumthetho othi masifundiswe ngokusebenzisana nabantu ekuletheniintuthuko. Buka nje manje, abantu sebenezimpawana zokuhlukanaphakathi. Kukhona asebengibuka njengento engathi shu. Abanyebazonda uDuma egameni lokuthi usethathe isikhundla samiengasinikwa uMvelinqangi kanye nobabamkhulu.(Ahebeze ngezandla sakuphika) Cha! Cha! Noma ngabe lo mthethoushaywe ePitoli noma eKapa inkosi iyohlale iyinkosi. Angifundileokuyaphi kepha ngiyazi ukuthi ngaphambi kokushaya umthetho,kudingeka kube nocwaningo. Phela kumele bacwaninge ngosikompilolwama-Afrika kuqala ze bakwazi ukushaya umthetho ongachithiokukhona ngoba bakwethu, kuse-Afrika lapha.(Aneke izandla sakuzivula, okukaMfundisi eshumayela) Ngivumelananawe MaNgema. Uyazi kuyasho ukuthi walunguza esikoleni. Futhi-kenje akukhona ukulunguza ukufunda uze ube nguthisha. Phela uhleli njeungafundisi ngoba yimi kanye nobaba esanquma ukuba ube yinkosikaziyenkosi egcwele1. Phawula ngodweshu lwangaphandle olwaba khona phakathi kukaMaShezinoDuma ngesikhathi kufike unogada wenkosi emzini kaDuma. ","answer":"Unogada wafika emzini kaDuma ezomtshela ukuthi inkosi icela ukudlanaindlebe noDuma. UDuma wala waphetha ukubonana nenkosi uShandu,kwaba nokuphikisana okukhulu phakathi kukaMbandlwa, uDuma kanyenoMaShezi. UMaShezi waze wayalela uMbandlwa ukuba aphume apheleemzini wakhe. Lokhu kwamthukuthelisa uDuma. Emva kokuhambakukanogada uMaShezi wathatha isinqumo sokuphindela kubo. "},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أحرف الجزم؟","answer":"الإجابة: لمْ، لَمّا، لام الأمر، لا الناهية، إنْ، ما، مَنْ، أنّى، مهمَا، أيّ، متَى، أيّانَ، أيْنَ، إذْما، حَيْثُمَا، كَيْفَمَا، إِذَا"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai jawi makan, dimamah dahulu baru ditelan\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya ialah sebelum melakukan sesuatu pekerjaan terlebih dahulu ditimbangkan dan dirundingkan."},{"question":"Frage: Wem gehört das Delano Hotel in Las Vegas? Antwort:","answer":"Das Hotel gehört der Firma MGM Resorts International."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ල‍‍ංකා​වේ නිපදවන ප්‍රධාන සගන්ධ තෙල් වර්ග කිහිපයක් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ශ්‍රී ල‍‍ංකා​වේ නිපදවන ප්‍රධාන සගන්ධ තෙල් වර්ග කිහිපයක් පහත පරිදි දැක්විය හැක.1. කුරුඳු කොළ තෙල් (cinnamon leaf oil)2. කුරුඳු පොතු තෙල් (cinnamon bark oil)3. පැඟිරි තෙල් (citronella oil)4. ගම්මිරිස් තෙල් (pepper oil)5. කරදමුංගු තෙල් (cardamom oil)6. සාදික්කා තෙ​ල් (nutmeg oil)7. කරාබු නැටි තෙල් (clove bud oil)8. යුකැල්ප්ටස් තෙල් (eucalyptus oil)"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira das Maldivas.","answer":"A bandeira das Maldivas é composta por um campo vermelho com um retângulo verde no canto superior esquerdo. No centro do retângulo verde, há uma lua crescente branca e uma estrela branca de cinco pontas. A cor vermelha representa a bravura e a coragem do povo maldiviano, o verde simboliza a vegetação das ilhas, a lua crescente representa o islamismo, e a estrela simboliza a unidade e a paz."},{"question":"Rujuk petikan di bawah dan jawab soalan dalam bahasa yang sama dalam petikan:  Petikan: Di Israel, tradisi Yahudi Tu B'Av telah dihidupkan semula dan berubah menjadi setara Yahudi Hari Valentine. Ia disambut pada hari ke-15 bulan April (biasanya pada akhir bulan Ogos). Pada zaman dahulu, gadis-gadis akan memakai gaun putih dan menari di kebun anggur, manakala lelaki akan menunggu mereka (Mishna Taanith akhir Bab 4). Sekarnag, Tu B'Av dirayakan sebagai cuti kedua cinta oleh orang sekular (bersama dengan Hari Valentine), dan ia berkongsi banyak adat yang berkaitan dengan Hari Valentin di masyarakat barat. Dalam budaya Israel moden Tu B'Av adalah hari yang popular untuk mengisytiharkan cinta, mencadangkan perkahwinan, dan memberikan hadiah seperti kad atau bunga.  Soalan: Bilakah Tu B'Av dirayakan?","answer":"15 April"},{"question":"Andininy voalohany: mainty sy fotsy ny saka an'i Julie.Andininy faharoa: Ny saka an'i Julie dia volondavenona avokoa. Mifanaraka ve ireo fehezanteny roa ireo?","answer":" Tsia, mifanohitra izy ireo."},{"question":" « Omaly sy afaka omaly no efa nifampitolomany tamin’ny fahatezerana mirehitra noho ny namonoana ny vadiny i Ramavo ». Inona no fihetseham-po fonoson’io fanambarana io ?","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho fihetseham-po miiba satria fahatezerana nohon’ny nahafaty tsy fidiny ny vady."},{"question":"Complete the following phrase:  Si bien las primeras demostraciones públicas del invento tuvieron una gran repercusión en la sociedad capitalina, esta disciplina fotográfica terminó utilizándose por un reducido número de habitantes, estimándose en una veintena de personas las que hicieron uso de este invento en Montevideo y el resto del país. Los altos costos del aparato sumado a la difícil situación económica que atravesaba el país, sumido en una","answer":"crisis financiera, contribuyeron a limitar la adopción masiva de esta tecnología."},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:تلاها تحليل نشرته الجهة نفسها في الفترة نفسها، أظهر أن ممارسة دقيقة واحدة من النشاط البدني القوي، من 3 إلى 4 مرات في اليوم، يمكن أن يُقلل خطر الوفاة بسبب أمراض القلب والأوعية الدموية بمقدار النصف تقريبا.ويعني هذا أن الدراسة الجديدة والأبحاث السابقة اتفقتا على نتيجة مفادها أن","answer":"\\"محاربي عطلة نهاية الأسبوع\\" يحصلون على فوائد للقلب من خلال بضعة أيام فقط من التمارين الرياضية، دون أن يتعرضوا للإصابة أكثر من المتدربين الآخرين."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa sanadkii la aas aasay Jabhaddii SNM iyo dalkii lagu aas aasay?","answer":" Waxaa la aas aasay sanadkii 1981kii, waxaana lagu aasaasay dalka Ingiriiska."},{"question":"नानासाहेब पेशवे","answer":" विठूरचे पेशवे दुसरे बाजीराव यांचे दत्तकपुत्र. १८५७ सालच्या स्वातंत्र्य युध्दाचे शिल्पकार. जन्म- १९ मे १८२१, माथेरानजवळ वेणू गावात. मृत्यू- नैमिषारण्यात. मृत्यूची तारीख नक्की नाही."},{"question":"新約聖書から出た言葉で、あることがきっかけで急に物事の真相や本質がよく分かるようになることを、「目から何が落ちる」というでしょう？","answer":"鱗（うろこ）です。"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أكبر صحراء في العالم؟","answer":"الإجابة: صحراء أنتاركتيكا"},{"question":"Wayesababuka kanjalo ngenkathi kungqongqozwa kanye emnyango, kuvulekaisicabha, kungena uXolani ehefuzela, amehlo egcwele izinyembezi. Wangenaesalokhu ehayizile uNontobeko, ebalisa, ebalisa.'Yeka ukukuthanda kwami Mhlengi!''Ngiyaxolisa Nontobeko.''Yisona sizathu owangalela sona lesi?''Yebo,' evuma ngamahloni.'Wawungangitsheli ngani pho?''Kwakulukhuni. Kwakungelula neze,' ephendula ngezinyembezi.'Yeka ukukuthanda kwami! Yeka ukuzethembisa kwami ukuthi sizotholana, sibuyelane,siqhubeke lapho esasigcine khona, si …' Akhale kakhulu. Usevele wankema njeuXolani. Kakulula nokuthi kube khona abuza kuyena. Kuyamdida konke lokhuakuzwayo.'Mahlengi, kwenzenjani?' ebuza ezidela amathambo.1. Chaza isizathu sokuthi uNgidi asebenzise uShezi ekwenzeni uphenyo","answer":"Isizathu ukuthi uNgidi wayesebonile ukuthi akulula ukuzenzela umsebenziongawufundele wokuphenya. Wayesezamile ukuzithungathela uMhlengikwaMashu naseMlazi kodwa wangamthola ngakho-ke kwabalula kuSheziukuthola uMhlengi ngaphandle kokuthatha isikhathi eside njengobawayewufundele lo msebenzi."},{"question":"Inona no vanim-potoana nanitarana Fanjakana Merina tamin’ny andron’i Radama I?","answer":"Teo anelanelan’ny taona 1810 sy 1828 no nisy ny fanitarana ny Fanjakana Merina tamin’ny andron’i Radama I."},{"question":"Qual é a temperatura média da superfície em Vênus?","answer":"460 ° C (860 ° F)"},{"question":"Tambaya: Yaushe ne waƙar rapper's delight ta fito?","answer":"16 ga Satumba, 1979, \\"Rapper's Delight\\" ya kai lamba 36 a cikin Janairu 1980 akan taswirar Billboard Hot 100 na Amurka, lamba hudu akan taswirar Billboard Hot Soul Singles a watan Disamba 1979."},{"question":"Ƙirƙirar kanun labarai don rubutu mai zuwa: A karon farko, Shugaba Muhammadu Buhari na Najeriya ya yi wa 'yan kasar jawabi game da matakan da gwamnatinsa ke dauka a yaki da coronavirus. 1. Tun daga alamun farko da ke nuna coronavirus ko COVID-19 ta zama annoba kuma aka ayyana dokar ta-baci a kanta, gwamnatin tarayya ta fara shiri na daukar matakai na kariya idan har cutar ta shigo Najeriya. 2. Hankalin gwamnati ya tattara ya koma kan tunkarar abin. Zuwa yanzu ta zama matsalar lafiya ta gaggawa da matsalar tattalin arziki. 3. Najeriya, abin takaici, ta tabbatar da bullar cutar a ranar 27 ga Fabrairun 2020. Tun lokacin kuma sannu a hankali muke samun karuwar wadanda suka kamu da cutar. 4. Daga safiyar 29 ga Maris 2020, jimillar wadanda suka kamu a Najeriya sun kai 97. 5. Abin bakin ciki, mun kuma samu mutuwar farko, tsohon ma'aikacin PPMC, wanda ya mutu ranar 23 ga watan Maris 2020. 6. Muna yi masa addu'a da jajantawa iyalinsa a wannan lokaci mai cike da kalubale. Muna kuma yin addu'ar fatan samun sauki cikin gaggawa ga wadanda suka kamu da cutar kuma suke karbar magani. 7. Har zuwa yau COVID-19 ba ta da magani. Masana kimiyya na ci gaba da kokarin gano riga-kafi. 8. Muna tattaunawa da wadannan cibiyoyi a yayin da suke kokarin samar da mafita da hukumomi za su tabbatar cikin kankanin lokaci. 9. A yanzu, hanya ma fi dacewa ta kaucewa kamuwa da cutar ita ce bin matakai na tsafta da kuma nisanta da juna. 10. Mu kasance babban makami na yaki da wannan babbar annoba ta hanyar wanke hannu ko yaushe da sabulu da kuma ruwa mai tsafta, da tsaftace wuraren da muka yi amfani da su, yin tari ta hanyar rufewa da kyalle, ko tsakanin gwiwar hannu da kuma musamman kiyaye matakan kariya na lafiya da za mu iya kamuwa da cutar. 11. Tun da aka fara bayar da rahoton barkewar cutar a China, gwamnatinmu ke bibiyar al'amarin da nazari kan matakan da kasashe suka dauka. 12. Babban daraktan hukumar da ke yaki da cuttuttuka masu yaduwa ta Najeriya NCDC, yana cikin mutum 10 manyan masu ruwa da tsaki a harkar lafiya da Hukumar Lafiya ta Duniya ta gayyata domin ziyartar China don lakantar irin matakan da suka dauka. Ina alfahari da Dr Ihekweazu da ya yi wannan aikin a madadin 'yan Najeriya. 13. Tun dawowarsa, NCDC ke daukar matakai da dama da shirye-shirye a Najeriya domin tabbatar da dakile tasirin cutar a kasarmu. Muna yin kira ga 'yan Najeriya su bayar da goyon bayansu ga ayyukan da  Ma'aikatar lafiya da NCDC suke yi. 14. Ko da yake mun rungumi matakai da aka dauka a wasu kasashen duniya, amma an tsara shirye-shiryenmu daidai da yanayinmu. 15. A Najeriya muna daukar matakai guda biyu. 16. Na farko, mu kare rayukan 'yan Najeriya da kuma mazauna nan, na biyu, kare ma'aikata da 'yan kasuwa domin tabbatar da iyalinsu sun samu sauki cikin mutunci a wannan mawuyacin lokaci tare da kyakkyawan fata da kwanciyar hankali. 17. Zuwa yanzu, mun dauki matakai na kiwon lafiya da tsare kan iyakoki da matakai da suka shafi kudi. Kuma za mu ci gaba har abubuwa su daidaita. 18. Wadannan matakan ko shakka babu za su kawo cikas ga yawancin 'yan kasa. Amma wannan sadaukarwa ce da dukkaninmu za mu yi domin amfanin kasarmu. 19. A yaki da coronavirus, kowanne irin mataki muka dauka ba zai yi yawa ba kuma ba zai yi kadan ba. Maganar kawai ita ce ta daukar matakin da ya dace a lokacin da ya dace daga kwararrun ma'aikata. 20. Don Haka, a matsayinmu na gwamnati, za mu ci gaba da dogara da shawarwarin masana da kwararru a ma'aikatar lafiya da hukumar da ke kula da yaduwar cututtuka, NCDC, da sauran hukumomi a wannan lokaci na tsaka mai wuya. 21. Don haka, nake kira ga duka 'yan kasar nan da su bi dokokin da ake fitarwa a kai a kai. 22. Kamar yadda muka sani, Legas da Abuja ne wuraren da ke da mafi yawan mutanen da aka samu dauke da cutar a Najeriya. Don haka mun mayar da hankali wajen gaggauta dakatar da yaduwar cutar, kuma mu taimakawa sauran jihojin da yankuna iya karfinmu. 23. Shi ya sa ma muka samar da dala biliyan 15 don tallafawa 'yan kasa a lokacin da ake yaki da wannan cuta. 24. Mun kuma kaddamar da wani kwamitin shugaban kasa wato Presidential Task Force, don samar da wani tsari na matakan yaki da wannan cuta, wanda kuma ake bitarsa kullum. Wannan tsari ya kunshi hanyoyin da aka amince da su a fadin duniya amma mun tsara shi yadda zai dace da yanayin da kasarmu ke ciki. 25. Burinmu shi ne mu tabbatar duka jihoji na da goyon baya da karfin daukar matakai da gaggawa. 26. Kawo yanzu, a Legas da Abuja, mun dauki daruruwan ma'aikata na wucin gadi don kara karfin cibiyoyinmu na amsa waya da kuma tallafawa kokarinmu na gano mutanen da ake tunanin suna dauke da cutar da kuma wadanda aka yi wa gwaji. 27. Na kuma bukaci duka gwamnatocin jihohi, ta hanyar Kungiyar Gwamnonin Najeriya, da su tura likitoci da ma'aikatan jinya ga hukumar NCDC da gwamnatin jihar Legas domin horar da su kan hanyoyin hana yaduwar cutar ko da za ta yadu zuwa wasu jihohi. 28. Horon zai hada da wakilan bangaren lafiya daga dakarunmu da sauran jami'an tsaro da hukumomin leken asiri. 29. A matsayinmu na kasa guda, dole ne matakan da muke dauka su zama cikin tsari da kwarewa. Akwai bukatar samar da bayanan bai daya a fadin kasar. Za a kawar da duk wani bambanci a manufofi tsakanin gwamnatin tarayya da jihohi. 30. Kamar yadda na fada a baya, kawo yanzu mutum 97 ne aka tabbatar suna dauke da cutar. Mafi yawansu a Legas da Abuja. Dukkansu suna samun kulawar da ta kamata. 31. Hukumominmu a yanzu haka suna aiki don gano wasu masu dauke da cutar da kuma mutanen da suka yi mu'amala da wadanda aka riga aka gano suna da cutar. 32. Kalilan daga cikin wadanda aka gano suna dauke da cutar a Legas da Abuja sun yi mu'amala ne da masu ita da suka yi tafiya. 33. Don haka muna aiki don tabbatar da cewa an dakatar da zirga-zirga tsakanin jihohi don hana ci gaba da yada cutar. 34. Duba da shawarar Ma'aikatar Lafiya ta tarayya da kuma NCDC, na bayar da umarnin hana duk wata zirga-zirga a Legas da babban birnin tarayya Abuja har tsawon kwana 14, daga ranar Litinin 30 ga watan Maris da 11:00 na dare. Wannan doka za kuma ta shafi jihar Ogun saboda kusancinta da Legas da kuma cunkoson da ake samu tsakanin jihohin biyu. 35. Ana umartar dukkan mazauna wadannan yankuna su zauna a gidajensu. A dakatar da tafiye-tafiye tsakanin garuruwa. A dakatar da dukkan harkokin kasuwanci tare da rufe ofis-ofis a wadannan garuruwa tsawon wannan lokaci. 36. Tuni an sanar da gwamnonin Legas da Ogun da kuma Ministan Birnin Tarayya. An kuma sanar da shugabannin hukumomin tsaro. 37. Za mu yi amfani da wannan dama wajen gano tare da killace dukkan wadanda suka yi mu'amala da mutanen da aka riga aka tabbatar sun kamu da cutar. Za mu tabbatar da cewa an kula da wadanda suka kamu a asibiti yayin da za mu takaita yaduwarta zuwa sauran jihohi. 38. Wannan dokar ba ta shafi asibitoci da sauran cibiyoyin lafiya ba da kuma wuraren da ake samarwa da rarraba magunguna ba. 39. Haka nan ba ta shafi wuraren kasuwanci ba kamar su; a. Wajen sarrafa abinci da kamfanonin da ake sari; b. Wuraren da ake rarraba man fetur da gidajen mai, c. Kamfanonin rarrabawa da samar da wutar lantarki; d. Haka zalika ban da kamfanonin tsaro masu zaman kansu 40. Duk da cewa dokar ba ta shafi wadannan wurare ba, to za takaita ziyarrtarsu kuma za a sa ido. 41. Za a bar ma'aikatan kamfanonin wayoyin salula da ma'aikatan watsa labarai - na rediyo da talbijin da jarida - wadanda suka tabbatar cewa ba za su iya aiki a gida ba, su je wuraren aikinsu. 42. Dukkan tashoshin jiragen ruwa da ke Lagos za su ci gaba da aiki kamar yadda dokoki suka tsara. Jami'an lafiyar da ke tashoshin jiragen ruwa za su binciki dukkan motoci da direbobinsu wadanda ke dauke da kayayyaki daga tashoshin jiragen ruwa zuwa wasu sassan kasar nan kafin su bar tashoshin. 43. Kazalika, za a binciki dukkan motocin da ke dauke da abinci da sauran kayayyakin agaji zuwa tashoshin jiragen ruwa daga wasu sassan kasar nan kafin a bar su su shiga wadannan killatattun wurare. 44. Haka kuma, an bayar da umarni ga Ministan Lafiya ya aika dukkan jami'an lafiya da aiki zuwa tashoshin jiragen ruwa wadanda a baya aka girke su a filayen jiragen saman Lagos da Abuja zuwa muhimman hanyoyi wadanda suka kasance mashiga da mafita daga wadannan killatattun wurare. 45. An dakatar da zirga-zirgar dukkan jiragen saman fasinja, na haya da kuma na masu kashin-kai. Za a bar su su yi amfani ne kawai idan akwai matukar bukatar hakan. 46. Muna sane cewa daukar wadannan matakai zai jefa 'yan kasa cikin kuncin rayuwa. Amma wannan batu ne na ko a mutu ko a yi rai, idan muka yi la'akari da mutanen da suka mutu a Italiya da Faransa da kuma Spaniya. 47. Don hakan, ya zama wajibi a gare mu mu kalli wannan batu a matsayin wani nauyi domin kare kasarmu daga yaduwar wannan cuta. Saboda haka ina yin kira ga dukkanmu da wannan batu ya shafa mu sarayar da jin dadinmu domin kare kanmu da sauran al'umma. Za mu kawar da wannan cuta ce kawai idan muka yi aiki baki daya sannan muka bi umarnin da masana kimiyya da masana harkokin lafiya suka yi mana. 48. A yayin da muka shirya domin tursasa wa mutane bin wadannan dokoki, ya kamata mu yi la'akari cewa wannan wata sadaukarwa ce da za mu yi wajen yaki da COVID-19. Kasashe da dama sun dauki matakan da suka fi namu tsauri wadanda suka ga amfanin su a kokarinsu na hana yaduwar wannan cuta. 49. Daga yanzu zuwa makonnin da ke tafe za mu bayar da kayan agaji ga mutanen da ke zaune a yankunan karkara da ke kusa da Lagos da Abuja wadanda za su fuskanci mawuyacin hali sanadiyar matakan da muka dauka. 50. Kazalika, ko da yake an rufe dukkan makarantu, amma na bayar da umarni ga ma'aikatar bayar da agajin gaggawa ta yi aiki da gwamnatocin jihohi domin samar da tsarin ci gaba da bayar da abinci ga 'yan makaranta a wannan lokaci ba tare da yin karan-tsaye ga dokar yi wa juna tazara ba. Ministar ma'aikatar bayar da agajin gaggawa za ta tuntubi jihohin domin su amince kan tsarin da za a bi wajen aiwatar da wannan tsari. 51. Haka kuma na bayar da umarni ba tare da wani bata lokaci ba da a daga wa masu biyan bashin kudin tallafi na Tradermoni da MarketMoni da kuma FarmerMoni kafa tsawon wata uku. 52. Na kuma umarci da a yi irin wannan sassauci ga dukkanin basukan da gwamnatin tarayya ta bayar ta hannun, Bankin Masana'antu da Bankin Manoma da kuma Bankin Shigarwa da Fitar da Hajoji daga Najeriya. 53. Ga wadanda ke amfani da kudaden basuka na abokanan huldarmu na duniya, na umarci cibiyoyinmu na kudaden Samar da ci-gaba da su tattauna da cibiyoyin na waje da suka bayar da bashin kan yadda za a sassauta wa wadanda aka ba wa bashin. 54. (Ga masu raunin da ake ba wa taimakon kudi na wata-wata don inganta rayuwarsu kuwa, na bayar da umarnin da a biya su na wata biyu na gaba. 'Yan gudun hijira ma za su samu tallafin kayan abinci na wata biyu a makonnin da ke tafe. 55. Muna kuma kira ga dukkan 'yan Najeriya Najeriya su dauki nauyin taimakawa wadanda ba su da wadata a cikin al'ummarsu ta hanyar taimakonsu da duk abin da za iya bukata. 56. A yayin da muke addu'ar samun mafita ta alkhairi, za kuma ci gaba da shiryawa duk wani abu da ka iya faruwa. 57. Wannan dalili ne ya sa na umarci a mayar da filayen kwallo da sansanin alhazai na gwamnatin tarayya su zama cibiyoyin killace marasa lafiya. 58. Ya ku 'yan Najeriya, a matsayinmu na gwamnati, za mu samar da dukkan abubuwan da ake bukata don kula da marasa lafiya. Za mu ci gaba da jajircewa don yin duk abin da za mu iya don tunkarar annobar COVID-19 a kasarmu. 59. Muna matukar farin cikin ganin yadda ake samun tallafi daga manyan 'yan kasuwa da kuma sauran abokan huldar muwajen dakile annobar nan. 60. A wannan gaba, zan bukaci a hada duk wata gudunmuwa ko tallafi waje guda don tabbatar da cewa an yi amfani da su ta hanyar da ta dace. Kwamitin shugaban kasa da ke yaki da COVID-19 ne zai ci gaba da zama mai tsara duk abin da ya shafi annobar. 61. Ina so na tabbatar muku cewa dukkan ma'aikatun gwamnati da hukumomin da suke da rawar da za su taka suna aiki tukuru don shawo kan wannan annobar. 62. Kowace kasa ta duniya na fuskantar kalubale a wannan lokaci. Amma mun ga kasashen da jama'arta suka taimaka wajen rage yaduwar cutar. 63. Don haka zan ci gaba da kira a gare ku da ku bi dokokin da aka sanya kuma ku yi naku kokarin wajen bai wa gwamnati hadin kai da kuma taimakon marasa karfi a al'ummarku. 64. Zan yi amfani da wannan damar na godewa cibiyoyin lafiyarmu da ma'aikatan lafiya da hukumomin da ke kula da gabar teku da sauran ma'aikatan da aikinsu ya zama wajibi a kowane yanayi domin jajircewarsu da sadaukarwarsu. Lallai kun cika gwaraza. 65. Na gode muku duka da saurarata da kuka yi. Allah Ya ci gaba da yi mana albarka da kare mu duka.","answer":"Tabbas, ga kanun labarai na rubutun da aka bayar - Coronavirus: Abu 65 da Buhari ya fada a jawabinsa ga 'yan Najeriya"},{"question":"ලෝක දෑත් සේදිමේ දිනය ?","answer":"ඔක්තෝබර් මස 15"},{"question":"Onye dere uri Akpa Uche na mgbe odere yá?","answer":"Onye dere Àkpà uchè: akwụkwọ okwu nkiri nà mbèm Ìgbò (an anthology of modern Igbo verse) bụ R. M. Ekechukwu, na 1975."},{"question":"س274- شهر هجري أنزل فيه القرآن ؟","answer":"ج274- شهر رمضان"},{"question":"ગુજરાતનો નાથ કાવ્ય નું વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"ગુજરાતનો નાથગુજરાતનો નાથ,એક શાહી નામ,એક સ્વર્ગીય સ્થાન,એક ગુજરાતીનું ગૌરવ.ગુજરાતનો નાથ,એક શક્તિશાળી રાજ્ય,એક સંપન્ન સમાજ,એક ગુજરાતીની ઓળખ.ગુજરાતનો નાથ,એક ઇતિહાસની કહાણી,એક ગુજરાતીની આત્મા,એક ગુજરાતીની સંસ્કૃતિ.ગુજરાતનો નાથ,એક ભવિષ્યની આશા,એક ગુજરાતીનું અસ્તિત્વ,એક ગુજરાતીની શ્રેષ્ઠતા.આ કાવ્ય ગુજરાતના ભવ્ય ઇતિહાસ અને તેની સમૃદ્ધ સંસ્કૃતિને વર્ણવે છે. કાવ્ય ગુજરાતની ગૌરવ અને શ્રેષ્ઠતાને પણ પ્રતિબિંબિત કરે છે."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਦੁਆਦਸੀ ਦਾਨੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਇਸਨਾਨੁ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰਹੁ ਤਜਿ ਮਾਨੁ ॥ਹਰਿ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਪਾਨ ਕਰਹੁ ਸਾਧਸੰਗਿ ॥ਮਨ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਾਸੈ ਕੀਰਤਨ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਰੰਗਿ ॥ਕੋਮਲ ਬਾਣੀ ਸਭ ਕਉ ਸੰਤੋਖੈ ॥ਪੰਚ ਭੂ ਆਤਮਾ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮ ਰਸਿ ਪੋਖੈ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪੂਰੇ ਤੇ ਏਹ ਨਿਹਚਉ ਪਾਈਐ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਰਾਮ ਰਮਤ ਫਿਰਿ ਜੋਨਿ ਨ ਆਈਐ ॥੧੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 299 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਖ਼ਲਕਤਿ ਦੀ) ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰੋ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪੋ, ਤੇ, ਜੀਵਨ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਰੱਖੋ । (ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹੋ ।ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਪੀਂਦੇ ਰਹੋ । ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੀਜ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਮਨ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ) ਮਿੱਠੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਹਰੇਕ (ਇੰਦੇ੍ਰ) ਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੇਂਦੀ ਹੈ, (ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਮਨ ਪੰਜ ਤੱਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਤੋ ਅੰਸ ਦੀ ਘਾੜਤ ਵਿਚ ਘੜਿਆ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਫੁੱਲਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ ਯਕੀਨੀ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ ਫਿਰ ਜੂਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਵੀਦਾ ।੧੨।\\""},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικό γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Η διοργάνωση των πρώτων μουντιάλ δίνονταν στις χώρες κατά τη διάρκεια των συναντήσεων της συνέλευσης της FIFA. Η επιλογή της τοποθεσίας διεξαγωγής των αγώνων υπήρξε τότε πεδίο αντιπαράθεσης, ιδιαίτερα ανάμεσα στις χώρες της Λατινικής Αμερικής και της Ευρώπης, τα δύο ποδοσφαιρικά κέντρα της εποχής, αλλά και του σήμερα. Κι αυτό γιατί τις δύο ηπείρους χώριζε ταξίδι τριών εβδομάδων με πλοίο. Για παράδειγμα, η επιλογή της Ουρουγουάης ως τη χώρα που θα διοργάνωνε το πρώτο μουντιάλ, οδήγησε στη συμμετοχή μόνο τεσσάρων ευρωπαϊκών εθνικών ομάδων στο τουρνουά. Τα δύο επόμενα Παγκόσμια Κύπελλα διεξήχθησαν στην Ευρώπη και ιδιαίτερα η απόφαση για το δεύτερο συνεχόμενο μουντιάλ στην Ευρώπη το 1938, αποτέλεσε πεδίο διαμάχης, καθώς οι αμερικάνικες ομάδες ήθελαν το μουντιάλ να εναλλάσσεται διαδοχικά ανάμεσα στις δύο ηπείρους. Το αποτέλεσμα ήταν οι εθνικές ομάδες της Αργεντινής και της Ουρουγουάης να μποϊκοτάρουν το Παγκόσμιο Κύπελλο του 1938, στη Γαλλία.","answer":"Η αντιπαράθεση για την διοργάνωση του μουντιάλ ανάμεσα στις χώρες της Λατινικής Αμερικής και της Ευρώπης."},{"question":"label=(Prompt)","answer":"label=(Completion)"},{"question":"Бул жомоктун уландысын жазып берчи: \\"Үч бир тууган болуптур. Ата-энесинен эрте жетим калышат экен.\\"","answer":"Бул жомоктун уландысы мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Балдар эр жетип чоңоюп, өз алдыларынча оокат кылып, үй-жай күтүүгө аракеттенишип, байга малай жүрүшөт. Күндүр-түндүр кара жанын карч уруп, байдын жумушун аткарышат. Канчалык эмгектенишсе да, күндүк тапканы күнүмдүк оокатына жетпейт. \\""},{"question":"volana inona no hankalazana ny krismasy?","answer":"volana desambra no hankalazana ny krismasy"},{"question":" Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Asxaabigii Loo-Aqoon Jiray Tartamaagii Quraanka Kariimka","answer":" Wuxu Ahaa Cabdullaahi Bin Cabaas Rc"},{"question":"සිංහල  කතන්දරයට සුදුසු මාතෘකාවක් දෙන්න. එක ගමක ගැමියන් නිතර ගමන් ගන්නා පාරක මැදට වන්නට විශාල ගලක් පෙරළී තිබුණා. නිතරම ගැමියන් පාරේ එහෙට මෙහෙට ඇවිද ගිය ද සියල්ලෝම ගල දෙස බලා, එය පිළිබඳව සැලකිල්ලක් නොදක්වා ම තම තමන්ගේ ගමන් බිමන් වල යෙදුණා.කිසිවෙකුට ත් එය ඉවත් කිරීමට සිතුණේ නෑ. ඔන්න එන්න එන්නම රෑ බෝවීගෙන ආවා. රාත්‍රී කාලයේ ගමන් ගන්නා විට ගලක් ඇති බව අමතක වීම නිසා, බොහෝ අය ගලේ හැපී බිම වැටී තුවාල සිදු වුණා.වැටුණු පිරිසද ඉක්මනින්ම නැගිට, තමාට තුවාල සිදු වී ඇති ද යන්න බැලුවා මිස ගල ඉවත් කර දැමීමට සිතුවේ නෑ. දින කිහිපයක් ගත වුණා. දිනක් දුප්පත් ගොවියෙක් කුඹුරු වැඩ නිම කර, රෑ බෝවී, නිවස වෙත යමින් සිටියා. හාත්පසම අඳුරු වී තිබුණු බැවින් පෙරලී ඇති ගල් ගෙඩිය මේ ගොවියාට පෙනුනේ නෑ.ඔහු ද ගලේ හැපී වැටෙන්නට ගියා.\\"මේ ගල මෙතන තිබුනොත් බොහෝ දෙනෙක්ට අනතුරු විය හැකි\\" සිතා, ගල පෙරලා පාරෙන් ඉවතට දැමුවා. ගල පෙරලන විට ගල ලෝහයකට වැදීමෙන් නැගෙන ශබ්දයක් ඇති වුණා. ඔහු ගල ඉවත් කළ තැන පිරික්සුවා. සඳ එළියට දිලිසෙන යමක් එහි තිබෙනු දුටු ඔහු එය අතට ගෙන බැලුවා.රනින් තැනූ බරැති පෙට්ටියක් එහි තිබුණා. එහි කොටා තිබුණේ \\"ගල පෙරලන්නා ට තෑග්ගක්\\" යනුවෙනි. ගොවියා ඉතා සතුටින් රන් පෙට්ටියත් ගෙන නිවසට ගියා.","answer":"යහපත් වැඩට යහපත් විපාක"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa noocyo cuntada ka mid ah oo ay dhaqaatiirtu ku dardaarmaan In maalin kasta la cuno & Sababta?","answer":"Cuntada aynu cunnaa waa halka uu ka bilowdo caafimaadkeenna runta ahi, iyada ayaa sabab u noqon karta caafimaad darro ka dhalata miisaan dheeraad ah iyo noocyo badan oo xanuunnada ka mid ah iyo caafimaadka oo wanaagsanaada labadaba.Waxaa jira cuntooyin uu inta badan cilmigu ku taliyo in la caadaysto cunistooda, si uu jidhku uga helo faa’iidooyin nafaqo oo muhiim ah oo ay leeyihiin. Waxa kale oo iyaduna muhiim ah in cuntooyinka aynu cunaynaa ay noqdaan noocyo kala duwan.Qormadan oo aynu ka soo xigannay shabakadda Aljazeera waxa aynu ku eegaynaa afar nooc oo ka mid ah cuntooyinka ay khubarada caafimaadku sheegaan in ay qasab tahay in aynu maalin kasta wax ka cunno ugu yaraan nooc ka mid ah:1. SHAFKA DIGAAGGA:Digaaggu waxa uu ka mid yahay cuntooyinka caafimaadka u fiican, gaar ahaan hilibkeeda ku yaalla shafka oo aynu uga jeedno inta ka soo hadha labada lugood iyo garbaha. Hilibka halkan laga soo jaraa waxa uu si gaar ah ugu fiican yahay dadka ku jira is xammaynta ay miisaanka kula dagaalamayaan. Waxa uu ka kooban yahay barootiinno saafi ah, dufankuna aad ayaa uu ugu yar yahay. Sida oo kale hilibka digaagga ee intan dhexe ku yaallaa waa cad caloosha u fudud, oo casho fudud noqon kara. Sidaas awgeed waxa ay xeeldheereyaasha nafaqadu ku taliyaan in la cuno hilibka digaagga.2. KOOSTADA:Caleenta koostadu waxa ay ka mid tahay khudradaha cagaaran ee ay dhakhaatiirtu ku talinayaan in aynu maalin kasta hal mar cunno. Waxa ay xoojisaa xusuusta, waxa ay ka hortagtaa miisaanka dheeraadka ah waxa aanay u fiicantahay caafimaadka dheefshiidka.Waxaa intaasba ka sii muhiimsan in koostada ay ku jirto maaddada ‘Lutein’ oo muhiimad aad u weyn u leh shaqooyinka maskaxda, kana hortagta in unugyadeedu aanay burburin ama hawlgabin.3. LIIN BAYDARIIN:Liin baydariintu waxa ay hodan ku tahay Faytamiin ‘C’ iyo maadadda loo yaqaanno ‘Pectin’ oo ka mid ah ganka lakabka ku ah derbiyada unugyada dhirta. Liin baydariintu waxa ay leedahay faa’iidooyin badan oo caafimaad. Waxaa ka mid ah dufanka (Kalastarool) oo ay jidhka ku yarayso, sida oo kale waxa ay wanaajisaa xaddiga sonkorta dhiigga ku lammaan.4. KALLUUNKA SALAMON:Noocyada kallunka badankoodu waxa ay hodan ku yihiin maaddooyinka ‘Magnesium’ iyo ‘Phosphorous’ laakiin kalluunka Salamon ka loo yaqaanno ayaa lagu tiriyaa in uu yahay kalluunka ugu fiican noocyada kalluunka, sababtuna waa in xaddiga maadadda ‘Magnesium’ ee ku jiraa uu ka badan yahay kalluumada kale oo dhan.Maadaddan ayaa u wanaagsan shaqada habdhiska dareen-wadayaasha. ‘Magnesium’ oo jidhka ku yaraataana waxa ay sababtaa xaalado ay ka mid yihiin, Daal iyo burbur jidheed oo joogto ah iyo muquryada iyo neerfayaasha oo isku urura ama guntama. Akhriso Faaidooyinka Kalluunka Salmon"},{"question":"How does Sri Lanka's flag represent unity?","answer":"The Sri Lankan flag, with its vibrant colors of saffron, green, and maroon, represents unity by symbolizing the diversity and harmony among different ethnic and cultural communities. The lion emblem on the flag signifies strength, courage, and sovereignty, fostering a positive national identity."},{"question":"Који су најпознатији српски научници?","answer":"Ово су неки од најпознатијих научника српског порекла:1. Михајло Пупин - Био је научник, проналазач и професор на универзитету Колумбија. Током свог научног и експерименталног рада дао је значајне закључке важне за поља вишеструке телеграфије, бежичне телеграфије и телефоније, потом рентгенологије, а има и великих заслуга за развој електротехнике. Такође је заслужан и за проналазак Пупинових калемова. 2. Никола Тесла - Био је српски и амерички проналазач, инжењер електротехнике и машинства и футуриста, најпознатији по свом доприносу у пројектовању модерног система напајања наизменичном струјом. 3. Милутин Миланковић - Био је српски математичар, астроном, климатолог, геофизичар, грађевински инжењер, доктор техничких наука, као и популаризатор науке и физичар.4. Јосиф Панчић - Био је српски лекар, ботаничар, универзитетски професор и академик. Панчић је био први председник Српске краљевске академије. Открио је нову врсту четинара која је по њему названа Панчићева оморика."},{"question":"Bangui moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Bangui moy péeyu réwum République Centrafricaine"},{"question":"ආසියාවේ පළමු ව්‍යවස්ථාමය සමූහාණ්ඩූව","answer":"චීනය"},{"question":" வினா : இந்தியாவின் முதல் பசுமைத் துறைமுகமாக எந்தத் துறைமுகம் உருவாக்கப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது?1) தீன்தயாள் துறைமுகம்2) பரதீப்3) போர்ட் பிளேயர்4) ஹால்டியா துறைமுகம்","answer":" ஹால்டியா துறைமுகம்."},{"question":"மக்கும் குப்பை , மக்காத குப்பை  எவை என கீழ்வரும்  சொற்களைக் கொண்டு  பிரித்தறிக. கண்ணாடித்துண்டு, நெகிழிப்பைகாகிதத்தாள், சணல்பை,பீங்கான்,\\tஇலை","answer":"மக்கும் குப்பை காகிதத்தாள், சணல்பை,இலை.                மக்காத குப்பை கண்ணாடித்துண்டு, நெகிழிப்பை, பீங்கான்.                                         "},{"question":"\\"Компаниянын имараты, програмчылар үчүн түзүлгөн шарты абдан сонун экен, бир катар ичин кыдырып көрүп, суктанып, алдыда биз дагы кандай имараттарды курабыз, кандай шарттарды түзөбүз көңүлгө түйүп алгандай болдук.\\" -  бул текстте кандай маанай берилген?","answer":"Бул сүйлөмдө суктануу бар, анткени автор компаниянын шартын көрүп суктанганын билдирди."},{"question":"දහම්පාසල් ගුරු අභ්‍යාස විද්‍යාලය පිහිටා  තිබෙන්නේ කොහෙද?","answer":"දහම්පාසල් ගුරු අභ්‍යාස විද්‍යාලය  කඩවත රන්මුතුගල පිහිටා  ඇත."},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa Asxaabigii Nebiguﷺ u sheegay inuu Alle jecelyahay","answer":" Wuxuu ahaa Miqdaad binu Camar (RC)"},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:సమస్త భూమండలాన్ని పరిపాలిస్తున్న కోసలరాజు భగీరథుడు. తన పూర్వీకులైన సగర మహారాజు పుత్రులు ఏవిధంగా కపిల మహర్షి కోపానికి భస్మం అయిన తీరును మంత్రుల ద్వారా తెలుసుకున్నాడు. వారికి మోక్షం కలిగించాలని నిశ్చయించుకున్నాడు. భగీరథునికి పుత్ర సంతానం లేని కారణంగా తన రాజ్య భారాన్ని మంత్రులకు అప్పగించి, గోకర్ణం వెళ్లి, అక్కడ వేయి సంవత్సరాలు గొప్ప తపస్సు చేశాడు.ఆ తపస్సుకు మెచ్చిన బ్రహ్మ ఏం వరం కావాలో కోరుకో అంటే భగీరథుడు సంతోషించి, సాగరుల భస్మరాశులపై దేవనదీ నీటిని ప్రవహింప చేయమని మొదటి వరంగా, తన వంశాన్ని ఉద్ధరించే ఒక కుమారున్ని అనుగ్రహించమని రెండవ వరంగా కోరాడు.","answer":"అలా భగీరథుడు కోరుకోగానే బ్రహ్మదేవుడు తేజస్సు కల కుమారుడు నీకు జన్మిస్తాడు. కానీ దివ్యలోకాలలో ప్రవహించే నది భూమిపై పడితే భూమండలం భరించలేదు. కావున శివున్ని మెప్పిస్తే దేవనదిని ఆయన భరిస్తాడు అని చెప్పి బ్రహ్మ అదృశ్యం అయ్యాడు. భక్తితో కాలి బొటన వేలును మాత్రమే భూమిపై మోపి, తన హృదయాన్ని పద్మంగా మార్చుకొని శంకరుని గూర్చి కఠినమైన తపస్సు చేశాడు. ఆరాజు తపస్సుకు మెచ్చిన శివుడు దేవలోకంలోని నీటి ప్రవాహాన్ని నా తలపై భరిస్తాను.అని చెప్పగా భగీరథుడు విజయం సాధించానని సంతోషించాడు. శివుడు ఇచ్చిన మాటకు కోపగించిన గంగ తన ప్రవాహ వేగంతో శివున్ని పాతాళానికి తొక్కి వేస్తానని భావించింది. గంగాదేవి గర్వానికి అత్యంత కోప స్వభావుడైన శివుడు ఆమె గర్వాన్ని తొలగించాలని మనస్సులో అనుకున్నాడు.దేవలోకంలో ప్రవహించే గంగానది సహింపరాని వేగంతో, మూడులోకాలకు భయాన్ని కలిగించే విధంగా శబ్దం చేస్తూ హిమాలయ పర్వతంలాగా ప్రకాశిస్తున్న శివుని తలపై పడింది. ఆ శివుని జడలనే అడవిలో ఎన్నో సంవత్సరాలు మబ్బులలో కదులుతున్న మెరుపులాగా తిరుగుతూ ఉండి పోయింది. దేవతలందరూ శంకరుని వద్దకు వచ్చి, నీ గొప్ప మహిమ తెలియక దేవనది అయిన గంగ ప్రదర్శించిన గర్వము నీ మాయచేత నశించింది. నిజభక్తుడైన భగీరథునిపై గల కరుణతో అయినా దేవనదిని విడుదల చేయవలెను. ఈ గంగా జలముతో సగరపుత్రుల ప్రేతాత్మలు శాంతిని పొందుతాయి. మానవ లోకానికి, పాతాళ లోకానికి గొప్పతనము కలుగుతుంది. అని దేవతలు వేడుకొనగా శివుడు పరమ సంతోషంతో ఆ గంగానదిని సముద్రంలోకి వదిలాడు."},{"question":"Apibendrinti straipsnį:  Patrikas Bamfordas antradienio vakarą įmušė savo 19-ąjį \\"Middlesbrough\\" tikslą sezono metu. Visi klausė: ar jis galės pasiekti \\"Chelsea\\" rungtynes kitą sezoną? 21 metų užpuolikas buvo labai produktyvus savo paskolų metu \\"Boro\\", \\"Derby\\" ir \\"MK Dons\\", tiek, kad \\"Sportsmail\\" supranta, kad jo tėvų klubas pradeda derybas su juo dėl naujos sutarties. Nereikia nė sakyti, kad tai padidintų jo atlyginimą nuo dabartinio 7500 svarų per savaitę. Jis taip pat turės galimybę padaryti įspūdį Jose Mourinho \\"Chelsea\\" vasaros turnejoje, nors jo pabaigoje jis tikimasi, kad jis vėl išeis iš paskolos. Tačiau šį kartą Bamfordas bus išsiųstas į premjero lygos klubą, pageidautina Aitor Karanka's Middlesbrough, jei jie prisijungia prie \\"Blues\\" aukščiausiame lygyje. Važiuok žemyn vaizdo. Patrcik Bamford (centras) antradienį įmušė į \\"Middlesbrough\\" 2-1 pergalę prieš \\"Wolves\\". Bamfordas švenčia po to, kai užmušė savo 19-tą sezoną visų varžybų tašką. 21 metų (centras) žaidėjo spinduliuojanti forma paskatino jo tėvų klubą \\"Chelsea\\" pradėti derybas dėl naujos sutarties. Nerimauja, kad tai ta pati taktika, kurią klubas naudojo su Romelu Lukaku, kuris galiausiai buvo parduotas \\"Evertonui\\". Bet Bamfordas yra pasitikintis savimi jaunuolis ir tiki, kad jis gali imituoti Tottenhamo Harry Kane ir priversti Chelsea ranką. Bamfordas šiuo metu yra vienas iš 26 žaidėjų, paskolintų iš \\"Stamford Bridge\\" - penki iš jų yra varžovai - o akademijos puolėjai Dominicas Solanke ir Isaiah Brownas jau laimėjo pakylėjimą į vyresniojo lygio komandą. Ir dar yra Diego Costa, Loic Remy ir Didier Drogba, kurie jau konkuruoja dėl to vienintelio vaidmens. Tu manai, kad šansų, kad Bamford'as kitą sezoną pasiektų savo ženklą, yra mažai. Bet ar nebuvo taip pat neįprasta, kad Kane'as savo sėkmingame sezone \\"Spurs\\" užmušė 29 taškus, o savo debiutiniame žaidime Anglijoje užmušė net? Bamfordas jau padarė įspūdį Mourinjui savo požiūriu. ","answer":"Straipsnio apibendrinimas: \\"Middlesbrough\\" antradienį nugalėjo \\"Wolves\\" 2: 1. Patrikas Bamfordas įmušė savo 19-ąjį tašką sezone \\"Boro\\" pergalėje. Bamfordas yra vienas iš 26 žaidėjų, kurie šį sezoną buvo išnuomoti iš \\"Chelsea\\". 21 metų žaidėjas pradėjo derybas su \\"The Blues\\" dėl naujo kontrakto."},{"question":"Bakit kaya sobrang mahal ng mga smartphones kagaya ng iPhone?","answer":"Ang pangunahing dahilan kung bakit napakamahal mga kilalang smartphones kagaya ng iPhone dahil kilala ang manufacturer nito para sa kanilang mahusay na hardware, kabilang ang mga pinakamahusay na in-class na camera, mabilis na performance at napakahusay na software."},{"question":"Explain the concept of a dangling modifier.","answer":"A word or phrase that is positioned incorrectly in a sentence and leaves the reader unclear about what it modifies is known as a dangling modifier."},{"question":"Ile-ẹjọ ti fun Baba Ijẹṣa ni beeli","answer":"Ileeẹjọ to n ri si awọn ẹsun to ba ṣe pataki ti wọn n pe ni Special Offence Court to wa niluu Ikẹja, nipinlẹ Eko, ti gba beeli Baba Ijẹṣa, wọn ni ko tile waa maa jẹjọ ẹsun ṣiṣe ọmọde baṣubaṣu ti wọn fi kan an.Nigba ti Adajọ Toyin Taiwo to  gbọ ẹjọ naa n gbe ipinnu rẹ kalẹ, o ni oun ṣetan lati fun Baba Ijẹṣa ni beeli, ṣugbọn awọn ohun to rọ mọ gbigba beeli ọhun niyi gẹgẹ bi Adajọ Toyin ṣe sọ.Akọkọ ni pe o gbọdọ fa ẹlẹrii meji kalẹ. Bakan naa ni agbẹjọro rẹ gbọdọ duro fun un. Yatọ si eleyii, ọkan ninu awọn mọlẹbi rẹ gbọdọ wa laarin awọn oniduuro yii, ti wọn si gbọdọ ni miliọnu meji, o kere tan, lakaunti wọn. Bẹẹ ni wọn gbọdọ ni iwe-ẹri owo-ori ọdun mẹta ti wọn ti san sipinlẹ Eko.Olori awọn lọọya to gbẹjọro fun Baba Ijẹṣa ni Babatunde Ọgala, oun naa wa lara awọn ti wọn duro fun un. Ọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn, ketadinlọgbọn ati ikejidinlọgbọn, oṣu to n bọ, ni wọn sun igbẹjọ oṣere naa si ti yoo tun fara han nile-ẹjọ."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan fakta yang membincangkan kebaikan menyertai aktiviti kokurikulum. ","answer":"Kegiatan kokurikulum ialah aktiviti yang dijalankan di luar bilik darjah. Kokurikulum yang merangkumi persatuan, kelab, badan beruniform dan permainan.Menyertai kokurikulum banyak mendatangkan kebaikan kepada murid-murid. Penyertaan aktiviti kokurikulum dapat menanam semangat kerjasama, bertanggungjawab, dan berdisiplin.Murid-murid akan dilatih bagaimana untuk mengendalikan pasukan yang dipimpini oleh mereka. Contohnya, ketua dalam pasukan pengakap.Dengan menyertai kegiatan kokurikulum juga, murid dapat memperoleh kemahiran yang sangat berguna. Murid-murid juga dapat menambahkan pelbagai ilmu pengetahuan jika melibatkan diri dalam kegiatan ini.Kesimpulannya, penyertaan murid dalam kegiatan kokurikulum mendatangkan banyak kebaikan. "},{"question":"Mengapakah warna coklat atau hitam tidak wujud dalam pelangi?","answer":"Warna coklat dan hitam tidak wujud dalam pelangi kerana warna hitam terbentuk apabila tidak ada cahaya sama sekali seperti pada malam hari, manakala warna putih merupakan gabungan dari semua warna. Ketika cahaya putih dibiaskan melalui tetisan air, ia terurai menjadi spektrum warna, dan warna putih hilang."},{"question":"Ποια είναι η ερώτηση στο: \\"Ένα παιχνίδι ρόλων (RPG ή και παιχνίδι ρόλων) είναι ένα παιχνίδι στο οποίο οι παίκτες αναλαμβάνουν τους ρόλους χαρακτήρων σε ένα φανταστικό περιβάλλον.\\"; Το θέμα είναι το παιχνίδι ρόλων.","answer":"\\"Τι είναι ένα παιχνίδι ρόλων;\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kecil tak boleh disangka anak, besar tak boleh disangka bapa'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud pengetahuan dan kelebihan itu tidak khusus pada orang-orang tua sahaja (selalu juga ada pada orang-orang muda)"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ በአማካይ መኪና ምን ያህል ክፍሎች (ሽክርክሪት እና ቦልቶች የተካተቱ) አሉት? መልስ፦ ","answer":"30,000"},{"question":"\\"Ny baolina kitra an-dalambe, antsoina koa hoe \\"futsal\\" any amin'ny faritra sasany, dia dikan-teny tsy ara-potoana amin'ny ireo lalao atao eny an-dalambe na eny amin'ny zaridainam-panjakana na eny an-tsaha manodidina. Mamela ny mpilalao amin'ny sokajin-taona rehetra haneho hevitra malalaka sy hampivelatra ny fahaizany ao anatin'ny tontolo sariaka sy mifaninana izany.\\"Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia ny baolina kitra."},{"question":"Bác Hoa đi chợ và Bác chỉ mang ba loại tiền: loại (có mệnh giá) 1 nghìn (1 000) đồng, loại 10 nghìn (10 000) đồng và loại 100 nghìn (100 000) đồng. Tổng số tiền bác phải trả là 492 nghìn đồng. Nếu mỗi loại tiền, bác mang theo không quá 9 tờ thì bác sẽ phải trả bao nhiêu tờ tiền mỗi loại để người bán không phải trả lại tiền thừa?","answer":"492 được biểu diễn thành: 492 = (4 x 100) + (9 x 10) + 4 x 1Vậy để người bán hàng không phải trả lại tiền thừa thì số tờ tiền mỗi loại bác phải trả là: 4 tờ loại 100 nghìn (100 000) đồng; 9 tờ 10 nghìn (10 000) đồng và 4 tờ loại 1 nghìn (1 000) đồng"},{"question":"नेपालमा वन्यजन्तु संरक्षणमा \\"एक सिङ्गे गैँडा\\" को प्रभावबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"एकसिङ्गे गैँडा नेपालको प्रमुख प्रजाति हो, जसको संरक्षण र वासस्थान संरक्षणमा केन्द्रित संरक्षण प्रयासहरू छन्।"},{"question":"ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਸਾਰਾ ਸਾਮਾਨ ਗੁਆ ਦਿੱਤਾ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਘਰ ਵੇਚ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗ ਲੱਗ ਗਈ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗ ਲੱਗ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"Mắt em bị cận từ 10 tuổi, nay khoảng 5 độ, em muốn phẫu thuật để dự tuyển vào ngành công an, xin cho em lời khuyên?","answer":"Đối với các ngành lực lượng vũ trang và quân đội, yêu cầu bắt buộc là phải bỏ kính. Nên việc phẫu thuật là cần thiết nếu cháu muốn thi vào ngành này. Lời khuyên của chú, lựa chọn tốt nhất là phẫu thuật Smile, đảm bảo khi sau này tham gia luyện tập sẽ tránh các biến chứng."},{"question":"… Noma ngabe uDumisani usekhulile nje, ngeke ungibone ngimganamina. Mina angisiye owokuganga. Naye ngizomgada manje umaefikile. Uma engeshela nje ngiyomkhombisa ikheli. Ngimbuze ukuthiungithanda manini nje. Uma enganakile futhi siyodumelana kubekuncane indawo.Uyazi angimazi nalo muntu owasungula isikolokungenwa wayehlushwe yini. Abantu bayathanda ukusungulaamasiko adala izinkinga. (Ezwe izigi) Nangu umama eza. Uma eqala lendaba yesiko lakhe uzongizwa kahle namuhla. Angihleki angithi nsi.Angifuni ndoda nje eduze kwami manje.Uyawuthanda lo msebenzi wokuthunga koti bo. (Ahlale phansi)Ngenzela ukuthi ngingakhohlwa mama. Nawo umshini awufuniukuhlala isikhathi eside ungasebenzi.Kuzofuneka ungifundise nami makoti ngizithungele.Awu mama uthi kungalunga ufundiswa imfundamakhwela?Akubonakali ukuthi usafunda koti. Ukwenza kwakho kukhombisaubumpetha. Impela ngicela ungifundise. Siningi kabi isikhathiesizosihlala nawe ngingagcina sengiwushaya njengawe nje.Usho ukuthini umama uma ethi sisazohlala isikhathi eside?Kanti uyahamba yini?Ngingeze ngasho ukuthi ngiyahamba mama. Uma sekukhunyulweinzilo bengizocela ukuba ngibuyele ekhaya.(Ashaye izandla) Nansi indaba bo! Wawukuzwaphi ukuthi umakotiushiya lapho endele khona abuyele kubo?Bengisho ngoba ngisemncane mama. Nomuntu owangiletha laphanakhu esesheshe wangishiya.1. Ngubani igama lomfowabo womyeni kaThenjiwe?","answer":"NguDumisani"},{"question":"米国の哲学者パースが提唱した考え方で、日本語では実用主義と呼ばれるのは何でしょう？","answer":"プラグマティズムです。"},{"question":"மணியம்மையின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினைத்தரவும்.","answer":"மணியம்மை, வேலூரில் வாழ்ந்த சுயமரியாதை இயக்கத் தொண்டரான கனகசபை என்பவருக்கும் பத்மாவதி என்பவருக்கும் 1917ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச் திங்கள் 10 ஆம் நாள் பிறந்தார். இவருக்குப் பெற்றோர் இட்ட பெயர் காந்திமதி என்பதாகும். அன்றைய தென்னாற்காடு மாவட்டத்தின் திராவிடர் இயக்கத் தலைவர்களில் ஒருவரான அண்ணல்தங்கோ, இவருக்கு அரசியல்மணி எனப் பெயர்சூட்டினார். அரசியல்மணி வேலூரில் உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளிக்கல்வியை முடித்தார். பின்னர் தமிழிலக்கியம் படித்துப் புலவர் பட்டம் பெற்றார்.மணியம்மையின் மேற்கோளுக்குச் சான்று : \\"எப்படியும் நம்மை ஒழித்துக் கட்டிவிட எதிரிகள் நம்மீது ஒரு கண் வைத்துக் கொண்டுதான் இருக்கிறார்கள். தோழர்களே, நீங்கள் தற்காத்துக் கொள்ள உடற்பயிற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்வீர்களாக!\\"  என்பதாகும் ."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Vid VM i Östersund 2008","answer":"vann hon 3 guldmedaljer och hade då sammanlagt 6 VM-guld, lika många som Magdalena Forsberg"},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.ගසට නමකි ගසමැරුනම වෙන නමකිගෙඩියට නමකි ගෙඩියේ සුඹුලට නමකිමදයට නමකි මද කනකොට වෙන නමකිමෙතුන් පදේ තෝරාලා කියන් සකි","answer":"ගසට ගොයම් ගස මැරුනම පිදුරු වෙතිගෙඩියට වී පොත්තට දහයියා  කියතිමදයට හාල් එය කනකොට බත් කියතිමෙතුන් පදය වී සදහා  කියයි සකි"},{"question":"妊娠した女性に対して市町村が交付する、健康診査や保健指導を受けたときにその内容を記載するための手帳を何と言うでしょう？","answer":"母子(健康)手帳です。"},{"question":"Тасма ( кино) тартканда кандай суроолор көп берилет?","answer":"\\"Сиз кино тартып жүрөсүзбү?\\"Бөтөн айылга мусаапыр болуп келгенимден бери бул суроо дарыянын доошундай көнүмүш болуп калган. Андан кийин кыска маек күтүлгөн сценарий менен уланат. \\"Качан тартасың? Кимдер катышат? Эмне жөнүндө? Эмнеге биздин айыл?\\". Дүжүр суроолорго дүжүр жоопторум да даяр. Азыр да дүжүр жообумду ыргыта салып басып кетмекмин, ансыз деле ашказан тешилгени калган. Бирок бул суроо, аны берген үн кулакка жаңыча кирди. Бул тоолордун арасында момунтип зыңкыйган жигит өзү теңдүү, балким кичүү, адамды \\"сиз\\" деп турганы чоочун обон. Айылдын салттуу иерархиясын бузуп сүйлөгөн бу неме ким деп карап калдым. Даватчылар шунетип жасакерленип калышчу. Кейпи аларга окшобойт. Элпеңдеп чуркап келип, дароо кино жөнүндө сөз салып кирди. Окуумал. Ач курсакка шалдырабаганымда, бу жигит менен далайга тил чаңытышып отура бермек экенимди түшүндүм. Сөзү ордунда, үнү уккулуктуу экен. Өзүн \\"Азат\\" деп тааныштырды. \\"Тыныстан\\" деп колун кысып койдум. \\"Мен да кино тартканы даярданып жүрөм\\" дейт. Дагы бир нерселерди айтты. А мен асмандан түшкөн \\"собеседнигиме\\" сүйүнүп угуп эле турам. Кинонун сүйгөндөрдүн баарын жакшы көрөрүмдү айтканга үлгүрдүм.\\"Звягинцевди билесизби?\\" деп калды.\\"Билем.\\"\\"Менде китеби бар, берип турайынбы?\\"\\"Берип туруңуз.\\" Саалдан кийин Звягинцевдин \\"Сценарийлери\\" колума түштү. Китепти аларда, \\"Менден улуу болсоңуз керек, сизди аке, байке, ака, эмне дейин?\\" Чын эле менден жети жаш улуу экен. Эртең репетицияма келүүнү суранды. Мен ага Миттанын китебин убада кылдым."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cakar ayam'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud tulisan yang buruk. Contoh ayat: Tulisannya seperti cakar ayam dan sukar dibaca."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: ఖగము","answer":"పక్షి, బాణం, సూర్యుడు(గ్రహాలు), గాలి "},{"question":"Awọn ileewe ilẹ Yoruba yoo ṣi loṣu to n bọ","answer":"Awọn ileewe to wa lawọn ipinlẹ mẹfẹẹfa nilẹ Yoruba yoo ṣi lọjọ kẹta, oṣu to n bọ.Iwọle naa ni wọn fọwọ si lati jẹ kawọn ọmọ ileewe girama ṣe idanwo aṣekagba WAEC.Eyi waye lẹyin ipade ẹgbẹ itẹsiwaju ilẹ Yoruba ti wọn n pe ni DAWN waye.Wọn pinnu lati ba ajọ to n ṣegbatẹru idanwo naa sọrọ ki wọn le sun ọjọ idanwo siwaju diẹ sipari oṣu to n bọ, bẹẹ ni apero yoo waye pẹlu ijọba apapọ.Bakan naa ni DAWN ṣetan lati ri i daju pe gbogbo eto imọtoto lawọn ipinlẹ tẹle lasiko idanwo naa."},{"question":"Chirevo chinotevera chiri muChiShona, dudzira kuChirungu\\"Uri sei nhasi?\\"","answer":"\\"How are you today?\\""},{"question":"Apakah soalan kepada: \\"Sos gravy boleh diwarnai dan ditambahkan rasa dengan garam gravy (campuran sederhana garam dan pewarna makanan karamel) atau coklat gravy (garam gravy yang terlarut dalam air) atau kiub dan serbuk siap boleh digunakan sebagai pengganti daging semula jadi atau ekstrak sayur-sayuran\\"? Topiknya ialah Gravy.","answer":"\\"Apakah sos gravy dibuat dari?\\""},{"question":"ilmahu caano ku filan ma helayaa Naaska Hooyada?","answer":"Haddii ilmahaagu caano ku filan helayo,naasahaagu markasta waxay noqdaan qaar caanoka buuxaan, oo jiqista ka dib noqda qaardebecsan, haddana dib u buuxsama. Ilmahaagu wuxu:• Naaska jiqi doonaa 6 jeer ama in kabadan 24kii saacadood • Seexan doonaa inta u dhaxaysa laba jaqsiinood• Saxaroon doonaa in kabadan laba jeer maalintii • Miisaan ku kordho Ilmo caafimaad qaba, oo dhammays ah oocaanihiisa qaadanayaa uma baahna in la siiyo biyo amase cunto kale oo diyaarsan oo dheeri ah.  Ha siin ilmahaaga waxyaabo kale oodheeraad ah haddii aan dhakhtarku kugula talin sidaas.Kala hadal dhakhtarka ilmahaaga amakalkaalisada caafimaad amase qof ku takhasusayquudinta caanaha haddii aanad hubin inilmahaagu caano ku filan helaayo."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'golok kayu'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang bodoh yang berlagak pandai. Contoh ayat: Dia seperti golok kayu, kononnya dia tahu segala-galanya tentang perkembangan politik negara."},{"question":"Manana ity teny nakorontanan ity ianao: \\"ilmaaol\\". Vinavinao ilay teny rehefa alamina! ","answer":"Ilay teny rehefa alamina dia \\"milalao\\""},{"question":"ගැලීලියෝ ගැලිලි කිනම් ජාතිකයෙක් ද?","answer":"ගැලීලියෝ ගැලිලි ඉතාලි ජාතිකයෙක් වේ."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa  sanadkii uu dhul mareenkii Ibnu Batuuta yimid Soomaaliya?","answer":"Waxa uu yimid sanadkii 1331kii"},{"question":"கேள்வி : எண்ணத்தை வெளியிடுவதற்கும், சிந்தனையாற்றல் பெருகுவதற்கும் தாய் மொழியே துணை நிற்கும். இதனை வலியுறுத்தி பின்வரும் குறிப்புகளைக் கொண்டு கட்டுரை எழுதுக. தாய்மொழிக் கல்வியின் தேவைதாய்மொழிச் சிந்தனை – அறிஞர்களின் பார்வை – கற்கும் திறன் – பயன் – இன்றைய நிலை.","answer":"பதில் : முன்னுரை:“தாய்மொழி கண் போன்றதுபிறமொழி கண்ணாடி போன்றது”நமது எண்ணங்களைப் பிறருக்கு வெளிப்படுத்த உதவுவது மொழியே. மொழி ஒரு கருவி. மனிதன் மொழியால்தான் வாழ்கின்றான். மொழியால்தான் கருத்துப் பரிமாற்றமும் செய்கின்றான். தனது எண்ணத்தை வெளியிடுவதற்கும் சிந்தனையாற்றலைப் பெருக்கவும் துணையாக இருக்கும் தாய்மொழி வழிக் கல்வியின் சிறப்புகள் பற்றி இக்கட்டுரையில் காண்போம்.தாய்மொழிக் கல்வியின் தேவை :மனிதனின் அடையாளம் அவனது தாய்மொழிதான். கல்வி என்பது தாய்மொழி வழியாக மட்டுமே கற்பிக்க பட வேண்டும். மனிதனின் சிந்தனையும் கற்பனையும் தாய்மொழியில்தான் உருவாகின்றன. எனவே, மனிதனின் சிந்தனை வளர்ச்சிக்குத் தாய்மொழிக் கல்வியே சிறந்தது. சிந்திக்கின்ற மொழியிலே பயிற்றுவிக்கப்படுகின்ற கல்வி சிந்தனையைக் கூட்டுகின்றது. நுணுக்கங்களையும் அறிவியல் படைப்புகளையும் உருவாக்க மனிதர்களைத் தயார்ப்படுத்துகின்றது.தாய்மொழிச் சிந்தனை :தாய்மொழிதான் சிந்திக்கும் திறனின் திறவுகோலாக இருக்கின்றது. எத்தனை மொழிகள் கற்றாலும் எந்த மொழியைக் கற்றாலும் ஒருவனின் சிந்தனை உருவெடுப்பது தாய்மொழியில்தான். தாய்மொழியால் சிந்தனை பெருகும். மனிதர்களின் மனவெழுச்சி வாழ்விற்கு அடிப்படை. அத்தகைய மனவளர்ச்சியைத் தாய்மொழியால் மட்டுமே கொடுக்க இயலும். தாய்மொழியில் சிந்திப்பதால் உயர்ந்த கருத்துக்களைச் சிறந்த சொற்களைக் கொண்டு உணர்த்த முடியும்.அறிஞர்கள் பார்வை :உலகில் வாழ்ந்த பல அறிஞர்கள் தாய்மொழிக்கல்வியின் அவசியத்தைக் கூறியிருக்கின்றார்கள். காந்தியடிகள் கூறும் போது ஜெகதீஷ் சந்திர போஸ், பி.சி. இராய் முதலியோரின் சாதனைகளைக் கண்டு நாம் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறோம். ஆனால், தாய்மொழி மூலம் நமக்குக் கல்வி அளிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தால் நம்மிடையே பல போஸ்களும், இராய்களும் தோன்றியிருப்பார்கள் என்கிறார். சாகித் ஹுசைன் (1938-ஆம் ஆண்டு) குழு தாய்மொழியில் கற்றுக்கொடுத்தலை வலியுறுத்துகிறது, டி.எஸ். கோத்தாரி குழுவும் (1964) தேசியக்கல்விக் கொள்கையில் தாய்மொழி கல்வியை வலியுறுத்தியது.கற்கும் திறன் :தாய்மொழியைப் போற்றி வீழ்ந்த நாடும் இல்லை. தாய்மொழியைப் புறக்கணித்து வாழ்ந்த நாடும் இல்லை. தாய்மொழி மூலமாகவே ஒருவர் தான் கூற விரும்பும் கருத்தைத் தெளிவாகவும் முழுமையாகவும் ஆழமாகவும் தெரிவிக்க முடியும். கற்கும் திறன் அதிகரிப்பது தாய்மொழி வழியாகவே, தாய்மொழி வழியாகக் கற்கும் போது சிந்தனைத்திறன் அதிகமாகும்.தாய்மொழிக் கல்வியின் பயன் :“கருவில் உள்ள குழந்தை ஏழு மாதத்திலேயே மூளை முதிர்ச்சிப் பெற்று ஒலிகளைக் கேட்கிறது” என்கின்றனர். மருத்துவ அறிஞர்கள், குழந்தை வளரும் சூழல் மொழித்தாக்கத்திற்கு அடிப்படையாக அமைகிறது. அக்குழந்தைகள் தாய்மொழி வழியாகக் கற்கும் சூழல் ஏற்பட்டால் மிகச் சிறந்த அறிஞர்களாக, மேதைகளாக அக்குழந்தைகள் வளரும். குழந்தைகள் தாய்மொழி வழியாகக் கல்விக் கற்றால் தரமான கல்வியைப் பெறுவார்கள்.இன்றைய நிலை :இன்று தாய்மொழி வழியில் கல்விச் கற்பதைக் கௌரவக் குறைச்சலாகவும், கேவலமாகவும் நினைக்கின்றனர். தாய்மொழியில் கல்விக் கற்றவர்களைத் தரம் குறைந்தவர்களாகப் பார்ப்பது சமூகத்தில் நிலவி வரும் அவலங்களுள் ஒன்றாகும். தாய்மொழியில் கல்விக் கற்போருக்கு அரசுப் பணிகளில் முன்னுரிமை வழங்குதல் வேண்டும்.முடிவுரை :மொழி என்பது ஒரு தகவல் தொடர்புச் சாதனம் மட்டுமன்று. ஒரு பண்பாட்டின், ஒரு இனத்தின் அடையாளம் என்பதை யாவரும் உணர்ந்தாலே தாய்மொழியை அழிவிலிருந்து காக்கலாம்."},{"question":"Эң жалкоо жаныбар бул ...","answer":"Эң жалкоо жаныбар катары таанылган слот (sloth -анг. Жалкоо жаныбар) Американын жамгырлуу токойлорунда жашайт. Слоттун колдору менен буттарын дагы узун бармактары анын дарактарда жашоосуна абдан ыңгайланышкан. Ал гана эмес бутакка асылып башын төмөн каратып уктай алышат. Жерге түшсө ташбака менен да атаандаша албайт жай кыймылдаган бул жаныбар сүт эмүүчүлөрдүн арасында\\"эңи жалкоо\\"деген мүнөздөмөгө ээ."},{"question":"මත්පැන් බී 'වෙරි වුණා' යන්නෙහි 'වෙරි'  යනු සිංහල වචනයක් ද?","answer":"වෙරි යනු සිංහල වචනයක් නොවේ. එය දෙමළ වචනයකි. එය එක හා සමාන තේරුමකින් සිංහලයෙහි යෙදේ."},{"question":"Ọọni yoo gbe igbesẹ lori iwọde tawọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti ṣe nitori Oyetọla","answer":"Ọọni tilu Ileefẹ, Ọba Adeyẹye Ẹnitan Ogunwusi, ti ṣeleri lati da si ọrọ iwọde tawọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti ṣe lanaa, Ọjọbọ, Wẹsidee.Pẹlu omije loju ati aṣọ dudu lọrun lawọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti nipinlẹ Ọṣun fi wọ kaakiri ilu Ileefẹ ti wọn si pari irin wọn si aafin Ọọni Ogunwusi.Oniruuru akọle ni wọn gbe lọwọ ti wọn si n kede pe odidi idaji owo ọgbọn oṣu nijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ko fun awọn.Comrade Niyi Adefare to ṣaaju awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti ọhun ṣalaye laafin Ọọni pe iya nla lo n jẹ gbogbo awọn tiletile, bẹẹ lawọn si ti di alagbe laarin ilu.O ni arugbo lo pọ ju ninu awọn, o si nira lati ri owo itọju san nileewosan latari airi owo gba lọwọ ijọba.Laadin Ileefẹ, Oloye-agba Kayọde Awofiranye, to gba awọn eeyan naa lorukọ Ọọni, ba wọn kẹdun gbogbo nnkan ti wọn sọ pe awọn n la kọja.Awofiranye sọ fun wọn pe oun yoo jiṣẹ wọn fun Ọọni, kabiyesi yoo si gbe igbesẹ lọgan lati ri ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun lori ọrọ wọn."},{"question":"Sheeg qofkii ugu horeeyey ee Islaamka u hijrooda?","answer":"Qofkii ugu horeeyey ee Islaamka u hijrooda waa Cusmaan Bin Cafaan Iyo Rukhiya bintuMuxammed Rc"},{"question":"How does Colombo's culinary scene reflect its multicultural identity, and what positive contributions has it made to the global gastronomic landscape?","answer":"Colombo's culinary scene is a testament to its multicultural identity, featuring a diverse array of cuisines influenced by Sri Lanka's rich history. From traditional Sri Lankan dishes to international flavors, Colombo's restaurants and street food stalls cater to a variety of tastes. This culinary diversity not only enriches the local dining experience but also positions Colombo as a gastronomic destination, positively contributing to the global appreciation of Sri Lankan cuisine."},{"question":"Wasiu Ayinde, gbajugbaja onifuji, ti ku o","answer":"Agba ọjẹ lagbo ere Fuji, Alhaji Wasiu Salawudeen Gbọlagade Ayinde, ti jade láyé.Losan-an Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, lọkunrin to fi orin kikọ jọ Wasiu Ayinde (K1 Dé Ultimate) yii jade laye.Lẹyin to kirun ọsan tan ni wọn lo deede ṣubú lulẹ̀, ti ọkunrin ti ko ṣàìsàn tẹlẹ yii sì di ẹni tí wọn sáré gbe digba-digba lọ sileewosan fún itọjuṢugbọn nigba ti wọn yóò fi dọ́sibítù, ẹ́lẹ́ran ti túkùn lọrun akọni.Gẹgẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, gbajumọ olorin Fuji ti awọn èèyàn tun mọ si Wasiu Afárá yii fi orin atata da awọn éèyàn laraya nibi ariya kan ti wọn ṣe l’Ogbomọṣọ ti í ṣe ilu abinibi ẹ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ìyẹn lọjọ to ku ọlá to maa ku gan-an, lai mọ pe àkọgbẹ̀yìn orin oun loun kọ lọjọ naa.Oun lolorin Fuji to lamilaaka ju lọ niluu Ogbomọṣọ. Ta a ba sí yọwọ Alhaji Rasheed Ayinde Merenge ati Alhaji Taye Adebisi Currency ti wọn n gbe ilu Ibadan kuro, boya lolorin Fuji kan wa nipinlẹ Ọjọ to làlùyọ to ọkunrin to doloogbe yii. Bi eeyan ko ba sì jẹ ẹni to ti n gbọ orin awọn mejeeji tipẹ́, o ṣòro ki oluwa ẹ̀ tóo lè mọ pe ki í ṣe Wasiu Ayinde Ọba Fuji lo n pèdè nigbakugba ti Alhaji Wasiu Ayinde Ogbomọṣọ yii ba n kọrin.Itẹkuu awọn Musulumi to wa niluu Ogbomọṣọ ni wọn sinkú olorin Fuji naa si nirọlẹ Ọjọ́bọ̀, Tọsidee, kan naa to dagbere faye."},{"question":"Write a continuation for this paragraph - Danimarka milli takımıyla 145 maçta 167 gol atan Møllgaard, ilk milli maçını 3 Haziran 2006'da Hollanda'ya karşı oynadı. 2011 Dünya Erkekler Hentbol Şampiyonası'nda geniş kadroda yer aldı. İspanya'daki 2013 Dünya Şampiyonası ve kendi ülkesindeki 2014 Avrupa Şampiyonası'nda gümüş madalya kazandı. 2016 Avrupa Şampiyonası'nda, All-Star takımının en iyi savunma oyuncusu seçildi. 2019 Dünya Şampiyonası","answer":"'nda takımı dünya şampiyonu oldu."},{"question":"吊るし切りにして食べる魚といえばアンコウですが、一般に骨切りにして食べる魚といえば何でしょう？","answer":"ハモ（鱧）です。"},{"question":"Magbigay ka ng isang Pilipinong kanta na ang tema ay tungkol sa Pasok.","answer":"Isa sa mga sikat na kanta sa araw ng Pasko ay ang \\"Ang Pasko ay Sumapit\\" ni Levi Celerio na nilabas noong 1950. Ito ay binubuo ng mga lyrics na:Ang Pasko ay sumapitTayo ay mangagsiawitNg magagandang himigDahil sa Diyos ay pag-ibigNang si Kristo ay isilangMay tatlong haring nagsidalawAt ang bawat isaAy nagsipaghandog ng tanging alayBagong taon ay magbagong-buhayNang lumigaya ang ating bayanTayo'y magsikap upang makamtan natin ang kasaganaanTayo'y mangagsiawitHabang ang mundo'y tahimikAng araw ay sumapitNg Sanggol na dulot ng langitTayo ay magmahalanAting sundin ang gintong aralAt magbuhat ngayon kahit hindi pasko ay magbigayan"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa meelaha dadka laga duro ( injectin sites) ?","answer":"Nuucyada duriin ee ugu caansan ee laa iyo hada la adeegsado waa 5 nuu1.Duriinka xididka (interavenous injection) 2.Duriinka muruqa (intra muscular injection) 3.Duriinka maqaarka (intra derma) 4.Duriinka baruurta (subcutaneous) 5.Duriinka xangulaha(spinal injection) Muruqa meelo badan ayaa laga duraa waana duriin ubahaan in si  cilmiyeesan  qofka  loo  duro  waxaana  laga  qaataa  qeebo badan sida \\u0002Sinta           ( Ventrogluteal muscale of th hip) \\u0002Garabka     ( Deltoid muscle of the arm) \\u0002 Cajarka       ( Vastus lateralis site) Ujeedooyinka loodurayo muruqa waa n daawadu ku gaarto si tartiib ah jirka inta badan muruqa waxaa laga qaataa daawada ugu  tanka  badan  lana  doonayo  in  sitatartiib  ah  lagu  nuugo laguna darao dhiga,  Qiyaasta   daawada   ee   muruqa   lagu shubikaro   waa   2...5 mililiters."},{"question":"ترجم الجملة التالية إلى اللغة العربية: ?how are you doing","answer":"كيف حالك؟"},{"question":"作家柴田錬三郎が生んだ、円月殺法の達人として一世を風靡した剣士は誰でしょう？","answer":"眠狂四郎です。"},{"question":"Tôi làm văn phòng, thường xuyên chuẩn bị món ăn tại nhà từ sáng, mang đến cơ quan tiêu thụ, như vậy có tốt cho sức khỏe?","answer":"Thói quen mang cơm trưa đi làm rất tốt, vừa giảm gánh nặng kinh tế, vừa đảm bảo an toàn. Hiện nay, các dụng cụ đựng thực phẩm cũng rất hữu dụng, đa dạng và đảm bảo.Tuy nhiên, khi bạn nấu từ sáng, đến trưa mới ăn, cần chú ý đến chất lượng thực phẩm, nên lựa chọn thực phẩm và ăn uống đúng cách để không bị mất chất dinh dưỡng. Việc hâm lại thức ăn tưởng tốt nhưng nếu không chú ý sẽ làm mất chất dinh dưỡng, ảnh hưởng chất lượng món ăn. Nguyên tắc là tránh hâm nóng, hoặc chỉ làm ấm thực phẩm.Với cơm trắng, bạn có thể hâm nóng lại để dễ ăn hơn. Tuy nhiên, với các loại rau lá, nhất là canh rau, không nên hâm nóng lại, vì quá trình thái rửa chế biến đã mất nhiều vitamin, tiếp tục hâm nóng sẽ tiêu hao thêm chất dinh dưỡng.Các loại thực phẩm cung cấp chất béo và chất đạm như thịt, cá, trứng... không nên hâm nóng, vì ngoài mất chất dinh dưỡng, hương vị cũng kém phần thơm ngon. Tốt nhất nên ăn nguội cùng cơm nóng, vì đồ ăn được chế biến buổi sáng, bảo quản trong hộp kín thì tới trưa không thể ôi thiu được.Nhìn chung, ăn uống phụ thuộc nhiều vào vấn đề sở thích, điều kiện kinh tế, sự hiểu biết về dinh dưỡng nên mỗi người sẽ có những lựa chọn khác nhau. Tuy nhiên, làm sao để món ăn vừa ngon, vừa chứa nhiều chất dinh dưỡng là tốt nhất."},{"question":"Voltooi de zin: Philips de Blote was een","answer":"Hoek. Hij verdedigde als zodanig een blokhuis in Rotterdam, en was later hoofdman op de vloot. Hij stierf waarschijnlijk voor 10 december 1427, want toen erfde zijn jongere broer Dirc de Blote zijn bezittingen."},{"question":"Iza moa ny mpanjaka malagasy fantatra fa nampirisika ny olona ny hiova finoana ho kristianina?","answer":"Radama II no mpanjaka malagasy fantatra fa nampirisika ny olona hiova finoana ho kristianina."},{"question":"Quais são os 3 maiores times da cidade de São Paulo?","answer":"Os 3 maiores times da cidade de São Paulo são: Sociedade Esportiva Palmeiras, Sport Club Corinthians Paulista e São Paulo Futebol Clube."},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri kanun labarai dan wannan labari mai zuwa: Klopp ya yi sanadin kokar Parker kociyan Bournemouth","answer":"Bournemouth ta kori, Scott Parker, bayan da kungiyar ta sha kashi a gidan Liverpool da ci 9-0 ranar Asabar, bayan wasa hudu da ya ja ragama a Premier League. Rashin nasara da ta yi a hannun kungiyar Anfield ya zama karo na uku a jere da aka ci Bournemouth, bayan da ta fara doke Aston Villa 2-0. Tuni Bournemouth ta nada Gary O'Neil kociyan rikon kwarya, sannan Shaun Cooper da Tommy Elphick za su taimaka masa. Parker ya koma Bournemouth daga Fulham a Yunin 2021, wanda ya kai kungiyar gasar Premier League a bana, bayan da ta yi ta biyu a Championship a bara. Bayan da Bournemouth ta fara doke Aston Villa 2-0 a gida, kawo yanzu an zura mata kwallo 16 a wasa ukun da ta yi da 4-0 a hannun Manchester City da 3-0 a wurin Arsenal, sai Liverpool da ta zura 9-0 a Anfield. Rarar kwallo 14 a ragar Bournmouth shi ne rashin kokari mafi muni a babbar gasar tamaula ta Ingila, bayan fafatawa hudu da fara kaka a tarihi. Shi ne kocin farko a Premier League bayan shekara 18 da aka sallama cikin Agusta tun bayan Bobby Robson a Newcastle a 2004. Shi ne na 11 da aka kora bayan wasa hudu da fara kakar tamaula, na karshe-karshe da aka sallama shi ne Javi Gracia a Watford a 2019."},{"question":"\\"Адат — адат эмес\\" деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи ?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакаптын жообу мындай болушу мүмкүн : \\"Адат — адат эмес, жөн — адат\\""},{"question":"Mais tarde, a Peyton é vista ao telefone com o Larry, o seu pai adoptivo. O Larry foi visto mais tarde com a Peyton, o pai adoptivo, ao telefone. Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou não?","answer":"Não, as duas frases não têm o mesmo significado."},{"question":"දරිද්‍රතාව මුලිනුපුටා දැමීමේ අන්තර්ජාතික දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"දරිද්‍රතාව මුලිනුපුටා දැමීම සඳහා අන්තර්ජාතික දිනය ලෙස නම් කර ඇත්තේ ඔක්තෝබර් 17 දිනය යි."},{"question":"3 శూన్యేతర వాస్తవ శూన్య విలువలు కలిగిన బహుపది పరిమాణం ……………(A) 3 కంటే తక్కువ(B) 3 లేదా అంతకంటే ఎక్కువ(C) 3 లేదా అంతకంటే తక్కువ(D) ఏదీకాదు","answer":"(B) 3 లేదా అంతకంటే ఎక్కువ"},{"question":"Sa anong sikat na TV series bida ang karakter na Sheldon Cooper?","answer":"Ang karakter na Sheldon Cooper ay bida sa dalawang sikat na TV series, ang The Big Bag Theory at Young Sheldon."},{"question":"Eve Esin","answer":"Eve Esin jẹ́ òṣèré ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà kan tí ó ti gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti City People Entertainment Awards fún ẹ̀ka ti Òṣèrébìnrin tó ní ìlérí jùlọ ni Nàìjíríà ní ọdún 2015, àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti AMAA fún amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin tí ó dára jùlọ àti àmì-ẹ̀yẹ AMVCA fún ti òṣèrébìnrin tó dára jùlọ nínu eré ìtàgé.A bí Esin ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Akwa Ibọm, ní ìjọba agbègbè Oron, gúúsù Nàìjíríà. Esin parí ilé-ìwé alákọ̀ọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní ìlú abínibí rẹ̀ ní Akwa Ibom.Lẹ́hìn èyí, ó tẹ̀síwájú láti ka ìwé mẹ́wàá ní Immaculate Conception Secondary School tí ó wà ní agbègbè Itak-Ikono, Ìpínlẹ̀ Akwa Ibom níbi tí ó ti gba Ìwé-ẹ̀rí fún ìparí ẹ̀kọ́ mẹ́wàá rẹ̀. Lẹ́hìn náà, Esin lọ sí Yunifásitì ìlú Calabar ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Cross River níbití ó ti gba oyè ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ eré ìtàgé.Ṣáaj́u kí Esin tó darapọ̀ mọ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ fíìmù ti Nàìjíríà tí a mọ̀ ní Nollywood ní ọdún 2008, ó jẹ́ òṣìṣẹ́ ilé ìfowópamọ́ kí ó tó padà wá fi òpin sí ṣíṣẹ iṣẹ̀ náà láti lè gbájúmọ́ iṣẹ́ òṣèré. Esin darapọ̀ mọ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ fíìmù tí Nàìjíríà (Nollywood) ní ọdún 2008 lẹ́yìn ṣíṣe àyẹ̀wò láti kópa nínu fíìmù kan níbití ó ti ṣàṣeyọrí tó sì jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn olùkópa nínu fíìmù náà. Esin ṣe àkọ́kọ́ dídaŕi fíìmù pẹ̀lú dídarí fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Spirit. Gẹ́gẹ́bí ilé-iṣẹ́ oníròyìn The Tribune ti ṣe sọ di mímọ̀, Esin ti ní ìfihàn tó lé ní ọgọ́rùn-ún nínu fíìmù."},{"question":"Sonsuz aşk hangi çiçek?","answer":"“Sonsuz Aşk”ın Simgesi Maviçan Çiçeği."},{"question":"Gwam onye bu Nwa n'afọ,sere esere kuru ekuru","answer":"Ose"},{"question":"What role does the traditional \\"Kapruka\\" or wish-fulfilling tree play in Sri Lankan folklore, and how does it positively contribute to beliefs in luck and prosperity?","answer":"The traditional \\"Kapruka,\\" often referred to as the wish-fulfilling tree in Sri Lankan folklore, holds a special place in beliefs related to luck and prosperity. According to folklore, it is believed that tying a wish on the branches of the Kapruka tree will bring good fortune. The positive impact lies in the cultural significance of this ritual, fostering a sense of hope and optimism. The Kapruka tree becomes a symbol of collective aspirations, connecting individuals to a shared belief in the potential for positive outcomes and fulfilled wishes."},{"question":"පහත ගීතයට තනු නිර්මාණය කලේ කවුද?සරුංගලේ වරල් සැලේ..සරුංගලේ වරල් සැලේ නිසංසලේ ගුවන් තලේඅපෙන් මිදී වෙන රටකද යන්න හදන්නේඋපන් බිමට වැඩිය තැනක් කොහෙද තියෙන්නේසරුංගලේ බට පතුරෙන් නුඹ සැදුවේ අපේ ළමයිසරුංගලේ ලාටු උලා රැළි කෙරුවේ අපේ ළමයිසරුංගලේ කොල අලවා හැඩ කෙරුවේ අපේ ළමයිසරුංගලේ නුඹ අහසේ අපේ ළමයි තාම බිමයිසරුංගලේ නුඹ වෙනුවෙන් ගුටි කෑවේ අපේ ළමයිසරුංගලේ නූල් යොදා උඩ ඇරියේ අපේ ළමයිසරුංගලේ උඩ ගියදා මතක නැතේ අපේ ළමයිසරුංගලේ නුඹ වාගෙයි රට හැර යන අපේ ළමයි","answer":"සංගීතය:- නන්දා මාලිනී."},{"question":"\\"উত্তর\\" শব্দের বিভিন্ন অর্থ কি?","answer":"উত্তর মানে দিকউত্তর মানে একটি প্রশ্নের উত্তরও"},{"question":"Tử tù đầu tiên ở Côn Đảo là ai?","answer":"chị Võ Thị Sáu sinh năm 1933 trong một gia đình nghèo, cha làm nghề đánh xe ngựa, mẹ bán bì bún tại chợ. Đầu năm 1946, thực dân Pháp trở lại chiếm các địa bàn tại Bà Rịa lần thứ hai, trong đó có Đất Đỏ. Chị Sáu lúc ấy vừa tròn 11 tuổi.Năm 1947, lúc 14 tuổi, chị Sáu vừa làm nhiệm vụ mua hàng, vừa làm giao liên để nắm tình hình địch và làm mật hộ viên công an xung phong Đất Đỏ. Tuy còn nhỏ tuổi, chị rất mưu trí, lanh lẹ và luôn hoàn thành nhiệm vụ được phân công.Tháng 12/1949, chị Sáu sa vào tay giặc, bị giam giữ tại nhà tù Đất Đỏ, khám đường Bà Rịa, sau đó ở khám Chí Hòa. Dù không có bằng chứng, thực dân Pháp vẫn kết án chị tử hình và đày ra Côn Đảo. Chị Võ Thị Sáu hy sinh ngày 23/1/1952.Chị Võ Thị Sáu là tử tù đầu tiên ở Côn Đảo, cũng là nữ tù nhỏ tuổi nhất. Chị được nhà nước truy tặng danh hiệu Anh hùng Lực lượng vũ trang nhân dân vào ngày 2/8/1993. "},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Theo Bộ Y tế, hàng năm Việt Nam vẫn ghi nhận từ 600.000- 1.000.000 trường hợp mắc cúm mùa, số mắc ghi nhận quanh năm và có xu hướng gia tăng vào thời điểm chuyển mùa hè - thu, đông - xuân. Thực tế đáng lo ngại hiện nay là người dân mắc cúm đa số sẽ tự mua thuốc, tự điều trị tại nhà, thậm chí nhiều trường hợp tự tìm các thuốc trị cúm như Tamiflu trên mạng, mua về điều trị mà không theo sự kê đơn của bác sĩ. Liên quan đến vấn đề này, Cục Quản lý Khám chữa bệnh- Bộ Y tế vừa có văn bản khẩn gửi Sở Y tế các tỉnh, thành phố; Các Viện/ Bệnh viện trực thuộc Bộ Y tế; Y tế các ngành về việc tăng cường giám sát kê đơn, sử dụng thuốc kháng virus trong điều trị cúm. Về việc người dân tự tìm mua thuốc Tamiflu chứa hoạt chất oseltamivir để điều trị cúm, Cục Quản lý Khám chữa bệnh cho hay: \\"Đây là loại thuốc được chỉ định trong trường hợp người bệnh nhiễm cúm (nghi ngờ hoặc xác định) có biến chứng hoặc có yếu tố nguy cơ, không được tự ý sử dụng khi không có chỉ định của bác sĩ do làm tăng nguy cơ đề kháng thuốc dẫn đến những tác dụng không mong muốn và tổn thất về kinh tế\\". Do đó Cục Quản lý Khám, chữa bệnh đề nghị","answer":"các đơn vị tăng cường công tác truyền thông về phòng, chống bệnh cúm để người dân hiểu và không tự ý mua thuốc kháng virus để điều trị cúm. Đồng thời, chỉ đạo cơ sở khám bệnh, chữa bệnh trên địa bàn thực hiện điều trị cúm theo các hướng dẫn chẩn đoán và điều trị cúm của Bộ Y tế. Chú trọng công tác kê đơn an toàn, hợp lý và hiệu quả, đặc biệt với thuốc kháng virus để điều trị cúm. Theo BS Vũ Quốc Đạt, giảng viên Bộ môn Truyền nhiễm (Đại học Y Hà Nội), thành viên Mạng lưới đánh giá và ứng phó về lâm sàng các bệnh mới nổi của WHO, người dân không nên tự ý mua Tamiflu để điều trị bệnh cúm, vì thuốc Tamiflu hiện nay chủ yếu sử dụng đối với bệnh nhân mắc cúm nặng, hoặc đối tượng có nguy cơ bệnh tiến triển nặng. \\"Với những người không có bệnh lý nền, khỏe mạnh, khi mắc cúm triệu chứng nhẹ, việc dùng Tamiflu là không cần thiết. Nếu sử dụng Tamiflu không đúng cách sẽ dẫn đến tình trạng kháng thuốc. "},{"question":"Кублайдын акыркы блогу кайсы? ","answer":"Кытайдын түндүгүндөгү бийлигин бекемдегенден кийин, Кубилай монгол жана кытай империализминин салтына ылайык экспансиялык саясат жүргүзгөн. Ал түштүктөгү Сун династиясына каршы согуш жүргүзүүнү уланткан. Кубилай 1268 - 1273 - жылдары Сянянды курчоого алган. 1274 - жылы Жапонияга каршы ийгиликсиз деңиз экспедициясы жүргүзүлгөн. Кубилай 1276 - жылы Кытайдын эң бай шаары болгон Ханчжоунун Сундун борборун басып алган. Сун динин туткан эл баш калаадан качып чыгып, жаш баланы Сун императору кылып такка отургузушкан. Монголиялыктар 1279 - жылы Ямен согушунда Лоялисттерди жеңип алышкан. Сун династиясынын соңку императору сууга чөгүп өлөт. Сун династиясынын басып алуусу менен Кытайдын түндүгү менен түштүгү 300 жылдан бери биринчи жолу бириккен."},{"question":"كيف يمكن قياس النشاط الإشعاعي في الأغذية؟","answer":"يمكن قياس المواد المشعة المتسربة على إثر طارئة إشعاعية أو نووية في البيئة باستخدام طرق كشف مختلفة. ويمكن تحديد كميات صغيرة جدا من النشاط الإشعاعي، مثل تلك الموجودة بشكل طبيعي في الأغذية، باستخدام تقنيات الكشف الحساسة للغاية المتاحة حاليا. وينبغي أن يستهدف اعتيان الأغذية، على سبيل الأولوية، الأغذية الرئيسية التي يحتمل أن تساهم في التعرض للإشعاع، استناداً إلى قابليتها للتلوث الإشعاعي وأهميتها في النظام الغذائي لعامة السكان وأشد الفئات السكانية ضعفا، مثل الرضع وصغار الأطفال والنساء في سن الإنجاب. ومن المهم أن يوضع في الاعتبار أن تعرّض الأغذية للمواد المشعة يمكن أن يزداد نتيجة لارتفاع تركيز الأغذية الملوثة أو معدل استهلاكها، وبالتالي فإنه يلزم النظر في كلا الجانبين."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Shin yaya za a rubuta goma a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 10"},{"question":"Akụ mmiri igwe","answer":"nkpuru mmiri "},{"question":"Кыргызстанда канча район бар?","answer":"Кыргыз Республикасында 40район бар."},{"question":"\\"Азаматтын жакшысы азыраак сүйлөп ... \\" деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи! ","answer":" \\"Азаматтын жакшысы азыраак сүйлөп, көп тыңшайт\\""},{"question":"வினா: ரெனின் என்ற என்ஸைம் ……………… மீது வினைபுரிகிறது","answer":"விடை: கேஸினோஜன்"},{"question":"Sheeg magaca Gabyaagii curiyey tuducyada soo socda:Nin Ugaas walaalkii yahoo eeday baan ahayeNin ilo biyood soo arkoo oomman baan ahaye","answer":"Waxaa curiyey Raage Ugaas"},{"question":"Sino si Fernando Amorsolo?","answer":"Si Fernando Amorsolo ay isang kilalang pintor mula sa Pilipinas na tinaguriang \\"Grand Old Man of Philippine Art\\".  Isa siya sa mga pangunahing alagad ng sining sa bansa na kilala dahil sa kanyang mahusay na paggamit ng ilaw at kulay sa kanyang mga \\"impressionistic\\" na likha. Kilala rin siya sa kanyang mga obra na kadalasang napapakita ng mga tanawing at tauhang probinsyal, katulad ng makikita sa kanyang mga likha na \\"Rice Planting\\", \\"Fruit Pickers Under the Mango Tree\\" at \\"Dalagang Bukid\\". Itinatampok  ang kanyang mga likha sa iba't ibang museo at galeriya sa buong mundo."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමයේ සභාපතිවරයා වන්නේ","answer":"සාලිය පීරිස් මහතා"},{"question":"Ｆ１グランプリで、ワールドチャンピオンを６回獲得している唯一のドライバーは誰でしょう？","answer":"ミヒャエル・シューマッハー ※シューマッハのみでＯＫ。です。"},{"question":"How many tribes are there in Madagascar?1. 62. 183. 19 ","answer":"Answer: 2) 18There are 18 different ethnic groups in Madagascar, and each has its own way."},{"question":"Boribory ve ny tany?","answer":"Eny"},{"question":"Ajàkálẹ̀-àrùn COVID-19 ní Seychelles","answer":"Ajàkálẹ̀-àrùn COVID-19 jẹ́ kíkóràn dé orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles ní oṣù kẹ́ta ọdún 2020. Orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles ní àkọsílẹ̀ àwọn aláàrẹ̀ COVID-19 tí iye wọn jẹ́ mọ́kànlá ní ọgbọ̀n ọjọ́ oṣù Karùún ọdún 2020.Oṣù kẹ́ta ọdún 2020Orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles kéde akọsílẹ̀ ajàkálẹ̀ àrùn COVID-19 rẹ̀ ní ọjọ́ kẹrìnlá oṣù kẹta lára àwọn ènìyàn méjì tí wọ́n fara kó àrùn yí lára ẹ́nìkan tí ó ti ní àrùn yí tẹ́lẹ̀ ní Orílẹ̀-èdè Italy Ní ọjọ́ kẹéẹ́dógún oṣù kẹta, wọ́n ní akọsílẹ̀ ẹnìkẹta tí tí ó kó àrùn náà nígbà tí ó ń bọ̀ láti orílẹ̀-èdè Netherlands. Àwọn ẹlòmíràn náà tún ní àrùn yí nígbà tí àwọn náà ń darí bọ̀ láti orílẹ̀-èdè Netherlands yí kan náà.Nígbà tí oṣù náà yóò fi parí, àwọn mẹ́wàá ni ayéwò rẹ̀ ti fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ wípé wọ́n ti ní àrùn Kòrónà ní orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles tí ẹnikẹ́ni kò sì kú.Oṣù kẹrin ọdún 2020Ní ọjọ́ kẹfà oṣù kẹrin ọdún 2020, wọ́n ṣe ìtọ́jú àwọn ènìyàn méjì nínú àwọn aláàrẹ̀ COVID-19, tí wọ́n sì padà sí ilé wọn láyọ̀.Níparí oṣù kẹrin, àwọn ènìyàn mẹ́rin ninú àwọn aláàrẹ̀ COVID-19, ni wọ́n rí ìtọ́jú gbà tí wọ́n sì padà sí ilé wọn láyọ̀. Ò sì ku àwọn márùún gedengbe tí wọ́n kù tí wọn sì wà lórí àárẹ̀ náà.Oṣù Karùún ọdún 2020Ní oṣù Karùún, ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles kéde wípé kò sí ajàkálẹ̀ àrùn COVID-19 ní orílẹ̀-èdè náà mọ́ bí ó ti wulẹ̀ kí ó kéré mọ. Nígbà tí yóò fi di ọjọ́ kejìdínlógún oṣù Karùún, gbogbo àwọn aláàrẹ̀ náà ti gbádùn tán pátá pátá.Oṣù Kẹfà ọdún 2020Ní ọjọ́ kejìdínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kẹfà, wọ́n tún rí akọsílẹ̀ àwọn ènìyàn míràn tí wọ́n jẹ́ aláàrẹ̀ COVID-19 tí iye wọn tó mọ́kàndínlọ́gọ́ta, méje míràn ní ọjọ́ kọkàndínlọ́gbọ̀n ati mẹ́rin míràn ní ọgbọ̀njọ́ oṣù Kẹfà tí ó mú kí iye gbogbo wọn jẹ́ ogójì lápapọ̀ nínú oṣù Kẹfà nìkan.  Iye àwọn ènìyàn tí wọ́n ti ní àrùn COVID-19 láti ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ jẹ́ mọ́kànléláàdọ́rin lápapọ̀, tí àwọn mọ́kanlá ti gba ìtọ́jú tí wọ́n sì padà sí ilé wọn láyọ̀. Ó ku àwọn àádóje ènìyàn tí wọn ṣì ń bá àárẹ̀ náà jà., níparí oṣù kẹfà. All 70 had previously tested negative in Abidjan or Dakar but positive on arrival in Seychelles.Oṣù keje ọdún 2020Wón tún ní akọsílẹ̀ mélòó kan tí wọ́n tí ó tó mẹ́talá tí ó mú kí gbogbo iye àwọn tí ó ní àrùn yí gùnkè sí mẹ́rìnlélàádósán, tí àwọn mẹ́talá sì jẹ́ ará ilẹ̀ òkèrè. Wọ́n tún rí àìsan yí lára àwọn ènìyàn mẹ́fà míran tí wọ́n jẹ́ ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles, tí ó mú iye àwọn aláàrẹ̀ náà lápapọ̀ ó jẹ́ ọgọ́rùún. By 22 July all six local patients had recovered. Iye àwọn aláàrẹ̀ náà ti di mẹ́rìnlélọ́gọ́rùún nígbà tí àwọn mọ́kandínlógójì ènìyàn sì rí ìwòsàn gbà níparí oṣù kẹfà.Ìfagilé lílọ-bíbọ̀Ní ọjọ́ kẹsàán oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020, ìjọba ilẹ̀ Seychelles ti ẹnu ibodè wọn ní orí omi àti cruise ships. Ní ọjọ́ kẹsàán oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020, orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles fagilé ìrìn-àjò àwọn ènìyàn láti lọ sí orílẹ̀-èdè China, South Korea, Italy ati Iran àmọ́ wọ́n fi ayè gba àwọn tí wọ́n bá fẹ́ padà wá sílé.Ọkùnrin ẹni ọdún mẹ́rìndínlógún tí ó jẹ́ òṣìṣẹ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ pápákọ̀ òfurufú kan náà ní àrùn yí tí ó mú kí iye àwọn aláàrẹ̀ arùn Kòrónà ó di mọ́kànlá ní inú oṣù kẹ́rin. Lẹ́yìn tí wọ́n ṣàkíyèsí èyí ni wọ́n ṣe òfin kónílé-ó-gbélé fún gbogbo ènìyàn ayàfi àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ tí iṣè wọn ṣe kókó jùlọ. Òfin yí yóò bẹ́rẹ́ iṣẹ́ ní alẹ́ ọjọ́rú ọjọ́ kẹjọ oṣù kẹ́rin ọdún 2020, yoo sì wà ní lílò títí di ọjọ́ mọ́kànlélógún gbáko. It opened again to scheduled traffic on 1 August.Ilé Ìṣẹ̀mbáyéLẹ́yìn tí wọ́n sòfin kónílé-ó-gbélé ní ọjọ́ kẹsàán oṣù kẹ́rin ọdún 2020, ilé-iṣẹ́ tí ó ń mójú tó ilé ìṣẹ̀mbáyé ń múra láti ṣí ilé ọ̀hún padà fún àwọn ènìyàn ní ọjọ́ Kíní oṣù Kẹfà ọdún 2020, fúndí èyí orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles ni yóò jẹ́ orílẹ̀-èdè akọ́kọ́ tí yóò ṣí ilé ìṣẹ̀mbáyé fún àwọn ènìyàn lásìkò ìtànkálẹ̀ ajàkálẹ̀ àrùn COVID-19 ní apá àríwá ilẹ̀ Afirikà.Kí gbogbo ilé-iṣẹ́ ati okòwò ó tó lè bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ òòjọ́ padà, ilé-iṣẹ́ ìjọba tí ó ń rí sí ètò ìlera wọ́n ní láti ṣe àgbékalẹ̀ àwọn ìlàna àti ààtò kọ̀ọ̀kan kalẹ̀ láti lè dá ààbò bo àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ ilé ìṣẹ̀mbáyé náà àti àwọn olùbẹ̀wò ibẹ̀ gbogbo kí wọ́n má ba ma pín àrùn fúnra wọn. Lára awọn ìlànà àti ààtò náà ni wípé: mímójú tó iye ènìyàn tí yóò ma wọ ilé ìṣẹ̀mbáyé lásìkò kan náà. Fagilé ìgbẹ̀wò míràn bí ó bá ṣe é ṣe. Ṣíṣe ìmọ́tótó àyíkà gbogbo, àti ìtọ́jú òun ìrànwọ́ fún àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ náà.Mímú ìdẹ̀rùn bá àwọn òfinNí ọjọ́ kejìdínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kẹ́rin, Ààrẹ ilẹ̀ orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles ọ̀gbẹ́ni Danny Faure kéde wípé ìjọba ti ṣetán láti mú ìdẹ́rùn bá àwọn ará Ìlú lórí àwọn òfin tí wọ́n ti ṣe láti lè dẹ́kun ìtànkálẹ̀ ajàkálẹ̀ arùn COVID-19 ní orílẹ̀-èdè náà. Wọ́n gbójú kúrò luru òfin ìrìnà ní ọjọ́ kẹrin oṣù Karùún ọdún 2020, nígbà tí wọ́n tún fàyè gba àwọn ilé-ìtajà gbogbo láti ma bá iṣẹ́ okòwò wọn lọ ní ọjọ́ yí kan náà láti àárọ̀ títí di agogo mẹ́jọ alẹ́. Wọ́n ṣí àwọn ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gbogbo padà ní ọjọ́ kọkànlá àti ọjọ́ kejìdínlógún oṣù Karùún. Wọ́n sì fòpin sí gbogbo àwọn òfin náà ní ọjọ́ Kíní oṣù kẹfà ọdún 2020.Air Seychelles resumed domestic flights on May 4, and SEI reopened to international traffic on June 1.Gbèdéke lórí ìrìn-àjò lọ sókè òkunNí ọjọ́ kẹsàán oṣù Karùún, ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles fagilé ìwọlé sí orílẹ̀-èdè wọn láti ẹnu ibodè Victoria títí di ìparí ọdún 2021. Àwọn ènìyàn tí wọ́n bá darí sí orílẹ̀-èdè Seychelles láti orí ọkọ̀ ojú-omi, wọ́n ní láti wà ní iyàrá àdágbé fún ọjọ́ fún ọjọ́ mẹ́rìnlá gbáko. Nígbà tí àwọn àwọn tí wọ́n bá darí láti orí ọkọ̀ òfurufú, wọ́n ní láti ṣe ayéwò láàrín ọjọ́ méjì kí wọ́n tó dá wọn sílẹ̀."},{"question":"Kañ geén di tàmbli wax wolof degantaan?","answer":"Ñongi jàngg de"},{"question":"साबुनको बारेमा विज्ञापन लेख्न मलाई सहायता गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"चम्किलो, स्वच्छ र त्वचाको ख्याल राख्ने हाम्रो \\"सुर्योसाना साबुन\\" आएको छ।हाम्रो \\"सुर्योसाना सबुन\\"ले तपाईंको त्वचालाई रङ्गिन, मुल्यघटित र सुरक्षित बनाउँछ। नेपाली उद्योगको गर्व, हाम्रो साबुनले तपाईंलाई निश्चित गर्दछ कि तपाईंको त्वचाको देखरेखमा हामी सहायता गर्ने छ।हाम्रो साबुनको विशेषताहरूले तपाईंलाई प्रभावित गर्ने छन्:१. प्राकृतिक सामग्री: हाम्रो साबुन पूर्णतापूर्वक प्राकृतिक सामग्रीहरूले बनाइएको छ। यसको प्रयोग गर्दा, तपाईं अपूर्वता र निर्मलता संग चम्किला त्वचाको अनुभव गर्नुहुनेछ।२. नम्रता र मधुरता: हाम्रो साबुनले तपाईंलाई नम्रता र मधुरताको एक संयोग प्रदान गर्दछ। यसले तपाईंको स्नानको समयलाई आनन्दमय बनाउनेछ।३. त्वचाको क्षति नियन्त्रण: हाम्रो साबुनले त्वचाको क्षति नियन्त्रणमा मद्दत गर्दछ। यसले तपाईंको त्वचालाई मुलायमा, फुर्सदमा र स्वस्थताका ख्यालमा राख्नेछ।त्वचाका लागि राम्रो साबुन खोज्नुहुनेले हाम्रो साबुनलाई चिन्नुहोस्। \\"सुर्योसाना साबुन\\"ले चम्किला, स्वच्छ र सुन्दर त्वचाको लागि सधैं साथी बन्नेछ।अबैं साथ चलौं, त्वचाको जिवनमा सुख र प्रभावित हुन तपाईंको \\"सुर्योसाना साबुन\\"सँग।"},{"question":"O cineasta Frank Capra, famoso por It's a Wonderful Life, nasceu em que país mediterrâneo?","answer":"Itália"},{"question":"Tuberkulosis (TBC) di Indonesia memiliki sejarah panjang. TBC di Indonesia diduga sudah ada sejak abad ke-8. Dugaan tersebut merujuk pada penemuan relief di panel Lalitawistara, salah satu relief Candi Borobudur, yang menggambarkan seorang bertubuh kurus sedang sakit Berdasarkan paragraf di atas, pada abad keberapakah penyakit TBC diduga masuk pertama kali ke Indonesia? Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya.Jawaban:","answer":"Penyakit TBC diduga masuk pertama kali ke Indonesia sejak abad ke-8. Dugaan ini didasarkan pada jejak peninggalan sejarah yang terukir di panel Lalitawistara, salah satu relief Candi Borobudur, yang menggambarkan seorang bertubuh kurus yang sedang sakit."},{"question":"Onye dere akwụkwọ \\"Abụ na Egwuregwu Odinaala Igbo\\"?","answer":"Onye dere \\"Abụ na Egwuregwu Odinaala Igbo\\" bụ N. Ugonna n'afọ 1980."},{"question":"ප්‍රාශ්වස වාතයේ වැඩිපුරම අඩංගු වායුව කුමක්ද?","answer":"කාබන් ඩයොක්සයිඩ්"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity.Fanambarana: \\"Nahazo tapak'ila amin'ny rindran-kira ankafiziko indrindra aho!\\"","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho fifaliana. Faly be ilay olona vao fantany fa nahazo tapak'ila sy handeha hijery rindran-kira amin'ilay tena ankafiziny izy."},{"question":"Rufaffiyar Gaɓa?","answer":"Kan + n, za ta zama Kann, sautin da babu shi a Hausa.Kan + o, za ta zama Kano wanda kuma ya zama kalma kenan mai gaɓoɓi biyu kamar haka: /ka/no/."},{"question":"Sheeg Nimcooyinka uu dhulka Soomaaliya kaga ficnyahay wadamada kale?","answer":"Waxaan leenahay  Xeeb ballaaran oo bilicsan, sido kalane laga hello kallun aad u badan , dalkeno wuxu sido kale qani Ku yahay beraha iyo ganacsiga, sido kale waa Dal aad u cimilo fican ,dalkuna waa Barwaaqo, Dadkiisuna waa dad fiican."},{"question":"Inona no hevitr'ity ohabolana ity: \\"Aza manao mpitari-bato vilam-bava, ny tondroin'ny molotra hafa, ny ataon'ny tanana hafa\\"?","answer":"Ny hevitry ny ohabolana hoe \\"Aza manao mpitari-bato vilam-bava, ny tondroin'ny molotra hafa, ny ataon'ny tanana hafa.\\" dia ny tokony hampifanojoana lalandava ny zavatra tenenina sy ny zavatra atao."},{"question":"എന്താണ് സിംഹവാലൻ കുരങ്ങൻ?","answer":"ദക്ഷിണേന്ത്യയിലെ പശ്ചിമഘട്ടത്തിൽ കാണപ്പെടുന്ന ഒരു പ്രൈമേറ്റ് ഇനമാണ് സിംഹവാലൻ കുരങ്. സവിശേഷമായ സിംഹത്തെപ്പോലെയുള്ള മേനിന് പേരുകേട്ട ഇത് വംശനാശഭീഷണി നേരിടുന്ന ഒരു ഇനമാണ്, ആവാസവ്യവസ്ഥയുടെ നാശവും വിഘടനവും ഭീഷണിപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. അതുല്യവും പാരിസ്ഥിതിക പ്രാധാന്യമുള്ളതുമായ ഈ പ്രൈമേറ്റിനെ സംരക്ഷിക്കുകയാണ് സംരക്ഷണ ശ്രമങ്ങൾ ലക്ഷ്യമിടുന്നത്."},{"question":"Ndị agha Naịjirịa were nwayọ na-akpasu ndị otu IPOBO kwuru na ọkwụ ọkụ mmụọ Nnamdi Kanu kwuru bụ eziokwu mana ndị ọchịchị Naịjirịa anaghị ekwu eziokwu.Achalla kwuru na ihe Nnamdi kanu na-achọ bụ ndị ọchịchị nye ndị Igbo ohere ka ha mee mbinye aka  nke nwereonwe ha nke a na-akpo referendum.O kwuru na ndị agha Naịjirịa amaghị ọrụ ha ọfụma makana ọ bụrụ na ha ma ha ga-eje kpọpụta ndị ọchị ehi na-egbusisi ụmụ mmadụ.Ọ jụrụ ebe ndị agha Naịjịrịa nọ mgbe Nnamdi Kanu pụrụ na Naịjirịa.Cheta na ụlọọrụ ndịisiagha Naịjirịa dị n'Abuja kwuru na ha dịla  njikere ị memina onyeisi otu IPOB bụ Nnamdi Kanu makana o kwuru na ọ ga-ewete ọkụ mmụọ ma ọ bata obodo Naịjirịa.Ha kwekwara mkwa na ha ga-akwụsị onye ọbụla maọbụ otu ọbụla ga -achọ i bute ọgbaghara na Naịjirịa.Ha nyere onye ọbụla na-ekpokoba ngwaagha maka ị ghasasi ntuliaka 2019 na ha chegharịa maọbụ ha chere ogolo aka iwu obodo ga-adakwasi ha.Ọ bụ onyeisi Ngalaba mgbasaozi ha bụ Brig-Gen. John Agim dọọrọ aka na nti a mgbe ọ na-agwa ndị ntaakụkọ maka etu ndị Naịjirịa sị emeri na atụmaatụ ha na Naijirịa na Abuja.N'ọnụ okwu ya, nhazi 777 na-aga n'ihu, onye ọbụla bu ọkụmmụọ abata Naịjirịa mara amara na ha na nhazi 777 ga-akwatụ ya, ọsọ kwa ya ya bụrụ Nnamdi maọbụ onyeọbụla.\\"Agim kwuru na ọ bụ maka ndị na-achọ itisa Naịjirịa ka eji wepụta atụmaatụ 777.O kwuru na nhazi 777 nke bidoro n'ọnwa October asatọ, egbuola ndị ekperima na oshi ruru iri atọ na ise ma nwụchie mmadụ a na-enyocha maka nrụrụaka ruru iri itoolu na asatọ.Agim kwuru na ọ bụrụ na ha nyocha ndị a chọpụta na aka ha adịghị ọcha, ha ga-ewere ha nyefee n'aka ndị uweojii.Nye m isiokwu dabara akụkọ a dị n'elu.","answer":"Isiokwu dabara akụkọ a bụ - Nnamdi Kanu: Ihe ndị agha Naịjiria kwuru maka ihe onyeisi ndị IPOB kwuru"},{"question":"ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਦਿ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਦੀ ਸਥਾਪਨਾ ਦੀ ਕਿਉਂ ਲੋੜ ਪਈ ?","answer":"ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਸਨ ਤਾਂ ਜੋ ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਸਾਹਿਬਾਨ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁੱਧ ਬਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਪੜ੍ਹ ਅਤੇ ਸੁਣ ਸਕਣ ।"},{"question":"Klima boğaz enfeksiyonu yapar mı?","answer":"Klima zararlarından korunma yollarıYaz aylarını kapalı ortamlarda çekilir hale getiren ve yaşam konforumuzu artıran klimalar bazen hastalıklara da neden olabiliyor. Bu rahatsızlıklar arasında ateşli boğaz enfeksiyonları, lejyoner hastalığı gibi hastalıklar bulunuyor."},{"question":"ታሊየም የተባለው የሰሜን ኮሪያ ቡድን ምስጢራዊ መረጃዎችን በመመዝበሩ በየት ተከሰሰ?","answer":"በምሥራቃዊ ቨርጂኒያ"},{"question":"Triều Nguyễn (1802-1945) trải qua bao nhiêu đời vua trị vì?a. 11b. 12c. 13d. 14","answer":"c. 13triều Nguyễn có 13 đời vuaTriều Nguyễn thành lập năm 1802 khi vua Gia Long lật đổ nhà Tây Sơn, lên ngôi hoàng đế; kết thúc năm 1945 khi Cách mạng tháng Tám thành công, vua Bảo Đại thoái vị, trao ấn kiếm lại cho chính quyền Việt Nam Dân chủ Cộng hòa. Đây là triều đại cuối cùng trong lịch sử phong kiến Việt Nam.Nhà Nguyễn trải qua 13 đời vua trị vì, gồm: Gia Long (1802-1820), Minh Mạng (1820-1841), Triệu Trị (1841-1847), Tự Đức (1847-1883), Dục Đức (1883), Hiệp Hòa (1883), Kiến Phúc (1883-1884), Hàm Nghi (1884-1885), Đồng Khánh (1885-1889), Thành Thái (1889-1907), Duy Tân (1907-1916), Khải Định (1916-1925), Bảo Đại (1926-1945)."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:కం. చుక్కలు తలపూవులుగానక్కజముగ మేనువెంచి యంబరవీథిన్వెక్కసమై చూపట్టిననక్కోమలి ముదము నొందు నాతృస్థితికిన్.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :అంబరవీధిన్ = ఆకాశవీధిలోనున్నచుక్కలు = నక్షత్రములుతలపూవులుగాన్ = తలలో పూవులవలె అయ్యేవిధంగా (అనగా నక్షత్ర లోకం దాకా)అక్కజముగన్ = ఆశ్చర్యపోయేట్లుగామేనువెంచి (మేను + పెంచి) = శరీరాన్ని పెంచివెక్కసమై (వెక్కసము + ఐ) = అధికంగాచూపట్టినన్ = కనబడగాఅక్కోమలి (ఆ + కోమలి) = ఆ సీతఆత్మస్థితికిన్ = తన పరిస్థితికిముదమున్ = సంతోషాన్నిఒందెన్ = పొందినదితాత్పర్యం :ఆకాశవీధిలోని నక్షత్రములు తన తలలోని పూవులు అయ్యే విధంగా ఆశ్చర్యం కలిగేటట్లు శరీరాన్ని పెంచి, హనుమంతుడు కనబడ్డాడు. అప్పుడు సీత తన స్థితికి సంతోషపడింది."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي تربى في بيت النبوة وكان ابن عمه؟","answer":"الإجابة: علي بن أبي طالب كرم الله وجهه"},{"question":"Iza amin’ireo portogey mpikaroka tany no voalohany nandeha sambo nanodidina ny tendrony atsimon’i Afrika, ka nanokatra ny lalana ho any amin’ny Ranomasimbe Indianina?","answer":"Bartolomeu Dias ilay mpikaroka portogey izay voalohany nandeha sambo nanodidina ny tendrony atsimon'i Afrika."},{"question":"Ity misy toe-java-niseho: “Nahita karazana vorona tsy fahita firy antsoina hoe Scarlet Macaw i Emily, tany an’ala.” Raha mamorona fanontaniana avy amin'io toe-java-niseho io isika, ary ny valin'io fanontaniana io dia \\"Emily\\", inona no fanontaniana?","answer":"\\"Iza no nahita ny karazana vorona antsoina hoe Scarlet Macaw tao an'ala ?\\" no fanontaniana azo apetraka raha \\"Emily\\" no valiny."},{"question":"ルルー原作の世界的大ヒットしたミュージカルの名前は「何座の怪人」でしょう？","answer":"オペラです。"},{"question":"د افغانستان قومي ویش په اقتصادي پراختیا او د منابعو په تخصیص څه اغیز کړی دی؟","answer":"په افغانستان کې توکمیز ویش په اقتصادي پراختیا او د منابعو په تخصیص باندې ژوره اغیزه کړې ده، چې توپیرونه او نابرابرۍ په بیلابیلو سیمو کې څرګندې دي. د منابعو غیر مساوي ویش، لکه د کرنې وړ ځمکې او اوبه، د توکمیزو ډلو ترمنځ د شخړې سرچینه ده، چې ډیری وختونه موجوده تاوتریخوالی لا پسې زیاتوي. د ښاري او کلیوالي سیمو ترمنځ اقتصادي توپیر، چیرې چې مختلف قومونه متمرکز دي، د پراختیا هڅې نورې پیچلې کوي. برسېره پر دې، د شوروي یرغل او وروسته د جګړو په ګډون تاریخي عوامل، اقتصادي فعالیتونه ګډوډ کړي او د یو باثباته اقتصادي بنسټ د جوړولو مخه ونیسي. دې ننګونو ته د رسیدو لپاره د توکمونو، اقتصادي پالیسیو، او د منابعو د مدیریت تر منځ د مداخلې په اړه د پام وړ پوهاوی ته اړتیا ده ترڅو دوامداره پرمختګ ته وده ورکړي چې د خلکو ټولو برخو ته ګټه ورسوي."},{"question":"Ahoana no hanaovana fiaramanidina taratasy? Manana vahaolana roa azo atao ianao:Vahaolana 1: Aforeto ny taratasy iray ho endrika fiaramanidina.Vahaolana 2: Manaova sokitra tanimanga iray ho endrika fiaramanidina.","answer":"Ny vahaolana 1 dia mitombina kokoa. Mora kokoa ny mamoritra taratasy iray ho endrika fiaramanidina raha oharina amin'ny fanaovana sokitra tanimanga."},{"question":"Ijọba fẹẹ mu Sunday Igboho ni gbogbo ọna","answer":"Adiẹ ba le okun, ara o rọ okun, ara o si rọ adiẹ, lọrọ gbajugbaja ọkunrin ajijagbara ilẹ Yoruba nni, Ṣunday Adeyẹmọ tawọn eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho da funjọba ati ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ilẹ wa bayii, latari bi wọn ṣe n wa gbogbo ọna lati fi pampẹ ofin gbe e ju satimọle.O kere tan, o ti di ẹẹmeji ọtọọtọ tawọn agbofinro ti gbe igbesẹ lati mu Sunday Igboho sahaamọ wọn, eyi to kẹyin ni ti lẹta ti ọga agba patapata fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nilẹ wa, IG Mohammed Adamu, kọ si ọkunrin naa l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii, wọn ni wọn fẹẹ ri i ni olu-ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ilẹ wa, l’Abuja.Ileeṣẹ akolẹta kan ti wọn kọkọ fi lẹta naa ran jiṣẹ fawọn ẹmẹwa Sunday nile rẹ to wa n’Ibadan, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn ẹmẹwa naa kọ lati gba lẹta ọhun lọwọ wọn, ẹyin eyi ni wọn lawọn ọlọpaa bii mẹẹẹdogun ya bo ile naa lọsan-an Ọjọbọ ọhun, wọn lọgaa awọn lo ran awọn niṣẹ lati fun Sunday Igboho ni lẹta. Mọto ayọkẹlẹ Toyota Corona kan lawọn kan lara wọn gbe wa.Awọn ẹṣọ alaabo to wa pẹlu Oloye Adeyẹmọ lo gba lẹta naa, wọn lawọn aa fi jiṣẹ fun un.Nirọlẹ ọjọ naa ni amugbalẹgbẹẹ oniroyin rẹ, Ọlayọmi Koiki, kọ atẹjade kan lori iṣẹlẹ ọhun pe Sunday Igboho ko ni i yọju sẹnikan lasiko yii, wọn ni ki ọga ọlọpaa kọkọ kọwe pe awọn agbebọn atawọn Boko Haraamu ti wọn n ṣọṣẹ kaakiri, ti wọn si n pa tọmọde tagba lẹkun lori ilẹ wọn na.Atẹjade naa fi kun un pe ki ọga ọlọpaa kede ni gbangba pe oun fẹ ki Sunday Igboho yọju soun, dipo ti yoo fi maa kọ lẹta labẹnu, tori awọn ṣi ranti bawọn kan ṣe fi lẹta oni-bọmbu pa Dele Giwa, gbajugbaja akọroyin ilẹ wa kan.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, lọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn, oṣu to kọja, lawọn ọlọpaa atawọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ kan lọọ rẹbuu Sunday Igboho lagbegbe ibudokọ Guru Maharaji, loju ọna marosẹ Eko s’Ibadan, diẹ lo ku ki wọn fi tipa tikuuku wọ ọkunrin naa lọ, ṣugbọn awọn ọdọ agbegbe naa ko jẹ ko ṣee ṣe fun wọn.Ohun ta a gbọ ni pe ijọba apapọ atawọn alagbara oṣelu kan ni wọn n wà lé IG Adamu lọrun pe afi ko wa gbogbo ọna ti wọn yoo fi mu Sunday Igboho, paapaa latari bi ọkunrin naa ṣe kede laipẹ yii nibi ipade kan ti wọn ṣe niluu Ibadan lọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu kẹta, pe dandan ni ki ẹya Yoruba ya kuro lara Naijiria, o ni Yoruba maa ni orileede tiwọn, to pe ni Oduduwa Republic.Olobo kan sọ pe latigba ti Sunday Igboho ti kede pe kawọn Fulani kẹru wọn kuro nilẹ Yoruba, ki wọn wabomi-in gba lọ, lawọn kan ti n dọdẹ ati mu ọkunrin naa, ṣugbọn ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa tun n bẹru ohun to le tidi ẹ yọ tiru nnkan bẹẹ ba ṣẹlẹ, tori ọgọọrọ ẹya Yoruba lo fara mọ igbesẹ Sunday Igboho, ti wọn gba tiẹ, ti wọn si n ṣatilẹyin fun un.Wọn lawọn ọlọpaa n woye pe tawọn ba fi pampẹ ofin mu un sahaamọ, afaimọ ni ki yanpọnyanrin ma bẹ silẹ, eyi si le da omi alaafia gbogbo agbegbe ilẹ Yoruba ati ti orileede lapaapọ ru, idi niyẹn ti wọn fi fiwe pe e s’Abuja.Amọ ṣa o, ọpọ awọn agbaagba ilẹ Yoruba ti da si igbesẹ tijọba fẹẹ gbe yii, bẹẹ ni wọn n laago ikilọ pe ọrọ naa le da wahala nla silẹ, ti ko si ni i yanju bọrọ.Amofin agba ilẹ wa ati ajafẹtọọ ọmọniyan, Fẹmi Falana, sọ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii, fawọn oniroyin pe ijọba o le mu Sunday Igboho lai kọkọ lọọ mu Shehu Gumi, aafaa ẹsin Islam to n ṣe agbodegba fawọn janduku agbebọn lapa Oke-Ọya.Falana ni “Ijọba o le mu Sunday Igboho tori awọn ti wọn ti kede pe kawọn ẹya mi-in kuro lori ilẹ awọn naa lapa Oke-Ọya wa tijọba o mu wọn. Ṣhehu Gumi to n da iyapa ẹsin silẹ, to si n ṣe wọle-wọde pẹlu awọn agbebọn naa wa nibẹ, wọn gbọdọ kọkọ mu awọn yẹn na.’’Bakan naa ni minisita fun igbokegbodo ọkọ ofurufu nigba kan, Oloye Fẹmi Fani-Kayọde, naa sọrọ ikilọ, o ni “Ohun to le tete da alaafia ati iṣọkan Naijiria ru, to le fọ gbogbo nnkan loju pọ, ni bawọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba apapọ kan ṣe faake kọri pe dandan ni ki wọn mu ọrẹ mi ati arakunrin mi, Sunday Igboho sahaamọ. Aṣiṣe nla gbaa lo maa jẹ fun ijọba ti wọn ba fi dan iru ẹ wo.” Ninu atẹjade kan to fi ṣọwọ sawọn oniroyin lo ti sọrọ ọhun lọjọ Eti.Amofin agba mi-in, Oloye Ifẹdayọ Adedipẹ, sọ pe oun o ri ẹsẹ kan ninu bi Sunday Igboho ṣe kọ lati gba lẹta ipe ọga agba patapata ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa. O ni ko si nibi kan ninu iwe ofin ilẹ wa to sọ pe dandan ni keeyan gba ipe iru ipe bẹẹ, ko si sohun to buru nibẹ teeyan ba kọ ọ lori ipilẹ to nitumọ."},{"question":"Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Gabyaagii Rasuulka (NNKH)?","answer":"Gabyaagii Rasuulka (NNKH) Wuxu Ahaa Xasaan Binu Thaabit."},{"question":"Spam ve ity mailaka manaraka ity, valio eny sa tsia.\\"Nisy holana ny fandefasana vola nataonao. Mba amahana izany dia tsindrio ny #*# arahin'ny laharana miafiana\\"","answer":"Eny, toy ny spam io mailaka io."},{"question":"أكمل الجملة التالية:  الكولونيل العام فاليريان ألكسندروفيتش فرولوف وُلد في بيتروغراد بالإمبراطورية الروسية بتاريخ 07 يونيه 1895 (بحسب التقويم الجديد أو 26 مايو 1895 بحسب التقويم القديم)، وتوُفي بالمدينة نفسها بعد تغيير اسمها إلى لينينغراد في 06 يناير 1961، شارك في الحرب العالمية الأولى والحرب الأهلية الروسية، كما شارك في","answer":"الحرب السوفيتية الفنلندية قبل تسلمه قيادة الجيش الرابع عشر خلال الحرب العالمية الثانية ومنه انتقل لقيادة الجبهة الكاريلية في الفترة ما بين سبتمبر 1941 وحتى فبراير 1944، ومع نهاية الحرب عام 1945 عُين قائدا عاما لمنطقة البحر الأبيض العسكرية ثم منطقة أرخانغيلسك العسكرية قبل أن يُحال إلى الاستيداع عام 1956."},{"question":"ਹੁਕਮੀ ਹੋਵਨਿ ਆਕਾਰ ਹੁਕਮੁ ਨ ਕਹਿਆ ਜਾਈ ॥ ਹੁਕਮੀ ਹੋਵਨਿ ਜੀਅ ਹੁਕਮਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥ਹੁਕਮੀ ਉਤਮੁ ਨੀਚੁ ਹੁਕਮਿ ਲਿਖਿ ਦੁਖ ਸੁਖ ਪਾਈਅਹਿ ॥ ਇਕਨਾ ਹੁਕਮੀ ਬਖਸੀਸ ਇਕਿ ਹੁਕਮੀ ਸਦਾ ਭਵਾਈਅਹਿ ॥ਹੁਕਮੈ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਸਭੁ ਕੋ ਬਾਹਰਿ ਹੁਕਮ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਹੁਕਮੈ ਜੇ ਬੁਝੈ ਤ ਹਉਮੈ ਕਹੈ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥੨॥","answer":"ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਬਣਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਪਰ ਇਹ) ਹੁਕਮ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਿ ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਰੱਬ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹੀ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ ਜੰਮ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹੀ (ਰੱਬ ਦੇ ਦਰ 'ਤੇ) ਸ਼ੋਭਾ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ। ਰੱਬ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਚੰਗਾ (ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ) ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਭੈੜਾ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ (ਆਪਣੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦੇ) ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਦੁੱਖ ਤੇ ਸੁਖ ਭੋਗੀਦੇ ਹਨ। ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਕਦੀ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ (ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਕਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨਿੱਤ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਭਵਾਈਦੇ ਹਨ।ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਰੱਬ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਜੀਵ ਹੁਕਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ (ਭਾਵ, ਹੁਕਮ ਤੋ ਆਕੀ) ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝ ਲਏ ਤਾਂ ਫਿਰ ਉਹ ਸੁਆਰਥ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ (ਭਾਵ, ਫਿਰ ਉਹ ਸੁਆਰਥੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਛੱਡ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ।2।"},{"question":"maswera a mpira wa netball","answer":"Mpira  kuyambira kalekale akhala masewera otchuka kwa atsikana asukulu. Malawi ndi membala wa bungwe la \\"International Federation of Netball Associations\\", ndipo pano ili pa nambala 6 padziko lonse lapansi. Timu ya dziko la Malawi ya netball ndiyomwe yayika dziko la Malawi pa mapu a mu Africa, kukwanitsa komanso kukhala patsogolo pa mpikisano wachigawo monga \\"COSANA\\"."},{"question":"\\"Салат эмнеден жасалат?\\"","answer":"Суроонун мааниси: \\"Соусту соустук туз (түл менен карамел тамак-аш боёгучтун жөнөкөй аралашмасы) же соустук күрөңдөгөн (сууда эриген соустук туз) же даяр кубиктер жана порошоктор менен дагы түстүү жана даамдуу кылып, табигый эт же жашылча экстракттарынын ордуна колдонсо болот\\" - бул Грейви."},{"question":"बॉक्सर इवांडर होलीफील्ड को किस नाम से जाना जाता है?","answer":"बॉक्सर इवांडर होलीफ़ील्ड को 'द रियल डील' (The Real Deal) नाम से जाना जाता है. इवांडर होलीफ़ील्ड एक पूर्व अमेरिकी पेशेवर मुक्केबाज़ हैं. उन्होंने 1984 से 2011 तक प्रतियोगिताओं में हिस्सा लिया. "},{"question":"රෝඩ් සේෆ්ට් ලෙජන්ඩ් ක්‍රිකට් තරඟාවලිය පැවැත්වෙන රට ?","answer":"ඉන්දියාව"},{"question":"Est-ce que la fleur de lys est l’emblème du Québec ?","answer":"Non. La fleur emblématique du Québec, ce n’est pas le lys, mais bien l’iris versicolore. L'iris versicolore est une superbe plante vivace à rhizome des milieux humides (fossés, marais, rivages, bordures de tourbières, etc.). Son aire de répartition géographique au Canada s'étend du Manitoba à Terre-Neuve. On le retrouve aussi dans plusieurs états de l'est des États-Unis. Formant des colonies denses, il offre en juin-juillet par ses fleurs d'un bleu violet un spectacle qu'on aime revoir année après année."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Anak Olin M. Jeffords, berkhidmat sebagai Ketua Hakim Mahkamah Agung Vermont, dilahirkan dengan nama James Jeffords di Rutland, Vermont. Ayat 2: Anak Olin M. Jeffords, yang berkhidmat sebagai Ketua Hakim Mahkamah Agung Vermont, James Jeffords dilahirkan di Rutland, Vermont. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya, betul."},{"question":"குருதிப்புனல் (நாவல்)எனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர்? \\t","answer":" விடை :  இந்திரா பார்த்தசாரதி"},{"question":"*من هو الصحابي الملقب بسيد الشهداء ؟","answer":"سيدنا حمزة بن عبد المطلب"},{"question":"\\"කැරකෙන රෝදේ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"කැරකෙන රෝදේ පුංචි කරත්තේඉඳගෙන මම ඉන්නේපදික වේදිකා පසු කර යන්නටතල්ලු කරන් පුතුනේකැඩුණු පාවහන් කුඩ නිමවාලාදවසේ වියදම සරි කරවාලාඅඳුර වැටෙන්නට කලියෙන් ගෙදරටතල්ලු කරන් පුතුනේකිරි කැටි දෙ අතේ සවි බල දියවේපමා වුණොත් අප මහ මග තනි වේඅම්මා මග ඇති නෙත් හරවා ගෙනතල්ලු කරන් පුතුනේඑඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩිසිරිල් සමරකෝන්කළණි පෙරේරා "},{"question":"ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਨੇ ਪੇਪਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਟਾਲਮਟੋਲ ਕੀਤੀ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਪੇਪਰ ਜਲਦੀ ਸੌਂਪ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸ ਨੇ ਪੇਪਰ ਅਧੂਰਾ ਜਮ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਰਵਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸ ਨੇ ਪੇਪਰ ਅਧੂਰਾ ਜਮ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਰਵਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।"},{"question":"வினா:   அந்தகக் கவிராயர் எழுதிய உலா எது? ","answer":"விடை:   திருவாரூர் உலாஅந்தகக்கவி வீரராகவர் என்பவர் காஞ்சிபுரம் மாவட்டம் பூதூர் எனும் ஊரில் பிறந்தவர். பொன்விளைந்த களத்தூரில் வாழ்ந்தவர். இவர் இசையிலும் பயிற்சி உள்ளவர். கவிஞரும் ஆவார்.இவர் தந்தையார் வடுகநாதர் என்பவர். வீரராகவர் பிறவியிலேயே கண்ணொளி இழந்தார். கேள்வியறிவின் வாயிலாகக் கல்வி கற்றார். இவர் இயற்றிய பாடல்கள் சொற்சுவையும் பொருள்நயமும் உடையவை. வள்ளல்கள் மீதும் சிற்றரசர்கள் மீதும் பல தனிப்பாடல்கள் பாடிப் பரிசுகள் பெற்றுள்ளார்.இவர் இலங்கை சென்று பரராசசேகர மன்னனைப் பாடி ஒரு யானை, பொற்பந்தம், ஓர் ஊர் ஆகியவற்றைப் பரிசிலாகப் பெற்று ஊர் திரும்பினார். இதனால் இவர் புகழ் கடல் கடந்தும் பரவியது."},{"question":"Firil ma kàddu gii ci Wolof: \\"The wolof alphabet is made of 11 vowels and 21 consonants\\".","answer":"Day i loy yi Wolof 11 maas ak 21 riirale la."},{"question":"මිනිස් සිරුරේ කුඩාම අස්ථිය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ස්ටේප්ස් (කන් අස්ථි)"},{"question":"السؤال: أذكر نص قانون نيوتن الثالث؟","answer":"الإجابة: لكل فعل رد فعل مساوي له في المقدار ومعاكس له في الاتجاه."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు భావం రాయండిమ. వలకుం జేరక, ప్రోగులుం దెరణ డ్రైవ్వంటిక్కి యా నేటకస్థల ముల్లంఘన కేసి, లుకుల యుత్నంబెల్ల వారింది. ది.క్కులు దదరు రఘుదుర ధ్వనులచే ఘర్జిల్లఁగా నొక్మ యేకల మేగు గని, తిన్నండప్పుడు ధను:కాందోల్లస్పూడి","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్ధము :ఒక్క + ఏకలము = ఒక అడవి పంది.వలకున్ = ఉచ్చులోచేరక = చిక్కుకొనకప్రోగులున్ = పోగు డు (వేటాడే చోట చుట్టి ఏర్పరచే త్రాడు)తెరలున్ = తెరచీరలనే వస్త్రాలు (వీటిలోకి జంతువులను తోలి వాటిని బంధిస్తారు లేదా వధిస్తారు. దీనిని తెరవేట అంటారు.) .త్రెవ్వన్ = తెగిపోవునట్లు,తొక్కి = కాళ్ళతో అదిమిఆఫీటక స్థలము = ఆ వేటాడే ప్రదేశమునుఉల్లంఘన చేసి = దాటిపోయిలుమికుల = బోయలయొక్కయత్నంబు + ఎల్లన్ = ప్రయత్నమంతటినివారించి = నిరోధించి; ప్రతిఘటించితదే = దాని (అడవి పంది)ఘర్షుర ఘర్షుర ధ్వనుంచేన్ = పంది అరుపులచేదిక్కులు = అన్ని దెసలుఘార్జిల్లఁగా = ప్రతిధ్వనించగాఏగన్ + కని = పారిపోవుటకు ప్రయత్నించగా చూచినతిన్నడు = తిన్నడుఅప్పుడు = ఆ సమయంలోధనుస్ + కాండ = విల్లు, అమ్ములతో (బాణములు)ఉల్లసత్ = మెరయుచున్నపాణియై = చేతులు గలవాడై యున్నాడు.భావం :ఒక అడవి పంది ఉచ్చులో చిక్కుకొనక వేటాడటానికి ఏర్పరచిన పోగుతాడు, తెరచీరలనే వస్త్రాలు తెగిపోవునట్లుగా కాళ్ళతో అదిమి, ఆ వేటాడే ప్రదేశాన్ని దాటి పోయి బోయల యొక్క ప్రయత్నమంతటినీ నిరోధించింది. దాని అరుపులు అన్ని దిక్కులు ప్రతిధ్వనించగా పారిపోవుటకు ప్రయత్నించగా, తిన్నడు ఆ సమయంలో విల్లమ్ములు చేతబట్టి మెరయుచున్నాడు."},{"question":"\\"සමෝධානය \\" යන්නෙහි අර්ථය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"එකිනෙක අන්තර් ක්‍රියා මඟින් සම්බන්ධ වීම.උදාහරණයක්:ගෙදරයි ගෙවත්තයි ගමු.ගෙදර විසි කරන දේවල් ගෙවත්තට යොදවනවා..ඒවා යොදාගෙන හැදෙන ගෙවත්තෙන් ලැබෙන දේ ගෙදර පරිභෝජනය කරනවා..(Integrated)"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Sa Jëmmi Boroom doŋŋ fiy des, moom miy boroom màgg gi ak teraanga.","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Sa Jëmmi Boroom doŋŋ a fi'y des, moom mi'y boroom màgg gi ak teraanga."},{"question":"Ijamba ọkọ gbẹmi eeyan kan ninu ijamba ọkọ nitosi Arakeji, l’Ọṣun","answer":"Ọkunrin kan niwadii ti fidi rẹ mulẹ bayii pe o gbẹmi mi ninu ijamba ọkọ kan to ṣẹlẹ niluu Olootu-Agbe, nitosi Ikeji Arakeji, nipinlẹ Ọṣun.Ni nnkan bii aago kan kọja iṣẹju mẹwaa ọsan Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, la gbọ pe iṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹlẹ. Ọkọ Toyota  Sienna kan to ni nọmba EKY 482 GG ati ọkọ akoyọyọ (Truck) kan to ni nọmba  BDG 123 XA ni wọn jọ sẹri mọ ara wọn.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ajọ ẹsọ ojuupopo l’Ọṣun, Agnes Ogungbemi to fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ sọ pe eeyan mẹfa; ọkunrin marun-un ati obinrin kan, ni wọn wa ninu awọn mọto mejeeji.O ni loju ẹsẹ ni ọkunrin kan ku nibẹ, awọn ọlọpaa atawọn oṣiṣẹ O’Ambulance si ti gbe ẹni to ku atawọn ti wọn fara pa lọ sileewosan Wesley Guild Hospital, niluu Ileṣa."},{"question":"విహారయాత్ర అంటే ఏమిటి? ఎందుకు వెళతారు?","answer":"వినోదం ప్రధానంగా చేసుకొని, చేసే యాత్రను విహారయాత్ర అంటారు. పుస్తక పఠనం వల్ల పుస్తక జ్ఞానం మాత్రమే లభిస్తుంది. లోకానుభవం, ప్రజల ఆచార వ్యవహారాలు, మన సంస్కృతి తెలుసుకోవాలంటే పర్యటనలు తప్పనిసరి. పుస్తకాలలో ఉన్న విషయాలను పూర్తిగా ఆకళింపు చేసుకోవాలంటే యాత్రలు చేయవలసి ఉంది. విజ్ఞానయాత్రల వలన మానసికోల్లాసంతోపాటు, విజ్ఞానం పెరుగుతుంది. ప్రసిద్ధమైన పరిశ్రమలు, ప్రాజెక్టులు, తీర్థయాత్ర స్థలములు, అందమైన దృశ్యాలు, చారిత్రక ప్రదేశాలు, బౌద్ధ విహారాలు, శిల్పకళా క్షేత్రములు మొదలయిన వాటిని ప్రత్యక్షంగా చూసి తెలుసుకుంటారు."},{"question":"География: Байкал көлү кайсы жерде жайгашкан? ","answer":"Байкал көлү Орусияда жайгашкан."},{"question":"ప్రభుత్వానికి బడ్జెట్ ఎందుకు అవసరం ? బడ్జెట్ పన్నుల గురించి ఎందుకు మాట్లాడుతుంది? ","answer":"కేంద్ర ఆర్థిక మంత్రి పార్లమెంటులో ప్రవేశపెట్టే బడ్జెట్ రాబోవు ఆర్థిక సంవత్సరం ప్రభుత్వం వివిధ కార్యక్రమాలపై చేయబోయే ఖర్చును తెలుపుతుంది.ఈ ఖర్చులను భరించటానికి ఏ విధంగా ఆదాయాలను సేకరిస్తుందో కూడా తెలుపుతుంది.అందువలన ప్రభుత్వం రానున్న ఆర్థిక సంవత్సరానికి ఎంత ఆదాయం వస్తుంది. ఎంత వ్యయం చేయడంలోను ఒక ప్రణాళికాబద్ధంగా వ్యవహరిస్తుంది. దీనినే “బడ్జెట్” అంటారు.ప్రభుత్వం ఆదాయ వ్యయాలపై ముందుచూపు లేకుండా వ్యవహరించినట్లయితే తరువాత ఇబ్బంది పడాల్సి వస్తుంది.వివిధ విధుల నిర్వహణకై ప్రభుత్వానికి చాలినంత డబ్బు అవసరం.ఆయా విధుల నిర్వహణకై కావాల్సిన డబ్బును ప్రజల నుండి పన్నుల రూపంలో సేకరిస్తుంది.ప్రభుత్వం వివిధ రకాల పన్నులను వసూలు చేస్తుంది.ఈ విధంగా వసూలు చేసిన పన్నులే ప్రభుత్వ రెవెన్యూ (ఆదాయం ) అవుతుంది.అందుకనే బడ్జెట్ లో పన్నుల ప్రస్తావన ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"Peygamber çiçeği nerede yetişir?","answer":"Kilyos peygamber çiçeği (Centaurea kilaea), papatyagiller (Asteraceae) familyasından Türkiye'de endemik olan çok yıllık bir peygamber çiçeği türü. Boiss., Fl. Orient. 3: 643 (1875). Türkiye'de Düzce, İstanbul, Kırklareli, Kocaeli ve Sakarya illerinin sahil kısmındaki kumul sahalarda yetişir."},{"question":"A kò fẹ́ ọlọ́pàá mọ́! Aráàlú faraya lẹ́yìn tí àwọn ajínigbé pa èèyàn nílùú Alalubosa","answer":"Awọn ajinigbe kọlu ilu Alalubọsa ni ipinlẹ Kwara nibi ti wọn ti ṣe ọpọlọpọ ọṣẹ nibẹ.Nigba ti iji ọṣẹ wọn yoo fi dawọ duro, eeyan kan ti padanu ẹmi rẹ ti ọpọlọpọ miran si tun fi ara pa yannayanna.Ohun ti awọn olugbe naa sọ ni pe nnkan bii agogo mẹwaa alẹ ni awọn oniṣẹ ibi naa wọ ilu naa pẹlu ibọn atamatase AK47.Gẹgẹbi alaye ti wọn ṣe, wọn ni iwo awọn to ṣe ikọlu naa jọ ti awọn Fulani.Ibọn ti awọn ajinigbe naa n yin kaakiri , la gbọ wi pe, o ba eeyan mẹta kan to joko sita n gba atẹgun lalẹ ọjọ buruku eṣu gbomimu naa.Ọkan ninu awọn ti ibọna ba naa ti orukọ rẹ njẹ Abdulrasheed pada jade laye.Awọn meji yoku wa ni ile iwosan ti wọn n gba itju bayii.Bakan naa lọpọ miran tun fara ṣeṣe loni ran an ran lori iṣẹlẹ naa.‘Awọn ọlọpaa ko wulo fun wa mọ’Awọn olugbe ilu naa ṣalaye pe ni kete ti ikọlu naa n waye lawọn ti fi ipe ranṣẹ si awọn agbofinro ṣugbọn ti wọn ni ṣe ni wọn n fi gbigbọ ṣe alaigbọ fun awọn.Wọn ni awọn fijilante lawọn araalu wa pe to wa koju awọn ajinigbe naa. Nigba ti wọn yoo si fi de ibẹ wọn dana ya awọn ajinigbe naa ti ọwọ wọn si tẹ ọkan ninu wọn.Isiak Abdulahi to ba BBC sọrọ ṣalaye pe ‘awọn ọlọpaa ko wulo fun awọn mọ lori ọrọ abo lagbegbe naa.'Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ni ipinlẹ Kwara, Ajayi Ọkasanmi rọ awọn eeyan agbegbe naa lati fi iye denu.O ni ọlọpaa n gbiyanju lori ọrọ abo nibẹ, ‘kii ṣe pe awọn ọlọpaa mọọmọ maa fẹ tete de.”Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ni ipinlẹ Kwara naa ṣalaye pe aitete mọ agbegbe ti ilu Alalubọsa wa, jijina ilu naa si agọ ọlọpaa agbegbe ọhun, ati pe ko si ọkọ to to oju iwn fun awọn ọlọpaa lagbegbe naa."},{"question":"තෝමස්‌ කූන් ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"තෝමස්‌ කූන් - Thomas Samuel Kuhn (/ˈkuːn/; July 18, 1922 – June 17, 1996) යනු ඇමෙරිකානු ජාතික භෞතික විද්‍යාඥයෙක්, ඉතිහාසඥයෙක් මෙන්ම විද්‍යාවේ දාර්ශනිකයෙකි. 1962 දී පලවූ 'විද්‍යාත්මක විප්ලවයන්ගේ ආකෘතිය' නමැති ඔහුගේ පොත උගතුන්ගේ මෙන්ම සාමාන්‍ය පාඨකයාගේද දැඩි අවධානයට ලක්විය. එහි දී හදුන්වාදුන් 'සුසමාදර්ශ වෙනස' (paradigm shift) නම් වදන එදා සිට ඉංග්‍රීසි භාෂාවේ තහවුරුවිය."},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:વિચાર વગરની શ્રદ્ધા","answer":"\\"અંધશ્રદ્ધા\\"અંધશ્રદ્ધા એ એવી માન્યતા છે જે તર્કસંગત પુરાવાઓ વિના હોય છે. તે વિચારો અને વર્તનમાં પ્રગટ થાય છે. અંધશ્રદ્ધામાં આધિદૈવિક અદૃશ્ય બળો, જાદુ, મેલી વિદ્યા, શુકન-અપશુકન, બૂરી નજર, ભૂત વગેરે વિશેની માન્યતાઓનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.અંધશ્રદ્ધાને ત્રણ રીતે વર્ગીકૃત કરી શકાય છે:1) ધાર્મિક અંધશ્રદ્ધા ધાર્મિક માન્યતાઓ પર આધારિત હોય છે. ઉદાહરણ તરીકે, કેટલાક લોકો માને છે કે ભગવાન માનવ જીવનમાં દખલ કરે છે અથવા કેટલીક વસ્તુઓ અશુભ હોય છે.2) સામાજિક અંધશ્રદ્ધા સામાજિક પરંપરાઓ અને માન્યતાઓ પર આધારિત હોય છે. ઉદાહરણ તરીકે, કેટલાક લોકો માને છે કે નવા વર્ષે નવા કપડાં પહેરવાથી ભાગ્ય સારું રહે છે.3) વ્યક્તિગત અંધશ્રદ્ધા વ્યક્તિગત અનુભવો અને માન્યતાઓ પર આધારિત હોય છે. ઉદાહરણ તરીકે, કેટલાક લોકો માને છે કે તે ભૂતો અથવા અન્ય અદૃશ્ય બળો દ્વારા ઘેરાયેલા છે."},{"question":"\\"පාත ඉඳන් අපි ආවේ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"පාත ඉඳන් අපි ආවේනා මල් පූජා කරන්නදළදා හාමුදුරුවනේපාත මාලයට වඩින්නහීල් හෙවණෙ හිඳගෙන බෑහේන් කුඹුරු වැඩ කරන්නඇඟ පත කළු වුණත් අපේකිළි කුණු නැති හිත බලන්නදළදා හාමුදුරුවනේපාත මාලයට වඩින්නමූදු ගියා ලෙලි තැළුවාපිළි ගඳින් බෑ මිදෙන්නඒත් අපේ මල් සුවඳයිඑපා බාර නොගෙන ඉන්නදළදා හාමුදුරුවනේපාත මාලයට වඩින්නවික්ටර් රත්නායකරත්න ශ්‍රී විජේසිංහවික්ටර් රත්නායක"},{"question":"'Cha mama, nawe dadewethu, ngizoya laphaya kumthandazi njengoba nisho kodwamina ithemba lami elikhulu likuNonkamfela. Nokho-ke ukuze nigculiseke, okungconongibona kungcono siqale laphaya kumthandazi, kwaHlazakazi sengiyovukela khonaekuseni kusasa.''Cha fana, ngoba asikazilungisi kahle zonke izimfanelo zakhona, kungcono siye khonakusasa uma usubuya kwaHlazakazi.''Hhayi kulungile mama, kungcono ngisale sengikwenza konke khona kusasa ngobanakhu sengathi selishonile kanti nale ndlela ikude. Sengiyovuka ekuseni ukuzengisheshe ngibuye ngithole nethuba lokuya esayonini.'Nebala ukusa kwaziwa nguye amabombo wawabhekisa khona kwaHlazakazi. Esahlezingasemthonjeni ecabanga ukuthi uzokwenzenjani, wezwa ngezwi lihayela phansiokomuntu obulawa umzwangedwa. Uma ethi uphakamisa amehlo wazithela kuyeuNokulindela ecula iculo losizi ebhekise ikhanda phansi. Uhamba nje uNokulindelaakuhambi yena inhliziyo ibalisa ngesoka lakhe.'Hawu ntombazana, wahaya elosizi kwenzenjani, ufelwe yizwe yini?''Hawu nkosi yami! Kodwa Sandanezwe ubekwa yini lapha? Ungaze ungibuze ukuthingifelwe yizwe nje uphumaphi? Wanyamalalisa okomphefumulo, awusabhali,awusathini, kwenzenjani, wahlekisa ngami ezweni ngenzeni?' washo uNokulindelasezigobhoza izinyembezi.'Kahle nkosazana ngamatshe, sengizophendula muphi ngiyeke muphi njengobauyiletha iba yimvula njena? Lalela ntokazi ngikuchazele, ungathathi ngamawala ngobaakusho ukuthi lokhu okwenzekayo nami ngakwenza ngamabomu,' kuchazauSandanezwe …1. Fingqa kafishane isigameko esenzeka ngesikhathi uSandanezwe ehlangananoZabalaza ehamba nezinsizwa zangakubo. Bhala amaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Wahaya ingoma enamagama ahlabayo/ ayiziswana ewabhekisekuSandanezwe.  UZabalaza wabingelela uSandanezwe, wambuza ukuthi wakhonkobalanje sengathi inkonyane ingancelile.  Waphinda wamtshela ukuthi uyakufihla ukugula kwakhe.  Wathukuthela uSandanezwe kodwa ingekho into ayengayenza ngobauZabalaza wayehamba neviyo lezinsizwa zangakubo."},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau dựa vào nội dung của văn bản bên dưới: Tại sao người Mỹ ngày càng bi quan về kinh tế?Đoạn văn: Số liệu sơ bộ do Đại học Michigan công bố hôm 10/11 cho thấy chỉ số niềm tin tiêu dùng đã giảm 5% trong tháng 11. Đây là tháng thứ 4 liên tiếp chỉ số này đi xuống, sau khi đã cải thiện hồi mùa hè. Mức giảm này chủ yếu do lãi suất hiện ở mức cao nhất 22 năm.\\"Chiến sự tại Dải Gaza và Ukraine cũng gây sức ép lên người tiêu dùng\\", Joanne Hsu - người phụ trách khảo sát này cho biết.Niềm tin giảm mạnh nhất với nhóm người trẻ và thu nhập thấp tại Mỹ. Trong khi đó, số liệu này với \\"nhóm nắm giữ nhiều cổ phiếu lại tăng 10%, do thị trường thời gian qua đi lên\\".Tiêu dùng đã giúp kinh tế Mỹ tăng tốc vài quý gần đây. Tuy nhiên, xu hướng này được dự báo đi xuống trong các quý tới. Đầu tháng này, những người Mỹ có nợ học phí Đại học đã phải bắt đầu thanh toán khoản vay trở lại sau 3 năm được hoãn.","answer":"Người Mỹ ngày càng bi quan về kinh tế vì một số lý do, bao gồm:- Tăng lãi suất: Lãi suất ở mức cao nhất trong 22 năm đã làm giảm niềm tin tiêu dùng. - Chiến sự tại Dải Gaza và Ukraine: Các sự kiện quốc tế như chiến sự tại Dải Gaza và Ukraine đã tạo ra sức ép thêm lên tình hình kinh tế và tạo ra không chắc chắn về tương lai, dẫn đến sự bi quan của người dân về tình hình kinh tế.- Sự chênh lệch về thu nhập: Số liệu cho thấy niềm tin giảm mạnh nhất ở nhóm người trẻ và thu nhập thấp tại Mỹ, trong khi những người nắm giữ nhiều cổ phiếu lại có niềm tin tăng. Sự chênh lệch về thu nhập và tài sản gây ra sự không bình đẳng và làm tăng sự bi quan về kinh tế.- Thanh toán nợ học phí Đại học: Đầu tháng này, những người Mỹ có nợ học phí Đại học đã phải bắt đầu thanh toán khoản vay trở lại sau 3 năm được hoãn. Việc này có thể tạo ra áp lực tài chính cho những người có nợ học phí và làm tăng lo ngại về tình hình tài chính cá nhân."},{"question":"வினா:  இராஜஸ்தானில் சமண கட்டடக் கலைக்கு மிகச் சிறந்த எடுத்துக்காட்டாக குறிப்பிடுவது  எது ?1. தில்வாரா கோயில் 2. சமணர் கோயில்3. கோமதீஸ்வரர் கோயில்4. கஜூராஹோ","answer":"விடை: 1. தில்வாரா கோயில் "},{"question":"Inona avy ireo karazana kabary?","answer":"Maro karazana ny kabary, fa hosinganina manokana ireto :·         Ny kabary am-panambadiana·         Ny kabary am-pandevenana·         Ny kabarin’ny mpanjaka·         Kabary am-pamadihana·         Kabary am-pahoriana·         Kabary ambony vavahady·         Kabary politika na ny mpitondra"},{"question":"महाराष्ट्रात संपूर्ण विद्युतीकरण झालेला प्रथम जिल्हा कोणता आहे?","answer":"महाराष्ट्रात संपूर्ण विद्युतीकरण झालेला प्रथम जिल्हा वर्धा आहे."},{"question":"Ọga ọlọpaa patapata ṣabewo ibanikẹdun si Sanwo-Olu atawọn ọmọọṣẹ rẹ l’Ekoo","answer":"Ni ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, ni Ọga agba ọlọpaa patapata nilẹ wa, Muhammed Adamu, ṣabẹwo si ipinlẹ Eko, lati ki Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu pẹlẹ ti ajalu to ṣẹlẹ nipinlẹ naa, nibi ti ọpọ ẹmi ati dukia ti ṣofo latari bi awọn ọmọọta kan ṣe ja iwọde SARS tawọn ọdọ n ṣe gba, ti wọn si n lo asiko naa lati jale, ati lati ba oriṣiiriṣii nnkan jẹ.Ọga ọlọpaa naa ni oun waa ba Sanwo-Olu kẹdun lori bi awọn janduku naa ṣe ba ọkẹ aimọye dukia ipinlẹ Eko ati ti awọn aldaani jẹ, ti ọpọ ẹmi si tun ba iṣẹlẹ aburu naa lọ.Bẹẹ lo tun lo asiko naa lati da awọn ọmọ iṣẹ rẹ lọkan le nitori bi awọn kan ninu wọn ṣe ba iṣẹlẹ naa lọ, ti awọn janduku naa si tun dana sun ọpọlọpọ agọ ọlọpaa. O ni ki wọn ma jẹ ki akọlu ti awọn ọmọọta yii ṣe si awọn ọlọpaa ati agọ wọn kaakiri orileede yii omi tutu si wọn lọkan.Nigba to n sọrọ nile ijọba to wa ni Marina, l’Ekoo, lasiko abẹwo rẹ, Adamu sọ pe, oun waa ṣe abẹwo si awọn agọ ọlọpaa ti wọn bajẹ lati ri ipo ti gbogbo nnkan wa. O waa rọ awọn ọlọpaa pe ki wọn ri iṣẹlẹ naa gẹgẹ bii ara ipenija to rọ mọ isẹ wọn.Ọga ọlọpaa yii ni bi a ko ba ni i purọ, iṣẹlẹ naa da omi tutu si ọkan awọn agbofinro kaakiri, ṣugbọn oun rọ wọn lati mu ọkan le, ki wọn si ri iṣẹlẹ naa bii ohun ti iṣẹ wọn pe fun lati daabo bo ẹmi ati dukia araalu."},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"À noite todos os gatos são pardos\\"?","answer":"Esta expressão popular da língua portuguesa significa que as coisas ficam parecidas no escuro, já que não é possível distingui-las com clareza. Usada metaforicamente, a ideia está ligada ao fato de que, em meio à multidão, não é possível enxergar as particularidades.Exemplo: “Ele bem que tentou ganhar a atenção dela na festa, mas à noite todos os gatos são pardos!”"},{"question":"Menene digiri na biyu a fannin fasaha?","answer":"Digiri na biyu shine wanda ake yi bayan kammala digirin farko a jami’a ko kwaleji. Ya daukan tsahon shekara daya ko biyu."},{"question":"グリニッジ標準時で０時のとき、日本では何時になっているでしょう？","answer":"（午前）９時"},{"question":"Wane tsauni ne mafi girma a Russia?","answer":"Elbrus"},{"question":"Qui était le peintre Jérôme Bosch ?","answer":"Hieronymus Bosch, un peintre néerlandais des débuts des Pays-Bas, est réputé pour ses représentations imaginatives et souvent surréalistes de créatures et de scènes fantastiques. Son triptyque « Le Jardin des délices terrestres » est une représentation vivante de son approche complexe et symbolique de la description de la condition humaine et de la moralité."},{"question":"வினா: பெர்கின் என்பவரால் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்ட செயற்கை நறுமணப் பொருள் எது? ","answer":"விடை: கூமாரின்"},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng cho câu hỏi sau:Kết quả của phép tính (– 50) + 30 là:A. – 20     B. 20     C. – 30     D. 80","answer":"Lời giảiTa có: (– 50) + 30 = –  (50 – 30) = – 20Chọn đáp án A."},{"question":"A – Bకి వియుక్త సమితిA) A ∪ BB) B – AC) AD) పైవన్నీ","answer":"B) B – A"},{"question":"초전도체가 뭐예요?","answer":"초전도체는 임계 온도 이하의 극저온, 극고온 상태에서 직류 전류에 대해 저항 없이 에너지를 전달할 수 있는 완전도체입니다. 저항이 없다는 건 그만큼 에너지 손실 없이 전기 또는 열을 전달할 수 있다는 것인데, 이는 매우 효율적이며 다양한 곳에 활용할 수 있습니다. 대표적인 활용 예시는 밑과 같습니다.1. 강력한 자기장 생성: 자기공명영상(MRI), 핵자기 공명 분광법(NMR), 초고주파 전자회로2. 자기 부력 기술: 부유열차, 부력 저장 장치3. 자기 센서: 지진, 지구 자기장, 자기 탐지4. 전력 전송과 저장: 초전도 자기 저장 장치(SMG)"},{"question":"Siapakah Cheryl Samad dan apakah latar belakangnya?","answer":"Cheryl Samad (lahir 23 Mac 1980)  dengan nama penuhnya Cheryl Marina binti Abdul Samad merupakan seorang pengacara, pelakon dan penyanyi Malaysia. Beliau dilahirkan pada 23 Mac 1980 di Ampang, Selangor dan dibesarkan di Kuala Lumpur. Cheryl mempunyai adik-beradik seramai tiga orang serta berdarah kacukan Melayu Portugis, beliau merupakan pemegang ijazah Sarjana Muda Undang-Undang Universiti Malaya (UM). Beliau berkahwin dengan pengarah terkenal, Ng Ping Ho pada 30 April 2011 dan dikurniakan seorang cahaya mata perempuan yang bernama Stella yang dilahirkan pada 18 Oktober 2013."},{"question":"82 inç kaç cm?","answer":"82 inç / 208 cm Televizyonlar, LED Ekranlar Modelleri ve Fiyatları & Satın Al."},{"question":"Qual time que joga no Wrigley Field e tinha Anthony Rizzo como jogador?","answer":"O time que joga no Wringley Field e tinha Anthony Rizzo como jogador é o Chicago Cubs."},{"question":"O que caracteriza o signo de Touro?","answer":"O signo de Touro é graficamente simbolizado pelos cornos do próprio touro, que representa a Lua Crescente com toda a sua fecundidade e fartura. Afinal, esse é o signo que exalta a materialidade, os recursos e a produtividade. Sendo o maior animal do zodíaco, Touro é a própria força física que resiste e cumpre com as mais árduas tarefas.Seu elemento solar é a Terra, universo da segurança e da razão. Os pés firmes no chão te permitem seguir com confiança e determinação. Entre as datas dos signos do Zodíaco, a data do signo de Touro é aproximadamente de 21 de abril a 20 de maio, mas isso pode mudar dependendo do seu ano de nascimento.Você é uma pessoa que prefere viver de acordo com a realidade da vida, já que a racionalidade te permite acessar a segurança que tanto valoriza. Aliás, é justamente esse pragmatismo que faz com que as suas realizações sejam sempre fruto de trabalhos cumpridos com responsabilidade, eficiência e, acima de tudo, satisfação.O desejo de desfrutar os inúmeros prazeres da vida é o que faz com que você se esforce para ter acesso à estabilidade financeira. Comer bem, cercar-se do que é belo, viver com conforto… Explorar os sentidos traz real motivação e contentamento aos seus dias."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的農作物是哪一種？","answer":"答案：小麥"},{"question":"Unsa diay nang bubble tea?","answer":"Ang bubble tea kay usa ka ilimnon nga naggikan sa Taiwan niadtong early 1980s. Gidala ni og mga Taiwanese immigrants sa United States sa 1990s, pirmero sa California, pero nagkasikat pod ang bubble tea anang panahona sa ubang nasod nga naay daghang nagpuyo nga gikan sa East Asia."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mengusir asap, meninggalkan api'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud melepaskan keuntungan kecil yang sudah tentu kerana mengharap keuntungan besar yang belum pasti"},{"question":"வினா: ‘கயற்குலமே பிறழ்ந்தொழுகும்கைத்தாயரே கடிந்தொறுப்பர்’ – இடஞ்சுட்டிப் பொருள் விளக்கம் தருக.","answer":"விடை : இடம் சுட்டுதல் :இராசராச சோழனின் மெய்க்கீர்த்திப் பகுதியில் இவ்வரிகள் இடம்பெறுகின்றன.பொருள் விளக்கம் :இராசராச சோழன் நாட்டில் குளத்து மீன்கள் பிறழ்ந்து செல்கின்றன. ஆனால் மக்கள் நிலை பிறழ்வதில்லை. செவிலித்தாய் சினம் காட்டுவார். ஆனால் வேறு யாரும் சினம் கொள்வதில்லை."},{"question":"Abu na farko cikin ashirin da Waziri Aku ya faɗa wa ɗansa Fasih, a Magana Jari Ce Na III, na A. Imam, shi neA)dangana ga AllahB)girmama jama’aC)lura da mutaneD)taimakon mutane","answer":"A)dangana ga Allah"},{"question":"नेपालमा दक्ष व्यक्तिहरूलाई कायम राख्न र ब्रेन ड्रेनलाई सम्बोधन गर्न व्यावसायिक संघहरू र उद्योग समूहहरूको भूमिकाबारे छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"व्यावसायिक संघ र उद्योग समूहहरूले व्यावसायिक विकासलाई समर्थन गर्ने नीतिहरूको वकालत गरेर, मेन्टरशिप कार्यक्रमहरू सिर्जना गर्न र समुदायको भावनालाई बढावा दिएर नेपालमा दक्ष व्यक्तिहरूलाई कायम राख्न र मस्तिष्कको बहावलाई सम्बोधन गर्न महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेल्न सक्छन्।"},{"question":"MOTHER'S CURSEChapter 12","answer":"MOTHER'S CURSEChapter 12\\"I'm pregnant for Izunna, he got me pregnant before leaving\\", she lied.\\"Okay, Izunna how come? You told us you were no longer with her, how come she's now pregnant for you?\\" his elder sister asked.\\"Adanne, I don't know what this imposter here is talking about. After she gave birth to light she never allowed me to touch her again. She knows who the father of the unborn child is\\", Izunna defended.\\"This pregnancy belongs to you Izunna; I have never cheated on you\\", she said crying.\\"Crocodile tears. Your plans will never work\\", Izunna's mum Anthonia screamed at her.\\"Even if that child is mine like you claimed, I can never take you back because you frustrated my life and I'm filled\\", Izunna told her.\\"Mama, I know you hate me so much but it's just as well I go since you all decided to push me off. And you, Izunna, you will regret ever knowing me. I'm done with my regrets, you're cursed, we ain't meant for each other. Go and meet your martins\\".  Cassandra's phone rang. She frowned as she picked up the call.\\"Please come back home, your grandmother wants to talk to you\\", her mum said.\\"What does she wants to tell me? Please nobody should disturb me because I'm trying to fix things with my husband\\", she replied and ended the call. \\"Who's your husband, young lady? When you were starving me and your children, collecting money from men and doing all sort of nonsense; you didn't remember, I'm your husband. Cassy, what do you want from me?\\"\\"I want you back please\\", she said as everyone laughed.\\"He is married, Cassandra love\\", Maris smirked. \\"Ogbanje\\", Anthonia shouted and went in.Cassandra felt defeated. She turned her back and left the compound crying loudly. \\"Where's grandma?\\" She asked as soon as she got home.\\"My daughter come inside\\", her grandma said from inside. Cassandra went in and sat beside her sniffing.\\"Please, I'm sorry for everything. I'm sorry for laying a curse on you\\", she coughed. Cassy stared at her mum and their eyes met.\\"What's she saying mum?\\", she asked.\\"Can't you just pay rapt attention and listen???\\" her mum bellowed.\\"The curse has destroyed your marriage.  I'm really sorry my grandchild. Your mother is the cause of everything\\", she coughed again.THROWBACK\\"Stop visiting that boy, Chinelo. He is not good for you. Leave Onaka alone.\\""},{"question":"கேள்வி:   சூழலுக்கேற்ற உணர்வைத் தெரிவு செய்க.(சிரிப்பு, மகிழ்ச்சி, வருத்தம், வியப்பு, அச்சம்)","answer":"பதில்:  பாட்டி புத்தாடை வாங்கித் தரும்போது ஏற்படுவது  மகிழ்ச்சி  குறிப்பு:       மகிழ்ச்சி என்பது நீண்ட நாள் நல்வாழ்க்கைக்கான உணர்வு, அமைதி மற்றும் நமது வாழ்வோடு சேர்ந்த திருப்தி – அதைத் தான் நாம் எல்லோரும், எல்லா நேரமும் தேடிக்கொண்டிருக்கிறோம். அதன் சுவையை சிறிது சுவைத்துவிட்டாலும், அதனை எப்போதும் தொடரவே விரும்புகிறோம். மகிழ்ச்சியில் திளைத்திருத்தல் குறித்து மக்கள் அவ்வப்போது குழப்பிக் கொள்கிறார்கள். நல்ல உணவை உண்டு, விலை உயர்ந்த ஆடைகளை அணிந்து, எப்போதும் வேடிக்கையாக இருந்தால் நாம் மகிழ்ச்சியாக இருப்பதாக நினைத்துக் கொள்கிறோம். ஆனால் உண்மையில் இது நிறைவைத் தராது. நம்முடைய சுயதேவைகள் மற்றும் விருப்பங்கள் அனைத்தையும் திருப்தி செய்தால் நாம் மகிழ்ச்சியாக இருக்கலாம் என்று கூட நினைக்கலாம். ஆனால் உண்மையில், நம்மைப் பற்றி மட்டுமே அக்கறைப்படுதல் என்பது தனிமையையும், மனஅழுத்தத்தையுமே முன்னெடுக்கும்.           நம்முடைய சிந்தனைகள் மற்றும் உணர்வுகளால் சில நேரங்களில் தனிமையில் இருப்பது அசவுகரியமாக இருக்கும், எனவே நாம் இசை, கணினி விளையாட்டு, உணவு, பாலுறவு மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு என குறுக்கீடுகளைத் தேடுவோம். ஆனால் இவை உண்மையில் மற்றவர்களுடன் இணைக்காது, அதே போல உண்மையான மகிழ்ச்சியையும் தராது.         மகிழ்ச்சியாகவும், பிறரோடு தொடர்பில் இருக்கவும் விரும்பினால், நாம் உடனே சமூக ஊடகத்தை நாடுவோம். நமது செல்ஃபிகளுக்கு கிடைக்கும் விருப்பங்கள் அல்லது நண்பர்களின் தகவல்கள் மூலம் சிறிது நேர இன்பம் கிடைக்கலாம், ஆனால் இது நாம் மேலும் தெரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்பதை மட்டுமே தூண்டும். நாம் அடிக்கடி நம்முடைய போனை எடுத்துப்பார்ப்போம், அடுத்தது என்ன? என எதிர்பார்ப்புடன் காத்திருப்போம், ஆனால் எத்தனை விருப்பங்கள் மற்றும் தகவல்களை நாம் பெறுகிறோம் என்பது பெரிதல்ல, முடிவில் நாம் மற்றவர்களுடன் குறைவான தொடர்பிலேயே இருக்கிறோம் என்பது தெரியவரும்.             உண்மையான மகிழ்ச்சியின் மிகப்பெரிய ஆதாரமே பிறரை நேசிப்பது தான் என்று புத்தர் கூறி இருக்கிறார். நாம் பிறரின் நலன் மற்றும் மகிழ்ச்சியில் உண்மையான அக்கறை காட்டினால், நமது மனம் இலகி, மற்றவர்களுடன் திறந்த மனதுடன் தொடர்பில் இருக்கவும், நாமும் உண்மையான மனிதன் என்ற உணர்வையும் ஏற்படுத்தும். நாம் உடலளவிலும் சிறப்பாக உணர்வோம். மற்றவர்களின் மகிழ்ச்சியில் அக்கறை செலுத்தும் போது, நம்மால் முடிந்த வரை அவர்களுக்கு உதவ முயற்சிக்க வேண்டும், பிறருக்குத் தீங்கு ஏற்படுத்தும் காரணங்களை தவிர்க்கலாம். இது நம்பகத்தன்மையான நட்பை உருவாக்கும், நம் வாழ்வை அர்த்தமுள்ளதாக்கும். நண்பர்கள் மற்றும் குடும்பத்தினரின் உணர்வுப்பூர்வமான ஆதரவு, வாழ்வில் என்ன நடந்தாலும் அதனை எதிர்த்து நிற்பதற்கான உறுதியை தேடித்தரும்.           பிறரின் மகிழ்ச்சியில் அக்கறை செலுத்தும் முன்னர் முதலில் நம்மிடம் இருந்தே தொடங்க வேண்டும். நமக்குள்ளான மகிழ்ச்சிக்கான விருப்பத்தை ஏற்படுத்த முடியாவிட்டால், பிறர் மகிர்ச்சியாக இருக்க நாம் எப்படி விரும்ப முடியும்? பௌத்தத்தில் மகிழ்ச்சிக்கான விருப்பம் அண்டத்தை உள்ளடக்கியது. மகிழ்ச்சி என்பது உள்ளார்ந்த அமைதியை சார்ந்தது, அவை அன்பான மனதை சார்ந்திருக்கிறது.  -14வது தலாய் லாமாஇன்றைய உலகில் நம்மால் எந்த தாக்கத்தையும் ஏற்படுத்த முடியவில்லை, நமக்கு எந்த சக்தியும் இல்லை என்று நினைப்போம். “என்ன நடந்தாலென்ன. கவலை ஏன் சகோ?” எனவே நாம் கருதுவோம். ஆனால் யதார்த்தத்தில் நமக்கு அறிமுகம் இல்லாதவர்களின் நலன் பற்றி சிந்தித்தும் அவர்களுக்கு உதவ முயற்சித்தும் கூட தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்த முடியும். ஒரு சிறு புன்னகை அல்லது புறப்பாடு வரிசையில் நிற்கும் போது, நமக்கு முன்பு கடந்து செல்ல யாரையேனும் அனுமதிப்பது உள்ளிட்டவை நாம் வேற்றுமையை ஏற்படுத்துகிறோம் என்ற உணர்வைத் தரும்.        இது சுய மதிப்புக்கான உணர்வை அளிக்கும் – நமக்கு கொடுப்பதற்கு ஏதேனும் இருப்பதால், அது சிறப்பாக உணர்வைத் தரும். வாழ்க்கையோடு நாமும் மகிழ்ச்சியானவராக மாறிவிடுகிறோம்.  நம்முடைய மதிப்பை காட்டி நாமே மகிழ்ச்சியடைந்து கொள்வதைவிட, பிறருக்கு எவ்வாறு மகிழ்ச்சியைத் தரலாம் என்று சிந்திப்பதும், அவர்களுக்கு எப்படி உதவலாம் என்ற சிந்தனையுமே மற்றவர்களோடு நம்மை இணைக்கிறது. சுருக்கமாகச் சொன்னால் இதுதான் சுயநலத்திற்கும், பிறரின் நலனில் உண்மையான அக்கறைப்படுவதற்கும் இருக்கும் வேறுபாடு.  மனிதர்களாகிய நாம் சமூக விலங்குகள்: பிறருடன் தொடர்பில் இருந்தால் மட்டுமே நம்மால் செழித்து வளர முடியும். மகிழ்ச்சியான வாழ்க்கை வாழ முக்கிய அம்சங்களான கருணை, பிறருக்காக அக்கறைப்படுதல் ஆகிவயற்றை நாம் வளர்த்தெடுக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Кытайлык кыргыздар жөнүндө толук маалымат бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Кытайлык кыргыз дегенде эле, көз алдыбызга, кызыл жүздүү, нукура кыргызча сүйлөгөн, айтоор кымыз жыттанган кыргызды элестетүүгө болот. Коомдун, замандын өзгөрүшү, технологиянын укмуштуудай өсүп-өнүгүп, айыл чарбасынын дүркүрөшү кытайлык кыргыздардын кытай эллине жакындап аргындашуусуна алып келди. Бирок, ошентсе да Манасты туу тутушуп, кыргыздын салт санаасын таза сактоого аракет кылышат. Бүгүн биз улутташтар программасында кытайлык кыргыздардын салт санаасынынын айрым маанилүү жактары менен сиздерди тааныштырганга аракет кылабыз. Кыргыз жеринен оолактап, башка жерди мекендеп калган боордошторубуз, кыргыз деген атын затын жоготпостон, каада салт урпа адаттарыбызды бекем сактап келет. Кытайда кыргыздар дал ошондой. Бала төрөлүп, нак 40 күн толгондгу жөрөлгө. Кошуна аялдарды чакырып, кырк кашык суу менен кырк кашык тузду бир идишке даярдап, ошол сууга баланы киринтет. Бул баланын эти ырбаак болбой туздай катсын деген тилек. Баланы киринтип болгон соң, алдын-ала даярдалган кырк курак көйнөк кийгизишет. Анан ушул баланын тайакелеринин бирөөнө кырк күндүк карын чачын алдырып коюшат. Анткени кыргыз тайын пирибиз деп айрыкча урматтайт, аны бийик көрөт. Бул баланын кыркын чыгаруу деп аталат. Баланын чачын бир ирет алгандан баштап эле жээк чач коюлат. Жээк чач коюнун негизги себеби, баланын чачын алган сайын жээгине устара тийе берип, баланын чачы ылдыйлап кетпесин десе, ал эми айрым жагдайларда баланын жээк чачын бар-жоктугуна карай, анын атасынын бар-жогун билишет экен. Бул жерде эскерте кете турган нерсе, баланы киринткенде же чоң кишилер боюн сууга сала турган болгондо чөөгүндүн түбүнө азыраак суу калтырып коюшат. Анын мааниси ушундай таза болуп, үзүлбөй улантылып турсун дегени. Кытайлык кыргыздарда бешик той негизинен эркек балага берилет. Бешик тойду үй ээси шартына жараша өткөрөт. Колунда бар малдуу, жандуу киши болсо бир же бир нече бодо союп, тууган-туушкандарынын баарын чакырып, той өткөрөт. Тойдо ат чабыш, жорго салдыруу, улак тартыш, жамбы атмай деген оюн-зооктор болот.Тушоо кесүү бала кас туруп басайын деп калганда, оң ийрилген ак жип менен сол ийрилген кара жипти бириктире чыйратып туруп, баланын бутун тушайт. Анан балага бир маки же бир бычак берип туруп, балдарды белгилүү аралыктан жарыштырышат. Алдыга чыгып келген балага макини берип, тушалган жипти кестирет. Алдыга келген балдарга кытайлык кыргыздарда калем, дептер сыяктуу нерселер таратылып берилет. Тушоо кесилери менен эле тушоо жипти кескен бала менен бөбөктүн энеси экөөлөп тай-тай, тай күлүк деп биртке жерге ылдамдата жетелейт. Тушоо кесүүнүн мааниси: балабыздын башына кедерги болуп турган тоскоолдукту алып ташта, эми ал тай кунандай оюн салып кетсин дегенди туюндурат. Ал эми ак жип, кара жип; балабыз акты-караны айра билсин, бычак болсо – бычактай курч болсун дегенди билдирет. «Атка мукул бака бут»-деп аталган салт бар. Бул салт боюнча (балакатка жеткен мезгилде, өткөрүлүүчү ырым-жырым) эркек бала 7-8 жашка келгенде атасы аны айырмач токулган кунанга мингизип, канжыгасына кымкап, шайы, ноот, драп сыяктуу баалуу кездеменден жасалган бир чапанды байлап алып, эң жакын кишинин үйүнө ээрчитип барат. Ал киши бир малын союп, жакшы конок кылып, чапанды алып калат. Балаңыз атка мингенге жарап калыптыр деп, башка бир ат токуп мингизип, кунанын коштотуп жолго салып коөт. Ал эми кыз бала болсо, энеси жакшы көргөн аялга кызынын чачын бака бутар кылып өрүп, седеп топчу тагып берет. Кыз энеси шартына жараша ыраазы кылат. Бул аталган салттар кыз бала менен эркек баланын балакатка жеткен мезгили болот. Кытайлык кыргыздарда «Сөйкө салуу» салты кеңири тараган. Бул боюнча бала чоңоюп калган кезде, ата-энеси астыртан белгилүү бир киши менен куда болууга кам урат, эки жак сүйлөшкөн соң, сөйкө салып келүү күнү болжонот, уулдун ата-энеси жакын көргөн эки-үч кишини ээрчитип, кыздын үйүнө барып сөйкө салат. Сөйкө салганда уул тарап колунан келгенин алып барат. Эки жак келишип, той түшүрөөр күн белгиленген соң, уул тарап калыңга берер малын камдайт. Мында эки жак тең эле журтуна таянат. Атап айтканда, жалпы тууган-урук, дос-тамыр, куда-сөөктөр жана башка алыш-бериш кылган кишилер түгөл кабарланат, алардан жардам суралат. Чакырылган кишилердин ар кимиси өзүнө тиешелүү жакка мал-пул, кыз жакка чапан, көйнөк, жоолук сыяктууларды кошот Мында деле калыңга түшкөн бир өлчөм болбойт. Бүгүнкө күндө калыңга кошуп, эгерде кызматтагы кыз болсо, мотоцикл, ал эми үйдө олтурган кыздарга велосипед берүү салтка айланып бара жатат. Мезгилдин нугуна карай жогорку окуу жайларын бүтүргөн кыздардын калыңы кыйла жогору .Кудалашкан адам, жылкыга кебез байлап, бир койду куйкалап (муну куйка кой деп атайт, мунун оң кол, сол бутунун шыйрагын кеспейт) калган калыңдык малды айдап уул тарап кыз жактын үйүнө түшөт. Кыз жак уул тарапка берген калыңына жараша мынча тогуз кийит деп көйнөк, чапан, жоолук берет. Кыз жак өзүнө караштуу кишилерге калыңды жетишинче бөлүп, ырым кылат. Уул тарап дагы куданын берген кийитин жетишинче өз жагына бөлүп берип, ырым кылат. Ал той ушинтип аяктайт. Кудалашканда күйөө менен күйөө жолдош жанбаштык байланып келет. Жанбаштык дегенибиз куржун, ал куржунга боорсок жана кант, бир козунун бышырылган эти, бөйрөк, шыйрак, керчөөсү менен кошо салынат. Күйөө кудага келген элдин артынан кечигип келет. Айылдын чекесинен аны кыздын жеңелери тосуп чыгышат. Күйөө жана күйөө жолдош жүгүнөт, жеңелер аларды алкайт да, айылга алып барып, арналуу үйгө түшүрөт, канжыгадагы жанбаштыкты чечип, бөлүп алышат. Мындай жанбаштык алып баруу кийинки жүз көрүшүү тоюнда да болот. Айта кетерибиз жаштар жеңелердин кылдаттыгын байкоо үчүн жанбаштыкты канжыгага чапан түйүп байлап салышат, аны чечип алуу абдан кыйын. Эгер кыштын күнү болуп калса, чапан түйүлгөн жерге суу куюп ташташат, ал тоңуп, аны чечүү ого бетер кыйындайт. Жеңе болгондор чече албай аргасы кеткенде ээр-токумду кошо алып, үйгө кирип чечүүгө аракеттенишет. Анткени, канжыганы кесип алуу мүмкүн эмес, эгер кесип алса айып төлөйт, ал тургай чоң чыр чыгат. Куйка койго кошуп алы барлар бирден бодо, жогу бирден койду кошо бере турган иш да бар. Муну жыгач бастырар деп коюшат. Бул кийинки тойлордо да боло берет. «Тебетей кошуп кудага өтүүнүн» эки кудага тең байланышы бар. Кээ бир кишилер баландай мал менен кудага өтөм дейт, уул тарап мал тизмелейт. Бирок уул тарап кыз жакка айткандарынын баарын эле аткара бербейт. Ал тебетей деп аталып, балким бул биринин тебетейин бирине кийгизди дегенден чыкса керек. Чөнтөк аңтаруу деген салт жүз көрүштүрүүдө же кийинки чоң тойдо болот. Күйөө менен күйөө жолдош самын-бет май сыяктуу кыз-келиндерге ылайык нерселерди салып барат, күйөө жандаган келиндер аны алып, алардын чөнтөгүнүн абалына карай калпак, топу, көйнөк, кээде чапан, шым кийгизет. Күйөө жолдош болгон киши жанына сөзгө чечен, ырчы-комузчу ышкыбоз жигиттен бир-экини өзүнө жолдош кылып алып барат. Бул аталма ар кайсы жерде ар башка айтылат. Мисалы: күйөө котчу, күйөө койчу, күйөө жолдош сыяктуу ар жерлерде ар башкача айтылат. Акчий жергесинде кийитти тек гана кыз жак уул жакка берет. Кийит көйнөк, чапан, жоолук сыяктуулардан турат, уул тарап кийит бербейт. Уул жактын бергендери кийит деп аталбай, калың деп аталат. Келиндин атын уккан уулдун атасы, кыздын атасына «келиндин атын укканым» деп бир бодо мал берет. Кыздын атасы да ага бир жакшы чапан кийгизет. Бул бодо мал калыңга, тигил чапан кийитке киргизилбейт. «Эшик-төрүн көрүү» салты боюнча кыздын ата-энеси ылайыктуу бир күнү «кудабыздын эшик-төрүн көрөбүз» деп уул атасыныкына барат. Уул атасы аларды жакшы сыйлап, кетеринде бир мал берип, кудага чапан, кудагыйга көйнөк кийгизип узатат. Ылайыктуу бир күнү кыз атасы да уул тарапты өз эшик-төрүн көрүүгө чакырат. Алар да барган соң жакшы сый көрүп, кудасынын бергенин алып кайтышат. Эки тарап тең бири-биринин эшик-төрүн көргөнү барганда эң жакын кишилеринен бир-экөөнү ала барышат. Бирок адам саны чектелүү болот деп билдирди бизге берген маалыматында адабиятчы Сакен Өмүр. Кытайда мал чарбачылык өнүккөндүктөн «согум берүү» салты да сакталып калган. Согум убагы болгондо уул тарап кыз жакка кыштык согумуң деп бир семиз бодо мал берет. Бул сөөк кажатуу деп да аталып жүрөт. Кыргыз эли байыртадан эле көчүп-конуп жүргөндүктөн, ушул сыяктуу салт-санааларды кеңири колдонуп келген. Кыз жактын уландары мал жайлоодон түшөөрдө уул тараптын коюунан бир койду кармап алса «көч кой» деп, эгерде бир жылкы кармап ала турган болсо «чаң жылкы» деп коюшат. Муну колунда бар кишилер гана жасай алат. Арпа-буудайды оруу маалында уул тарап кыз жакка бир кой энчилеп берет. Мунун мааниси орок менен кармашып каржалдыныз, жаш шорпо ичиңиз дегенди билдирет. Бул салтты болсо кытайлык кыргыздар «орок кой» деп коюшат. Ал эми жазгы көктөмдө мал арыктап турган кезде бир семиз кой берилет. Бул жазгы үзүмчүлүктө жутадыңыз, жиликтирөөк шорпо ичиңиз дегенди билдирет. Муну «арык кой» деп коюшат. Балдар бойго жеткен мезилде уулдун атасы өзүнүн жакындарын ээрчитип алып, кыз менен баланы жүз көрүштүрөт. Келинди алып кетүү убактысын такташып, алып кетер күндү болжошот. Келинди алып кетер күн «жооп суроо» деп аталат. Жүз көрүштүргөндө эки жак тең топуратып конок чакырбай, саналуу гана жакын кишилер менен күтөт. Жооп сураганда тойдун убактысы, калыңы, каада-салттары сыяктуу иштер кеңешип бекитилет. «Кеңеш аяк»-деген салтында болсо,мында куда түшүү убактысы белгиленип, кыз тарап өз жакындарын, алыш-бериш кылынгандарын атап айтканда, ошол тойдо оорчулуктарын тең көтөрүшүп бере турган кишилерин чакырып, конок кылат. Аларды иштин чоо-жайы менен тааныштырышат, кыз себинин эмнелери бүткөнүн, кандай кем-карчысы бар экенин, кудаларга канча кийит берилерин, канча үй конок аларын жана ушул тойго байланыштуу бардык жасала турган иштерди ошолор менен кеңешет, кимдин эмне жардам кыларын, түндүктү ким көтөрөөрүн тактайт. Уул тарап да ушундай кеңеш өткөрүп, калыңга канча мал берилерин, канча чачыла бышырылаарын, тойго эмне соөрун, алардын канчалык даражада даяр экендигин тааныштырат, жакындарынан ким эмне берери такталат. Кытайлык кыргыздарда «Түш салуу» деген да салт бар. Анын жөнү мындай: күйөө болчу уулдун атасынын же эң жакынынын элге белгилүү күлүк аты, жоргосу, алгыр бүркүтү, кушу атан төөсү же мылтыгы сыяктуу көзгө басар оокаты болсо, кыздын атасы кудасына ошол малыңа же оокатыңа түш салдым, ошону бербесең түндүк көтөрбөйм деп туруп алат. Эки жак кеңешип бир чечимге келишет, аталган буюм же куну ошого барабар башка нерсе берилет. Ал эми «секиртмейде» же «түш салуу» сыяктуу шылтоолорду таап, түндүктү көтөрбөй туруп алышат, буга да ылайыгына жараша бир нерсе алышат."},{"question":"Dokończ następujący akapit: Julian Wieniawski urodził się 5 lutego 1834 roku w Lublinie położonego na terenach zaboru rosyjskiego. Julian Wieniawski był starszym bratem najsłynniejszego polskiego skrzypka i zawarzem kompozytowa Henryka Wieniawskiego. W młodości uczestniczył w powstaniu styczniowym, po jego upadku ","answer":"wyemigrował za granicę, gdzie studiował ekonomię i prawo. Po powrocie do kraju w 1865 roku został aresztowany i więziony w Cytadeli Warszawskiej. Był jednym z założycieli i dyrektorem od 1872 roku Towarzystwa Wzajemnego Kredytu w Warszawie. W 1872 roku opublikował zbiór szkiców „Wędrówki delegata”. W swoich utworach nawiązywał do tradycji gawędy szlacheckiej. Zmarł 23 września 1912 roku w Warszawie i jego twórczość po II wojnie światowej popadła w zapomnienie."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న: భారత దేశంలోని మహాజన పదాలలో రాజులకు సైన్యం ఎందుకు అవసరం?","answer":"భారత దేశంలోని మహాజన పదాల రాజులు వారి తెగను, రాజ్యాన్ని కాపాడాల్సి వచ్చేది. ఇతరుల దండయాత్రల నుండి వారిని రక్షించాల్సి వచ్చేది. అంతేగాక పన్నులు చెల్లించడానికి నిరాకరించేవారిని శిక్షించడానికి, ప్రజలు రాజు ఆజ్ఞలను పాటించేలా చూడటానికి కూడా సైనికులు అవసరం."},{"question":"Apakah itu Kumpulan Wang Simpanan Pekerja (KWSP) di negara Malaysia?","answer":"Kumpulan Wang Simpanan Pekerja (KWSP) merupakan sebuah institusi keselamatan sosial yang ditubuhkan di bawah Undang-Undang Malaysia, Akta Kumpulan Wang Simpanan Pekerja 1991 (Akta 452) yang menyediakan faedah persaraan kepada ahlinya melalui pengurusan simpanan mereka secara cekap dan boleh dipercayai. KWSP juga menyediakan sistem yang efisien dan mudah bagi memastikan para majikan memenuhi tanggungjawab undang-undang serta kewajipan moral mereka untuk mencarum kepada KWSP bagi pihak pekerja mereka.Kenggotaan wajib kepada pekerja sektor swasta dan pekerja tidak berpencen sektor awam. Sehingga Jun 2022, KWSP mempunyai seramai 15.5 juta ahli. Bilangan ahli aktif dan masih mencarum adalah seramai 8 juta. Bilangan majikan aktif pula adalah seramai 572,847Semua caruman di KWSP akan dibayar dividen dan dijamin oleh kerajaan pada kadar minimum 2.50% bagi Simpanan Konvensional. Kadar dividen untuk Simpanan Shariah adalah berdasarkan prestasi sebenar pelaburan patuh syariah yang diuruskan dan dilaburkan oleh KWSP.Caruman adalah wang yang dikreditkan ke akaun individu ahli di KWSP. Amaun tersebut terdiri daripada caruman pekerja dan caruman majikan dan dikira berdasarkan gaji bulanan pekerja. Kadar caruman semasa adalah 21% daripada gaji pekerja dimana 9% adalah caruman pekerja yang dipotong daripada gaji bulanan pekerja manakala 12% adalah caruman oleh majikan.Caruman bulanan anggota dilaburkan melalui beberapa instrumen kewangan yang diluluskan untuk menghasilkan pendapatan. Ini termasuklah Sekuriti Kerajaan Malaysia, Instrumen Pasaran Wang, Bon & Pinjaman, Ekuiti dan Hartanah.KWSP memastikan simpanan anggota selamat dan mendapat dividen yang berpatutan. KWSP menjamin dividen sebanyak 2.5 peratus setahun. Untuk memastikan bayaran dividen, KWSP melaburkan caruman melalui instrumen kewangan yang diluluskan bagi mendapatkan pulangan yang optimum.Dividen dimasukkan ke dalam akaun pencarum setiap tahun. Kadar dividen yang diisytiharkan oleh KWSP adalah tertakluk kepada pulangan pelaburan yang dibuat melalui instrumen-instrumen yang diluluskan.Dividen tahunan dikira berdasaran baki pembukaan simpanan pencarum setakat 1hb Januari setiap tahun. Dividen bulanan pula dikreditkan ke akaun anggota berdasarkan jumlah caruman bulanan yang diterima.Jumlah aset KWSP setakat Mac 2022 adalah sebanyak RM1 trilion.Sejak 1 Januari 2007, simpanan anggota KWSP dibahagi dalam dua akaun. Akaun pertama, digelar \\"Akaun 1\\", menyimpan 70% daripada caruman anggota, manakala akaun kedua, digelar \\"Akaun 2\\", menyimpan baki selebihnya (30%). Pengeluaran Akaun 1 terhad kepada pengeluaran mencapai 55 tahun, kehilangan upaya, meninggalkan negara atau meninggal dunia. Akaun 2 pula membenarkan pengeluaran untuk bayaran pendahuluan atau penyelesaian pinjaman rumah pertama, tujuan pendidikan dan belanja perubatan, pelaburan dan apabila mencapai 50 tahun."},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :আরিফুল ইসলামআরিফুল ইসলাম বলেন, বাড়ি থেকে টেনে-হিঁচড়ে তাকে গাড়িতে তোলা হয়। \\"আমাকে জোর করে গাড়ীতে উঠানো হয়। আমি তাদের বলি আমার অপরাধ কী আমাকে বলেন। আমার কোন ভুল হয়ে থাকলে আমাকে মাফ করে দেন। আমি তাদের কাছে বার বার মাফ চেয়েছি।\\"সে সময় উপস্থিত জেলা প্রশাসনের একজন কর্মকর্তাকে উদ্ধৃত করে আরিফুল ইসলাম বলেন,  তিনি আইনশৃঙ্খলা বাহিনীর যেসব সদস্য ছিল তাদেরকে বলেন,  'এর হাত পা বেঁধে ফেল, আজকে একে এনকাউন্টারে দিয়ে দেব।' \\"আমাকে অকথ্য ভাষায় গালিগালাজ করছিল। আমি তখন তাদের কাছে মাফ চাই, কিন্তু তিনি বলেন তুই কলেমা পড়, তোকে এনকাউন্টারে দেব, তুই সমাজের জঞ্জাল।\\"\\"আমাকে তিনি জিঞ্জেস করেন তুই কি ডিসির বিরুদ্ধে লিখিস? ডিসি কি ঘুষ খায়? আমি বললাম আমি এমন কিছু লিখি না, আমার ভুল হলে মাফ করে দেন।\\" 'তোর সময় শেষ তুই কলেমা পড়'\\"আমি তাদের বলেছিলাম আমার দুটি সন্তান আছে, আমি মারা গেলে ওদের কে দেখবে। ওদের উপর রহম করে আমাকে আপনারা ছেড়ে দেন।\\"\\"উনি (ঐ কর্মকর্তা) কোন কথাই শুনছিলেন না। শুধু বলছিলেন তোর সময় শেষ তুই কলেমা পড়। আমার চোখ যে কাপড় দিয়ে বাঁধা ছিল সেটা কোন রকম একটু সরিয়ে আমি দেখতে পেলাম... ","answer":"ধরলা ব্রিজ পার হয়ে আমাকে নিয়ে যাওয়া হচ্ছে যেটা আমার বাড়ি থেকে ৭/৮ কিলোমিটার দুর।\\" \\"আমি তখন শুধু আল্লাহকে ডাকছিলাম। এর ২/৪ মিনিটের মধ্যে তারা ফোনে কথা বলে, মেসেজ পাঠায় তারপর সিদ্ধান্ত পরিবর্তন করে আবার গাড়ী ঘুরিয়ে নিয়ে আসে।\\"আরিফুল বলেন, চোখের কাপড়ের ফাঁক তিনি দেখতে পান তাকে ডিসি অফিসে নিয়ে আসা হয়েছে।তারপর শুরু হয় প্রচণ্ড মারধোর।  'আমাকে বিবস্ত্র করে মারে, ছবি তোলে'\\"ঐ কর্মকর্তা আমাকে বলতে থাকে তোর বাপের নাম ভুলিয়ে দেব। আমাকে বিবস্ত্র করে মারে, ছবি তোলে , ভিডিও করে।\\"অরিফুল বলেন, পরে তাকে কাপড় পরিয়ে জোর করে চারটা স্বাক্ষর করে নেয়া হয়। \\"আমি এখনো জানি না এই স্বাক্ষরগুলো কেন, কোথায় নেয়া হয়েছে।\\"এরমধ্যেই পুলিশ চলে আসে, কিন্তু তিনি বলেন পুলিশ কি করতে পারবে!  তাকে দ্রুত কারাগারে নিয়ে আসা হয়। বাড়ি থেকে তাকে বের করা হয় রাত সাড়ে ১২টার দিকে। আর কারাগারে পাঠায় রাত দেড়টা থেকে দুইটার দিকে। আরিফুল ইসলাম বলেন, এক/দেড়ঘন্টার মধ্যে এসব কিছু হয়েছে।আরিফুল ইসলাম কুড়িগ্রাম জেলা প্রশাসনের ঐ কর্মকর্তার নাম বিবিসির কাছে বলেছেন। কিন্তু অভিযোগগুলো যেহেতু খুবই গুরুতর, তাই ঐ কর্মকর্তার বক্তব্যের জন্য তার মোবাইল ফোনে বার বার যোগাযোগের চেষ্টা করা হয়। প্রতিবারই তার ফোন বন্ধ পাওয়া যায়। ফলে ঐ কর্মকর্তার নাম উহ্য রাখা হলো।"},{"question":"Biriiji Agege-Pen Cinema yoo pari ninu oṣu keji, ọdun to n bọ","answer":"Bi ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ba mu ileri rẹ ṣẹ, a jẹ pe oṣu keji, ọdun to n bọ, ni wọn yoo ṣi oju ọna Agege-Pen Cinema ti wọn ti n kọ lati aye ijọba Akinwumi Ambọde.Sanwoolu lo sọ eleyii di mimọ ni Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii lasiko to ṣabewo si biriiji oni kilomita meji din diẹ (1.7km) yii.Akọwe iroyin gomina, Gboyega Akọsile, sọ lorukọ rẹ pe iṣẹ ti fẹrẹ pari lori ọna Agege-Pen-Cinema, ida aadọrin iṣẹ naa lo si ti jẹ ṣiṣe bayii.Gomina ni gbogbo iṣẹ to jẹ mọ biriki lawọn ti ṣe tan, nnkan meji to kan ku ni lati ri i pe awọn oju ọna naa mọ toni toni, ati fifi ami atọka si i, eyi to ni awọn yoo ṣe nibẹrẹ ọdun to n bọ.Bẹẹ nijọba ti fun awọn agbaṣẹṣe naa ni ọsẹ mẹfa pere lati ṣe gbogbo awọn atunṣe to ba yẹ lori iṣẹ oju ọna naa.Sanwoolu ni igbesẹ yii waye lati mu ileri ti awọn ṣe pe gbogbo iṣẹ ti ijọba ana n ṣe lọwọ ko too kuro nipo lawọn yoo pari ṣẹ.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ijọba Akinwumi Ambọde lo bẹrẹ biriiji naa. Ireti rẹ ni lati pari rẹ ni saa ẹlẹẹkeji rẹ ko too di pe wọn ko fun un ni tikẹẹti lati dije dupo lorukọ ẹgbẹ APC l’Ekoo."},{"question":"Tôi hay ngoáy tay vào rốn cậy những vết cặn đen bẩn để làm sạch. Hành động này có ảnh hưởng đến vệ sinh không?","answer":"Về bản chất, rốn lõm sâu nên có thể chứa nhiều loại vi khuẩn, bụi bẩn, bã nhờn (dầu) và tế bào da chết. Những thứ này ở trong rốn có thể gây nên các vấn đề về da như mụn trứng cá, mụn đầu đen. Rốn cũng có thể làm phát triển lông mọc ngược ở khu vực này, gây viêm nang lông.Khi bạn càng cố gắng kích thích bằng tay hoặc cậy da rốn, tình trạng sẽ càng trở nên tồi tệ hơn, nguy cơ bị nhiễm trùng hoặc phát triển mô sẹo. Lâu ngày, các hậu quả của việc ngoáy rốn bao gồm nhiễm trùng tụ cầu khuẩn hoặc tụ cầu vàng kháng methicillin, tạo điều kiện nấm men phát triển quá mức hoặc nốt sần ngứa xảy ra.Vậy làm thế nào để làm sạch rốn? Thực tế, có ‌một số‌ vi khuẩn trong rốn là điều bình thường. Da của bạn có hệ vi sinh vật của riêng nó, bao gồm hàng triệu vi khuẩn, nấm và virus, giúp bảo vệ cơ thể khỏi thế giới bên ngoài. Vì vậy, bạn không nên cố gắng để làm cho rốn của mình quá sạch sẽ và hoàn toàn không có vi khuẩn.Nếu nhận thấy rốn đang có dấu hiệu nổi mụn trứng cá, viêm nang lông hoặc ngứa, có mùi, bạn cần làm sạch một cách nhẹ nhàng bằng cách rửa rốn dưới vòi hoa sen bằng xà phòng và nước. Sau đó, nhẹ nhàng chà rốn bằng tăm bông thấm cồn và giữ đến khi khô ráo. Nếu bạn cào da quanh rốn, nên dưỡng ẩm vùng da đó và băng lại."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai antah melukut, lapar sangat baru berguna\\"?","answer":"Kalau tidak ada yang lain, baru digunakan"},{"question":"Inona ary izany: Tsy nify tsy vazana nefa tsy mandà sakafo?","answer":"Afo no valiny."},{"question":"கேள்வி :கஞ்சக் கருவிகள் என்று அழைக்கப்படுவது எது?1) தோல் கருவிகள்2) கனக் கருவிகள்3) நரம்புக் கருவிகள்4) துளைக் கருவிகள்","answer":"பதில் :2) கனக் கருவிகள்"},{"question":"銃型やライフル型、時にはローラーやバケツといった武器を駆使し、さらに2017年に発売されたシリーズ2作目では傘を武器にして戦う事も。4対4のチームに分かれインクで地面をを塗り合ってその面積を競う、イカが主人公のこのゲームシリーズのタイトルは何でしょう？","answer":"Splatoon（スプラトゥーン）です。"},{"question":"Sistem tubuh manakah yang berfungsi utama adalah kelanjutan spesies? Pilih jawapan anda dari: (1) pencernaan(2) saraf(3) ekskresi(4) pembiakan","answer":"(4) permbiakan"},{"question":"Irú oúnjẹ wo ni a lè pè ní oúnjẹ Afáralókun? ","answer":"Oúnjẹ Afáralókun ni àwọn oúnjẹ tí wọ́n máa ń fún ara ní agbára láti túnbọ̀ ṣe iṣẹ́. Àpẹẹrẹ àwọn oúnjẹ wọ̀nyí ni iṣu, gàárì, ìrẹsì, Àmàlà, iyán, Búrẹ́dì àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ."},{"question":"  ______merupakan lambang bagi negara Malaysia.A  Radio Televisyen MalaysiaB  utusan MalaysiaC  Sukan MalaysiaD  Jalur Gemilang","answer":"D  .Jalur Gemilang"},{"question":"Inona no hitan'i Marie Curie momba ny radioactivity?","answer":"Nahita ny radioactivity ny singa sasany, toy ny polonium sy radium i Marie Curie."},{"question":"Ìjàpá kó gbogbo ọgbọ́n Ayé sínú kèǹgbè","answer":"Apààlọ́ :Ààlọ́ o!Agbe Ààlọ́ :Ààlọ̀!Apààlọ́ : Ààlọ́ mí dá gbà-á, ó dá gbò-ó, ó dá fìrìgbagbóò, o dálérí Ìjàpá, Tìrókò, ọkọ Yáńníbo. Nígbà kan, Ìjàpá rò ó nínú ara rẹ̀ pé kí òun kó gbogbo ọgbọ́n ayé jọ pamó s'íbí kan kí òun wá di alákòóso rẹ̀, nitori Ìjàpá je ẹranko to ni ọgbọ́n èwé oríṣiríṣi lọ́wọ́ tó sì fẹ́ kí gbogbo ènìyàn mo. Ó fẹ́ di olókìkí àti gbajúgbajà látàrí bee. Ìjàpá wa akèrègbè, ó rìn láti ìlú rẹ̀ sí òmíràn káàkiri láti wá gbogbo ọgbọ́n ayé jo. Ó kó wọn sínú akèrègbè. Nígbàtí ó ṣe, o padà si ìlú rẹ̀, ó wá ọkùn tí ó nípòn láti fi so akèrègbè náà. O gbìyànjú láti gbe akèrègbè náà gun igi ṣùgbọ́n gbogbo ìgbìyànjú rẹ̀ láti àárọ̀ títí oòrùn fi wọ̀ pàbó ló já si. Níbití ó ti ń se kìràkìtà ni ọdẹ kan ti rí i, ó sì bií pé kí ló fẹ́ ṣe: Ìjàpá kẹ́jọ́ o rò bí ó ṣe kó ọgbọ́n ayé jo sínú akèrègbè tí ó fẹ́ gbe gun igi láti le di alákóso ọgbọ̀n ayé."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਪੂਰਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਸ੍ਰਬ ਠਾਇ ਹਮਾਰਾ ਖਸਮੁ ਸੋਇ ॥ਏਕੁ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਸਿਰਿ ਛਤੁ ਦੂਜਾ ਨਾਹਿ ਕੋਇ ॥੧॥ਜਿਉ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਿਉ ਰਾਖੁ ਰਾਖਣਹਾਰਿਆ ॥ਤੁਝ ਬਿਨੁ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ਨਦਰਿ ਨਿਹਾਰਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਪ੍ਰਤਿਪਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਆਪਿ ਘਟਿ ਘਟਿ ਸਾਰੀਐ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਮਨਿ ਵੁਠਾ ਆਪਿ ਤਿਸੁ ਨ ਵਿਸਾਰੀਐ ॥੨॥ਜੋ ਕਿਛੁ ਕਰੇ ਸੁ ਆਪਿ ਆਪਣ ਭਾਣਿਆ ॥ਭਗਤਾ ਕਾ ਸਹਾਈ ਜੁਗਿ ਜੁਗਿ ਜਾਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਜਪਿ ਜਪਿ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਕਦੇ ਨ ਝੂਰੀਐ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਦਰਸ ਪਿਆਸ ਲੋਚਾ ਪੂਰੀਐ ॥੪॥੭॥੧੦੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 398 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਸਾਡਾ ਉਹ ਖਸਮ-ਸਾਈਂ ਹਰੇਕ ਥਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਹੈ (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਉਹ) ਇਕੋ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ (ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਦੀ ਬਾਦਸ਼ਾਹੀ ਦਾ) ਛੱਤ੍ਰ (ਉਸੇ ਦੇ) ਸਿਰ ਉਤੇ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ ।੧। ਹੇ ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਸਮਰਥ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਜਿਵੇਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗੇ, ਉਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੇਰੀ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਕਰ । ਮੈਂ ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਅਜੇ ਤਕ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਵੇਖਿਆ ਜੋ ਤੇਰੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਹੋਵੇ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਹਰੇਕ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਬੈਠਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹਰੇਕ ਦੀ ਸਾਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹਰੇਕ ਦੀ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਫਿਰ ਭੁਲਾਂਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ।੨। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਹਰੇਕ ਜੁਗ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਗਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।੩। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪ ਜਪ ਕੇ ਫਿਰ ਕਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਨੀ ਪੈਂਦੀ (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਦਾਸ) ਨਾਨਕ ਨੂੰ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰਸਨ ਦੀ ਪਿਆਸ ਹੈ (ਨਾਨਕ ਦੀ ਇਹ) ਤਾਂਘ ਪੂਰੀ ਕਰ ।੪।੭।੧੦੯।\\""},{"question":"烤肉的起源是什么？","answer":"答：烤肉的起源可以追溯到史前时代，当人类发现火并学会用火烹饪食物后，烤肉便成为了一种常见的烹饪方式。"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Theo Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên-Huế, vào khoảng 12h30 ngày 31/7, một đối tượng sử dụng súng AK bất ngờ xông vào hai tiệm vàng Hoàng Đức và Thái Lợi ở chợ Đông Ba. Tại đây, đối tượng nổ súng chỉ thiên uy hiếp chủ tiệm vàng rồi cướp vàng. Tiếp đó, đối tượng đem số vàng này vứt ra phía vỉa hè rồi đi bộ đến khu vực cầu Gia Hội. Ngay khi nhận được tin báo, Giám đốc Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên-Huế đã trực tiếp chỉ đạo các lực lượng chức năng trong Công an tỉnh và Công an TP.Huế nhanh chóng có mặt tại hiện trường, triển khai đồng bộ các biện pháp nghiệp vụ, khoanh vùng và ngăn không để người dân di chuyển vào hiện trường. Do đây là khu vực trung tâm thành phố, đông dân, để đảm bảo an toàn cho người dân, lực lượng công an đã tìm cách hướng đối tượng di chuyển đến khu vực Công viên Trịnh Công Sơn. Lúc này, đối tượng có biểu hiện kích động, muốn tự vẫn. Đại tá Phạm Văn Toàn - Trưởng phòng Cảnh sát hình sự, Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên-Huế và một số cán bộ công an khác trực tiếp tiếp cận, trò chuyện và thuyết phục đối tượng buông súng. Tuy nhiên, đối tượng đã yêu cầu được nói chuyện với đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn - Phó Giám đốc Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên-Huế. Khi được đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn gặp gỡ, động viên, thuyết phục, đối tượng đã đồng ý hạ và giao nộp vũ khí. Danh tính đối tượng được xác định là Ngô Văn Quốc (SN 1984, trú tại thị xã Hương Thủy, Thừa Thiên-Huế). Hiện vụ việc đang được cơ quan công an tiếp tục điều tra làm rõ. ","answer":"Công an Thừa Thiên-Huế thông tin vụ nổ súng cướp tiệm vàng"},{"question":"Quelle couleur est souvent associée à l'énergie, à l'espoir et à la créativité ?a) Jauneb) Noird) Bleue) Gris","answer":"a) Jaune est la couleur souvent associée à l'énergie, à l'espoir et à la créativité."},{"question":"கேள்வி :  கீழ்கணடவற்றில் எந்த தமிழ் தேசியவாதி “பாலபாரதி” என்ற இலக்கிய சஞ்சரிகையை வெளியிடார்.1. சுப்ரமணியபாரதி2. சுப்ரமணிய சிவா3. வ.உ.சி4. வ.வே.சு.ஐயர்","answer":"பதில்4. வ.வே.சு.ஐயர்   வரகனேரி வேங்கடேச சுப்பிரமணிய ஐயர் (வ. வே. சு. ஐயர், 2 ஏப்ரல் 1881–4 ஜூன் 1925) இந்திய விடுதலைக்காக முதன்மை பங்காற்றியவரும், சிறந்த இலக்கிய வாதியும், மொழி பெயர்ப்பாளரும் ஆவார். இவர் தமிழகத்திலுள்ள திருச்சிராப்பள்ளியைச் சேர்ந்தவர். தமிழ் இலக்கிய பங்களிப்புகளுக்காக இவர் தமிழ்ச் சிறுகதை தந்தை என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார்.   கிரேக்கம், இலத்தீன், பிரெஞ்சு, ஆங்கிலம், சமஸ்கிருத, தமிழ் மொழிகளில் ஆழ்ந்த புலமை பெற்றவராய் விளங்கினார்.  1922-இல் சேரன் மாதேவியில் தமிழ்க்குருகுலம் என்ற கல்வி நிலையத்தைத் தொடங்கினார். அதை நிர்வகிக்க பரத்வாஜ் ஆசிரமத்தையும் அமைத்தார். 1924-இல் பாலபாரதி என்ற இதழைத் தொடங்கினார். தொழிற்கல்வியும் அறிவுக் கல்வியும் மாணவர்க்கு அளித்தார்.   தமிழ்நாடு அரசு வ.வே.சுப்பிரமணியம் நினைவைப் போற்றும் வகையில் திருச்சியில் வரகனேரி, அக்ரஹாரத்தில் உள்ள அவர் வாழ்ந்த இல்லம் வ.வே.சு. ஐயர் நினைவகம் எனும் பெயரில் நினைவு இல்லமாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இங்கு நூலகம் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. வ.வே.சு. ஐயர் வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு தொடர்பான புகைப்படங்கள் கண்காட்சியாக வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. மேலும் இவரது நினவாகத் சேரன்மகாதேவியில் வ.வே.சு. ஐயர் மாணவர் விடுதி உள்ளது"},{"question":"2 log 3 + log 5 = log N అయిన N విలువను కనుగొనుము.","answer":"2 log 3 + log 5 = log N= log 3^2 + log 5= log 9 + log 5= log 45 = log N [∵ log m + log n = log mn]∴ N = 45"},{"question":"මා ලබා ගත යුතු බයිසිකලය තීරණය කරන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"වැඩිහිටියන් සඳහා බයිසිකල් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් කල, වෙළඳපොලේ විවිධ වර්ග තිබේ. ඔබ එය භාවිතා කිරීමට කැමති ආකාරය මත පදනම්ව බයිසිකලයක් තෝරන්න. යතුරුපැදි පහත පරිදි වර්ග කළ හැක: 1. මාර්ග බයිසිකල් - මෙම බයිසිකල්වල සුපිරි සිහින් ටයර් ඇති අතර ඒවා බොහෝ විට මාර්ගවල බයිසිකල් පැදීම සඳහා යොදා ගනී. මේවා ඔබට සාපේක්ෂව ඉක්මනින් ඉහළ වේගයක් ලබා ගැනීමට උපකාරී වේ. 2. මවුන්ටන් බයිසිකල් - මෙම බයිසිකල් බයිසිකල් පැදීමේදී ඔබට හමුවිය හැකි රළු භූමි ප්‍රදේශයට ඔරොත්තු දීම සඳහා සාදා ඇත. ටයර් වඩාත් ඝන වන අතර ඔබව ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට සහ ඔබට අවශ්‍ය සහය ලබා දීමට සාදා ඇත. 3. Hybrid/Commuter bikes - මෙම බයිසිකල් ඉහත වර්ග 2 මැදට වැටේ. ඔබ මාර්ග බයිසිකල් පැදීම සහ මවුන්ටන් බයිසිකල් පැදීම ටිකක් කළ හැකි යැයි ඔබ සිතන්නේ නම්, මෙය ඔබේ හොඳම විකල්පය විය හැකිය. වැඩි විස්තර ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ඔබට බයිසිකල් විකිණීම සහ අලුත්වැඩියා කිරීම පිළිබඳ විශේෂිත වෙළඳසැලකට යා හැකිය."},{"question":"Lọọya Kunle alawada ṣegbeyawo bonkẹlẹ l’Ogbomoṣọ","answer":"Ọpọ eeyan ni ko mọ pe Abdul-Gafar Abiọla, Cute Abiọla tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Lọọya Kunle, fẹẹ ṣegbeyawo. Afi lọjọ Ẹti to kọja yii ti ọdọmọkunrin alawada naa gbe arẹwa obinrin kan torukọ ẹ n jẹ Kudirat Mosunmọla niyawo. Recreation Centre, niluu Ogbomọṣọ ni wọn ti ṣe e, ko si pẹ ti fidio ati fọto ayẹyẹ yii fi gba ori ayelujara kan.Aṣọ oke alawọ buluu ni Lọọya Kunle atiyawo rẹ wọ, wọn tun wọṣọ funfun balau nibi kan, bẹẹ ni wọn n rẹrin-in muṣẹ bawọn alaga iduro ati tijokoo to dari ayẹyẹ idana naa ṣe n da orin aladun, ti wọn si n ṣadura nla nla fun wọn.Bi igbeyawo yii ṣe ba awọn kan lojiji lawọn mi-in n sọ pe o ya awọn lẹnu pe Lọọya Kunle ko fẹ ọmọbinrin kan ti wọn jọ maa n ya fọto bii ololufẹ lori ayelujara, iyẹn Adedamọla Adewale ti wọn n pe ni ‘Ade herself.’Ṣugbọn a gbọ pe ọna ti jin ti Cute Abiọla ati Kudirat ti n fẹra wọn, Ade herself paapaa ko si jiyan eyi, ohun to sọ ni pe oun ati Lọọya Kunle ki i ṣe ololufẹ, ọrẹ lasan lawọn.O ni awọn ti wọn ro pe awọn n fẹra awọn ṣaa ti ri i wayi, pe Abdul-Gafar Abiọla ti fẹyawo tiẹ, eyi to fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ki i ṣe ọrẹkunrin oun bawọn eeyan ṣe n gbe e kiri."},{"question":"હોળી વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"હોળી, જેને રંગોનો તહેવાર પણ કહેવામાં આવે છે, તે ભારત, સુરીનામ, ગુયાના, ટ્રિનિદાદ, યુનાઇટેડ કિંગડમ અને નેપાળમાં ભારે લોકચાહના ધરાવતો હિંદુ તહેવાર છે. તેને 'દોલયાત્રા' કે 'વસંતોત્સવ' તરીકે પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે.આ તહેવારનો પ્રથમ દિવસ હોળી અને બીજો દિવસ ધુળેટી તરીકે ઓળખાય છે. હોળી ફાગણ માસની પુનમનાં દિવસે મનાવવામાં આવે છે. આ દિવસે સાંજે ગામનાં પાદર કે મુખ્ય ચોક જેવા સ્થાન પર છાણા, લાકડાં ની 'હોળી' ખડકવામાં આવે છે. ત્યાર બાદ બધાં લોકો ત્યાં વાજતે ગાજતે (ઢોલ,શરણાઇ જેવાં વાજીંત્રો વગાડતાં) એકઠા થાય છે અને હોળી પ્રગટાવવામાં આવે છે. લોકો તેની પ્રદક્ષિણા કરે છે તેમજ શ્રીફળ વગેરે પવિત્ર મનાતી વસ્તુઓથી તેમનું પૂજન કરે છે. જો કે ભારતમાં વિવિધ પ્રાંતો અને સમુદાયોમાં હોળીની ઉજવણીની અલગ અલગ રીતો હોય છે, પરંતુ દરેકની ભાવના એક જ હોય છે કે હોળી પ્રગટાવી અને આસુરી તત્વોનો નાશ કરવો અને દૈવી શક્તિઓનું સન્માન કરવું. હિંદુ ધર્મમાં આને લગતી \\"હોળીકા અને પ્રહલાદ\\"ની કથા બહુ જાણીતી છે.હોળીનાં બીજા દિવસે ધુળેટી મનાવાય છે. આ તહેવાર 'રંગોનો તહેવાર' એટલેજ કહેવાય છે કે આ દિવસે સવારથી સૌ કોઇ નાના મોટા એકબિજા પર અબિલ, ગુલાલ તેમજ કેસુડાનાં રંગો છાંટી પોતાનો ઉત્સાહ અને આનંદ વ્યક્ત કરે છે. જો કે હવેનાં સમયમાં ક્યાંક ક્યાંક રસાયણિક રંગોનો ઉપયોગ પણ કરાય છે, જેનો ઉપયોગ બને તેટલો ટાળવો હિતાવહ છે.આંધ્ર પ્રદેશમાં હોળીકા દહનનો તહેવાર \\"કામ દહન\\" તરીકે ઓળખાય છે."},{"question":"छत्रपती राजारामने मराठ्यांची नवी राजधानी कोठे स्थापन केली ? ","answer":"छत्रपती राजाराम ने मराठ्यांची नवी राजधानी रायगड किल्ल्यावर स्थापना केली. रायगड किल्ला महाराष्ट्रातील एक प्रमुख पर्वतकिल्ला आहे आणि ते मराठा साम्राज्याच्या मुख्य केंद्रित्री किल्ल्यामध्ये आपल्याला एक आहे. छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराजांच्या काळात, रायगड किल्ल्यावर स्वाराज्याची ध्वज झळझळवायला पाहिजे ह्याचा आणि त्याच्या शासकीय आणि सैन्यक्रिया क्रियाकलापांसाठी ह्या ठिकाणी एक महत्त्वाचा स्थान आहे."},{"question":"வினா  :உலகின் கூரை என்று அழைக்கப்படும் இடம் எது?","answer":"விடை: திபெத்திய பீடபூமி."},{"question":"Tamin'ny oviana ny Repoblika voalohany teto Madagasikara ? ","answer":"1960- 1973 ny Repoblika voalohany teto Madagasikara "},{"question":"ممكن تديني نبذة عن صلاح جاهين.","answer":"بالتأكيد، خد عندك نبذة عن الفنان صلاح جاهين.صلاح چاهين شاعر ورسام كاريكاتير ، وكاتب سيناريو وممثل مصرى مشهور . كتب شعر باللغه المصريه الحديثه. ابنه الشاعر بهاء جاهين. من أشهر أعماله أوبريت الليلة الكبيرة اللى تقريباً مفيش حج فى مصر مسمعهوش. صلاح جاهين اعتمد على اللغة العامية فى التعبير و ده خلاه قريب من الناس و من أشهر الأمثلة لكده الرباعيات بتاعته. كمان زي ما قلنا صلاح جاهين كان ممثل و ظهر فى أدوار كتير على الشاشة المصرية، من الأفلام اللى ظهر فيها: اللص و الكلاب (1962)، و لا وقت للحب (1963). صلاح جاهين كمان هو اللى كتب كلمات أغنية داليدا المشهورة جداً \\"أحسن ناس\\". و عجبيأقدر أساعدك بحاجة تانية؟"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:సీత ఆశీస్సులు : “నాయనా ! హనుషి.. ! నీవల్ల శ్రీరాముని క్షేమవార్తను విన్నాను. నా కష్టాలు అన్నీ రామునికి తెలిసేటట్లు చెప్పగలిగాను. అయితే, నేను నీకు తిరిగి ఉపకారం ఏమి చేయలేను. నీవు బ్రహ్మకల్పముల పర్యంతమూ చిరంజీవిగా ఉండు” అని హనుమను సీత దీవించింది.సీత రామునకు పంపిన సందేశము : “ఎప్పుడూ రాముని పాదములు నా హృదయములోనే ఉన్నాయి. ఈ విషయం శ్రీరామునికి చెప్పు. నీవు వింటూ ఉండగా, రావణుడు నాతో మాట్లాడిన పరుష వాక్యములను అన్నిటినీ నాయందు దయ కలిగేటట్లు రామునికి చెప్పు. నేను ఈ లంకా నగరం అనే అడవిలో జడలు కట్టిన జుట్టుతో మలిన వస్త్రం ధరించి, నేలపై నిద్రిస్తూ, తారకమంత్ర జపం చేస్తున్నాను. రాముణ్ణి నాకు ప్రత్యక్షం కమ్మని చెప్పు. లక్ష్మణుడు గుణవంతుడు. అతణ్ణి నేను అవివేకంతో అనరాని మాటలు అన్నాను. దాని పాప ఫలితం అనుభవించానని లక్ష్మణుడితో చెప్పు నేను అన్న మాటలు తన మనస్సులో ఉంచుకోకుండా, నా మానాన్ని కాపాడమని లక్ష్మణుడికి చెప్పు” అని సీత రామలక్ష్మీణులకు సందేశం చెప్పింది.","answer":"హనుమ సీత మాటలు విన్నాడు. సీతను తన వీపుపై కూర్చోమన్నాడు. సూర్యోదయం అయ్యేటప్పటికి రాముడు వద్దకు సీతను తీసుకొని వెడతానన్నాడు. హనుమంతుడు అంతటి సమర్థుడే అని, సీత అంగీకరించింది. కానీ తాను హనుమంతునితో వెడితే, రాముణ్ణి దొంగ అని లోకులు అంటారని చెప్పింది. రావణుడినీ, అతడి మిత్రులనూ చంపకుండా, దొంగతనంగా తీసికొని వెళ్ళడం రాజులకు తగిన పని కాదని చెప్పింది. రాముడు ముల్లోకాలలో మహావీరుడు. కాబట్టి రావణుని చంపి, తనను తీసుకొని వెళ్ళడమే ధర్మం అని తెలిపింది.హనుమంతుడు పుత్రుడితో సమానుడు కాబట్టి, అతని వెంట వెళ్ళడం తప్పు కాకపోయినా, శత్రుసంహారం జరగాలి అన్నది. రామునికి ఈ విషయాలు అన్నీ చెప్పి, ఆలస్యం లేకుండా లంకకు శ్రీరాముని వెంటపెట్టుకొని రమ్మని, హనుమకు సీత చెప్పింది. హనుమ, సీతను ఊరడించడం : “అమ్మా ! నీ భర్త సముద్రాన్ని దాటి, సుగ్రీవ . సుషేణాది వానరవీరులతో లంకకు వచ్చి, నీచుడైన రావణుని యుద్ధంలో చంపి, .. నిన్ను అయోధ్యకు తీసుకొని వెడతాడు. ఇది నిజము, నమ్ము” అని సీతకు హనుమంతుడు చెప్పి, ఆమెను ఊరడించాడు."},{"question":"वन्दे वृन्दावनचरं वल्लवीजनवल्लभम् ।जयन्तीसम्भवं धाम वैजयन्तीविभूषणम् ॥","answer":"अर्थ : वृंदावनामध्ये विहार करणार्‍या, गोपीजनांना आनंद देणार्‍या, जयन्ती योगावर (म्हणजे श्रावण कृष्ण अष्टमीच्या मध्यरात्री रोहिणी नक्षत्र असतां) जन्मलेल्या, भक्तांचे आश्रयस्थान असलेल्या, वैजयंती माळेने सुशोभित झालेल्या भगवान श्रीकृष्णाला मी नमस्कार करतो."},{"question":"යකඩ සමනලයා(iron butterfly) යන අන්වර්ථ නාමයෙන් හඳුන්වනු ලැබූ පිලිපීන ජාතිකයා නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ඉමෙල්ඩා මාකෝස්"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'gelap hati'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud sukar (tidak mudah) belajar. Contoh ayat: Murid yang gelap hati dalam mata pelajaran Matematik akan diberikan bimbingan khusus."},{"question":"囲碁で、あと一つ石を打つと、相手の石を取れる状態のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"あたりです。"},{"question":"Em que ano os Beatles foram aos EUA pela primeira vez?","answer":"Após alcançar significativo sucesso na Europa, a banda The Beatles viajou aos Estados Unidos da América em 7 de fevereiro de 1964 para começar sua turnê no país."},{"question":"Inona no fanalavana ny JIOI?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny JIOI dia \\"Jeux des Îles de l’Océan Indien\\"."},{"question":"Leg het concept van een \\"bubble sort\\" algoritme uit aan een niet-technisch publiek.","answer":"Stel je voor dat al je vrienden hun naam en telefoonnummer op een strook papier hebben geschreven, en al die stroken in een zak zijn gestopt en door elkaar zijn gehusseld. Je wilt een lijst van al deze contacten, maar je hebt ze nodig in alfabetische volgorde. Zo gebruik je een bubble sort om dat te doen: 1) Leg alle namen van links naar rechts uit. 2) Begin bij de meest linkse strook. Vergelijk het met de strook rechts ervan. Als de naam verder in het alfabet staat dan de naam van zijn rechterbuurman, wissel dan van plaats. 3) Kijk nu naar de strook één-na-links (dit kan dezelfde strook zijn als daarvoor, als deze net van plaats is gewisseld). Vergelijk de naam met zijn rechterbuurman, net als daarvoor. Wissel ze indien nodig van plaats. 4) Ga door met dit proces totdat je bij de meest rechtse strook bent. Je weet nu dat de meest rechtse strook de naam heeft van de persoon die het laatst in het alfabet staat. Door door te gaan en indien nodig van plaats te wisselen, heb je de laatste naam in het alfabet 'omhoog gebubbeld', waar de naam bubble sort vandaan komt. 5) Ga nu terug naar de meest linkse strook en herhaal het proces, maar deze keer kun je stoppen bij de op één-na-rechtse strook omdat je al weet dat dit de laatste naam in het alfabet is. 6) Ga weer terug naar de meest linkse strook, herhaal het proces en stop bij de op drie-na-rechtse strook. 7) Ga door totdat de hele lijst is gesorteerd. Bubble sorteren op deze manier is heel eenvoudig, maar kan erg tijdrovend zijn bij lange lijsten. Andere benaderingen kunnen worden aanbevolen voor langere lijsten."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut:  Sangat kecil, berwarna coklat agar kemerahan, kalau digigit, sakit rasanya. Api ada di namaku, tekalah siapakah saya.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah semut api"},{"question":"เหตุการณ์สำคัญที่เกี่ยวข้องกับข้อความต่อไปนี้คืออะไร: โดยภาพยนตร์เรื่องนี้ได้รับการคัดเลือกให้เป็นหนึ่งใน 10 ภาพยนตร์ยอดเยี่ยมประจำปี 2020 โดยนักวิจารณ์ภาพยนตร์ 52 คน รวมทั้งได้รับรางวัลออสการ์​ 2 สาขา ในงานประกาศผลรางวัลออสการ์ ครั้งที่ 93​ ได้แก่สาขาออกแบบเสียงยอดเยี่ยม และ สาขาลำดับภาพยอดเยี่ยม จากการถูกเสนอชื่อเข้าชิงถึง 6 สาขา​ , ได้รับรางวัลแบฟตา​ 2 สาขา ได้แก่ตัดต่อภาพยอดเยี่ยมและบันทึกเสียงยอดเยี่ยม และได้รางวัลอินดิเพนเดนต์สปิริตอะวอดส์​อีก 3 สาขา","answer":"งานประกาศผลรางวัลออสการ์ ครั้งที่ 93"},{"question":"Жер бетиндеги көптөгөн процесстер тектоникалык плиталардын чегинде же анын жанында жүрөт. Тектоникалык плиталардын чегинде кандай геологиялык кубулуштар көп кездешет?а) эрозия жана калдыктар;б) ураган жана торнадо; в) жер титирөөлөр жана жанар тоолор; d) суу толкундары жана чөкмөлөр;","answer":"в) жер титирөөлөр жана жанар тоолор; "},{"question":"Inona no biby an-tanety lehibe indrindra?","answer":"Ny biby an-tanety lehibe indrindra dia ny elefanta afrikanina."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe aretina nendramboalavo na « varicelle » ary ahoana ny fomba hifindrany ?","answer":"Ny nendramboalavo dia aretina vokatry ny otrikaretina antsoina hoe «varicelle-zona ». Aretina mora mifindra ny nendramboalavo ka matetika dia mora miparitaka na miteraka ilay atao hoe « épidémie ». Mifindra amin’ny alalan’ny fifaneraserana amin’ny olona efa voa ny nendramboalavo, indrindra amin’ny alalan’ny piti-drora na ny fikasoahana ilay mibontsimbotsina amin’ny vatana. Mety hamindra izany aretina izany ihany koa ny fikitihana zavatra voakasok’ilay marary."},{"question":"Którą planetą od Słońca jest Ziemia?","answer":"Ziemia jest trzecią planetą od Słońca, za Merkurym i Wenus."},{"question":"Kan moo fent nosukaay (ordinnateur) ?","answer":"Charles Babbage"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Ronald George Wreyford Norrish. ","answer":"Ceimicí fisiciúil a rugadh i gCambridge Shasana, bunaitheoir na fótaiceimice nua-aoisí ab ea Ronald George Wreyford Norrish (9 Samhain 1897 - 7 Meitheamh 1978). Le George Porter, cheap sé an splancfhótalú chun imoibrithe tapa a anailísiú. Le Porter is Manfred Eigen, bhuaigh sé Duais Nobel sa cheimic i 1967 as. "},{"question":"فالقوات الأمريكية وحلفاؤها المحليون يسيطرون على مناطق واسعة ومهمة استراتيجيا في الجزء الشرقي من سوريا، وقد ألحقوا الهزيمة، ولو بشكل تقريبي وليس نهائي، بتنظيم ما يُعرف بالدولة الإسلامية هناك. وفي الآونة الأخيرة، أعلن البيت الأبيض أن القوات الأمريكية ستكمل مهمتها، بالقضاء على فلول تنظيم الدولة، لكنه قال إن ذلك لا يجب أن يستغرق وقتا طويلا. هذا ما يبدو حتى الآن، منذ أن بدا أن الرئيس، دونالد ترامب، يعيد صياغة سياسة بلاده بشأن سوريا على عجل، عبر إعلانه أن بلاده ستنسحب من هناك \\"في أقرب وقت ممكن\\". وعلى الرغم من نجاح الحملة العسكرية الأمريكية على تنظيم الدولة، إلا أن القضاء عليه تماما لن يكون سريعا، كما يأمل ترامب، ولا سيما أن مقاتلي التنظيم قد أثبتوا صلابة شديدة. وخرج الحليف المحلي الرئيسي للولايات المتحدة، وهم الأكراد، من المعركة ضد تنظيم الدولة، لكي يساعدوا إخوانهم، شمالي البلاد، الذين يتعرضون لهجوم من حليف آخر  للولايات المتحدة وهو تركيا. لذلك بدا الأمر في غاية التعقيد مع تعليق العمليات البرية ضد تنظيم الدولة الشهر الماضي.ولكن حتى إذا جاءت لحظة تسمى \\"النصر\\"، فإن وزارة الدفاع الأمريكية \\"البنتاغون\\" تخشى من أن الانسحاب الكامل للقوات الأمريكية سيترك فراغا خطيرا. وقد يكون في الواقع تنازلا عن المناطق، التي تسيطر عليها الولايات المتحدة، لصالح نظام الرئيس بشار الأسد وحلفائه الروس، الأمر الذي سيمثل خيانة لحلفاء واشنطن السوريين، كما أنه سيحبط جهودها لفرض نفوذها على نظام ما بعد الحرب، الذي يأخذ في الاعتبار مصالح واشنطن ومصالح حلفائها الإقليميين. بالإضافة لذلك سيعطل استراتيجية الإدارة الأمريكية، الرامية للمساعدة على دعم استقرار مناطق القتال المدمرة، بهدف منع عودة تنظيم الدولة مرة أخرى، وذلك عبر توفير الخدمات الأساسية، التي تمكِّن النازحين من العودة لمنازلهم. وتتفق وزارتا الدفاع والخارجية الأمريكيتان على هذا النهج.وسيسمح الانسحاب أيضا لإيران بتوسيع نفوذها الكبير بالفعل، في سوريا والمنطقة برمتها، كما سيسهل جهود طهران الرامية لتأسيس طريق مؤن بري، يمتد عبر العراق إلى سوريا، وصولا إلى حليفها في بيروت، وهو حزب الله. لكن ذلك يمثل مبعث قلق خطير لإسرائيل، التي تخشى من وجود عسكري لإيران على حدودها، وكذلك للسعودية المنافس الإقليمي الأكبر لإيران. أعطني عنوانًا جيدًا للمقالة أعلاه.","answer":"هل ستغادر القوات الأمريكية سوريا \\"قريبا\\"؟"},{"question":"ਮੁੰਬਈ, 3 ਮਾਰਚਭਾਰਤੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਿਯੰਕਾ ਚੋਪੜਾ ਨੂੰ ਯੂਨੀਸੈੱਫ ਦੇ ਸਦਭਾਵਨਾ ਦੂਤ ਵਜੋਂ ਹਟਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਇਕ ਆਨਲਾਈਨ ਪਟੀਸ਼ਨ ਦਾਇਰ ਕਰੇਗਾ। ‘ਆਵਾਜ਼’ ਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਨਲਾਈਨ ਮੰਚ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਦਾਖ਼ਲ ਇਸ ਪਟੀਸ਼ਨ ’ਤੇ ਸਾਢੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਦੇ ਕਰੀਬ (3519) ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਦਸਤਖ਼ਤ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਪਟੀਸ਼ਨ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗੇ ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਤੇ ਯੂਨੀਸੈੱਫ ਨੂੰ ਟੈਗ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਪਟੀਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ‘ਦੋ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਦਰਮਿਆਨ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਜੰਗ ਤਬਾਹੀ ਤੇ ਮੌਤ ਵੱਲ ਹੀ ਲਿਜਾਏਗੀ। ਯੂਨੀਸੈੱਫ ਦੀ ਸਦਭਾਵਨਾ ਦੂਤ ਵਜੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਿਯੰਕਾ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਰਪੱਖ ਰਹਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਅਮਨ ਦਾ ਸੁਨੇਹਾ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਸੀ, ਪਰ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਥਲ ਸੈਨਾ ਦੇ ਹੱਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਟਵੀਟ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਕੁਝ ਹੋਰ ਹੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਬਿਆਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਲਿਹਾਜ਼ਾ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਐਜਾਜ਼ ਦੇ ਹੁਣ ਯੋਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।’ਚੋਪੜਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਲ 2016 ਵਿੱਚ ਯੂਨੀਸੈੱਫ ਦਾ ਆਲਮੀ ਪੱਧਰ ’ਤੇ ਸਦਭਾਵਨਾ ਦੂਤ ਨਿਯੁਕਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਕਾਬਿਲੇਗੌਰ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਿਯੰਕਾ ਚੋਪੜਾ ਨੇ ਲੰਘੀ 26 ਫਰਵਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਖੈਬਰ ਪਖਤੂਨਖਵਾ ਸੂਬੇ ਦੇ ਬਾਲਾਕੋਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੈਸ਼-ਏ-ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਦੇ ਦਹਿਸ਼ਤੀ ਕੈਂਪਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਸ਼ਾਨਾ ਬਣਾਏ ਜਾਣ ’ਤੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹਵਾਈ ਫ਼ੌਜ ਨੂੰ ਵਧਾਈ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ।ਯੂਐੱਨ ਤੇ ਯੂਨੀਸੈੱਫ਼ ਨੂੰ ਟੈਗ ਕੀਤੀ ਇਸ ਆਨਲਾਈਟ ਪਟੀਸ਼ਨ ’ਤੇ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਲਿਖੇ ਜਾਣ ਤਕ ਸਾਢੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਲੋਕ ਦਸਤਖ਼ਤ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਸਨ।ਕਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਸ਼ਕਤੀਆਂ ਸਿਰਫ ਤਬਾਹੀ ਅਤੇ ਮੌਤ ਵੱਲ ਲੈ ਜਾਣਗੀਆਂ?","answer":"ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਸ਼ਕਤੀਆਂ ਸਿਰਫ ਤਬਾਹੀ ਅਤੇ ਮੌਤ ਵੱਲ ਲੈ ਜਾਣਗੇ।"},{"question":"Kedụ onyé éjị egwu Egedege mara?","answer":"Oriakụ Theresa Onuorah bụ ónyé éjị egwu Egedege mara. A maara ya nke ọma dị ka Queen of the Coast na chi Egedege Dance nke Unubi."},{"question":"ماهو الحدث المهم الذي يتحدث عنه النص التالي: بعد مونديال كأس العالم لعام 2002 من أهم البطولات القارية والأكثر متعة والذي فازت بها البرازيل على ألمانيا.","answer":"الحدث المهم الذي يتحدث عنه النص و الإدأهم هو: مونديال كأس العالم لعام 2002"},{"question":"Муссондор  бул...","answer":"Муссондор-багыты жылына эки жолу карама-каршы өзгөрүп турган туруктуу сезондук шамалдар:кышында кургактыктан океанды көздөй (кышкы муссон) жана жайында океандан кургактыкты көздөй(жайкы муссон) согот."},{"question":"Сый жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Сый-сыйга жарашат.Сый билбеген адашат."},{"question":"Iza no nanamboatra ny “La Guernica”?","answer":"“La Guernica” dia sangan'asan'ilay mpanao hosodoko Espaniola Pablo Picasso. Ity sary hosodoko ity dia maneho ny loza sy ny horohoron'ny ady."},{"question":"Jinsi ya kupika bagia za dengu","answer":"Naandaa unga naweka Amira kidogo na chumvi kwaaili ya ladha naweka vitunguu maji na vitunguu saumu unga ukiw tayari naweka kikaango jikoni na mafuta yakichemka naweka bagia kwenye mafuta"},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික උරුම සත්වයා  නම් කරන්න.","answer":"අලියා  ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික උරුම සත්වයා වේ "},{"question":"Cuba jawab teka-teki berikut: Dalam diri kita, anggota badan manakah yang paling manis?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah jari"},{"question":"Нукура  деген сөздүн синоними кандай?","answer":"Нукура  деген сөздүн синоними  – чыныгы болуп саналат."},{"question":"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ වත්මන්(2023) මහ ලේකම් ?","answer":"අන්තෝනියෝ ගුටරෙස්"},{"question":"Misalan Ƙarin harrufan \\"uwa\\" a suna ","answer":"Namiji: Gajere, Mace: Gajeruwa.Namiji: Dogo, Mace: Doguwa.Namji: Baƙo, Mace: Baƙuwa.Namiji: Tsoho, Mace: Toshuwa.Namiji: Gwauro, Mace: Gwauruwa."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Ak ba ngeen waxee ne: \\" Yaw Muusaa, dunu la gëm ba ba nuy gis Yàlla ne jàkk ci Moom\\" !... Faf xaacu ga fàdd leen, ngeen di gis loolu.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Ak ba ngéen wàxee ne: \\"Yaw Muusaa, du nu la gëm ba ba nu'y gìs Yàlla ne jàkk ci Moom\\"!... Faf xaacu ga fàdd léen, ngéen di gìs loolu."},{"question":"I wonder మహానంది గ్రామంలో నంది పొడవు ఎంత?","answer":"మహానంది ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రములోని కర్నూలు జిల్లా, మహానంది మండలం లోని గ్రామం, ఈ మండలానికి కేంద్రం. ఇది ప్రముఖ శైవ క్షేత్రం.ఇది నంద్యాలకు 14 కి.మీ దూరంలో ఉంది. ఇక్కడ గల స్వామి మహానందీశ్వరుడు, అమ్మవారు కామేశ్వరీ దేవి. ఇక్కడి మహానందీశ్వర దేవాలయం 7వ శతాబ్దినాటిది. ఈ ఆలయ శిల్పశైలిని బట్టి ఇది బాదామి చాళుక్య చక్రవర్తి వినయాదిత్యుని పాలనాకాలం (680-696) నాటిదని అంచనా. ఇచ్చట గల శివలింగము ఎత్తుగా కాక కొంచెము తప్పటగ వుంటుంది. పుట్టలో గల స్వామివారికి ఆవు పాలు ఇస్తుండగా కోపించిన యజమాని ఆవుని కొట్టగా పుట్టలో గల స్వామివారిని ఆవు తొక్కుట వలన లింగము కొంచెము అణిగివుంటుంది. ఆవు గిట్ట గుర్తు లింగముపై వుంటుంది. ఇచ్చట శుద్ధ స్ఫటిక వర్ణంలో కనిపించే జలం జలజలా ప్రవహించే దృశ్యం మహానంది ప్రత్యేకత. ఈ పుష్కరిణిలు విశ్వబ్రాహ్మణ శిల్పుల యొక్క పనితనాన్ని తెలియచేస్తుంది.ప్రధాన ఆలయానికి ఆలయ ముఖ ద్వారం గోపురానికి మధ్యలో ఉన్న పుష్కరిణి లోనికి స్వచ్ఛమైన నీరు సర్వ వేళలా గోముఖ శిల న్నుండి ధారావాహకంగా వస్తుంటుంది. ప్రధాన ఆలయంలోని లింగం క్రింద భూమిలో ఐదు నీటి ఊటలు ఉన్నాయి. లింగము క్రింద నుండి నీరు ఊరుతూ వుంటుంది. ఆ నీరు పుష్కరిణిలోనే బయటకు కనిపిస్తుంది. అందులోనికి వచ్చిన నీరు గోపురం ముందున్న రెండు గుండాల ద్వారా బయటకు పారుతుంది. ఈ నీరు బయటకు ప్రవహించే మార్గాల అమరిక వలన పుష్కరిణిలో నీరు ఎల్లప్పుడు ఒకే స్థాయిలో (1.7 మీటర్లు) నిర్మలంగా, పరిశుభ్రంగా ఉంటుంది. ఈ నీరు ఎంత స్వచ్ఛంగా వుంటుందంటే నీటిపై కదలిక లేకుంటే నీరున్నట్టే తెలియదు. ఇక్కడి శివలింగం కింది నుంచి ఏడాది పొడవునా ఒకేస్థాయిలో స్వచ్ఛమైన ఔషధ గుణాలున్న నీటి ప్రవాహం కొనసాగుతుంటుంది. వేసవిలో చల్లగా.. శీతాకాలంలో వెచ్చగా, వానాకాలంలోనూ మలినాల్లేకుండా తేటగా.. సూది సైతం స్పష్టంగా కనబడేస్థాయి స్వచ్ఛతతో ఉండటం ఈ నీటి ప్రత్యేక లక్షణం! ఐదున్నర అడుగులు లోతున్నా క్రిందనున్న రూపాయి బిళ్ల చాల స్పష్టంగా కనబడుతుంది. ఆలయ ఆవరణంలో కొన్ని బావులున్నాయి. అన్నింటిలోను ఇలాంటి నీరే ఉంది. ఈ నీటిని తీర్ధంగా భక్తులు తీసుకెళతారు. ఈ మహానంది క్షేత్రంలో ఊరే నీరు సుమారు 3000 ఏకరాలకు సాగు నీరు అందజేస్తుంది.ఇచ్చట బ్రహ్మ, విష్ణు, రుద్ర గుండాలు (పుష్కరుణులు) ఉన్నాయి. మహాశివరాత్రి పుణ్యదినమున లింగోధ్బవసమయమున అభిషేకము, కళ్యాణోత్సవము, రథోత్సవములు జరుగుతాయి. కోదండరామాలయం, కామేశ్వరీదేవి ఆలయం ఇతర దర్శనీయ స్థలాలు. మహానందికి 18 కిలోమీటర్ల..."},{"question":"Peribahasa : Harapkan pegar, pegar makan padi","answer":"Maksud : Orang yang kita harapkan dapat menolong tetapi dia yang berbuat jahat."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọja Bodija fẹsun kan awọn aṣọbode, wọn ni wọn ko ẹru atowo lọ ni ṣọọbu awọn","answer":"Pẹlu bi awọn oṣiṣẹ aṣọbode ṣe lọọ jalẹkun awọn ṣọọbu kan ninu ọja Bodija loru mọju Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee to kọja, Alukoro fun ileeṣẹ aṣọbode ipinlẹ Ọyọ ati Ọṣun, Ọgbẹni Kayọde Wey, ti sọ pe awọn aṣọbode lo ṣiṣẹ naa loootọ, ṣugbọn awọn eeyan awọn lati ilu Abuja ti i ṣe olu ilu ilẹ yii ni wọn ṣiṣẹ naa, ki i ṣe awọn aṣọbode n’Ibadan.Ṣugbọn Iyalọja ọja Bodija, Oloye Victoria Onipẹde, ti ṣapejuwe igbesẹ ti awọn agbofinro gbe ọhun gẹgẹ bii ọna lati fara ni araalu.Yatọ si ọkẹ aimọye apo irẹsi ati ogunlọgọ kẹẹgi ororo ti wọn ko ninu awọn ṣọọbu naa lẹyin ti wọn fipa ja awọn ilẹkun ṣọọbu wọnyi wọle, nnkan bii miliọnu mẹẹẹdogun Naira (#15000) lapapọ owo ta a gbọ pe wọn tun ji ko ninu awọn sọọbu naa.Ẹkun asun-kawọleri lọpọ ninu awọn to n ṣowo irẹsi tabi ororo ninu ọja Bodija, n’Ibadan, fi aarọ kutu Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, sun, awọn ti iba si rẹ wọn lẹkun ko mọ iru arọwa ti wọn iba pa fun wọn, wọn mọ pe ijọba lo fa sababi ohun to pa wọn lẹkun.Lọsan-an ọjọ naa lawọn ti ọrọ yii kan pẹlu awọn ara ọja ọhun mi-in lọ si Sẹkiteriati ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ lati fẹhonu wọn han sijọba ipinlẹ yii.Ẹnikẹni iba ti mọ pe awọn aṣọbode lo jalẹkun ṣọọbu awọn oniṣowo ni Bodija ti wọn si ko wọn lẹru ọja atowo nla lọ, awọn kọsitọọmu funra wọn ni wọn fi awọn agadagodo mi-in to jẹ tiwọn tun awọn ilẹkun naa ti, ti wọn si tun lẹ iwe mọ ara ilẹkun lati jẹ ki gbogbo aye mọ pe awọn lawọn ṣiṣẹ naa.Ninu iwe ti wọn lẹ mọ ara awọn ṣọọbu ti wọn ja wọnyi ni wọn ti ṣekilọ pe ẹnikẹni ko gbọdọ jalẹkun tabi wọ inu awọn ṣọọbu wọnyi lai gba aṣẹ lọwọ awọn, bi eeyan ba dan iru ẹ wo, oluwa ẹ yoo ṣẹwọn ọdun mẹwaa tabi ko fi miliọnu lọna ọgọrun-un naira (N100 m) gbara.Nigba to n b’ALAROYE sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ aṣọbode ẹkun ipinlẹ Ọyọ ati Ọyọ, Ọgbẹni Kayọde Wey, sọ pe “Awọn eeyan ti pe mi lori ọrọ yẹn lataarọ, ṣugbọn a ko mọ nnkan kan nipa ẹ rara.“Ki i ṣe awa la ṣiṣẹ yẹn, a ko tiẹ mọ nipa ẹ rara. Awọn ara Abuja lo ṣe e, mi o si mọ iru iroyin ti wọn gbọ ti wọn fi gbe igbesẹ yẹn.”Ṣugbọn gẹgẹ bii olori ọja, iṣẹlẹ yii ko dun mọ Oloye Victoria ti i ṣe Iyalọja ọja Bodija ninu, o ni ọna lati ni araalu lara nigbesẹ ti awọn aṣoju ijọba apapọ ilẹ yii gbe ọhun.O ni “Awọn kọsitọọmu lẹ iwe mọ awọn ṣọọbu ti wọn ja lati fi han pe awọn lawọn ko ọja inu awọn ṣọọbu wọnyẹn. Nitori naa, iṣẹlẹ yẹn ti kuro ni pe wọn jale.“Gẹgẹ bi wọn ṣe sọ fun mi, ni nnkan bii aago mẹta oru lawọn kọsitọọmu waa jalẹkun ṣọọbu awọn onirẹsi kan ti wọn si ko awọn irẹsi wọn lọ.“Ki i ṣe gbogbo ṣọọbu ni wọn ja, awọn ṣọọbu ti wọn ko irẹsi ti wọn ko wa lati ilẹ okeere si nikan ni. Ṣugbọn apo irẹsi ti wọn ko lọ ko to tirela mẹẹẹdogun (15) ti awọn oniroyin n pariwo nitori aago mẹta oru ni wọn wa, ko si ṣee ṣe ki wọn ti sare ko aduru nnkan bẹẹ yẹn laarin asiko yẹn si aarọ yẹn nitori bii wakati meji lawọn alabaaru maa n lo lati ko tirela apo irẹsi kan tan.“Loootọ, a mọ pe ọja to ta ko ofin ni irẹsi ti wọn ba ko wa lati ilẹ okeere nitori ijọba ti ṣe irẹsi kiko wọ ilẹ yii lati orileede mi-in leewọ, ṣugbọn ta a ba maa sọ eyi to jẹ ootọ ọrọ, inira ti ofin yii n mu ba araalu pọ ju anfaani ibẹ lọ.“Erongba ijọba pẹlu ofin yẹn ni lati jẹ ki awọn eeyan maa ra nnkan ti awọn awa funra wa ba n pese lorileede yii. Ṣugbọn irẹsi ti a n gbin lorileede yii ko ti i to wa a jẹ debi ti ijọba maa fofin de ti ilẹ okeere.“Ọpọ eeyan ni ko mọ pe ki i ṣe anfaani kekere ni irẹsi ilẹ okeere n ṣe fun wa. Idi ni pe, ni gbogbo  igba ti ijọba ba ti ti ẹnu ibode pa, ti awọn eeyan ko raaye ko irẹsi wọle mọ, niṣe nirẹsi wa nilẹ yii maa n gbowo lori, nigba to jẹ pe irẹsi ti a n gbin nilẹ yii ko ti to waa jẹ.“Irẹsi tiwa-n-tiwa wọn ju tilẹ okeere lọ. Nigba ti ijọba ti bode pa, a n ra kongo kan irẹsi ilẹ yii ni ẹgbẹrin naira (N800). Ṣugbọn nigba ti wọn ṣi bode, ti irẹsi ilẹ okeere de, ẹgbẹrin naira ni kongo kan oun naa, iyẹn lo mu ki owo irẹsi tiwa-n-tiwa ja wa silẹ pẹlu aadọta naira (N50). Awọn to n tiraka lati ko awọn ọja wa lati ilẹ okeere ni wọn n jẹ ki adinku ba owo ọja bayii“Iranlọwọ ijọba apapọ lawa oniṣowo nilo, lati jẹ ko rọrun fun wa lati maa ri ọja ra nirọrun, ki gbogbo araalu to taja naa ma baa maa ra a pẹlu owo gọbọi nitori owo ọhun naa ko si nibikankan.”"},{"question":"Amọtẹkun fija pẹẹta pẹlu awọn janduku n’Ibadan, eeyan mẹrin lo dero ọrun","answer":"O kere tan, eeyan mẹrin ni wọn yinbọn pa laduugbo Lalábíran, n’Ibadan, ninu ija ibọn ati oogun abẹnu-gọngọ to waye laarin awọn ọmọ iṣọta agbegbe náà pẹlu awọn ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun.Àdúgbo Labiran yii lo n gbona janjan lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii, nitori bi awọn janduku ṣe n fi ojoojumọ kọ lu awọn araadugbo naa, ti wọn sì máa n ja wọn lole t’ọsan-t’oru.Laarin oru Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, sí aarọ ọjọ Àbámẹ́ta, Sátidé, ọpọlọpọ ile ati  mọto lawọn tọọgi náà dana sun.Ninu ikọlu ti wọn tun ṣe sí àdúgbò yìí loru mọju leeyan mẹrin ti ku, nigba ti awọn oṣiṣẹ ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun lọọ koju wọn.Ọkan ninu awọn ọdọ àdúgbò Labiran fìdí ẹ mulẹ pe “Awa gan-an ko wulẹ sun mọ́ lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii, niṣe la n ṣọdẹ yika gbogbo adugbo wa ko ma di pe àwọn wèrè yẹn yoo lo oore ọfẹ ikọlu wọn láti máa fi jale.“Ọkan ninu wa lo pe awọn Amọtẹkun lati waa ran wa lọwọ nigba ti awọn eeyan yẹn dé. Bi awọn Amọtẹkun ṣe dé ni wọn n yinbọn soke kẹ̀ù! kẹ̀ù! Bẹẹ lawọn tọọgi naa n yinbọn.“Mẹrin ninu awọn tọọgi yẹn ti wọn n jẹ Monsuru, Ridwan pẹlu awọn meji mi-in lawọn Amọtẹkun pa.”ALAROYE gbọ pe wọn ti sìnkú awọn ọdọkunrin naa laaarọ ọjọ Abamẹta.Bó ṣe di nnkan bíi aago meji ọsan yii lọrọ tun di bó-ò-lọ-yàgò, nigba ti awọn ọmọ iṣọta wọnyi ti wọn ko din ni ọgọ́rùn-ún (100) niye tun gbàjọba oju popo gbogbo ladugbo Labiran yíi kan naa.Bo tilẹ jẹ pé lọgan lawọn Amọtẹkun dé sibẹ láti pana laasigbo ọhun, ṣugbọn ọgbọọgbọn ti agbalagba fi í sá fún maaluu la gbọ pe wọn fi sa kuro nibẹ nitori pe awọn ẹruuku naa pọ jù wọn lọ.Ṣugbọn laipẹ lawọn oṣiṣẹ eleto aabo naa pada de lakọtun pẹlu awọn agbofinro min-in bíi ọlọpaa ati Operation Burst, nigba naa lawọn alájààgbilà naa tóo juba ehoro.Pẹlu ibẹru bojo lawọn ara Labiran fi n gbe bayii, awọn ti ọkàn wọn ko sí fi bẹẹ le ti fi adugbo naa silẹ lọọ fi ibomi-in ṣebugbe."},{"question":"Flutter SDK кайсы тилде жазылган?а) С++б) Java в) Dartг) Python","answer":"Туура жооп: в) Dart"},{"question":"கேள்வி  : தன் நூலை தானே மொழிபெயர்த்து  சிறப்பு பெற்றவர்  யார்?","answer":"பதில் : இரவீந்திரநாத் தாகூர். தான் வங்க மொழியில் எழுதிய கவிதைத் தொகுப்பான கீதாஞ்சலியை ஆங்கிலத்தில்  மொழிபெயர்த்ததனால்  நோபல் பரிசு பெற்றார். "},{"question":" Firy ny zanak'i Andry Rajoelina?","answer":"i Andry Rajoelina dia manan-janaka 3 , 2 lahy dia 1 vavy"},{"question":"Kum bir karışım mıdır?","answer":"Kum; bölünmüş kaya ve mineral parçacıklarından oluşan granül bir malzemedir. Çakıldan daha ince ve siltden daha kaba olur. Kum ayrıca bir dokusal toprak veya toprak türüne de atıfta bulunabilir. Yani, kütle olarak %85'den fazla kum boyutlu parçacık içeren bir topraktır."},{"question":"帝国領内にいる全ての自由民に市民権を与えたことや、大浴場を作ったことで知られる、古代ローマの皇帝は誰でしょう？","answer":"カラカラ帝です。"},{"question":"뭔가 떠오르는데 기억이 안나요. 제목은 'genuine stone' 였습니다. 메인스트림 언론에서 애디슨을 소개하는 내용이었습니다. 그녀의 대중 예술, 광고판, 남자친구들에 대한 내용과 함께요.","answer":"좀 더 자세한 맥락을 제공해주시면 답변해드리겠습니다."},{"question":"මයිකල් ෆෙල්ප්ස් ජයග්‍රහණය කළ ඔලිම්පික් රන් පදක්කම් සංඛ්‍යාව කීයද?","answer":"විසි තුනයි"},{"question":"ജീവിതത്തിൽ നിങ്ങൾ വിജയിച്ച അടയാളങ്ങളുടെ ഒരു ലിസ്റ്റ് നൽകുക. ","answer":"\\"1. നിങ്ങളുടെ വീട് നിങ്ങളുടേതാണ്2. നിങ്ങളുടെ വിദ്യാർത്ഥി വായ്പകൾ നിങ്ങൾ അടച്ചു3. നിങ്ങൾ വൈകാരികമായും ശാരീരികമായും ആരോഗ്യവാനാണ്4. നിങ്ങൾക്ക് അർത്ഥവത്തായ ബന്ധങ്ങളുണ്ട്5. നിങ്ങൾ സ്വയം ബഹുമാനിക്കുകയും സ്നേഹിക്കുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നു6. നിങ്ങളുടെ കുട്ടികളും പങ്കാളിയും സംതൃപ്തരാണ് 7. നിങ്ങൾ സുഖമായി വിരമിച്ചു\\""},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න.මා අමතක වී යාවීදුරු රට ගියදා නුඹ මා හැරදා","answer":"මා අමතක වී යාවීදුරු රට ගියදා නුඹ මා හැරදාමා අමතක වී යාවිකාලය හිමිහිට පියඹාවීකෙදිනක හෝ අප හමුවේවීලොවට හොරා සැඟවී රහසේසැනසුනි නම් මා නුඹ තුරුලේමගෙන් නොලද රැකවල් මැද්දේපාළු කියයි නුඹ තනි යහනේමටත් හොරා ඉකිබිඳ රහසේනැවතුනිනම් නුඹ මා තුරුලේමෙවන් මිහිරි හැඟුමන් දෙහදේරැඳී තියේවිද හෙට දවසේමා අමතක වී යාවී //"},{"question":"கேள்வி :உலகிலேயே பத்திரிகைகளுக்கு அதிக நேரம் பேட்டியளித்த பிரதமர் யார்?","answer":"பதில்:திரு. வி.பி.சிங். (விஸ்வநாத் பிரதாப் சிங்) இவர் பதவியேற்ற இரண்டாவது சந்திப்பில் எண்ணூறுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட பத்திரிகையாளர்களின் கேள்விகளுக்கு டெல்லி ஸ்ரீபோர்ட் ஆடிட்டோரியத்தில் இரண்டு மணி நேரம் வரை பதில் அளித்து உலக சாதனை புரிந்தார்."},{"question":"Inona no fanangonana tononkalo voalohany nataon'i Jean Joseph Rabearivelo?","answer":"Nantsoina hoe \\"Sylves\\" ny fanangonana tononkalo voalohany, an'i Jean Joseph Rabearivelo, ary nivoaka tamin'ny 1927."},{"question":"How is attention visualized in a Transformer model?","answer":"Attention can be visualized by creating attention heatmaps, which show how much attention each element in the input sequence pays to others. Visualization helps interpret the model's focus and understand which parts of the input contribute most to predictions."},{"question":"સપ્તર્ષિ નક્ષત્રના સાત તારાઓ  જણાવો.","answer":"૧.\\tક્રતુ\\t૨.\\tપુલહ૩.\\tપુલસ્ત્ય૪. અત્રિ૫.\\tઅંગિરા૬.\\tવસિષ્ઠ૭.\\tમરીચિ"},{"question":"اقرأ الفقرة التالية ثم أجب عن السؤال:أول صورة في الوطن العربي في مصر كانت بحضور محمد علي باشا في ٤ نوفمبر ١٣٦٩ م، أي بعد أربعة أشهر من إيداع داجير الاختراع آلة التصوير الأولى في أكاديمية العلوم بفرنسا، كان هذا في الإسكندرية ومنها انطلقت أول مجموعة مصورين فرنسيين إلى الشام وفلسطين، كتب الرحلات المنشورة في أوروبا وروسيا للمستشرقين في عشرينات وثلاثينيات القرن التاسع عشر التي تصف سحر الشرق ولوحات الرسامين التي تنقل هذا السحر حثت أكثر المصورين على اكتشاف العالم العربي، تغيرت الوسيلة فقد انتقل الغربي أو المستشرق من القلم والريشة إلى آلة التصوير، لكنه مع الأسف حافظ على الرؤية نفسها خاصة الجيل الأول من المصورين، إما استعلائية وإما عجائبية، يقول بونفيس معلقا على ما رآه في بيروت في كتابه \\"ذكريات المشرق\\" الذي جمع الكثير عن التصوير والوطن العربي في ذلك العصر: كل شيء يبدو ثابتا في الشرق، حتى في التفاصيل الدقيقة، عشرون قرنا مرت دون أي تغير في الشكل أو الديكور في هذه الأرض الفريدة، لذا علينا العمل بسرعة للتمتع بهذه المناظر، فالتقدم سوف ينهي هذه المشاهد أو يدمرها، والمدينة التي تدخل في كل منحى من مناحي الحياة سوف تنتهي في هذه البالد كما أنهت في بالد أخرى خصوصيتها.السؤال: لماذا انطلقت أول مجموعة مصورين إلى الشام و فلسطين ؟","answer":"الجواب: بسبب الكتب والصور التي نقلها المستشرقون عن العالم العربي"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਪ੍ਰਥਮੇ ਮਿਟਿਆ ਤਨ ਕਾ ਦੂਖ ॥ਮਨ ਸਗਲ ਕਉ ਹੋਆ ਸੂਖੁ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਗੁਰ ਦੀਨੋ ਨਾਉ ॥ਬਲਿ ਬਲਿ ਤਿਸੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕਉ ਜਾਉ ॥੧॥ਗੁਰੁ ਪੂਰਾ ਪਾਇਓ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ॥ਰੋਗ ਸੋਗ ਸਭ ਦੂਖ ਬਿਨਾਸੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਸਰਣਾਈ ॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਗੁਰ ਕੇ ਚਰਨ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਵਸਾਏ ॥ਮਨ ਚਿੰਤਤ ਸਗਲੇ ਫਲ ਪਾਏ ॥ਅਗਨਿ ਬੁਝੀ ਸਭ ਹੋਈ ਸਾਂਤਿ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਗੁਰਿ ਕੀਨੀ ਦਾਤਿ ॥੨॥ਨਿਥਾਵੇ ਕਉ ਗੁਰਿ ਦੀਨੋ ਥਾਨੁ ॥ਨਿਮਾਨੇ ਕਉ ਗੁਰਿ ਕੀਨੋ ਮਾਨੁ ॥ਬੰਧਨ ਕਾਟਿ ਸੇਵਕ ਕਰਿ ਰਾਖੇ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਬਾਨੀ ਰਸਨਾ ਚਾਖੇ ॥੩॥ਵਡੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਪੂਜ ਗੁਰ ਚਰਨਾ ॥ਸਗਲ ਤਿਆਗਿ ਪਾਈ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਸਰਨਾ ॥ਗੁਰੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਜਾ ਕਉ ਭਇਆ ਦਇਆਲਾ ॥ ਸੋ ਜਨੁ ਹੋਆ ਸਦਾ ਨਿਹਾਲਾ ॥੪॥੬॥੧੦੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 395 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਿਆਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ) ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਦਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਦੁੱਖ ਮਿਟ ਗਿਆ,ਫਿਰ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਨ ਆਨੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਵੀਰ! ਜਦੋਂ ਦਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਗ ਸਾਰੇ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁੱਖ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ ।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ) ਮੈਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਏ ਹਨ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਮਨ-ਇੱਛਤ ਫਲ ਮਿਲ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ) ਅੱਗ ਬੁੱਝ ਗਈ ਹੈ (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਪੂਰੀ ਠੰਢ ਪੈ ਗਈ ਹੈ ।ਇਹ ਸਾਰੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਹੀ ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ ।੨।ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕਿਤੇ ਢੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ) ਥਾਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨਿਮਾਣੇ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਆਦਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਮੇਰੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ) ਬੰਧਨ ਕੱਟ ਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਸੇਵਕ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਲਿਆ,ਹੁਣ ਮੇਰੀ ਜੀਭ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ (ਦਾ ਰਸ) ਚੱਖਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਵੱਡੀ ਕਿਸਮਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਪੂਜਾ (ਦਾ ਅਵਸਰ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ)ਮੈਂ ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਆਸਰੇ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆ ਪਿਆ ਹਾਂ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉੱਤੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਇਆਵਾਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੬।੧੦੦।\\""},{"question":"Mune rimwe danho redenderedzwa rekabhoni, munhu anofuridzira mamorekuru ecarbon dioxide (CO2) mumhepo. Ndechipi chezvinotevera chinogona kuitika pedyo neatomu recarbon iri mumorekuru iri? - Ndizvozvo. Sarudza mhinduro yako pane dzinotevera: 1). Inogona kushandiswa sechikamu cheshuga muchirimwa.. 2). Inogona kuva rutivi rweprotini iri mumhuka.. 3). Inogona kupedzwa sezvo mafuta anotsva anopiswa.. 4). Inogona kuora ikava kabhoni uye okisijeni nebhakitiriya..","answer":"1). Inogona kushandiswa sechikamu cheshuga muchirimwa."},{"question":"Какое из этих животных является хищником?A) КороваB) ЛисаC) КроликD) ЖирафВыберите правильный ответ (укажите букву).","answer":"Правильный ответ: B) ЛисаЛиса обыкновенная или рыжая (Vulpes vulpes) — широко распространенное хищное млекопитающее семейства псовых – самый крупный вид рода лисиц. Длина тела зверя 60-90 см, вес – 6-10 кг.Лисица – типичный хищник. Главную и наиболее постоянную ее добычу составляют мыши, к схватыванию которых превосходно приспособлены и тонкие резцы, и узкая морда."},{"question":"Таң калган Тыныстан эмне дейт?","answer":"Билимдүү немени көргөн сайын, адамдын көк беттигине таң кала берем. Ааламды акыл менен аңдагысы келген көрпенденин көк беттигине таң калбай болобу. Көк бет болгон жакшы да. Адам мээсинде  86 милиард нейрон бар экенин, асманда 200 секстилион жылдыз бар экенин билесиң. Дагы бир аз акылдуураак болсоң, “милиард” менен “секстилион” эки “л” менен жазылышын эстей жүрөсүң. Акылдуу болгон жакшы да. Толтура …измдерди, …логияларды аралаштырып сүйлөйсүң, анан оозуңдан “менин оюмча” сөзү түшпөй калат. Ооба, акылдуу болсоң, бардык нерсеге оюң болот, оюңду кызыктуу кылып айтып бере аласың, адамдар (кайсы бир деңгээлде) сени кызыгып угушат. Азыркы адам ушундай: көк бет, өжөр, билимдүү, акылдуу. Ага баарын эсептетип, тактатып, окутуп, сүйлөтүп эле койсо…Биз эсептеп, тактап, окуп, сүйлөп жүрүп кайда келип калдык, кайда баратабыз? Ушул суроону куржунуна артынып алып, өткөн айда Айбек байке (Байымбетов) бизди касиеттүү Ыйык-Көлгө чакырды. Бардык. Жалаң билимдүүлөр, акылдуулар, илимдин дөө-шаалары чогулуптур. Жээкке чыгып калган балыктай болуп мен эле жүрөм. Ошол топто эң кенжеси да, эң узуну да, эң арыгы да, эң акылдуу эмеси да мен экенмин. Таң калып эле отурдум. Таң калам деп айтпадымбы тексттин башында. Таң кала берип, таңым калбай калмай болду. Башкалар кээде мага тааныш, кээде мага тааныш эмес тилдерди, сөздөрдү сүйлөшөт. Мен таң калып бүтпөйм.  Ааламды тааныш үчүн өзүңдү тааны, өзүңдү тааныш үчүн кайда баратканыңды бил, кайда баратканыңды кайдан келатканыңдан бил, кайдан келатканыңды билиш үчүн тамырыңды изилде. Бул сөздөр меники эмес. Кимдики экени да эсимде жок. Ошо. Толтура билимдүүнүн бир жерге чогулганы да ошондон. Батыштын илимин чукуп жүрүп, өздөрүн таанырлык бир илмекей таба албай коюшуптур ошолор. Бул тууралуу биринчи күнү эле сөз болду. Биз, көчмөндөрдүн дүйнө таанымы, жашоо усулдары, ой-чабыты, дегеле баскан кадамы да тиги батыш таңуулап койгон илимдин категорияларына сыйбай турганын, биз өзүбүздүн илимий усулдарыбызды, өзүбүздүн илимибизди иштеп чыгышыбыздын зарылдыгы тууралуу сүйлөштү. Аны кантип аташ өзүнчө бир түйшүк болуп алды. “Көчмөндөрдүн/тамырлуу элдердин философиясы” деп айталы десек, батышта жаралган “философия” сөзүнүн өзү биздин дүйнө таанымга отурбай, притимитивдүү болуп калып жатпайбы. “Башкача философия” (Иная философия) деп бири, “Көчмөндөрдүн салттуу мурасынын философиялык маанилештирилиши” (Философское осмысление наследия кочевых традиций) деп экинчиси  сунуштады. Бирөө айтканы бирөөнө жакпай отуруп, акыры “Көчмөн элдердин этикасы” деген темага токтолдук. Буга да дароо эмес, экинчи күнкү Султан агайдын (Сарыгулов) маңыздуу кебинен кийин келдик. Азыр дүйнөлүк түзүм эл аралык конвенциялардан, мамлекеттердеги мыйзамдардан турса, көчмөндөрдөгү тартип этикадан келип чыккандыгы тууралуу кенен токтолду Султан агай. Мыйзам - кайсы бир топтун жашоо ыңгайы үчүн биргеликте кабыл алган эрежелери болуп, сырткы күч катары кабыл алынса, этика - адамды адам менен, адамды аалам менен тең салмакта, бакытта жашоосуна шарт түзгөн, адамдын ичиндеги күч, ичиндеги бейкуттук. Көчмөн этикасы, аны оңой изилдеген, түшүндүргөн жаңы методология... “келечектин кыргызы”... сырткы чабуулдардан элдин аң сезимин коргоо… мейкиндикти программалоо… манасчылар пайда кылган кубат талаасы… көлөкө менен иштөө… аялдык энергия - сүйүүнүн энергиясы… аялдагы ыйыктык ойгонгон доор… Сүйлөй берсе, акылды кытыгылаган сөздөр көп. Бирок көчмөндөрдүн өзгөчөлүгү ааламды акыл менен эмес, көкүрөк менен туйгандыгында. Кеп ошондо. Биз көп сүйлөштүк. Бирок андан көп нерсени сүйлөшпөй эле аңдап жаттык. Себеби баарыбыз көчмөнбүз, себеби баарыбыздын тамырыбызда кыргыздын каны агат. А эгер көкүрөгүң ачык да, акылың тунук да болсо, бул такыр башка кеп. Төрт күндүк жыйналыштын соңунда “Жаргылчак” деп аталып калган ошол топко чогулгандар ошондой акылы тунук, көкүрөгүндө көзү бар адамдар болуптур. Мен гана жүрдүм таң калып бүтпөй. Таң калган сонун да."},{"question":"திருவிகவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"நாடு என்பது ஓர் எல்லைக்கு உட்பட்ட வெறும் நிலப்பரப்பு மட்டுமன்று. நிலத்தின் இயற்கைத் தன்மையினினின்றும் முகிழ்ந்த வாழ்க்கை. அரசு, கலவி, தொழில், நாகரிகம் முதலியனவும் சேர்ந்த ஒன்றே நாடு என்பது."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Công an tỉnh Ninh thuận cho VOV hay đã nhận được đơn của ông Hồ Hoàng Hùng (SN 1961) khiếu nại về hồ sơ vụ tai nạn giao thông của con gái ông là cháu H.H.A (sinh năm 2004) đã tử vong vào ngày 28/6/2022. Ngoài Công an tỉnh, đơn khiếu nại của ông Hồ Hoàng Hùng còn được gửi đến các cơ quan chức năng khác gồm: Bí thư Tỉnh ủy, Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh, Viện trưởng Viện kiểm sát nhân dân tỉnh Ninh Thuận; Cơ quan điều tra hình sự khu vực 3 - Quân chủng Phòng không - Không quân;… Vietnamnet đưa tin, trong đơn khiếu nại, ông Hùng cho rằng sau khi con gái bị ô tô tông chết, cơ quan điều tra có \\"kết quả kiểm tra nồng độ cồn","answer":"của H. H.A. là 0,79 mg/100 ml máu\\", là không chính xác, gia đình nạn nhân khiếu nại, yêu cầu giám định lại. Gia đình yêu cầu như vậy bởi việc thu thập mẫu máu của cháu H.H.A lần trước không hề có sự chứng kiến của gia đình, các cơ quan chức năng như Viện Kiểm sát và người làm chứng hay thân nhân trong khi cháu còn đang là học sinh lớp 12 chưa thành niên. Bên cạnh đó, tại thời điểm bị tông chết, cháu A cùng các bạn đến trường THPT Lê Quý Đôn làm thủ tục chuẩn bị cho Kỳ thi tốt nghiệp trung học phổ thông lúc 7h sáng thì làm sao cháu lại có nồng độ cồn lên đến 0,79mg/100ml máu được? Ngoài ra, theo báo Lao Động, gia đình nạn nhân cũng kiến nghị cần giám định, đối chiếu mẫu máu mà Bệnh viện Đa khoa tỉnh Ninh Thuận đã xét nghiệm và cho rằng đó là mẫu máu của H.H.A. Cũng theo nguồn trên, ngày 12/7, hiện trường vụ tai nạn giao thông trên đã được Cơ quan CSĐT Công an TP Phan Rang - Tháp Chàm dựng lại. Cơ quan công an xét thấy vụ việc liên quan đến cán bộ quân đội đầy đủ hồ sơ, nên chuyển sang cơ quan điều tra Quân khu thụ lý theo thẩm quyền. Cũng trong thời gian này, cơ quan Điều tra Hình sự Khu vực 3 thuộc Quân chủng Phòng không - Không quân đã ra thông báo tìm nhân chứng của tai nạn giao thông trên. Tổng hợp"},{"question":"“దురాశ దుఃఖానికి కారణం” ఎలానో వివరించండి.","answer":"“ఆశకు అంతే లేదు” అన్నది ఆర్యోక్తి. “ఆశాపాశము తాకడున్ నిడుపు” అంటాడు వామనావతారం ఎత్తిన శ్రీహరి. “దురాశ దఃఖము చేటు” అన్న సామెత మనం నిత్యం వింటూనే ఉంటాం. ఈ సూక్తులన్నింటి లోనూ పేరాశ పనికిరాదనే హితోక్తి మనకు స్పష్టమౌతుంది. అయితే అసలు ఆశ అనేది వుండకూడదని మాత్రం దీని అర్థం కాదు.హద్దులు దాటని ఆశ, పరిథులు దాటని కోరిక మనిషిని ప్రయత్నశీలుణ్ణి చేసి, తాను ఆశించిన ఫలితాలను అందుకోవడానికి ప్రోత్సాహమిస్తాయి. జీవితంలో ఎన్ని కష్టాలు ఎదురైనా భవిష్యత్తుపైన ఉన్న చిన్ని ఆశ మానవుణ్ణి ధైర్యంగా ముందుకు నడిపిస్తుంది. అయితే ఈ ఆశ అత్యాశగా మారి హద్దుల్ని అతిక్రమిస్తే, అది మనిషిపాలిట శాపంగా మారి అతడిని నరకప్రాయం చేస్తుంది. కొన్ని సందర్భాలలో ప్రాణాలకు కూడా ముప్పు తీసుకువస్తుంది.మనలో కూడా చాలామంది ఇంకా ఇంకా సంపాదించాలని అత్యాశతో కుటుంబ సౌఖ్యాన్ని, వ్యక్తిగత ఆరోగ్యాన్ని పాడు చేసుకుంటున్న వాళ్ళు ఉన్నారు. దుర్మార్గాలకు, దౌర్జన్యాలకు పాల్పడి మానవ మనుగడను నరకంగా మారుస్తున్న వాళ్ళూ వున్నారు. నిజానికి వీరంతా ఆ సంపాదనను అనుభవిస్తున్నారా అంటే లేదు అనేది జగమెరిగిన సత్యం.ఇందులో చాలామంది తమ దురాశల పరుగుపందెంలో ప్రాణాలు పోగొట్టుకుంటున్నా రన్నది పచ్చినిజం. అందుకే అత్యాశకు పోకుండా వున్నదానితో తృప్తిగా జీవించటం మనం నేర్చుకోవాలి. ప్రాప్తమైనా లేశమైనా పదివేలు అనుకొని జీవితాన్ని ఆనందంగా గడపాలి. అప్పుడు ప్రతి ఇల్లూ ఆనందాల హరివిల్లుగా మారుతుంది. ఆత్మీయతల పొదరిల్లుగా నవ్వులు కురిపిస్తుంది."},{"question":"د ارسطو فلسفې په وروسته پاتې مفکرینو او د غربي افکارو په پراختیا څه ډول اغیز وکړ؟","answer":"د ارسطو کارونو د غربي فلسفې، الهیات او ساینس په برخه کې ژوره اغیزه کړې ده. د منځنیو پیړیو او رینسیسانس په اوږدو کې، د هغه لیکنې ساتل شوي او مطالعه شوي، په فیلسوفانو، علومو پوهانو او ساینس پوهانو اغیزه کړې. د هغه نظریاتو په مختلفو برخو کې، له اخلاقو څخه تر طبیعی علومو پورې د پام وړ نښه پریښوده، او د لویدیځ فلسفې د فکري میراث یوه حیاتي برخه ده."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Đó là khẳng định của ông Nguyễn Trọng Khoa - phó cục trưởng Cục Quản lý khám chữa bệnh (Bộ Y tế) - sau sự việc bác sĩ P.H.T. đang công tác tại khoa cấp cứu Bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định bị người nhà bệnh nhân to tiếng, quát tháo, ép vào tường và bóp cổ trong ca trực lúc 21h ngày 27-7.Cục Quản lý khám chữa bệnh chiều 28-7 vừa có công văn đề nghị Sở Y tế TP.HCM vào cuộc xử lý vụ việc.Trong công văn đề nghị Sở Y tế TP.HCM, Cục Quản lý khám chữa bệnh nêu Bộ Y tế nhận thấy hành vi hành hung bác sĩ tại Bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định có dấu hiệu vi phạm nghiêm trọng đến quyền của người hành nghề, gây tổn hại về thể chất, tinh thần và danh dự của bác sĩ trực tiếp hành nghề, cùng các nhân viên y tế khác.Sự việc này đồng thời gây mất an ninh, an toàn và trật tự tại nơi khám chữa cấp cứu; ảnh hưởng xấu đến tâm lý và thời gian khám chữa bệnh cho các bệnh nhân khác.Từ sự việc này, Cục Quản lý khám chữa bệnh (Bộ Y tế) đề nghị Sở Y tế TP.HCM sớm vào cuộc tiến hành xác minh vụ việc; phối hợp với Công an TP.HCM điều tra, đề xuất hướng xử lý nghiêm hành vi sai phạm. Song song đó, kịp thời động viên đối với bác sĩ hành nghề, chịu ảnh hưởng trực tiếp từ vụ hành hung nói trên.Chiều cùng ngày, trao đổi với Tuổi Trẻ Online, bác sĩ Đinh Hữu Hào - phó giám đốc Bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định - xác nhận sự việc nêu trên và cho biết hiện sức khỏe của bác sĩ T. (người bị hành hung) đã ổn định; sự việc cũng đang được phía công an vào cuộc điều tra.Trước đó, khoảng 21h ngày 27-7, một bé gái 10 tuổi bị hóc xương được chuyển đến khoa cấp cứu của bệnh viện. Sau khi thăm khám, bác sĩ ghi nhận sinh hiệu bình thường, trẻ không khó thở, cảm thấy nuốt vướng và đau.Lúc này, bác sĩ T. dặn trẻ ngồi chờ và liên hệ bác sĩ tai mũi họng nội soi gắp xương cho bé. Khoảng 5 phút sau, khi bác sĩ T. đang ngồi xem phim CT và X-quang của các trường hợp cấp cứu khác (nhiều trường hợp cấp cứu), đột nhiên một người tự xưng là bố của bé gái đi vào la hét.Tuy bác sĩ có giải thích về tình trạng của bé nhưng người này \\"không đồng ý chờ đợi\\", bất ngờ xông vào hành hung, đẩy bác sĩ vào tường, bóp cổ và quay clip. Thấy vậy, các đồng nghiệp đã kéo ra nhưng người này quyết xông lên hành hung tiếp, bảo vệ bệnh viện sau đó có mặt can ngăn.","answer":"Người đàn ông hành hung bác sĩ bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định có dấu hiệu của hành vi chống người thi hành công vụ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'biawak kudung masuk kampung'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tersesat ke kampung musuh atau pencuri yang dikenali oleh orang ramai"},{"question":"Burburkii dimoqraadiyada somaaliya7- LA WAREEGII HANTIDII GAARKA AHEYD IYO BARA KICII GANACSATADA. ","answer":"Burburkii dimoqraadiyada somaaliya7- LA WAREEGII HANTIDII GAARKA AHEYD IYO BARA KICII GANACSATADA. Markii aan qaadaney xoriyada dadku waxey bilaabeen iney ganacsi ka shaqeystaan iydoo wax dhib ah lagu heyn ilaa cashuurta dowlada mooyee, ganacsatadu waxey dibada la lahaayeen xiriir ganacsi oo damaanad leh,maal gashi ayey bilaabeen iyagoo shirkado caalami ah ku xiran, noloshu wey kala socotey meeshaad tagto somaliya oo dhan waxaad u baahato waad ka heleysey iyda oo sicir jaban oo macquul ah. Shirkado waaweyn oo dad Somali ah ku xiran ama doowlado la galey hishiis ayaa jirey waxoodana xor u ah, qofka soomaliga ah ee awoodo waxey siin jiree n sida bangiyada deymo uu qofku wax ku qabsadoin yar buu bishiina iska bixin jirey,waxaa kaloo jirey kuwo ku siinaayo qalabka beeraha ama gaari ama makiinadaha saliida sidoo kale in yar ayey bishii iska bixin jireen taasoo nolosha qofka u fududeyn jirtey in uu noloshiisa horomariyo wadankana horomariyo, waayo ganacsatadu waa lafdhabarka dalka, dalkasta oo horomara wuxuu la tashi la sameyaa ganacsatada iyadoo loo sameynayo nidaam aan wax udhimeyn waxna aysan ku dulmeynin. Iyada oo niyada dadku ay kor u sii kaceysey ayaa 21 oct 1969 waxaa xukunkii dalka la wareegey saraakiishii oct,waxeyna mudo yar ka dib iyagoo caga dhigan soo saareen wareegto lagu qarameynayo hantida gaarka ah, iyagoo iloobey in a xoog ku yimaadeen oo aan heysan codka dadka ganacsatada iyoshirkadaha caalamka ee aaminey ayeey ku fududaadeen go,aankaas waxeyna dhalisey in ganacsato badan bara kacaan wixii hanti dibada u yaalayna ey joojiyaan taasina markiiba waxaa laga dareemey dalka dhaqaalihiisii iyo noloshii dadka, waxana bilaabatey in la waayo waxyaalihii daruuriga ahaa iyo in ey dadku waxa ay hore u arki jirin la kulmaan ilaa iyo waqtigii nolosho ka bilaabatey soomaaliya, waxaa la yaab noqotey sida soomaliya oo ah wadan dhinaca beeraha Burburkii dimoqraadiyada somaaliya illaah dhul wanaagsan ugu deeqey ay dadku saf u galaan saliid baraamiil ku jirto oo nooceedu wanaagsaneyn iyo sonkor madow iyadoo wadanka ay ku taal warshada sokorta jowhar. "},{"question":"Tôi đang có bầu 4 tháng, tôi muốn tranh thủ trong lúc nghỉ sinh cháu đi mổ cận để có thời gian nghỉ ngơi cho mắt không làm việc với máy tính và điện thoại có được không ạ? Xin cho tôi lời khuyên.","answer":"Bạn nên đợi sau cai sữa, khi mà nội tiết tố sẽ trở lại bình thường, độ cận ổn định, bạn có thể mổ cận."},{"question":"අප්‍රිකාවේ ඉතිහාසය ගැන කෙටි විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"හෝමෝ සැපියානුවන් නැගෙනහිර අප්‍රිකාවෙහි පළමු පහලවීම පෙන්නුම් කිරීමත් සමග ඇරඹෙන අප්‍රිකාවේ ඉතිහාසය, වර්තමානය දක්වා පැවතඑන්නේ ප්‍රකීර්ණක සහ දේශපාලනමය ලෙසින් ප්‍රවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින ජාතික රාජ්‍යයන් මාලාවක ඇටවුමක් ලෙසිනි.උප-සහරානු අප්‍රිකාවෙහි විශාල කොටස් වලදී මුහුණදීමට සිදුව ඇති ලිඛිත මූලාශ්‍රයන්හී දුර්ලභත්වය හේතුවෙන් අප්‍රිකානු අධ්‍යයන ක්ෂේත්‍රයෙහි පර්යේෂකයන්හට අප්‍රිකාවේ ඉතිහාසය යන්න මහත් අභියෝගයක් බවට පත්ව ඇත. වාචික ඉතිහාසය ලේඛන ගතකිරීම, ඓතිහාසික වාග් විද්‍යාව, පුරා විද්‍යාව සහ ප්‍රවේණි විද්‍යාව වැනි ශාස්ත්‍රීය ශිල්පක්‍රම ඉතා වැදගත් වී ඇත.අප්‍රිකාවේ ඉතිහාසය නැගෙනහිර අප්‍රිකාවේ හෝමෝ සේපියන්ස් ගේ නැඟී ඒමත් සමඟ ආරම්භ වන අතර විවිධ හා දේශපාලනික වශයෙන් වර්ධනය වන ජාතික රාජ්‍යයන් රැසකගෙන් අණ්ඩ දමන ලද සිතියමක් සේ දිස්වන වර්තමානය දක්වා පැවතේ. ශිෂ්ටාචාරයේ  වාර්තාගත ඉතිහාසය ඇරඹෙන ලද්දේ කුෂ් රාජධානියේ තුළ වන අතර ඉන් පසුව පුරාණ මිසරය, සහේලය, මාඝ්‍රෙබ්, හා අප්‍රිකා ශෘංගය තුළ ද වේ. මධ්‍ය යුගයේ (ක්‍රි.ව. 5-15 සියවස්) දී, ඉස්ලාමය අරබියාවෙන් බටහිර දෙස ඊජීප්තුවටත් මාඝ්‍රෙබ් හා සහේලය දෙසටත් පැතිරුණි. යුරෝපීය යටත් විජිතකරණයට පෙර වැදගත් අප්‍රිකානු රාජ්‍යයන් අතර අජුරාන් අධිරාජ්‍ය, දා'අමත්, ඇඩල් සුල්තානය, වෝර්සැන්ගාලි සුල්තානය, න්රි (එරි?) රාජධානිය, නොක් සංස්කෘතිය, මාලි අධිරාජ්‍යය, සොන්ඝායි අධිරාජ්‍ය, අෂාන්තී අධිරාජ්‍යය,ඝානා අධිරාජ්‍යය, මොසි රාජධානි, මුතාපා අධිරාජ්‍යය, මපුන්ගුබ්වේ රාජධානිය, සයින් රාජධානිය, සෙන්නාර් රාජධානිය, සලූම් රාජධානිය, බෙයෝල් රාජධානිය, කෙයෝර් රාජධානිය, සිම්බාබ්වේ රාජධානිය, කොන්ගෝ රාජධානිය, කබූ අධිරාජ්‍යය, පුරාණ කාතේජය, නුමීදියාව, මෞරිටේනියාව, එක්සම් අධිරාජ්‍ය වේ.7 වන සියවස මැද සිට රාශිදුන් කලීෆය හා මකුරියා රාජධානිය අතර ක්‍රි.ව. 652 දී දෙවන දොන්ගෝලා සටනට පසුව ඇති වූ සටන් විරාමයෙන් පසුව අරාබි වහල් වෙළඳාමෙහි දී මුස්ලිම් අරාබීන් විසින් අප්‍රිකානුවන් වහල්ලු ලෙස අල්ලා ගන්නා ලදී. ආසියාතිකයින් හා යුරෝපීයයන් ද සමඟ ඔවුන් රතු මුහුද, ඉන්දියානු සාගරය, හා සහරා කතර හරහා ප්‍රවාහනය කරන ලදී.15 වන සියවස අග සිට, පෘතුගීසීන් අත්ලාන්තික වහල් වෙළඳාමේ කොටසක් වශයෙන් මුලින්ම වෙළඳාම හරහාත් පසුව බලහත්කාරයෙනුත් වහලුන් ලබා ගැනීමත් සමඟ යුරෝපීයයන් වහල් වෙළඳාමට එක් විය. ඔවුන් විසින් වහල් සේවයට අල්ලා ගන්නා ලද බටහිර, මධ්‍යම, හා දක්ෂිණ අප්‍රිකානුවන් එතෙර රටවලට ප්‍රවාහනය කරන ලදී.19 වන සියවස අග හා 20 සියවස මුල, අප්‍රිකාව සඳහා පොර වැදීමත් සමඟ අප්‍රිකාවේ යුරෝපීය යටත් විජිතකරණය සීඝ්‍රයෙන් දියුණු විය. යටත් විජිතකරණයට පෙර අප්‍රිකාවේ විශේෂ්‍ය භාෂා හා ගති පැවතුම් සහිත විවිධ රාජ්‍යයන් හා ස්වාධීන ඒකක 10,000ක් දක්වා පමණ තිබූ බව බොහෝ දෙනාගේ විශ්වාසයයි. නිදහස සඳහා මහාද්වීපයේ විවිධ පැතිවලින් ඇති වූ අරගලත් දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයෙන් පසු දුර්වල වූ යුරෝපයත් නිසා 1960 අප්‍රිකාවේ වර්ෂයෙන් සංක්‍රාන්තියට පැමිණි යටත් විජිතහරණය සිදු විය.මහාද්වීපයේ විශාල කොටසක ලිඛිත මූලාශ්‍ර හිඟ වීම හේතුවෙන්, විශේෂයෙන්ම වැදගත්ම ටිම්බක්ටූ අත්පිටපත් වලින් බොහොමයක් විනාශ වීම නිසා, අප්‍රිකානු අධ්‍යයන ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ අප්‍රිකාවේ ඉතිහාසය ගවේෂණය කිරීම අභියෝගාත්මක වී ඇත. එහි දී මුඛ ඉතිහාස වාර්තා, ඓතිහාසික වාග් විද්‍යාව, පුරාවිද්‍යාව, සහ ජාන විද්‍යාව වැනි උපක්ෂේත්‍රයන් තීරණාත්මක වේ."},{"question":"menene fi'ili?","answer":"fi’ili a hashen Hausa kalma ce ta aiki."},{"question":"Кызанак 🍅 (помидор) ыкмасы кандай иштейт?","answer":"Адам баласы жумуш аткарганда убактысын бөлүштүрүп жумуш жасаса мээ чаржайыт болуп чарчабайт 25 мүнөт иштеп алаксыбай 5 мүнөт эс алуу, 4 🍅 кайталагандан кийин 30 м эс алуу керек    25мүнөт.        5 м.     25 м.           5 м🍅---------🍅---🍅--------🍅---🍅    жумуш.       эс алуу    жумуш.     эс алуу                       🍅.                     🍅               30 м.                 30 м                               +                    60 м= 1 саат"},{"question":"إيش عاصمة المملكة ","answer":"الرياض"},{"question":"2013 ஆம் ஆண்டு சிட்னி அமைதி விருதை வென்றவர் யார்?","answer":"டாக்டர் சிந்தியா மாங் 2013 ஆம் ஆண்டு சிட்னி அமைதி விருதை வென்றவர்.பர்மாவின் மிகவும் பிரபலமான மருத்துவ மருத்துவர், டாக்டர் சிந்தியா மாங், 2013 சிட்னி அமைதிப் பரிசைப் பெறுவதற்காக ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்குச் சென்று நவம்பர் முதல் வாரத்தில் தனது கதையைச் சொன்னார்.சிந்தியா மாங் மற்றும் புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்கள். உள்நாட்டில் இடம்பெயர்ந்தவர்களுக்கு இலவச சுகாதார சேவைகளை வழங்கி வருகிறது மூன்று தசாப்தங்களாக தாய்-பர்மிய எல்லையில் உள்ள நபர்கள்மே தாவோ கிளினிக்கின் மருத்துவ மருத்துவர்.சமூகத் தலைமைக்கான தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியாவின் ரமோன் மகசேசே விருது மாங் பெற்றார். மொத்தத்தில் அவர் தனது பணிக்காக ஆறு சர்வதேச விருதுகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளார். 1999 ஆம் ஆண்டில், சுவிஸ் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க சுகாதார அமைப்புகளால் நிதியுதவி செய்யப்பட்ட ஜோனாதன் மான் விருது முதல் பெற்றவர்."},{"question":"బౌద్ధమత బోధనలను, భారత సమాజంపై వాటి ప్రభావాన్ని వర్ణించండి.","answer":"క్రీ.పూ. భారతదేశంలో జనించిన అనేక మతాలలో బౌద్ధమతం ఒకటి. దీని స్థాపకుడు గౌతమబుద్ధుడు. గౌతమబుద్ధుని జీవితం: గౌతమబుద్ధుని అసలు పేరు సిద్ధార్థుడు. ఇతడు క్రీ.పూ. 563వ సం||లో ‘శాక్య’ వంశమునకు చెందిన శుద్దోధనుడు, మాయాదేవీలకు లుంబినీవనమున జన్మించాడు. చిన్నతనమునే తల్లిని కోల్పోయి సవతి తల్లి ప్రజాపతి గౌతమిచే పెంచబడి ‘గౌతముడు’ అని పిలువబడ్డాడు. ఇతనికి ‘యశోధర’ అను రాకుమార్తెతో వివాహం జరిగింది. వారి కుమారుడు ‘రాహులుడు’.మహా పరిత్యాగము: సిద్ధార్థుడు తన 29వ ఏట ఒక ముదుసలిని, రోగిని, శవాన్ని, సన్యాసిని చూచి వైరాగ్యానికి లోనై సకల సంపదలను, భోగభాగ్యాలను, భార్యాబిడ్డలను వదిలి ఇల్లు విడిచి వెళ్ళాడు. ఈ సంఘటనతో అతని మనస్సు వికలమైంది. ప్రపంచమంతా దుఃఖమయమని, జీవితము అశాశ్వతమని గ్రహించి బవబంధములను తెంచుకొని అడవులకు వెళ్ళి సన్యసించాడు. ఈ సంఘటననే ‘మహా పరిత్యాగము’ లేక ‘మహాభినిష్క్రమణము’ అంటారు.జ్ఞానోదయమును పొందుట సన్యసించిన పిమ్మట సిద్ధార్థుడు సత్యాన్వేషణకై గయను చేరి అచ్చట ఒక అశ్వత్థ వృక్షము క్రింద 40 రోజులు ధ్యానము చేసి జ్ఞానమును పొందాడు. ఈ సంఘటనకే సంబోధి అని పేరు. అప్పటి నుండి సిద్ధార్థుడు బుద్ధుడు అని పిలువబడినాడు. బుద్ధుడు అనగా జ్ఞానము పొందినవాడు అని అర్ధము. బుద్ధుని శాక్యముని అని, తథాగతుడు అని పిలుస్తారు. నాటి నుండి అశ్వత్థ వృక్షము బోధి వృక్షముగాను, గయ బుద్ధగయగాను ప్రసిద్ధి చెందాయి.ధర్మచక్ర ప్రవర్తనము: బుద్ధుడు గయ నుండి సారనాథ్ చేరి సమీపమున గల జింకల తోటలో తన పూర్వ సహవాసులైన బ్రాహ్మణులకు మొదటిసారిగా తాను ఆర్జించిన జ్ఞానాన్ని ఉపదేశించాడు. ఈ సంఘటననే ధర్మచక్ర ప్రవర్తనము అంటారు. అప్పటి నుండి అనేక సంవత్సరములు బుద్ధుడు తన బోధనలను ప్రచారం చేశాడు. తన శిష్యులలో ప్రముఖులైన వారిని సంఘంలో ఏర్పరచాడు.నిర్వాణం: విస్తృతంగా బౌద్ధమతాన్ని ఉత్తరాపథమంతటా ప్రచారం చేసి బుద్ధుడు తన 80వ ఏట మల్ల రాజధానియైన కుశి నగరమున క్రీ.పూ. 483లో నిర్వాణం పొందాడు.బుద్ధుని బోధనలు: బుద్ధుని బోధనల ప్రకారం మానవ జీవితం కార్యకారణ సంబంధంతో ముడిపడి ఉన్నది. మానవుడు చేసిన కర్మఫలము వలననే ఈ శరీరము మరల మరల జన్మనెత్తవలసి వస్తున్నది. కర్మ ఆచరణకు కోర్కెలే మూలము. అజ్ఞానము వలన కోర్కెలు జనించుచున్నాయి. కోర్కెల వలన మానవుడు కర్మలు ఆచరిస్తాడు. ఈ కర్మ ఫలితమే పునర్జన్మ. పునర్జన్మలేని సుఖమైన, ప్రశాంతమైన జీవనమే నిర్వాణము అని బుద్ధుడు బోధించాడు. నిర్వాణ సాధనకు మానవుడు ఆర్య సత్యములను గ్రహించి అష్టాంగ మార్గమును, దశసూత్ర నీతిని పాటించవలెను.ఆర్య సత్యములు: గౌతమ బుద్ధుడు తన దివ్య పరిజ్ఞానము వలన నాలుగు ప్రధానమైన సత్యములను గ్రహించాడు. వీటినే ఆర్య సత్యములు అంటారు. అవి:ప్రపంచమంతా దుఃఖమయము.దుఃఖమునకు కారణము కోర్కెలు.దుఃఖమును అంతము చేయుటకు కోర్కెలను నిరోధించవలెను.కోర్కెలను నిరోధించుటకు అష్టాంగమార్గమును అవలంబించవలెను.అష్టాంగ మార్గము: నిర్వాణమును పొందుటకు మానవుడు తన నిత్య జీవితంలో ఈ అష్టాంగ మార్గమును అనుసరించిన చాలని బుద్ధుడు బోధించాడు. అవి: 1) సరియైన విశ్వాసము 2) సరియైన జ్ఞానము 3) సరియైన వాక్కు 4) సరియైన క్రియ 5) సరియైన జీవనము 6) సరియైన ప్రయత్నం 7) సరియైన ఆలోచన 8) సరియైన ధ్యానము. అష్టాంగ మార్గము ద్వారా ప్రతి వ్యక్తీ శీలసంపదను పెంపొందించుకొని జ్ఞాని కాగలడు. ఈ మార్గము అందరికీ అందుబాటులో ఉండుటచే దీనిని మధ్యేమార్గం అని అంటారు.దశసూత్ర నీతి: ఆర్యసత్యములు, అష్టాంగ మార్గములతోపాటు బుద్ధుడు పది అంశములు గల దశసూత్ర నీతిని ప్రబోధించాడు. ఈ సూత్రాలు:జీవహింస చేయరాదుఅసత్యమాడరాదు.దొంగతనము చేయరాదు.ఆస్తిపాస్తులు సమకూర్చుకొనరాదు.బ్రహ్మచర్యను పాటించవలెను.మత్తు పదార్దములు సేవించరాదు.పరుష వాక్యములు వాడరాదు.ఇతరుల ఆస్తులను కోరరాదు.అవినీతి పనులు చేయరాదు.విలాసాలను విడనాడాలి.నిర్వాణము: ఆర్యసత్యములను గ్రహించి, అష్టాంగ మార్గమును, దశసూత్ర నీతిని ఆదరించటం వలన మానవుడు మోక్షమును పొందుటకు అర్హుడవుతాడు. మోక్షమనగా పునర్జన్మలేని జన్మరాహిత్యము. దీనినే బుద్ధుడు నిర్వాణంగా పేర్కొన్నాడు. నిర్వాణ సాధనే ప్రతి వ్యక్తి ధ్యేయం కావలెను అని బుద్ధుడు బోధించాడు.బౌద్ధమతతత్వం: బుద్ధుడు భగవంతుని ఉనికిని గురించి, ఆత్మను గురించి మౌనం వహించాడు. హిందూమతమందలి కర్మ, పునర్జన్మ, మోక్ష సిద్ధాంతాలను అంగీకరించాడు. మహావీరుని వలె బుద్ధుడు కూడా యజ్ఞయాగాదులను, జంతుబలులను, బ్రాహ్మణుల ఆధికత్యను ఖండించాడు. వేదములను ప్రామాణిక గ్రంథములుగా బుద్ధుడు అంగీకరించాడు.ముగింపు: ప్రపంచమునకు శాంతి సందేశమునందించుటకు అవతరించిన మహాపురుషులలో సుప్రసిద్ధుడు గౌతమ బుద్ధుడు. కామ, క్రోధములతో, హింసాత్మక చర్యలతో కొట్టుమిట్టాడుతున్న మానవకోటిని ధర్మం, అహింస, కరుణ, మానవత అనే మహోన్నత ఆశయాలతో తీర్చిదిద్దుటకు అవతరించిన పుణ్య పురుషుడు. అందువల్లనే ఆసియా జ్యోతియని, ప్రపంచ జ్యోతియని శ్లాఘించబడ్డాడు."},{"question":"செயற்கைக் கோள் ஏவு ஊர்தியில் பொருந்தும் செயலியைப் பற்றி திரு. சிவன் கூறுவது யாது?","answer":"டாக்டர். கே. சிவன், விண்வெளித் துறையின் செயலாளராகவும், விண்வெளி ஆணையத்தின் தலைவராகவும், இந்திய விண்வெளி ஆராய்ச்சி மையத்தின் (ISRO) தலைவராகவும் ஜனவரி 2018 முதல் ஜனவரி 2022 வரை பணியாற்றினார்.அவர் 6D டிராஜெக்டரி சிமுலேஷன் மென்பொருளான  ‘SITARA’ இன் தலைமை வடிவமைப்பாளர் ஆவார், இது அனைத்து இஸ்ரோ ஏவுகணை வாகனங்களின் நிகழ்நேர மற்றும் நிகழ்நேரம் அல்லாத பாதை உருவகப்படுத்துதல்களின் முதுகெலும்பாக உள்ளது. அனைத்து இஸ்ரோ ஏவுகணை வாகனங்களிலும் பணி வடிவமைப்பு, துணை அமைப்பு நிலை சரிபார்ப்பு மற்றும் ஏவியோனிக்ஸ் அமைப்புகளின் ஒருங்கிணைந்த சரிபார்ப்பு ஆகியவற்றிற்குப் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் பணி தொகுப்பு மற்றும் பகுப்பாய்வுக்காக இஸ்ரோவில் உலகத் தரமான உருவகப்படுத்துதல் வசதியை இயக்குவதற்கு அவர் பொறுப்பேற்றார். பல்வேறு வானிலை மற்றும் காற்று நிலைகளின் கீழ், எந்த நாளிலும் ராக்கெட் ஏவுவதற்கு உதவும் ஒரு புதுமையான 'ஏவுதலின் நாள் காற்று சார்பு உத்தி'யை அவர் உருவாக்கி செயல்படுத்தினார். பிஎஸ்எல்வியின் ஒரே விண்ணில் 104 செயற்கைக்கோள்களை வெற்றிகரமாக விண்ணில் செலுத்தியதற்காக அவர் தலைமை பணி வடிவமைப்பாளராக இருந்தார்."},{"question":"Сахара чөлү жөнүндө маалымат бере аласыңбы?","answer":"“Сахара” арабдардын сөзү, бизче которгондо чөл дегенди билдирет. Сахара – Түндүк Африкадан орун алган планетабыздагы эң чоң чөл. Жалпы аянты 8,6 миллион чарчы чакырым. Сахара 11 өлкөнүн (Алжир, Египет, Батыш Сахара, Ливия, Мали, Марокко, Нигер, Судан, Тунис, Чад) айрым аянтын өз кучагына камтыйт. Чөлдүн оазистүү аймактарын гана эл турактап, көз кайкыткан калган бөлүктөрү ээн жатат. Африкадагы кээ бир элдер Сахараны кумдуу деңиз деп да аташат. Чөлдүн аймагынан мунайзат, газ, темир, жез, алтын, вольфрам, уран жана башкалар өндүрүлөт."},{"question":"شنو هي القارة الوحيدة اللي ما فيهاش طائر النحام؟","answer":"أستراليا"},{"question":"Menene yawan jama'ar Vietnam a cikin shekara ta 2020?","answer":"Yawan jama'ar ya kai miliyan 97.34"},{"question":"రాటిటే పక్షుల విలక్షణ లక్షణాలను తెలపండి. రెండు ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"రాటిటే/పేలియోనేతె/ఎగరలేని పక్షులు :ఇవి పరిగెత్తే, ఎగరలేని ఆధునిక పక్షులు. ఇవి డిప్నాయ్ (ఊపిరితిత్తి చేపలు), మార్సూపియల్స్ లాగా విచ్ఛిన్న విస్తరణను ప్రదర్శిస్తాయి. వీటిలో రెక్కలు క్షీణించి, ఉరోస్థి ద్రోణి లేకుండా తెప్పలాగా ఉంటుంది. మగ పక్షులలో మేహనం ఉంటుంది. వీటిలో శబ్దిని, జత్రుకలు మరియు ప్రీన్ గ్రంథి ఉండదు.ఉదా : స్ట్రుతియో కామిలస్ (ఆఫ్రికన్ ఆస్ట్రిచ్), కివి (న్యూజిలాండ్ జాతీయపక్షి), రియా (అమెరికన్ ఆస్ట్రిచ్), డ్రోమియస్ (ఇము), కాసువారియస్."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'getikkan puru di bibir'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tidak dapat membenci anak isteri (keluarga) yang buruk kelakuannya"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Mới đây, một đơn vị chuyên nhập khẩu siêu xe nổi tiếng tại Việt Nam đã chia sẻ hình ảnh về chiếc xe thể thao hạng sang Aston Martin Vantage 007 Edition, đặc biệt hơn đây là phiên bản số sàn chỉ có 25 xe trên toàn thế giới. So với Aston Martin Vantage bản tiêu chuẩn, phiên bản Vantage 007 Edition có khác biệt ở thiết kế như bên sườn xe có dấu hiệu nhận biết của bộ phận cá nhân hóa của Aston Martin, lưới tản nhiệt với nẹp viền bằng crôm và logo Vantage in nghiêng, mâm xe thiết kế khác biệt so với bản tiêu chuẩn. Đằng sau xe Aston Martin Vantage phiên bản 007 Edition có ống xả kép thay cho ống xả đơn của bản thường và quan trọng là xe có sẵn trang bị ván trượt tuyết cũng như khung cố định giá trượt tuyết, nếu cảm thấy vướng, chủ xe hoàn toàn có thể tháo rời, để ở nhà hoặc khoang hành lý xe. Các chi tiết được hoàn thiện màu vàng ở cánh lướt gió bên hông cũng là đặc điểm thiết kế riêng của phiên bản này. Bên trong, nội thất sở hữu logo 007 đặc biệt ở bảng điều khiển trung tâm cũng như được dập nổi trên lưng ghế. Con số đặc biệt \\"96.50\\" trên che nắng tượng trưng cho tần số radio FM mà James Bond đã dùng để tẩu thoát khỏi cảnh sát Nga. Aston Martin Vantage trang bị động cơ","answer":"V8, dung tích 4.0L tăng áp kép do Mercedes-AMG phát triển và sản xuất, cho công suất cực đại 503 mã lực và mô-men xoắn cực đại 685 Nm. Phiên bản này được trang bị tùy chọn hộp số sàn và cả hộp số tự động 8 cấp. Vantage có khả năng tăng tốc lên 100 km/h trong 3,6 giây trước khi đạt vận tốc tối đa 313 km/h. Tùy chọn hộp số sàn 7 cấp sẽ do Graziano chế tạo, được sắp xếp theo dạng chữ H cho số 1 trong khi số 2 đến số 7. Đi cùng hộp số sàn mới là công nghệ AMSHIFT của hãng siêu xe Anh Quốc, giống với công nghệ từng có mặt trên Vantage AMR. Hệ thống này sẽ sử dụng bộ ly hợp, vị trí răng số và cảm biến trục đỡ để tạo ra khả năng vào số mượt hơn mà không đòi hỏi quá nhiều kỹ năng đến từ người lái. CAMSHIFT cũng cho phép người lái chuyển số ở tốc độ cao mà không cần phải bỏ chân ga khi vào côn. Xe sở hữu nhiều công nghệ hiện đại hỗ trợ người lái như hệ thống kiểm soát ổn định chủ động DSC và điều biến véc-tơ mô-men xoắn DTV, hệ thống treo giảm chấn thích ứng chủ động ADS Bilstein DampTronic tích hợp công nghệ Skyhook cho phép tùy chỉnh 3 chế độ vận hành: Sport (thể thao), Sport Plus (hiệu năng cao) và Track (đường đua). Số tiền để sở hữu xe Aston Martin Vantage 007 Edition phiên bản số sàn tại thị trường Việt Nam hiện chưa công bố nhưng tại thị trường nước ngoài, phiên bản giới hạn Aston Martin Vantage 007 Edition có giá từ 161.000 bảng Anh (khoảng 4,9 tỉ đồng), cao hơn gần 600 triệu đồng so với bản tiêu chuẩn. Theo Thục Anh (Công Lý) https://congly.vn/aston-martin-vantage-007-edition-so-san-ve-viet-nam-211208.html Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS"},{"question":"सर आइजेक न्यूटन ","answer":"सर आइजेक न्यूटन एक महान भौतिकविद्, गणितज्ञ, र वैज्ञानिक हुन्। उनीले सप्तदशीं शताब्दीमा बिग्यान र गणितमा अनेक महत्वपूर्ण संशोधनहरू गरेका थिए।न्यूटनले \\"ग्रेभिटेशनल फोर्स\\" विषयमा अपनाएको सिद्धान्तले उनलाई विश्वमा मशहूर बनाएको छ। उनको \\"न्यूटनको नियमहरू\\" फिजिक्समा महत्वपूर्ण मानिन्छन् र इन्हाले गणित, भौतिकशास्त्र, अभियान्त्रिकी, खगोलशास्त्र र अन्य क्षेत्रहरूमा पनि महत्वपूर्ण योगदान प्रदान गरेका छन्।उनीले ग्रेविटेशन, आवर्तन, प्रकाशका किरणहरू, वेग, बल, आदि जस्ता महत्वपूर्ण अवधारणाहरू विकसित गरेका थिए।सर आइजेक न्यूटनले प्रसिद्ध \\"प्रत्येक कार्यलाई एक उत्कृष्ट कारणले व्याख्यान गर्ने\\" मन्त्रलाई अपनाउनुभयो।उनीले अपना योगदानले मानवताको विज्ञान र प्रौद्योगिकीलाई आगामी समयमा पनि प्रभावित गरेका छन्।"},{"question":"Firefox 浏览器有什么特点？","answer":"答：Firefox 浏览器以其速度快、安全性高和对隐私保护的重视而闻名。它支持多种网页标准，包括 HTML5 和 CSS3，并且具有强大的扩展插件支持。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਸਿਮਰਤ ਨਾਮੁ ਰਿਦੈ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਭਗਤਂੀ ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਇਆ ॥ਸੰਤਸੰਗਿ ਮਿਲਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਜਪਿਆ ਬਿਨਸੇ ਆਲਸ ਰੋਗਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੧॥ਜਾ ਕੈ ਗ੍ਰਿਹਿ ਨਵ ਨਿਧਿ ਹਰਿ ਭਾਈ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਜਿਸੁ ਪੁਰਬ ਕਮਾਈ ॥ਗਿਆਨ ਧਿਆਨ ਪੂਰਨ ਪਰਮੇਸੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਭਨਾ ਗਲਾ ਜੋਗਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੨॥ਖਿਨ ਮਹਿ ਥਾਪਿ ਉਥਾਪਨਹਾਰਾ ॥ਆਪਿ ਇਕੰਤੀ ਆਪਿ ਪਸਾਰਾ ॥ਲੇਪੁ ਨਹੀ ਜਗਜੀਵਨ ਦਾਤੇ ਦਰਸਨ ਡਿਠੇ ਲਹਨਿ ਵਿਜੋਗਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੩॥ਅੰਚਲਿ ਲਾਇ ਸਭ ਸਿਸਟਿ ਤਰਾਈ ॥ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਉ ਆਪਿ ਜਪਾਈ ॥ਗੁਰ ਬੋਹਿਥੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤੇ ਨਾਨਕ ਧੁਰਿ ਸੰਜੋਗਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੪॥੪੧॥੪੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 108 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਭਗਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ ਕੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਿਆ ।(ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਭਗਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ) ਪਰਗਟ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਸਦਾ ਹਰੀ-ਨਾਮ ਜਪਿਆ, ਉੇਸ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਆਲਸ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਗ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਏ ।੧।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਜਿਸ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਨੌ ਹੀ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਹਰੀ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ) ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਜਨਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਕੀਤੀ ਨੇਕ ਕਮਾਈ ਦੇ ਸੰਸਕਾਰ ਜਾਗ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ।ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪੂਰਨ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪੂਰਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੁੜੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਯਕੀਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਸਭ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਸਮਰਥਾ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ। ੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ) ਰਚ ਕੇ ਇਕ ਖਿਨ ਵਿਚ (ਇਸ ਨੂੰ) ਨਾਸ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਭੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਨਿਰਗੁਣ-ਸਰੂਪ ਹੋ ਕੇ) ਇਕੱਲਾ (ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ) ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪੇ ਤੋਂ ਸਰਗੁਣ ਰੂਪ ਧਾਰ ਕੇ) ਜਗਤ‑ਰਚਨਾ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਨੂੰ, ਜਗਤ-ਦੇ-ਜੀਵਨ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ । ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦਰਸਨ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਵਿਛੋੜੇ ਲਹਿ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ ਵਿਛੋੜਾ ਪਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਮਨ ਤੋਂ ਲਹਿ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ)।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ) ਪੱਲੇ ਲਾ ਕੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ) ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਨੂੰ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ॥ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ) ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਮ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਜਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਧੁਰ-ਦਰਗਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਦੇ ਸਬਬ ਬਣਨ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਗੁਰੂ-ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੪੧।੪੮।\\""},{"question":"Maro ireo tanora manana diplaoma nefa mitaingi-tamboha , tokony mbola anohy hianatra ve izaho sa hiasa amin'izay, Valio Eny na Tsia ?","answer":"Eny , Tokony mbola hanohy fianarana izaho fa tsy maika amin'izany asa izany"},{"question":"Ma'anar  Hikaya?","answer":"Hikaya labari ne da ya shafi wasu mala’iku, da waliyyai. Hikaya a wasu lokutan kuma takan zama ƙagaggen labarin da abin da ke cikinsa zai iya faruwa, ko kuma labarin wani abin mamaki da ya faru da wani mutum.Hikaya ta bambanta da ƙissa saboda ita ƙissa annabawa zalla ta shafa. Sannan kuma ta bambanta da almara (labarin da aka ƙaga kenan), saboda abin da labarin ke ɗauke da shi zai iya faruwa ko kuma ma ya riga ya faru.Ana gina labarun hikaya a kan mutane, iskokai, rauhanai, dabbobi, tsuntsaye, da sauran halittu.Labarun hikaya cike suke da nishaɗi, da kuma darrusan da suka shafi rayuwa, a wasu lokutan sukan zamo gargaɗi saboda zuwan irin labarin nan na gani-ga-wane, ya ishi wane tsaoron Allah a cikinsu."},{"question":"Sheeg Cuduradda Ugu Caansan Ee La is Qaadsiiyo?","answer":"Waxaa Kamid Ah Cuduradda Ugu Caansan Ee La is Qaadsiiyo:-b) Kuwa Hawada La isuku Mariyo  Sida Hargabka, Burukiitada, Iyo Tiibishada.t) Kuwa Galmada Lagu Kala Qaado Sida Isfiilitada, Jabtada, Iyo Aydhiska (AIDS).j) Kuwa Lagu Kala Qaado Cuntada Iyo Biyaha Wasakheysan Sida Daacuunka Iyo Tiifowga.x) Kuwa Cayayaanka U Kala Gudbiyo Sida Duumada Ay Soo Gudbiso Kaneecada."},{"question":"Gawea ringkesan nganggo loro (2) ukara berdasar artikel ing ngisor iki:  Squats utawa jongkok beban iku minangka latihan kekuatan sing ngedhunake pinggul saka posisi ngadeg lan banjur ngadeg maneh. Sajrone mudhun, sendi pinggul lan dhengkul dilenturna nalika sendi tungkak dorsofleksi; Sendi pinggul lan dhengkul dipanjangno lan plantarfleksi nalika ngadeg. Squats uga mbantu otot pinggul. Squats dianggep minangka latihan penting kanggo nambah kekuatan lan ukuran otot awak ngisor uga ngembangake kekuatan inti. Otot agonis utama sing digunakake nalika jongkok yaiku quadriseps femoris, adduktor magnus, lan gluteus maksimus. Jongkok uga secara isometris nggunakake erector spinae lan otot weteng. Squat iku minangka salah siji saka telung gerakan angkat ing olahraga angkat beban, bebarengan karo angkat beban dalam lan bangku beban. Iki uga dianggep minangka latihan pokok ing pirang-pirang program olahraga rekreasi populer.Ringkesan:","answer":"Squats (Jongkok Beban) minangka latihan kekuatan kanggo ningkatake kekuatan fisik, utamane otot tubuh bagian bawah, yaiku otot pinggul lan otot lutut. Gerakane squats iku utamane ngedhunake pinggul saka posisi ngadeg lan banjur ngadeg maneh tanpa cekelan alat peraga liyo. "},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga_\\"Ny teny toy ny _: raha foy manan’elatra.\\"","answer":"Ny teny toy ny atody: raha foy manan’elatra."},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： パンダのシャンシャン　最後の抽せんの申し込みが始まる","answer":"東京の上野動物園にいるパンダのシャンシャンは、今月21日に中国に返します。雌のシャンシャンは5歳で、赤ちゃんを産むぐらいの年になっています。上野動物園は、たくさんの人が見に来て混む心配があるため、先月から、シャンシャンを見る人を抽せんで決めています。そして3日、最後の2日間の抽せんの申し込みを始めました。今月18日と19日に見るための抽せんで、当たるのは1日に2600人までです。6日の午後1時まで、申し込むことができます。上野動物園で生まれたシャンシャンは、2歳になったら中国に返す予定でした。しかし、新型コロナウイルスが広がって、世話をする人が一緒に中国に行くことができないため、遅れていました。"},{"question":"Can you tell me the capital of Georgia?","answer":"Atlanta has been the capital of Georgia since 1868. It is the largest city in Georgia and the 9th largest metropolitan area in the United States. Atlanta is located in north-central Georgia at the Eastern Continental Divide. The capital of Georgia was previously Milledgeville. The post-war Constitutional Convention of 1867-68 voted to relocate the capital to Atlanta on a temporary basis. "},{"question":"Are entrepreneurs all business owners?","answer":"No, all business owners are not entrepreneurs."},{"question":"Pergunta: Qual dos impérios a seguir não possui um idioma escrito: Inca, Azteca, Egípcio ou Romano?","answer":"Inca"},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Keji)","answer":"Bi gbogbo aye ko ba ti i mọ ohun ti Gomina ipinlẹ Ekiti bayii, Ọmọwe Kayọde Fayẹmi, fẹẹ ṣe, ọkunrin naa ati awọn ti wọn sun mọ ọn yoo ti mọ lọkan ara wọn. Bi Fayẹmi ba fẹẹ di aarẹ Naijiria, yoo buru ṣa ko jẹ awọn Hausa ni yoo kọkọ maa sọ fun wa. Iyẹn to ba jẹ ohun to fẹẹ ṣe niyẹn o. Ṣugbọn ọrọ ti Sultan Ṣokoto ati Gomina ipinlẹ Kaduna, Nasir El-Rufai, sọ lọsẹ to kọja yii, ọrọ kan to ko awọn onilaakaye lọkan soke ni. El-Rufai lo pe Fayẹmi sibi ayẹyẹ ṣiṣi ile ikowee-pamọ-si kan ti wọn kọ ni orukọ Sardauna Sokoto tẹlẹ, Alaaji Ahamadu Bello. Nibẹ ni Fayẹmi ti jẹ alejo pataki, oun lo si sọrọ nibẹ. Bo ti sọrọ tan ni Sultan ni ọmọ kan ti Sultan bi sita ni Fayẹmi, awọn si ti gba a wọle gẹgẹ bii ọmọ baba awọn, iyẹn Ahamadu Bello. O ni gbogbo anfaani to ba tọ si ọmọ Ahmadu Bello ti tọ si Fayẹmi ni gbogbo ilẹ Hausa lati igba naa lọ. Nigba ti El-Rufai naa yoo si sọrọ, o ni ẹni to ba mọ awọn daadaa, yoo mọ pe awọn ki i deede peeyan wa si iru awujọ pataki bẹẹ. O ni o nidii pataki kan ti awọn fi pe Fayẹmi pe ko wa o, idi pataki naa yoo si han si gbogbo aye laipẹ jọjọ. Ko si idi pataki kan naa nibẹ ju pe wọn pe Fayẹmi ko maa bọ waa du ipo aarẹ Naijiria ni 2023 lọ. Wọn n sọ pe awọn fẹẹ kọyin si Tinubu, Fayẹmi to jẹ ọmọ awọn lawọn fẹẹ mu. Bi wọn ba ṣe eleyii, ko ha jẹ pe Fayẹmi yoo kọyin si ọga rẹ, wọn yoo si di ọta, o si ṣee ṣe ki ọrọ naa sọ ọ di ọta awọn ọmọ Yoruba mi-in. Ṣugbọn njẹ ohun ti wọn sọ pe awọn fẹẹ fun Fayẹmi yii le to o lọwọ ṣa. Awọn ti wọn ba Tinubu jẹ, ti wọn ba Tinubu mu, ti wọn leri fun un pe awọn yoo fun un ni nnkan, to waa di asiko yii, ti wọn ko fẹẹ fun un ni kinni ọhun mọ, ti wọn ni Fayẹmi lawọn fẹẹ fun, njẹ ki i ṣe ẹtan bayii bi o! Awọn yii kan naa ni wọn ba Abiọla jẹ, ti wọn ba a mu, ti wọn ni awọn yoo fun un ni nnkan, nigba ti asiko to, wọn ko fun un ni kinni naa mọ o. Ileri ti Fulani ba ṣe nidii oṣelu ati ipo agbara ko to o tẹle o, nitori ẹ, ki Kayọde Fayẹmi fẹsọ ṣe.Awọn wo ni wọn n tan Jẹgẹdẹ bayii na?Kaka ki Eyitayọ Jẹgẹdẹ ko iwọnba owo to ba ku lọwọ ẹ lẹyin inawo rẹpẹtẹ to ṣe lori idibo ipinlẹ Ọndo jọ, ko maa fi ṣe aye ẹ, ọkunrin naa ti tun gba awọn kan laaye lati maa tan oun, o loun n lọ sile-ẹjọ, ojooro nibo ti wọn di to gbe Rotimi Akeredolu wọle. Ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP ni Jẹgẹdẹ, orukọ ẹgbẹ naa lo si fi du ipo gomina, ṣugbọn ko wọle. Koda, Ajayi to n ṣe igbakeji gomina lọwọlọwọ, toun naa lọ si inu ẹgbẹ oṣelu mi-in, ko wọle bakan naa, Akeredolu ti APC lo wọle. Ọpọlọpọ nnkan ni yoo mu Akeredolu wọle, akọkọ ni pe oun ni gomina to wa ni ipinlẹ naa lọwọlọwọ, ẹẹkeji si ni pe ẹgbẹ oṣelu wọn, APC, lo n ṣẹjọba apapọ. Ọpọ agbara lo wa lọwọ Akeredolu ati ẹgbẹ oṣẹlu rẹ, ohun to si jẹ ko wọle naa niyẹn. Jẹgẹdẹ gbiyanju, nitori oun naa ni ibo to pọ daadaa. Boya ka ni ko si ija ninu PDP, tabi ko jẹ Ajayi Agboọla to kọkọ wa si ọdọ wọn duro sibẹ ni, o ṣee ṣe ki Jẹgẹdẹ wọlẹ. Ṣugbọn ọro ti ri bo ti ri, koda, awọn ọlọgbọn inu PDP mọ pe ko si bi Jẹgẹdẹ ti ṣe fẹẹ wọle. Bi ibo ba waye bayii to si lọ, ohun to maa n dara fun ẹni to ba kuna ni lati fọwọsọwọ pẹlu ẹni to ba wọle, iyẹn to ba ṣe pe ire ipinlẹ wọn lawọn mejeeji jọ n wa. Ohun ti yoo mu ilọsiwaju ba ipinlẹ naa niyẹn. Nidii eyi, ko si ohun to yẹ ki Jẹgẹdẹ wa gba ile-ẹjọ lọ, to ba jẹ loootọ, ire ati daadaa ipinlẹ Ondo lo n wa. Eyi to fẹẹ ṣe yii, wọn yoo tubọ tun bẹrẹ si i ko ọkan awọn eeyan ibẹ soke lasan ni, bẹẹ ni ijọba ko si ni i roju raaye lati ṣe awọn ohun to yẹ ko ṣe. Nigbẹyin, Jẹgẹdẹ yoo pada ja bọ naa ni, ki waa ni anfaani iko-araalu-lọkan-soke yii si. Bẹ ẹ ba ri Jẹgẹdẹ, ẹ sọ fun un ko ma fi akoko ati owo ẹ ṣofọ, ko jokoo jẹẹ jare.Mojisọla, aṣofin Eko, alasọjaamuLara ohun ti ko dara to n ṣẹlẹ si wa ni Naijiria, ati ni ipinlẹ rẹ gbogbo ni yiyan awọn eeyan ti wọn ko kun oju oṣuwọn si ipo giga. Ohun to maa n ṣẹlẹ ni pe ko si bi ipo naa ti le ga to, awọn eeyan yii yoo mu ipo naa wa silẹ ni, nipa ọrọ to ba n ti ẹnu wọn jade, ati iwa ti wọn ba n hu si araalu. Orukọ aṣofin to n ṣoju wọn ni agbegbe Amuwo Ọdọfin ni Mojisọla Alli-Macauley. Nigba tọrọ wahala to ṣẹlẹ lọsẹ to lọ lọhun-un di ohun ti wọn n jiroro nileegbimọ aṣofin, ọrọ to tẹnu aṣofin yii jade lo ku ti gbogbo aye n gbe kiri. O ni awọn ọdọ ti wọn n pariwo kiri yii, ọpọlọpọ wọn lo jẹ oogun oloro ni wọn n mu kiri, ki wọn mu igbo, ki wọn mu kokeeni, lo ba aye wọn jẹ, ki i ṣe nitori pe wọn ko niṣẹ lọwọ. O ni ki i ṣe Naijiria nikan ni awọn ọdọ wọn ko ti nisẹ lọwọ, arun to n ṣe wọn ni Naijiria yii naa n ṣe wọn l’Amẹrika, awọn ọmọ wọn ko si tori ẹ ya pooki sigboro, igbo lo n daamu awọn ọmọ tiwa nibi. Ọrọ yii bi gbogbo eeyan ninu, paapaa awọn ọdọ, wọn si sọrọ si obinrin naa daadaa. Ṣe ki i ṣe pe oun nikan lo wa nile-igbimọ, o kan jẹ oun lọrọ to sọ buru ju ni, ti ko si ba ọrọ tawọn eeyan n sọ nipa awọn ọdọ wa mu. Amẹrika tabi ilu oyinbo ti oun n sọ pe awọn ọmọ ti ko niṣẹ naa wa nibẹ, lọdọ tiwọn, ọmọ ti ko ba ni iṣẹ lọwọ rara, ijọba wọn niye ti wọn n ṣeto fun un ti yoo maa na, ti ko fi ni i huwa ti ko dara nigboro. Bakan naa ni ijọba maa n fun wọn ni ounjẹ, oloṣelu kan ko si ni i ko ounjẹ naa pamọ. Ni asiko arun Korona, awọn kan gbe aworan ounjẹ ti wọn fun awọn ara Amuwo-Ọdọfin jade, ṣugbọn to jẹ niṣe ni aṣofin yii ko o pamọ, to waa fi ṣe ẹbun fawọn eeyan lasiko ayẹyẹ ọjọọbi rẹ. Ọrọ ti Mojisọla sọ fi han bii ẹni ti ko mọ ohun to n lọ nipa awọn ọdọ wa, kaka ko si gbẹnu dakẹ, ohun to sọ si wọn ko daa, nitori o ni amugbo ni wọn. Ojuṣe oloṣelu ni lati ṣoju awọn eeyan rẹ, eeyan ko si le jẹ aṣoju awọn eeyan ti ko ba mọ tabi ti ko mọ ohun to n yọ wọn lẹnu. Mojisọla yii ko mọ ohun to n yọ awọn ọdọ lẹnu, ko si yẹ ko wa niru ile-igbimọ to wa yii, awọn to yan an sibẹ ko ṣe daadaa. Ki wọn tete pe e pada, ko loo kọ nipa iwa awọn ọdọ adugbo rẹ ati ti Naijiria, lẹyin naa, ko waa pada wa sileegbimọ aṣofin. Titi igba naa, orukọ ti wọn yoo maa pe e ni Mojisọla alasọjaamu!Ohun to ṣẹlẹ l’Ogbomọṣọ yii ko daaNigba ti awọn ti wọn n ṣe iwọde SARS kọ lu aafin Ajagungbade, Ṣọun Ogbomọṣọ lọsẹ to lo lọhun-un, Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde debẹ ba wọn daro, o si ṣe ileri pe ijọba oun yoo fun wọn ni miliọnu lọna ọgọrun-un Naira, ki wọn le fi tun aafin naa ṣe. Gbogbo eeyan lo patẹwọ fun gomina, inu ọba funra rẹ si dun. Ṣugbọn ko ju ọjọ mẹta kan lọ lẹyin ẹ ti iwe kan jade lati aafin ọba yii, nibi ti wọn ti sọ pe Ṣọun loun ko gba owo mọ, oun ko fẹ owo Makinde, ninu ọgọrun-un miliọnu to fẹẹ foun, ko kuku foun ni miliọnu mẹwaa pere, ko fi eyi to ku tun aye awọn ara ipinlẹ Ọyọ ṣe. Dajudaju, bi lẹta naa ti jade, o ti han pe ọwọ awọn oloṣelu wa nibẹ, ati pe wọn fẹẹ fi kinni naa da yẹyẹ gomina wọn silẹ ni. Ko pẹ rara ti eyi fi foju han daadaa, nitori Ṣọun funra ẹ jade, o ni oun ko mọ kinni kan nipa lẹta naa awọn ti wọn fẹẹ da wahala silẹ lo gbe e jade. Ṣugbọn lẹta naa, wọn fi iwe Ọba Ajagungade kọ ọ, wọn si fi orukọ ati adirẹsi aafin rẹ si i. Nidii eyi, o ṣoro ki ẹnikẹni too sọ pe lẹta naa ko wa lati aafin Ṣọun. Ṣugbọn ọba naa ni ki i ṣe ọdọ toun o. Bo ba ri bẹẹ, a jẹ awọn eeyan kan ti wọn n fi eto idagbasoke Ogbomọṣọ ṣe oṣelu ni wọn wa nidii ẹ, eleyii ko si daa. Ko daa nitori pe ki i ṣe gbogbo gomina ni yoo wa si Ogbomọṣọ lati waa fun wọn lowo fi tun aafin ṣe, awọn gomina mi-in n bọ ti wọn ko ni i mọ aafin Ogbomọṣọ, ti ohun yoowu to ba si ṣe wọn nibẹ ko ni i kan wọn rara. Eyi lo ṣe jẹ ohun yoowu ti wọn ba ri lọwọ gomina yii, ki wọn gba a lati tun ibẹ ṣe. Ati pe awọn ti wọn fi ọrọ yii ṣe oṣelu yii gbọdọ mọ pe owo naa ki i ṣe eyi ti wọn fẹẹ ko fun Ṣọun, owo ti wọn fẹẹ fi tun aafin ṣe ni, bi wọn ba si ṣe e daadaa, aafin naa yoo dapewo fun gbogbo aye. Bi wọn ba tun aafin yii ṣe daadaa, ti wọn tun awọn ohun iṣẹnbaye ibẹ ṣe, ki i ṣe Ajagungbade yii nikan ni yoo wa fun, gbogbo ẹni to ba jẹ Ṣọun ni. Ki waa ni wọn yoo fi ẹtanu ati oṣelu ba iru eyi jẹ si. Ohun ti ko dara leleyii, bii igba ti a n di ara ẹni lọwọ ni. Ẹ ma fi oṣelu, tabi ẹtanu, di eto idagbasoke lọwọ nibikibi nilẹ Yoruba, ohun to ṣẹlẹ l’Ogbomọṣọ yii ko daa!Dapọ Abiọdun ṣeun ṣeunNibi ti awọn gomina mi-in ṣi ti n pariwo ko ni i ṣee ṣe, awọn o le ṣe e, ati awọn ariwo mi-in bẹẹ, Gomina ipinlẹ Ogun, Dapọ Abiọdun, ti bẹrẹ si i san owo-oṣu tuntun fun awọn oṣiṣẹ ipinlẹ naa o. Awọn ti wọn gba owo tiwọn ni ipari oṣu kẹwaa yii kan ri i pe owo awọn ti le si i ni, ati pe owo oṣu tuntun lawọn gba. Eleyii daa gan-an ni, nitori ko si ẹni to gba a ti ko ni i rẹrin-in, tabi ti inu rẹ ko ni i dun si gomina wọn. Nnkan ti bajẹ ju, ọrọ naa ko si rọrun fun awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba rara. Ohun to ṣẹlẹ naa ni pe gbogbo ọja lo gbowo lori pata, ko si si ọna mi-in ti wọn yoo fi ṣe aye wọn pẹlu owo-oṣu to kere ti wọn n gba yii, afi ki ijọba funra ẹ ṣe atunṣe si owo wọn. Ohun ti ariwo ṣe wa niluu tẹlẹ ree, ti awọn mi-in si sọ pe awọn ko ni i ṣiṣẹ bi ijọba ko ba sanwo oṣu tuntun fawọn. Awọn gomina mi-in ti gba, awọn mi-in ṣi n ṣe agidi. Ninu awọn ti wọn gba paapaa, wọn ko ti i san an, wọn n fonii donii, fọla dọla ni. Eyi lo ṣe yẹ keeyan gboriyin fun Dapọ Abiọdun nipinlẹ Ogun, ọkan ninu awọn akọkọ gomina ti yoo sanwo oṣu tuntun. Kawọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba to ku pata yaa fara we e o, ki nnkan le daa yikayika fawọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba gbogbo."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Dalam banyak-banyak kereta, kereta apa yang tak ada tayar?","answer":"Jawapan : Kereta kabel"},{"question":"Редиф деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Редиф (араб тилинен -артынан келүүчү) - ыр сабындагы уйкаштыктан кийин келүүчү сөздөр жана сөз айкаштары. Мисалы:Суусамырдын сазындай,Былкылдаган сен кимсиң?Жинди болгон эмедей,Шылкылдаган сен кимсиң?Айылчылап күнүгө,Бир тынбаган сен кимсиң?Ашта-тойдо кууланып,Култулдаган сен кимсиң?Анык жинди болгондой,Жулкулдаган сен кимсиң?Атчан жүрсөң, жөө жүрсөң,Бир тынбаган сен кимсиң? (Калык Акиев)."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਨੀਕੀ ਕੀਰੀ ਮਹਿ ਕਲ ਰਾਖੈ ॥ਭਸਮ ਕਰੈ ਲਸਕਰ ਕੋਟਿ ਲਾਖੈ ॥ਜਿਸ ਕਾ ਸਾਸੁ ਨ ਕਾਢਤ ਆਪਿ ॥ਤਾ ਕਉ ਰਾਖਤ ਦੇ ਕਰਿ ਹਾਥ ॥ਮਾਨਸ ਜਤਨ ਕਰਤ ਬਹੁ ਭਾਤਿ ॥ਤਿਸ ਕੇ ਕਰਤਬ ਬਿਰਥੇ ਜਾਤਿ ॥ਮਾਰੈ ਨ ਰਾਖੈ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥ਸਰਬ ਜੀਆ ਕਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਸੋਇ ॥ਕਾਹੇ ਸੋਚ ਕਰਹਿ ਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਣੀ ॥ਜਪਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਅਲਖ ਵਿਡਾਣੀ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 285 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਸ) ਨਿੱਕੀ ਜਿਹੀ ਕੀੜੀ ਵਿਚ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਤਾਕਤ ਭਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਲੱਖਾਂ ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਲਸ਼ਕਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਆਹ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ ਦਾ ਸ੍ਵਾਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੱਢਦਾ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੱਥ ਦੇ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਮਨੁੱਖ ਕਈ ਕਿਸਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਜਤਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕੰਮ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।(ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਨਾਹ ਕੋਈ ਮਾਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਨਾਹ ਰੱਖ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੇਡਾ) ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ; ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਣੀ! ਤੂੰ ਕਿਉਂ ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ? ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਅਲੱਖ ਤੇ ਅਚਰਜ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰ ।੫।\\""},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : libros. ","answer":"¿Quién escribió : El Señor de los Anillos? "},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: സ്റ്റാർ വാർസിൽ ലിയ രാജകുമാരിയായി അഭിനയിച്ചത് ആരാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"സ്റ്റാർ വാർസിൽ ലീയ രാജകുമാരിയുടെ വേഷം കാരി ഫിഷർ ചെയ്തു."},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto: Reconocido como uno de los más grandes luchadores en la historia de WWE. Su rivalidad con John Cena ha sido catalogada como uno de los mejores y más largos feudos de WWE. Orton fue el último poseedor del Campeonato Mundial Peso Pesado, el cual unificaría con el Campeonato de WWE para convertirse en el Campeón Mundial Peso Pesado de WWE en de 2013. Además fue ganador del Money in the Bank Ladder Match de 2013, y de la Royal Rumble de 2009 y 2017, Orton también ha encabezado múltiples , incluidos WrestleMania 25 y WrestleMania XXX.","answer":"Que ganaron la competencia del 2017. "},{"question":"La domanda: Quanti anni ha l'attuale presidente dei Philadelphia 76ers?","answer":"La risposta: 49."},{"question":"Wacce farauta ce ta Sharani?","answer":"Farauta ce da yawanci yara ne ke yin ta a dajin da bashi da girma da kuma duhu, yawanci akan yi irin wannan farauta a lokacin rani. Samari da yara masu ƙwazo su ke yin wannan farauta. Sukan kaso dabbobi irin su zomo, bushiya, muzuru, yanyawa, gafiya, maciji da sauran ƙananan dabbobin da ba sa nisa da gari."},{"question":"Kedu ihe ụfọdụ ama ama na omenala Igbo taa?","answer":"Ụfọdụ ihe ndị a ma ama na omenala Igbo taa gụnyere mmemme ọdịnala, mmemme, nka, egwu, na ichekwa asụsụ Igbo, ụdị akwa ndi Igbo n'eyi, ekele, ụdị aha ndị Igbo na-agụ, nri ejiri mara ndị Igbo. "},{"question":"Gadzira unoenderana nemusoro uyu : \\"VanaChiremba Vanoshora Kushandiswa KwePfuti Pakumisa Kuratidzira.\\"","answer":"Sangano ravana chiremba vanorwira kodzero dzevanhu, reZimbabwe Association of Doctors for Human Rights, ZADHR, rashora zvikuru hurumende mukushandiswa kwemabara nemapurisa nemauto mukuedza kumisa vanhu vari kuratidzira. Vanhu muHarare, Epworth, Chitungwiza nedzimwe nzvimbo dzakapoteredza Harare neBulawayo vavhara migwagwa vachipisa matayi emota vachiratidza kutsutsumwa kwavo nekukwidzwa kwakaitwa mafuta emotikari mazuva maviri apfuura. Mutauriri ZADHR, Dr Fortune Nyamande, vaudza Studio 7 kuti vanachiremba vesangano ravo riri kurapa vanhu vazhinji vakuvadzwa mukuratidzira uku. Vaenderera mberi vachiti pane vakuvara, pane vamwe gumi nevatatu vanyanya kukuvadzwa kupfuura vamwe uye vari kutovhiyiwa muzvipatara. Hatina kukwanisa kubata vatauriri vemapurisa nemauto kuti tinzwe divi ravo panyaya iyi. "},{"question":"මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ වර්තමාන අගමැතිවරයා කවුද?","answer":"මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ වර්තමාන අගමැතිවරයා වන්නේ රිෂි සුනාක්"},{"question":"එක් වර්ෂයක් තුළ වැඩිම ලකුණු රැස් කළ ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"එක් වර්ෂයක් තුළ වැඩිම ලකුණු රැස් කළ ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයා පාකිස්තානයේ මොහොමඩ් යූසුෆ් ය."},{"question":"س142 - كم سنة استمرت الحرب بين فرنسا وبريطانيا ؟","answer":"ج142 - 100 عام"},{"question":"Orinasa tsy miankina iza no nahavita nandefa mpanamory sambon-danitra tamin'ny 2020?","answer":"SpaceX, naorin'i Elon Musk, dia nahomby tamin'ny fandefasana mpanamory sambon-danitra ho any amin'ny orbit tamin'ny 2020."},{"question":"Cria um haiku sobre gatos.","answer":"Aqui está um haiku sobre gatos:silêncio pela manhãolhos felinos que conspiram o mundocaos pela noite"},{"question":"Кыргызстанда биринчи акысыз онлайн программалоо курстары - бул чоң жаңылык. Коджаз долбоорунун артыкчылыктары:- Курстар кыргыз тилинде өтүлөт - бул программалоого кызыккан кыргыз тилдүү адамдар үчүн жакшы мүмкүнчүлүк. - Окуу процесси интерактивдүү жана ыңгайлуу. Студенттер өзүнчө окуй алышат.- Курстар программалоону баштап жаткандарга арналган. Интернет байланышы жана браузер гана керек.- Азыркы учурда Python курсу сунушталат. Кийинчерээк башка тилдердеги курстар да кошулмакчы.Бул ишке Мурат Жумашев негиз салган. Мындай пайдалуу долбоор үчүн ал кишини куттуктоого болот. Акысыз онлайн курстар Кыргызстандагы программалоо билимин өнүктүрүүгө чоң салым кошот деп ишенем.Кыргызстандагы алгачкы он-лайн програмдоо курсу эмне деп аталат?","answer":"Коджаз он-лайн програмдоо курсу"},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau bằng cách chọn câu trả lời phù hợp trong các câu dưới đây.Câu hỏi: Rằm tháng 7 còn gọi là Tết gì?A. Tết Thượng NguyênB. Tết Trung NguyênC. Tết Hạ Nguyên","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng là B. Tết Trung NguyênTheo quan niệm dân gian, rằm tháng Giêng hay Tết Nguyên tiêu còn gọi là Tết Thượng Nguyên, vì nguyên tiêu đứng đầu trong Tam nguyên: Thượng Nguyên - Trung Nguyên - Hạ Nguyên. Tết Trung Nguyên là rằm tháng 7 âm lịch. Tết Hạ Nguyên là rằm tháng 10 âm lịch.Ở miền xuôi, khác với hai ngày Tết Thượng Nguyên và Trung Nguyên được chú trọng và tổ chức nhiều hoạt động phong phú, Tết Hạ Nguyên chỉ được các đạo quán và chùa miếu tổ chức tụng kinh cầu nguyện, người dân sẽ đến các chùa miếu để dâng hương cầu an.Với người dân vùng cao, Tết Hạ Nguyên còn được gọi là Lễ mừng lúa mới hay Tết cơm mới. Đây là lễ hội quan trọng trong hệ thống các lễ hội cổ truyền của người dân ở vùng cao, không khác gì ngày Tết Nguyên đán."},{"question":"\\" દુર્જન કાગડો \\" બાળવાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક નદીના કિનારે શંકરનું એક મંદિર હતું. પછવાડે પીપળાનું મોટું ઝાડ. એ ઝાડ ઉપર એક હંસ અને કાગડો રહેતા હતા. કાગડો આ હંસની ખૂબ ઈર્ષા કરે. એને હંસ દીઠે ન ગમે. ઉનાળાના દિવસો હતા. એક થાકેલો-પાકેલો મુસાફર બપોરના સમયે પીપળાના ઝાડ પાસે આવ્યો. તેણે પોતાનાં ધનુષબાણ ઝાડના થડના ટેકે મૂક્યાં ને તે આરામ કરવા ઝાડના છાંયે સૂતો. થોડીવારમાં તે ઘસઘસાટ ઊંઘી ગયો. થોડા સમય પછી એના મોં પરથી ઝાડનો છાંયો જતો રહ્યો ને તેના મોં પર તડકો આવ્યો.ઝાડ ઉપર બેઠેલા હંસને મુસાફરની દયા આવી. મુસાફરના મોં પર તડકો ન આવે તે માટે પોતાની પાંખો પસારી છાંયો કર્યો. કાગડાએ આ જોયું. કાગડાને હંસની આવી ભલાઈ બિલકુલ પસંદ ન આવી. તેણે હંસને ફસાવી દેવાનો પેંતરો રચ્યો. કાગડો ઊડતો ઊડતો આવ્યો અને મુસાફર પર ચરકીને નાસી ગયો.કાગડાની ચરક મુસાફરના મોં પર પડવાથી તે જાગી ગયો. જાગીને તેણે ઉપર હંસને બેઠેલો જોયો. તેને થયું આ હંસ જ મારા પર ચરક્યો લાગે છે. ગુસ્સે થયેલા મુસાફરે હંસને બાણથી વીંધીને પોતાનો ગુસ્સો ઉતાર્યો.આમ દુર્જનની સાથે રહેવાથી પરોપકારી હંસે પોતાનો પ્રાણ ગુમાવ્યો."},{"question":"Lá cờ của đoàn quân nghĩa sĩ do Trần Quốc Toản lập thêu sáu chữ vàng \\"Phá cường địch, báo hoàng ân\\". Nền cờ màu gì?","answer":"nền cờ màu đỏTrần Quốc Toản sau đó về quê cùng người tướng già chiêu mộ binh sĩ, rèn luyện võ nghệ, dựng cờ khởi nghĩa rồi kéo quân đi diệt giặc. Đoàn nghĩa sĩ giương cao lá cờ đỏ, thêu sáu chữ vàng \\"Phá cường địch, báo hoàng ân\\" (phá giặc mạnh, báo ơn vua), liên tiếp lập nhiều chiến công lẫy lừng khiến quân giặc khiếp sợ.Sau đó, Trần Quốc Toản được lệnh đưa đoàn nghĩa sĩ về hội quân tại Vạn Kiếp. Lá cờ \\"Phá cường địch, báo hoàng ân\\" phất phới bay ngang hàng với cờ của các vương hầu khác. Trần Quốc Toản xin được ra trận lập công. Chàng được Hưng Đạo Vương Trần Quốc Tuấn cử làm tướng tiên phong dưới quyền Chiêu Văn Vương Trần Nhật Duật, đưa quân đánh tan đạo quân của Toa Đô ở cửa Hàm Tử.Lá cờ thêu sáu chữ vàng lại tiếp tục dẫn Trần Quốc Toản cùng đoàn nghĩa sĩ \\"đi mãi tới những nơi nào không có bóng quân Nguyên\\".Theo GS Phong Lê, Lá cờ thêu sáu chữ vàng hội đủ những gương mặt tiêu biểu, tượng trưng cho khí phách của vương triều như Trần Quốc Tuấn, Trần Quang Khải, Trần Nhật Duật, Trần Bình Trọng... xung quanh Trần Nhân Tông. Về phía giặc, đó là một loạt nhân vật từ sứ thần Sài Thung, thái tử Thoát Hoan đến viên tướng Toa Đô. Truyện với quy mô nhỏ nhưng bao chứa lượng nhân vật khá lớn - trên cả hai phía.Trần Quốc Toản sau đó về quê cùng người tướng già chiêu mộ binh sĩ, rèn luyện võ nghệ, dựng cờ khởi nghĩa rồi kéo quân đi diệt giặc. Đoàn nghĩa sĩ giương cao lá cờ đỏ, thêu sáu chữ vàng \\"Phá cường địch, báo hoàng ân\\" (phá giặc mạnh, báo ơn vua), liên tiếp lập nhiều chiến công khiến quân giặc khiếp sợ.Sau đó, Trần Quốc Toản được lệnh đưa đoàn nghĩa sĩ về hội quân tại Vạn Kiếp. Lá cờ \\"Phá cường địch, báo hoàng ân\\" phất phới bay ngang hàng với cờ của các vương hầu khác. Trần Quốc Toản xin được ra trận lập công. Chàng được Hưng Đạo Vương Trần Quốc Tuấn cử làm tướng tiên phong dưới quyền Chiêu Văn Vương Trần Nhật Duật, đưa quân đánh tan đạo quân của Toa Đô ở cửa Hàm Tử.Lá cờ thêu sáu chữ vàng tiếp tục dẫn Trần Quốc Toản cùng đoàn nghĩa sĩ \\"đi mãi tới những nơi nào không có bóng quân Nguyên\\".Theo GS Phong Lê, Lá cờ thêu sáu chữ vàng hội đủ những gương mặt tiêu biểu, tượng trưng cho khí phách của vương triều như Trần Quốc Tuấn, Trần Quang Khải, Trần Nhật Duật, Trần Bình Trọng... xung quanh Trần Nhân Tông. Về phía giặc, đó là một loạt nhân vật từ sứ thần Sài Thung, thái tử Thoát Hoan đến viên tướng Toa Đô. Truyện với quy mô nhỏ nhưng bao chứa lượng nhân vật khá lớn - trên cả hai phía."},{"question":"Siapakah yang digelarkan Bapa Perpaduan di Malaysia? ","answer":"Tun Hussein Onn digelarkan Bapa Perpaduan di Malaysia"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'empang sampai ke seberang, dinding sampai ke langit'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perselisihan yang tidak dapat dibaiki atau didamaikan lagi"},{"question":"Por qual país David Beckham jogou?","answer":" De 1992 a 2003, David Beckham jogou pelo Manchester United na Premier League. É o único jogador inglês a ser campeão nacional em quatro países diferentes. Foi campeão inglês no Manchester United, campeão espanhol no Real Madrid, campeão americano no Los Angeles Galaxy e, por último, campeão francês no Paris Saint-Germain, clube na qual anunciou sua aposentadoria ao final da temporada 2012–13."},{"question":"Quốc gia nào ở châu Á có tòa nhà cao nhất thế giới?","answer":"Trả lời: Các tiểu vương quốc Arab Thống nhấtTòa nhà Burj Khalifa ở thành phố Dubai, Các tiểu vương quốc Arab Thống nhất (UAE), được Tổ chức Kỷ lục thế giới Guinness xác nhận là tòa nhà cao nhất thế giới. Với chiều cao 828 m, Burj Khalifa cao hơn gấp đôi chiều cao của tòa nhà Empire State, Mỹ, và gần gấp ba lần kích thước của tháp Eiffel, Pháp, theo Guinness World Records.Tòa nhà 163 tầng được đặt theo tên của Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, tổng thống UAE. Lấy ý tưởng từ kiến trúc Hồi giáo, tòa tháp hoàn thành từ năm 2009 hiện giữ nhiều kỷ lục về kiến trúc như công trình thẳng đứng cao nhất thế giới, tòa nhà nhiều tầng nhất, thang máy trong nhà cao nhất, đài quan sát ngoài trời cao nhất."},{"question":"Porto-Novo mooy péeyu ban réew?","answer":"Porto-Novo mooy péeyu réewum Bénin."},{"question":"යාන්ත්‍රික තරංග ප්‍රධාන ආකාර 2 කි. ඒවා මොනවාද?","answer":"යාන්ත්‍රික තරංග ප්‍රධාන ආකාර 2 කි. ඒවා නම්, තීර්යක් තරංග හා අන්වායාම තරංග වේ."},{"question":"Arak'ity lahatsoratra manaraka ity, milazà toe-tsaina ananan'ny mpiasa izay mahatonga ny asany tsy ho lavorary.Tsy anisan' ny zatovo nahazo vatsim-pianarana na avy amin'ny fanjakana na avy amin' ny fikambanana ny tena. Ho sarotra ny ahita asa any amin'ny fanjakana avy hatrany amin' izao fotoana izao toy izay miseho isan'andro. Ho tsara kokoa ny manangana asa mahaleo tena sao dia voarohirohy amin' ny asam-birao mandavan-taona ka any aoriana any tsy hitady afa tsy ny fiandrasan-karama hisondrotra isan-taona. Ho fanetribe izany, indrindra raha tsy hifanentana amin'izay fianarana natao ny asa hosahanina. Raha mba mahazo toerana ambonimbony ka omena andraikitra mifanitsy amin'ny fari-pahaizana kosa dia « akohokely notsipazam-potsimbary aho ary hotratrariko ny lanitra raha ho tratrako ! ».Raha mba tonga ny andro ankehitriny ka izay nahavita fianarana dia azo antoka fa hahazo asa avy hatrany dia hiadana ny sarambabem-bahoaka, handry ivohon'ny vato ny tanora vao misondrotra. Asa rahoviana no ho tonga izany ? Raha tsy tonga amin'ny androko dia iriko indrindra mba ho tonga amin'ny andron-janako atsy ho atsy kokoa. « Afaka hifandrindra koa ve ny raharaham-barotra izay hampivezivezy ahy sy ny asan' ny mpampivelona izay antsoina andro dia andro, antsoina alina dia alina? Atao ahoana ny ankizy ? » Tsy maintsy haka mpanampy izahay satria tsy ho zakany no sady tsy atao ny mandevin-talenta ka hamono ny asa izay efa niomanany an-taona maro. Aina ny asa, iankinan'ny aina ny asa, esory amin'ny olona ny asa raha tianao ny hamono azy.","answer":"Arakan ny lahatsoratra, ireo toe-tsaina ananan'ny mpiasa izay mahatonga ny asany tsyho lavorary dia ny toe-tsaina tsy hitady afa tsy fisondrotan-karama ary ny toe-tsaina mitady ny asa tsy antonona ny fari-pahaizan' ny tena."},{"question":"శత్రర్థకము గురించి రాసి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"శత్రర్థకము - వర్తమాన అసమాపక క్రియను శత్రర్థకము అని అంటారు.ఉదా :రాము తింటూ వింటున్నాడు.అమ్మ వండుతూ చదువుతున్నది.లత పాడుతూ నటిస్తున్నది.శ్రీను పాఠం వింటూ రాస్తున్నాడు."},{"question":"س121 - كم سعرة حرارية في الماء ؟","answer":"ج121 - لاشيء"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'rajin seperti semut'? Berikan satu contoh ayat untuk.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang rajin bekerja. Contoh ayat: Walaupun dia tidak berpelajaran tinggi, namun kehidupannya senang kerana dia rajin seperti semut."},{"question":"Menene dalilin da shugaban Nigeria Bola Ahmed Tinubu ya cire sunan Dr. Maryam Shetty acikin jerin sunayen ministoci daya aika Majalisar ƙasa","answer":"An cire sunanta ne saboda dalilai na siyasa"},{"question":"तपाईलाई येशु को बारेमा थाहा छ?","answer":"येशु, जसलाई पनि येशु ख्रिस्ट, येशु मसीह, या ख्रिस्ती धर्ममा जस्तै चर्चा गरिने गरिइन्छ, ख्रिस्टीत बाच्नुहुन्छ भने, एक प्रमुख धार्मिक पर्वका आधारमा ख्रिस्तियताको पूजा गरिने गरिएको व्यक्ति हो। उहाँले बिबलमा लेखिएका उपदेश र गरेका कामहरूका आधारमा उनको शिक्षा र मिशनलाई प्रमुख बनाएका छन्।ख्रिस्ती धर्मका अनुसरण गर्दा, येशु ख्रिस्टले परमेश्वरको पुत्रको रूपमा आफ्नो जीवन दिनुभएको मान्छे मानिएको छ। उहाँले धार्मिक शिक्षाहरू प्रदान गरेका थिए र उनको शिक्षा, उपदेश, र जीवनका घटनाहरूले ख्रिस्टी धर्मको मूल बाट बिकास गरेको छ।ख्रिस्टियतामा, येशुले पापको मुक्ति प्रदान गर्नका लागि आफ्नो जीवन त्याग गरेका थिएका छन् र उहाँको जन्म र मृत्युले ख्रिस्टी धर्मका अनुसरण गर्दा प्राथमिक दर्शनीय घटनाहरूमा समाहित गराइएको छ।"},{"question":"(ephakamisa ikhanda) Sekunguwe njalo baba?(sakuncokola) Ubuza ibhasi libhaliwe?(naye athi ukumamatheka) Hawu! Kanti wena sewaba yibhasi? (bahlekebobabili)(ahlale kwesinye isihlalo) Uboshiwe ngempela uDlamini. Kusasa uzoyakobingelela imantshi.Ashile! Kuhle-ke uma eboshiwe. (athule kancane)Nginovadlwana kodwa mina baba.Kodwa! Kodwa! Uvadlwana! Yini manje?(ngokuzithoba) Baba! Igazi likaMbandlwa lichithekile, induna yaboshwa.Konke lokhu akusho lutho kuwe?(ngolaka) Uthini manje? Mina ngibona kuzobathambisa ukuboshwakwenduna.(aphakamise izwi nomoya wakhe wenyuke) Hhayi bo! Ubathathakancane wena abantu bakule ndawo. Uyakhumbula ngesikhathi sodlame?Iningi labantu balapha bayayithanda inkosi futhi bayayihlonipha. (ehliseumoya) Baba, ngicela ukubone lokhu engikushoyo. Mina bengingacabangiukuthi lesi simo sizoze sifike kuleli banga esesikulo. Uyabona, nenja umaikhonkotha uke unganaki. Wethuke uphele uma isizifikela ngamazinyokuwe. Baba, izwe lizobheduka. Mina ngibona kungcono wena uzehliseenkosini noma uyeke kwabona ubukhansela lobu.(ethukuthela) Hheyi! Hheyi! Kanti usudleni wena? Lezi zinto ozishoyozombili angizamukeli! Lungamane luchitheke uphoko! Lutho mfazi! Ngeke!(enyuke ngolaka naye) Ubani umfazi weBafana? Ubiza mina ngomfazi?Wena awufuni ukuboniswa! Ngiyakutshela, uyongikhumbula seluchithekilelolu phoko lwakho.(abhoke kakhulu) Uzwa kanjani wena! Angisilo ivaka mina! Futhi, vala lomlonyana wakho singaze sethusane.1. Uboshelweni uDlamini?","answer":"Uboshelwe ukushaya uMbandlwa"},{"question":"株式会社リネンが発表した「2017年心に残った音」の調査では、第1位に「これ」のサイレンの音が選ばれている、2017年8月と9月に北朝鮮からミサイルが飛来した際にも発動された、正式名称を「全国瞬時警報システム」と言うものを、通称「何」アラートというでしょう？","answer":"J（アラート）です。"},{"question":" Qual técnico português comandava o time do Flamengo na final do Mundial Interclubes em 2019, contra a equipe inglesa do Liverpool?","answer":"Jorge de Jesus."},{"question":"Inona ny fanavaozana ara-kolontsaina italiana ?","answer":"Ny fanavaozana ara-kolontsaina italiana dia vanim-potoana fanavaozana ara-javakanto, literatiora ary ara-tsaina tany Italia tamin'ny taonjato faha-14 sy faha-15. Nahitana ny fipoiran'ireo mpanakanto malaza toa an'i Leonardo da Vinci, Michelangelo ary Raphael, izay namorona sanganasan-kanto malaza toa ny Mona Lisa, ny fresco Chapel Sistine ary ny Sekolin'i Atena. Ny Renaissance Italiana koa dia nampiroborobo ny fivoaran'ny siansa, filozofia ary literatiora."},{"question":"Ngwala go tšwela pele ga serapa se - Tang o ile a tšeela Liu legato ka makgaolakganyeng ka moka ka morago ga go tlogela ga Liu. Go sa šetšwe go swanelega go ba maemong a bo-21 go bohle, ka ge a be a tšea sebaka sa maemo a botshelela Liu, o ile a bewa sehlopheng sa godimo sa go dikologa. Tang o ile a dira dipapadi tše nne tše maatla go thopa sefoka sa silibera sa go makatša ka go dikologa ka moka ka morago ga nkgwete ya lefase ya makga a mahlano Simone Biles wa United States le pele ga Dipapadi tša Yuropa tša 2019","answer":"Mofenyi Angelina Melnikova wa Russia. O ile a ngwala palo ya bobedi ye e phagamego kudu ya letšatši ka morago ga ya Biles. Mafelelo a a swaya go bewa ga godimo ga moatlelete wa mosadi wa mo-China ka go Dikgaisano tša Lefase goba histori ya Olympic, go bapetšwa le mafelelo a bobedi a Jiang Yuyuan ka Dikgaisano tša Lefase tša 2010. Gape e be e le tšhipi ya mathomo ya go kgabaganya ka moka yeo e thopilwego ke mosadi wa mo-China mo maemong a Lefase goba a Olimpiki go tloga ka tšhipi ya Yao Jinnan ya bronze go Dikgaisano tša Lefase tša 2011."},{"question":"Joxeel péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Noonu la Nu'y faye rafetalkat yi.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Noonu la Nu'y faye rafetalkat yi.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Noonu: ADVla: AUXNu: PRON'y: AUXfaye: VERBrafetalkat: NOUNyi: DET.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Công an yêu cầu dân trả lại vàng rơi vãi tại hiện trường vụ cướp","answer":"Công an TP Huế vừa phát thông báo đề nghị người dân nhặt được vàng có liên quan đến vụ cướp bằng súng tại chợ Đông Ba phải giao nộp cho cơ quan công an. Việc này nhằm phục vụ hoạt động điều tra của cơ quan công an, cũng như hoàn trả lại cho người bị hại sau khi kết thúc vụ việc. \\"Những trường hợp không trả lại tài sản liên quan đến vụ việc sẽ bị xử lý nghiêm theo quy định của pháp luật\\", Công an TP Huế nhấn mạnh. Như Dân trí đã thông tin, khoảng 13h ngày 31/7, một người đàn ông mang theo súng đến khu vực kinh doanh vàng tại chợ Đông Ba. Người này nổ nhiều phát súng phá tủ rồi cướp một lượng lớn vàng tại tiệm Thái Lợi và Hoàng Đức. Trong quá trình bị truy đuổi, người này ném nhiều vàng ra đường. Một số lượng lớn vàng rơi vãi khắp nơi trên đường phố, mắc tận các cành cây cao. Ngay sau khi kẻ cướp bị bắt giữ, lực lượng chức năng tổ chức thu gom vàng rơi vãi. Tuy nhiên, trước đó người dân cũng nhặt được nhiều vàng rơi vãi và giao nộp cho cơ quan chức năng."},{"question":"Unogona here kuronga kuti timu yega yega yeNFL inodaidzwa nezita?","answer":"\\"Arizona Cardinals - MhukaAtlanta Falcons - MhukaBaltimore Ravens - MhukaMabhiri eBuffalo - Akatumidzwa zita reBuffalo Bill CodyCarolina Panthers - MhukaChicago Bears - MhukaCincinnati Bengals - MhukaCleveland Browns - Akatumidzwa mushure meMurairidzi Mukuru Paul BrownDallas Cowboys - Yakatumidzwa zita revarume vanofudza mombeDenver Broncos - MhukaDetroit Shumba - MhukaGreen Bay Packers - Yakatumidzwa mushure mekutanga mutsigiri wechikwata, Indian Packing CompanyHouston Texans - Yakatumidzwa zita revanhu vanogara muTexasIndianapolis Colts - MhukaJacksonville Jaguars - MhukaKansas City Chiefs - Yakatumidzwa zita reaimbova meya weKansas CityLas Vegas Raiders - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anorwisa muvengi wavoLos Angeles Charger - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anoenda kumberi nesimba uye nesimbaLos Angeles Rams - MhukaMiami Dolphins - MhukaMinnesota Vikings - Yakatumidzwa zita reboka revanhu vanobva kuScandinaviaNew England Patriots - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anotsigira nyika yavoNew Orleans Saints - Inonzi mushure memunhu uyo zvitendero zvinoziva semutsvene uye akanakaNew York Giants - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu wehukuru hwakasiyanaNew York Jets - Yakatumidzwa zita rejet ndegePhiladelphia Eagles - MhukaPittsburgh Steelers - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anoshanda mufekitori yesimbiSan Francisco 49ers - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu akatora chikamu muGoridhe RushSeattle Seahawks - MhukaTampa Bay Buccaneers - Yakatumidzwa mushure memuparadziTennessee Titans - Inonzi zita remunhu ane simba kwazvoWashington Commanders - Anonzi mushure memunhu muuto\\""},{"question":"चन्द्र धरातलमा पाईला टेक्ने पहिलो अन्तरिक्ष यात्री निल अल्डेन आर्मस्टङ चन्द्र धरातलमा कहिले पुगेका थिए ?","answer":"निल अल्डेन आर्मस्टङ चन्द्र धरातलमा सन् १९६९ जुलाई २१ मा पुगेका थिए ।"},{"question":"अगर राष्ट्रपति पद रिक्त होता है, तो उसे कितनी अवधि के भीतर भरना आवश्यक होता है?","answer":"राष्ट्रपति पद रिक्त होने के बाद, उसे 6 महीने के अंदर भरना आवश्यक होता है।"},{"question":"Mẹ tôi 77 tuổi, là bệnh nhân COPD. Hiện nay 1 lá phổi hỏng, 1 lá còn 60%, phải thở oxy bằng máy tạo oxy cá nhân, hiện chưa dám tiêm vaccine Covid-19. Vậy mẹ tôi có thể được tiêm kháng thể đơn dòng này không ạ. Nếu có thì thủ tục đăng ký như nào ạ. Xin cảm ơn.","answer":"Mẹ bạn tuổi đã cao, chỉ còn 1 lá phổi hoạt động 60% do mắc COPD phải thở oxy như vậy hàng rào miễn dịch bảo vệ phổi của mẹ bạn đã giảm sút nhiều, lại chưa tiêm vaccine khi mắc Covid-19 thì nguy cơ sẽ trở nặng nguy hại đến tính mạng. Do vậy, kháng thể đơn dòng ngừa Covid-19 sẽ cung cấp kháng thể nhanh kịp thời cho mẹ bạn và được bảo về từ 6-12 tháng"},{"question":"问题：冰块的保质期是多久？","answer":"回答：冰块没有特定的保质期，但长时间冷冻会导致冰块质量下降，失去新鲜感。"},{"question":"Lanjutkan penggalan teks di bawah ini sehingga menjadi sebuah paragraf utuh dan runtun dari cerita pendek anak-anak.Judul: Singa dan Tikus.Suatu hari, ada seekor singat yang sedang tertidur. Lalu, seekor tikus melewati badannya. Sang singa pun terbangun dan ...Jawaban:","answer":"menangkapnya. Tikus memohon agar singa melepaskannya dan berjanji akan membalas kebaikannya. \\"Apabila kamu mau melepaskanku, aku akan berbuat kebaikan untukmu.\\" kata tikus. Mendengar kalimat tersebut, singa tertawa geli. Meski karena kasihan, ia pun memutuskan untuk melepaskan tikus itu pergi. Beberapa hari kemudian, seorang pemburu menangkap singa dan mengikatnya dengan tali. Mendengar singa mengaum kesakitan, tikus berlari dan mengigit talinya hingga putus. Singa pun berhasil bebas berkat bantuan si tikus. \\"Apakah kamu ingat dulu kamu tertawa dan berpikir aku tidak bisa berbuat sebuah kebaikan? Sekarang kamu lihat. Seekor tikus bisa berbuat baik,\\" tutur tikus."},{"question":"Buatlah pertanyaan dari jawaban berikut.Jawaban:Program sarjana (S1) Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS) menyediakan 37 pilihan program studi yang dapat dipilih berdasarkan 9 bidang Fakultas.Berdasarkan https://www.its.ac.id/id/kuliah-di-its/fakultas-dan-departemen/ per 12 September 2023, Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS) memiliki total 9 fakultas, di antaranya adalah:1. FAKULTAS SAINS DAN ANALITIKA DATA (FSAD) dengan 6 departemen atau program studi, yaitu: Fisika, Matematika, Statistika, Kimia, Biologi, dan Aktuaria.2. FAKULTAS TEKNOLOGI KELAUTAN (FTK) dengan 4 program studi, yaitu: Teknik Perkapalan, Teknik Sistem Perkapalan, Teknik Kelautan, dan Teknik Transportasi Laut.3. FAKULTAS TEKNOLOGI INDUSTRI DAN REKAYASA SISTEM (FT-IRS) dengan 5 program studi, yaitu: Teknik Mesin, Teknik Kimia, Teknik Fisika, Teknik Sistem dan Industri, dan Teknik Material.4. FAKULTAS TEKNOLOGI ELEKTRO DAN INFORMATIKA CERDAS (FT-EIC) dengan 6 program studinya, yaitu: Teknik Elektro, Teknik Biomedik, Teknik Komputer, Teknik Informatika, Sistem Informasi, Teknologi Informasi.5. FAKULTAS TEKNIK SIPIL, PERENCANAAN, DAN KEBUMIAN (FT-SPK) dengan 6 program studinya, yaitu: Teknik Sipil, Arsitektur, Teknik Lingkungan, Perencanaan Wilayah dan Kota, Teknik Geomatika, Teknik Geofisika.6. FAKULTAS DESAIN KREATIF DAN BISNIS DIGITAL (F-DKBD) dengan 6 program studinya, yaitu: Desain Produk Industri, Desain Interior, Desain Komunikasi Visual, Manajemen Bisnis, Studi Pembangunan, Manajemen Teknologi.7. FAKULTAS VOKASI (FV), dengan 6 program studi, yaitu: Teknik Infrastruktur Sipil, Teknik Mesin Industri, Teknik Elektro Otomasi, Teknik Kimia Industri, Teknik Instrumentasi, Statistika Bisnis.8. SEKOLAH INTERDISIPLIN MANAJEMEN DAN TEKNOLOGI dengan 1 program studi, yaitu: Manajemen Teknologi.9. FAKULTAS KEDOKTERAN DAN KESEHATAN dengan 3 program studi, yaitu: Teknologi Kedokteran, Kedokteran, Pendidikan Profesi Dokter.Pertanyaan:","answer":"Pertanyaan yang sesuai untuk jawaban tersebut adalah:Berapa jumlah fakultas di Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS) Surabaya yang menawarkan program sarjana (S1)? Sebutkan nama-nama fakultas tersebut beserta bidang studinya masing-masing!"},{"question":"¿Cúal es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿De quién fue la presidencia más breve de los Estados Unidos?","answer":"El tema principal es Historia de Estados Unidos. "},{"question":" sheeg kaadida bili'aadanka imisa ayaa biyo ah","answer":" jawab. kaadida bili'aadanka waxa biyo ah 95%."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini:  Bom apakah tidak boleh meletup?","answer":"Jawapan : Bomba"}]`),M={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:I},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:x,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},C={class:"search-container"},B={class:"card-container"},K=["disabled"],O={key:0},D={key:1};function L(e,a,s,d,t,u){const g=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",C,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",B,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,m)=>(i(),f(g,{key:m,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",D,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",O,"See more"))],8,K)):j("",!0)])}const P=h(M,[["render",L],["__scopeId","data-v-011520c2"]]),G=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"people/6.md","filePath":"people/6.md"}'),E={name:"people/6.md"},W=Object.assign(E,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(P)]))}});export{G as __pageData,W as default};
